<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
52a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
May 12, 1940.
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>We rec'd your letters and were very happy for them.</p>
<p>We're glad you liked the pansies &amp; dresses, Mom. Those are the best grade of pansies one can get.</p>
<p>Dad, you must have been very tired but you certainly didn't act it. You will no doubt be rested up soon. I think a trip is really wearing on one.</p>
<p>We hope we'll be seeing Sig one of these days. We do think he could get something up here.</p>
<p>Ol is on vacation now for 3 weeks! And <underline>are we</underline> happy?! We startedit off with a baby today by planting a tubful of perennials we got out at Ol's brother's in Henton: larkspur, cornflowers, African daises, Enlgish daises, jonquils, hibisbus,</p>
2
<p>mixed iris, mised mums, <underline>one</underline> wild pansy plant, etc. Our wisteria is sending out leaves now &amp; we're going to make a trellis for it on the east side of the porch. The two ivy plants we got from home &amp; planted at the fireplace chimney are both sending out shoots. Won't be long before they'll be on their way up the chimney. We're going to make an arbor over the steps to the house from the driveway &amp; have a reabler planted there already to climb over it. Our Scarlet O'Hara (red) &amp; Heavenly Blue Morning glories are up now &amp; we intend to put them on a trellis as well. We don't like vines right on the house. When you come up in June, I believe there'll be something to see here. We <underline>hope</underline> to start buying the place sooner than fall, possible, if all goes well in July. It has great possibilities, we think. And, we have it all planned how we want to fix it. Dad saw our "blueprint"!</p>
<p>We expect to get a lot done on the place during this vacation. It's</p>
52b
3
<p>pretty hard to leave a place you're so interested in, especially during this time of year when so much of importance can be accomplished when Ol's home. We're going to plant a couple silver maples on the east edge of the lot between the last front maple &amp; the far back maple. This will complete our boundary marking &amp; will be an addition as well. Mrs. H. has a <sic>flack</sic> of them in the back yard of one of her rented houses.</p>
<p>I hope this hasn't been too "house &amp; yardy"! But we're just wra[[ed up in this place, so you'll probably excuse us.</p>
<p>Ol's getting several more things tomorrow. He'll have it in his letter herewith.</p>
<p>Mom, Ol says you never address letters to him - but <unclear>pist</unclear> to me, so that's why he's addressing his to Dad! Guess</p>
4
<p>he feels he shouldn't address them to you cause you don't to him! Funny?!! Ha, ha! -But he's writing to you too, he says! He's a funny boy! No, he's swell &amp; perfect!</p>
<p>Haven't seen Hil &amp; Al just lately. Guess we will fairly soon <sic>tho'</sic>. We met Max one <sic>nite</sic> when we took in Hil's pillow &amp; quilt - just outside - Couldn't tell much what he was like in the dark! But he seems very nice.</p>
<p>Letters are so unsatisfactory, I always feel, when I finish one! A talk is far better! So you must come up sooner than possible!</p>
<p>Ol met a fellow at P.D. who said he knew Thelma Mewe &amp; she was asking where the Neihardts were &amp; wanted to get in touch with me. Ol &amp; I will go out &amp; see her soon. She's married, you know, &amp; has a kid or two.</p>
Loads <sic>o'</sic> love, always,
<underline>Enid</underline>
52c
fink
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 1
MAY13
6<underline>30</underline>PM
1940
BUY U.S. SAVINGS
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER
UNITED STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3
Dr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
Taney County
