<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
192 Fink Collection 66
NORFOLK
OCT 12
2 PM
1940
NEBR.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo. St. Louis County
67
Norfolk, Neb.
33 miles from
Wayne.
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Please get the letters I have written to Southwood, as it is hard to write the same thing twice and I was thinking of <underline>all</underline> of you dear children when I wrote there.</p>
<p>What I say is not important excepting that it Keeps us all closer together to hear than not to do so.</p>
<p>Enid we came through the place where you had to stop on your way to Kearney because of car trouble, and Daddy told me all about the trying thing it was for you both! Kearney has never been decent to Dad since! Is that not petty?! I'd hate to be head of a college and not be able to understand that even reliable <underline>could</underline> under certain circumstances <underline>have</underline> to miss an engagement, wouldn't you? - So we drove through Kearney where Daddy used to lecture, with no engagement this time although they could have gotten Daddy at cut rates <strike/>!</p>
<p>We are now in the cabin</p>
68
<p>where Daddy and I stayed when he finished the Messiah! It is nice to be back, and since the whole camp is empty right now, it is as though we were in our own estate quiet and comfortable. A grand place for Daddy to rest up. <underline>I</underline> am of course not tired and am enjoying myself in my own way!</p>
<p>Enid please tell me what pieces you most need and in what colors to continue your set of dishes that <underline>we</underline> started for you. <underline>Please do this</underline>, because I intend to get some additional pieces for your dear birthday, the 23rd, and if you do not tell me I shall get the wrong ones (as I have forgotten what you told me when I was with you), and that would be such a pity. so be good and tell me the truth!</p>
<p>We were sorry not to hear from you at Boulder nor Denver. Maybe we will have that pleasure at Wayne.</p>
<p>Daddy is not able to write on this trip so we are getting in a hurry to go home where he <underline>can</underline> do so.</p>
69
<p>Mr Davison asked me especially to remember him to each one of you children as he had a lovely memory of you all. Do you remember when Daddy had him out to dinner at Kirkwood? It was on Clay. I could not recall his visit, but Knew him as soon as I saw his face. His wife is very dear and sweet and certainly was lovely to us all. They have a big beautiful house of the older variety of stone city houses. It is indeed a wonderful Home - but Oh, I like <underline>ours</underline> so much better!! They have a maid etc and that I dislike so intensely too. It seems as though they could not get at the stuff of life directly enough. Truly such women are terribly handicapped! They spend hours and hours telephoning and entertaining and doing utterly silly things that in no way adds to their family's pleasure nor comfort. In fact, they do not live in a "<unclear/>" way at all. Mr Davison would <underline>so</underline> have loved the simple life too. I thought about you and Ollie, and how</p>
70
<p>for superior <underline>your</underline> way was to theirs!</p>
<p>They are caught in the net of things as they are, and have not individuality enough to do some other way even though the <underline>Poet</underline> would thrive by that other way! As it is, they love each other but both are dissatisfied, especially Mrs D. This is confidential for you, I'm just talking to you two dear children!</p>
<p>Daddy is sleeping as I sit here and just now he's waking up so I'll get the dinner on the table now!</p>
Loads of love and best wishes for that baby-plan -
from you devoted
Mama - Mother. 