<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
33a
9917 Emerson Ave. 
Overland, Mo.
April 30, 1940.
Dearest Mom:-
<p>We're at this moment having one of those lovely "warm" spring thunderstorms. When I say warm, I mean the kind that just does miracles for plants. Nite before last we had out first warm rain &amp; it simply did a wonderful thing to the whole outdoors! Everything leaped into greenery over nite. This second real warm rain will probably make a heaven and of things up here Our lawn is gorgeously green &amp; a bit past the time when it should have been cut. We're going to buy a mower from Ol's brother soon.</p>
<p>Today I planted out all our geraniums' on the last side of the sunroom. Also I planted the Swiss flowers Hil gave us. She took you some seeds too, I believe. Our peas are over an inch high &amp; our radishes will possibly be ready to eat when the folks come by again.</p>
<p>Mrs. Harrison's sister gave us a double bed with springs - very nice. When we get a new mattress for our bed we'll use the one on it for the bed she dave us. We've put it upstairs. So you see, it'll be handy for when you &amp; Dad come up as well as when Hil &amp; Al come out on week-ends. I have a very cute idea for fixing the attic up. Ol &amp; I want to fix it with celotex when we buy it. Then we want to put beds in the eaves wtih</p>
2
<p>drapes that may be pulled when someone is sleeping in there. That would accomodate at least two beds &amp; we'd make a small room out of the east end of the atti, which could serve as a closed bedroom.</p>
<p>Just made a cherry pie.</p>
-Several days have elapsed!-
May 4, 1940.
<p>Just rec'd your last letter, Mom, &amp; as usual were delighted to get it.</p>
<p>Ol's Mom is here with us till Monday v we're having a nice visit.</p>
<p>Last evening we went in to see how Hil &amp; Al are doing. They were well settled for the little time they've been in the apt. Hil had given the wicker set another coat to touch it up, as ell as the rocker. The set is simply lovely, Mom, &amp; we surely think it's beautiful in their place. We took that quilt Aunt Lu sent Alice that you had made for Grandma and Hil's two pillows that were here, in to them. Yes, I hope to help Hilda with her varnish work on her table. I also intend to make her drapes for her as soon as she decides on the material &amp; whether or not she thinks she can buy them ready-made to better advantage or not. I probably will get to go in this next week somtime to hlep her with the varnishing of her table &amp; chairs. You see, I can't well go while Ol's Mom is here. But after Mon. I can. Tuesday Hil &amp; Al are coming out for dinner when Dad, Sig &amp; Max come thru again.</p>
<p>About the ad in the P.D. Ol says he believes an ad of that sort would be 50<cent/> or very little</p>
33b
3
<p>more &amp; that it would be best to give the box no. at the P.D. If we gave our number, which is an out-of-town exchange, people would be apt to keep from calling if it was necessary to pay the nickel! That's funny, but just such things will stop people from answering! Ol suggests having the box no. listed in the ad &amp; then he'll collect the plies &amp; send them right to you &amp; Dad to look over. Doesn't this sound sensible to you? We'll mention it to Dad when he comes thru, shall we? And then Ol can put the ad in. Dad looked at a house whcih is for sale in the neighborhood, but they wanted a bigger price than he'd expected for it. However, Dad like th house very much &amp; will probably talk to you abou tit when he sees you in a day or two. There are others around here for sale that perhaps would be even nicer &amp; more to the satisfaction of you &amp; Dad I think. But, of course the thing to do now, is to sell the Branson place - then you can have almost any thing you want within reason when you have the cash!! So, if you &amp; Dad want it, Ol will put the ad in the P.D.</p>
<p>It'd be great to have you both up here. You &amp; Dad should have a place taht is just right for the two of you. Then, you &amp; Dad could do the things you want to do together. Dad could have some means of support for just you two. It is going to be necessary sooner or later for Sig to have his very own means of support for his family, isn't it? So, if he could <strike>get</strike> concentrate on getting a job of his own, which I know he wants to do sonner or later, everything would be fine. And, by being around here, he'd have the chance to grab anything that would show up. And, by bing way off there in Branson, he hasn't a chance. Sig &amp; Max were talking with me one day &amp; saying that they'd rather be near to</p>
4
<p>where they might be in contact with opportunities. Gee, it'd be great to have you all nearer to us! Then we could see each other oftener than one in a blue moon! And I agree with you, Mom, life <underline>is</underline> too short for you to be way off from us kids. And, we do miss you &amp; Dad a whole of a lot!</p>
<p>Was so nice you say Judge! How is he? I'll bet he was glad to see one of the Neihardts again.</p>
<P>We just mowed our lawn today. Got a nice mower form Ol's brother, Art. Ol got her mroe roses the other day. We're going to plant them tomorrow. Also we're going to fix up our Sinnia &amp; dahlia bed in the back.</P>
<p>Mom, I haven't as yet had the chance to make any dresses for Al. I've been making other things. But I have a costume pattern &amp; was intending to make her a couple costumes as soon as she got the material. IF you want the pattern &amp; have material to make them with, I'll send the pattern on to you. It requires about 13/<cent/> yds of 39" material, I believe. Either way is okay with me.</p>
<p>Wish you were here! Maybe you can come up <underline>soon</underline> to visit awhile. Do you think you could? We'd surely love to see you!</p>
Loads o' love, to the <underline>best</underline> of Mothers from
Enid &amp; Ollie
<p>We won't forget to get Dad to fix up an Ad! That might mean a lot! Ol thinks you should advertise in K.C. Star too! So do I.</p>
Love, 
Eny
33c
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH <underline>Fink</underline>
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 4
MAY 5
1230PM
1940
UNITED 
STATES 
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3
Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
<underline>Taney Co.</underline>