<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
149 Neihardt Collection 23
[Summer 1941]
[July 26, 1941]
Saturday Afternoon
Dearest Daddy and Mama!
<p>It is nearly time for dinner, but perhaps I can write you a few words first. Sig and I practiced awhile this afternoon, and we plan to do so tomorrow again. Is that not wonderful? It is such fun and means so much to me to sing with Sigurd and get his suggestions.</p>
<p>After coming home this afternoon, I sent off a seed order - by return mail - an example of <unclear>Hanbensak</unclear> service. Max says the seed business sould grow so that I can quit my job at the Cousulate and "devote 5/6 of my time to singing." Which would not be too bad would it?</p>
<p>We have been busy, particularly so, at the office of late, in the main because of the forthcoming 650th Anniversary. But it is so pleasant in the office now; one truly enjoys 78<symbol = "degree"/> when it is 100 <symbol = "degree"/> or</p>
24
<p>even more on the street outside! We regulate our temperature quite well now, and I think I am a bit used to the change now that is experienced upon going out.</p>
<p>Albert and I are going to Mung Opera this evening, for the first time this year, to see "Diva Rosa", a play about South American and, I understand, full of lovely music and dances.</p>
<p>Alice's birthday comes soon. I imagine you will bake and send her a fancy cake? If you need decorations, tell me, and I'll get them for you here. She will be thrilled to get a cake - I remember how I was always so happy to get the cake you sent <underline>me</underline> when I was away. to me nothing can mean more than those things. I have sent Alice some more dollars, so she is all right in that reguest. Alice has made me fell so good by writing me lovely letters.</p>
25
<p>How are you two dears feeling? I miss both of you very much and see your lovely, lighted faces before me so often. There is something about each of you that is wonderful beyond my power to express. Perhaps I am included to love you just the <underline>least</underline> bit!</p>
<p>Write me very soon, please!</p>
<p>I hope you have a fine time at <unclear>Gillespie's</unclear>!</p>
Endlessly loves you,
your Hilda
<p>Al's ring surely looks fine with that <unclear>cameo</unclear>!!</p>