<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
37
Fink Collection 
59-60
Norfolk Neb. 
NORFOLK JUN27 3 PM 1935 NEBR. 
<unclear/> 
The Neihardts. 
Branson, Mo. 
Taney County. 

38
Norfolk, Neb. 
Thursday
Dearest Girls:
It was so much like going to Heaven or some thing equally joyful - to re-ceive your good letters this A.M.! I feel happy about all of you and so much relieved! I'm sure the home is being kept just fine, and that you are all really in good shape
and contented - and I am intensely grateful and appreciative. As for Sigurd's good prospects in Harrison - well that is simp ly marvelous, and it makes me more happy than I can say - but I am eager now to hear from him and from Maxi - I have not had a single live from Max 'yet and I do hope this does not mean that she is feeling poorly. I dreamed of her and talked aloud in my sleep to her 

39
Daddy heard me tell her a lot of things that I meant to be helpful! 
I'm glad you, Hilda, are at home. Your time is better spent reading, and my advise with regard to your teeth is this: Ask Sigurd to take you along with him to Berryville. And while there find the dentist who does such excellent work in making false teeth. Call Mr Harine, and ask him to direct you to him. I was the person who directed him there, but I don't know the name - He was well pleased with that <del>ST.</del> Dentist, as everyone else has been that I know of. Find out what the Berryville man thinks and advises you to have done, and if he will undertake the job, find out what he will charge, and then write to Daddy and tell him all about it. Please do this. 
Enid, your letter is a peach; both Daddy and I are very proud 

40
of the special quality that is yoiurs, and that will make you indespensible to the right man I told you, did I not, that Mrs Conn got Dr Conn to write to Mr Mac Eachan? Dr and Mrs Conn have gone to Indi ana to settle an estate. They left Wayne a few minutes before we did. Mrs Conn is eager to get you a good posi-tion. As soon as Daddy finish 

es the Messiah he will be planning other things - and I trust you and he may do that trip together - but I also feel that we shoudl not leave any stone un-turned which might assist you do a real-ly good position. If the Wayne job works out - I believe you could go on that trip before the new term begins. In any case good things are in store 

41
for you; Never doubt that. 
Hilda dear, I meant to say that Daddy and I both think Miss Sche-mel easily the finest personality of the very fine faculty members. 
Do please plan to take Physics under Mr Brock - as he knows his field and loves it - and also Mathematics with I believe Miss Hove is her name. She was very delighted to knwo that you were really interested in Math. 
We have asked Miss Pierce to come down to Branson and work out the por-trait she has barely begun of Daddy. It was a mistake to show it as such an unfinished stage. I hope she will come. I'd love to have her for a good long while.
Alice dear,  you woudl love to be albe to play in the Wayne orchestral 

42
some day and must not give up your good start on the Violin. When I get back, I'll sure-ly start you once more - You'd hav elots of fun, to say the least, and you can learn all that I know in the 4 years you have to prepare in, if you will do your part. You could even earn money helping the other kids with the violin - They have no one. The director however, is very good and the children play well together. 
Daddy has started on the Messiah today - if we do not hear from Cha-dron we may stay here till the poem is all done, if it remains as cold as it now is. - 
Loads of love to all of my dear, good, wonderful children,
from Mother. 