<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
220 Fink Collection 15
BRANSON JUL19
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland, Missouri
<underline>over</underline>
(St. Louis Co.)
UNI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON, MISSOURI
<p>Your letter just rec'd. Bully to hear from you so soon.</p>
16
<p>Hello - and I'll write later!</p>
Mama
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
This Morning, 1940,
Here, Mo.
Dear Oddie and Enat:
<p>Our rain came exactly on time, after a long dry spell. It's still rainging this morning.</p>
<p>We stopped in Springfield and it required only 10 minutes to reduce car payments to $20 per <gap/>.</p>
<p>The place is very lovely.</p>
<p>I've begun going over the MS Enot Peanut, and there are, thus far, surprisingly few corrections. Beautiful job too - as usual. I'll soon send sheets to be corrected.</p>
<p>Max and the b-a-a-ad gals are well and happy.</p>
<p>Dr Katt says he didn't want to be president anyway as he is quite busy with his present territory.</p>
(over)
17
-2-
<p>We surely did have a lovely time with you <unclear/>, and we wish we were nearer to you - as we may be. Who knows?</p>
<p>We did not put anything in the basement. That was the ice man's trick.</p>
<p>Rec'd a coupld of really fine testimonials from the Pennsylvania engagements. These class talks are worth while evidently, and They refresh me strangely It's The "Otherness" Nothing is good without that.</p>
<p>Soon I'll be going on with Jed. Looks like a long run ahead, and I can arrange for enough monkey excrement to keep everything serene for a fruitful spell.</p>
<p>Mama and I are always happy together, and we'll enjoy the feel of eternity in</p>
18
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>the steady flow of days and nights.</p>
<p>Oddie, we're due in the desert mountians - maybe next year. It will rain on us there, and there will be some thunder. Or maybe just thunder.</p>
<p>It's good to feel that the kids are all set to go for awhile in St. Louis. It's a fine arrangemetn all around; and I'm sure they'll be happy together.</p>
<p>Listened to the Convetion awhile last evening. God! What powerful deliberaton! Vox populi, vox dei! Wow!</p>
<p>Still, I'm gald about Wallace, who has a good</p>
19
-4-
<p>spirit and does know the joker in our social comedy. (I'm assuming he <underline>was</underline> <strike/> chosen, as it seemed he would be when I went to bed.) But if he was chosen, the choice was not as popular one; it was <underline>dictated</underline>.</p>
<p>It's a pity the country has to go through the expensive nonsense of an election, considering that the result is known already.</p>
Endless love, dear good people!
Dad
