<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
70 Petri Collection 63
Saturday, Oct. 4.
Dearest Daddy and Mama!!
<p>It was wonderful, Daddy, to get your letter this morning. Alice just called me, and I read it to her over the phone. That title "I shalle be young with you" is in itself so beautiful. You must write it, as well as "The Song of the Great Migration".</p>
<p>By now you will have recieved my letter and the copies of Mr. Burke's article. It is surely a very fine thing.</p>
<p>I am <underline>so glad</underline> that you had Mr. and Mrs. Oesch there so many times. You are surely right, Daddy; Mr. Oesch needs a friend who can give him a sense of strength, not acquaintances who flatter themselves by making him feel bad. That is the wrong attitude toward him that nearly all the <underline>Swiss</underline> here have. Mr. Oesch will be so glad she got to know you, Mama.</p>
<p>It is another horrible rainy day. I have to buy something to give to one of Albert's sisters at the shower for her tomorrow. This is the second wedding in the family - she, Ann, will be married Oct. 18, and there will be another wedding party with six or eight hams, dozens of cakes, and a small</p>
64
<p>orchestra. It is really quite amazing how they do.</p>
<p>We are going to the horse show this evening.</p>
<p>Sig and I worked again on the Jewel Scene this morning. He is a dear, to say the least. Sig is so thrilled that Maxie is coming tomorrow.</p>
<p>Don't tell Mr. Oesch, but I am just terribly lazy here at the office. It is rather pleasant being here alone like this.</p>
<p>Mama, how are you feeling? How is your foot? Please write me all about you. I am very eager to see you. It seems to me Albert said we might drive home this next week-end! Oh, I <underline>hope</underline> we do!</p>
<p>I am going to have lunch with Irma today. It will be nice to see her again. I am wearing the lovely green blouse you made me, Mama. Everyone thinks it's lovely.</p>
<p>That was so cute about the "baby gentleman." We are glad Joanie liked the things from Auntie's Neihardt!</p>
<p>I shall hope to hear soon again from you. You have both been <underline>very</underline> good to me lately!</p>
Endless love, 
Hilda