<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
40
GAHART
DRHART
<figure/> 
NEW HOTEL 
Rosslyn
HART BROS. 
PROPRIETORS
<figure/>
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN
COR MAIN AND FIFTH STS.
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
Saturday noon 
LOSANGELES, CAL Feb. 23,'18.
Dear Ones:-
This is for all of you, and I know you won't care about my not writing individual letters.
I've had a great experience. Coming down here from Santa Fe was like experiencing a miracle. at <unclear/>. arizona, L G, 800 ft above the sea) it was raining, <unclear/> & unpleasant, with patches of snow scattered about. Inside of 2 hours we had <unclear/> 6,000 ft into July at the needles in the Mojave Desert. as we same down that 6000 feet I began to feel as though my ears were stuffed with cotton. Thought I was catching the devil of a cold. I heard several other fellows complaining that they had some hour caught an awful cold "- said they 

41
GAHART
DRHART
<figure/> 
NEW HOTEL 
Rosslyn
HART BROS. 
PROPRIETORS
<figure/>
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN
COR MAIN AND FIFTH STS.
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
Saturday noon 
LOSANGELES, CAL
-2-
couldn't hear. The porter overheard us & he said that it affected nearly everyone in that way - the rapidly in creating pressure on the ear-drums. Once out in the Mojave Desert, my ears began to get normal. 
Had a bully time on the long run from <unclear/>, n. m. a bunch of us fellows living out in the smoking <unclear/> & discussed everything - from sociology to metaphysics. There were some well educated fellows there. One was a Russian who was forced to flee from Russia because of Revolutionary activities He was 45 yrs; old but cooked 60 .F we old <unclear/> of a fellow His name is Dmitri <unclear/>. Graduated at 

42
GAHART
DRHART
    <figure/> 
    NEW HOTEL 
    Rosslyn
    HART BROS. 
    PROPRIETORS
    <figure/>
    AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
    RATES MODERATE
    HART BROS MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE
    NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN
    COR MAIN AND FIFTH STS.
    FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
    Saturday noon 
    LOSANGELES, CAL
2-3-
The university of moscow, & we talked about Greek poetry. He quoted some fine <unclear/> passages & I quoted some. He is going to write me. There was also a railroad official, an optometrist, a moving picture photographer, & a jeweler - we had cats of fur. I came up to the Rosslyn with the Catter - a fellow of 65 who looks 45. Talk about high <unclear/>! Why, Los Angeles is a cheap place to live. I pay $1 for a nice room in this really lux union hotel. you can't get a room for less anywhere in any <unclear/> of a place. And the meals! I had the following breakfast: 
-

43
GAHART
DRHART
    <figure/> 
    NEW HOTEL 
    Rosslyn
    HART BROS. 
    PROPRIETORS
    <figure/>
    AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
    RATES MODERATE
    HART BROS MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE
    NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN
    COR MAIN AND FIFTH STS.
    FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
    Saturday noon 
    LOSANGELES, CAL
-4-
Fruit, cereal, fish, Three pounds of meat or eggs (choice of there) potatoes, cakes, bread & butter, coffee & several other things. <unclear/> portions of each and paid 35c! My God! Our <del/> Laramie that would cost 1.75. And on a drier, they'd simply sell you into slavery for daring to eat so much! I've dodged the diners & have eaten three times at the Harry eating houses, where the train stops 25 mins. Pretty reasonable prices, considering. I've eaten prunes & milk mostly. and these with the blessed kissed cookies have opened up my rural regions nicely! Quite <unclear/> traffic down there this a !!

44
GAHART
DRHART
    <figure/> 
    NEW HOTEL 
    Rosslyn
    HART BROS. 
    PROPRIETORS
    <figure/>
    AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
    RATES MODERATE
    HART BROS MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE
    NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN
    COR MAIN AND FIFTH STS.
    FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
    Saturday noon 
    LOSANGELES, CAL
-5-
I'll stay here tonight & go on up to Palo Alto tomorrow, starting at 8 a.m. 
Lord! what a country! Looks impossible! Ripe oranges on the trees. And just yesterday I was in December. Here it is the gentlest kind of June weather. I'm afraid poor old Nebraska may lose its chief literary reason for existence one of these years! Yes & a sculptor & a Grandma & Three lovely <unclear/> too! Kiss those <unclear/> for Papa! Tell Hilda that Papa will positively in she another appearance I bring her a golden tangerine to put in her belly!
You musn't fancy hour much love this carries to all of <unclear/> 

-6-
45
you. 
I hope Enid has received her <unclear/> & Sig his Indian born. Pueblo Indians made both. I sent a lot of stuff about Santa Fe. Mona, you can explain to the <unclear/> about the Pueblos, wont' you? I hope you folks are feeling well. I do wish so much you were with me. And mona, dear you must know what a wonderful land we have: <figure/> to to big & so beautifully empty! 500 miles at a stretch that is vacant & weird as the moon. We must move West sooner or later. It's getting too swing back there. People get narrow with their banned hags & cable. Freer here. But I would prefer Santa Fe to Los Angeles. It's dinstinctive. no other place on earth like it-couldn't be. It gets its character from the ancient Pueblo Indians. 
