<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
11
Thursday 
63
[May 21, 1936]
My own Darling: 
When I have such great faith in you, and in the great work you have yet to do - why cannot you just let go and know without thinking tha tyou will be used to the utmost? It seems to me that this job is just what you say, and I am so grateful and glad for all you are doing with it. But it shoudl not last long. Enid should attain what she needs before long and by that time you should have enough in the Savings so that you can come break here and write Jed Smith. I feel you really must, because if you don't, something else will come in to take you elsewhere. You are going to go through the Salt Desert are you not this Summer? Oh God, Jobu I do hope you'll not get to do that <unclear/> man's history He was un knowingly right when he said he was not worth it - Of course he is not! 

64
I'm reading the Initiate, returned from Miss Edna Waltz with the "Unknown Disciple" thank Heavens! And why <del>I</del> are you not doing as much good as you go, to every one you meet, as he did? You are. he was not worried nor hurried, he just influenced all he came in con-tact with. You are doing this also - So please do not fret over this job being trivial - you have little idea how much good you are doing - There are hundreds who do not write all you mean to them. By the way, cannot you put a note at the bottom of your page, asking people to write in and express themselves about what the Page does for them? I think that would be a good idea, don't you? 
John dear I do feel so much better today - worked a little and am pro - 

65
gressing nicely. Darling please don't think I am thinking of my self in a profession - al way, for I know too well how <unclear/> are my powers. But if I could help you Oh God! how happy I would be! I cannot excavate Mr Good yet, that position hurts my side too much. I'm expecting Dr Stastney and Alice Home today - they may return late and I am not really worried about them. Alice is having a grand trip! 
Dr Carlis is not testing eyes any more now it seems - Mrs Carlis told me I had better go to Springfield. Please tell Enid to write at once to Mrs Spurlock who was taken with a dreadful internal hemorrhage <del>hemorrhage</del> suddenly a few days ago and is in bed with cold packs - they do not know what it is as yet but 

66
of course we fear Cancer. They say it cannot be a fibroid Tumor because the <unclear/> all her "things" removed years ago - so we are hoping for the best. 
Mrs Horine has returned from Springfield where she was operated upon for a tumor. She is getting along very well. 
Loads of Love to my own Darling from Mona. 
Neihardt Branson Mo 
BRANSON MAY 22 3-PM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Dr John Neihardt 
301 Ilene Apartm:
5544 Pershing 
St Louis. 
Mo. 
