<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
0a
(1)
Camp Nakanawa
Mayland, Tenn.
July 3, 1941.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Here I am in camp with all the other girls. I'm in charge of a half <unclear>double</unclear> cabin - 4 girls in each half. All but one of my girls have now checked in.</p>
<p>We had a lovely trip here on the train - Pullman, etc Left St. Louis at 10:50 P.M. Tuesday and rode to Nashiville, arriving at 7:35 Wed. - this morning. Then we rode to Mayland through <unclear/> Mts. - only a little higher in spots - no, not higher than the Dewey and Mutton Hollow region. The trees and other vegetation are just like our country Rode via mule wagon from Mayland to camp. Everyone seems lovely adn the lake is gorgeous - it's clear, cold, and large. Can't wait to go swimming. Mrs. Long my over instructor (Instructor of Dancing at Sr. Camp) will be away for a week, so I must take charge of these Jr. classes</p>
(2)
<p>right from the start. When <unclear/> we'll plan a regular schedule Hope everything goes as it should.</p>
<p>I'm quite tired now from lack of enough sleep last night, but hope to sleep like a log tonight. We'll have dinner at 6:10, then meeting of counselors after children are in bed. First, we'll have the drawing for the two divisions, Amazons and Valkyries.</p>
<p>It is really lovely here. I think it'll be lovely all around, and furthermore, doggone good for me.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<p>I do think I'll need those shorts, Mom, any and all - unlesss you or Max are wearing some, or course.</p>
<p>It's so quiet and peaceful here!</p>
<p>Thurs. 11:40 - Had counselors meeting last night Col. Pice, Dir told us all about Counselor's duties, privileges, etc. Had assembly and entertainment committee this morning. This is quite like a school in many ways, yet it's very different too - should be lovely when we get started! Please if I have a raincoat, will you send it?</p>
<note>sentences below are in margin of letter</note>
<p>Hope you have a marvelous time over the 4<underline>th</underline> with Hil, Ol, and Sig! Please do write me soon, all of you, won't you? We're going to do a can can tonight!</p>
0b
Alice Neihardt
Camp Nakanawa
Mayland, Tenn.
MAYLAND
JUL
3
2PM
1941
TENN.
<stamp>UNITED 
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Mo.