<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- letter is incomplete -->
43d
<p>Kiss Nei for me. Tell him he's stll my little gem! Kiss Joan and Elaine for me as well, and tell them please to write their Chicago Auntie.</p>
Hotel Berkshire
15 EAST OHIO STREET
CHICAGO
April 25, 1942
Dear Daddy, Mama, Eny, and Ollie, and Nei, (Sig, Mx Hilda Albert Joan, and Elaine as well!)
<p>I do hope you are all settled comfortably by the time you get this letter. It is marvelous that you are all together, and I know you are all together, and I knwo you and Nei will have great times together! I do so hope I may soon get to send you positive news in holding up my share of the load.</p>
<p><underline>So</underline> much has been happening thse very few days that we three feel in a dream - and we love it. Chicago is a <underline>glorious</underline> city - to me it is not like my conception of a city. It is so open, so beautiful, so invigorating, and the lake stretching out into endlessness is breathtaking. We will see the Art Institute and the Hall of Man at the Field Museum as soon as we feel the right to such leisure. Now we are busy with other things.</p>
(2)
<p>I will begin with Friday <unclear/>, while I left off in my last letter. We visited several homes, looking for room adn board, after locating these from ads in the Chicago Tribune. You see, it is much cheaper to live in a private home than to live in a hotel and keep all meals out. With little difficulty we found two lovely homes iwth nice comfortable rooms and good meals, the first of which wanted $9 and the 2<underline>nd</underline> $10.50 per week. After visiting both, which are two blks from the lake and near the Loop, for obvious rason. We took it and were just leaving when we were asked what we did for work. Upon being told we were dancers looking for employment and not yet definitely settled in a job, the attitudes of our landlady (prospective) and landlord changed form one of evident like to one of evident distrust. So, to make a long story short, we received a call this morning that several of her old girls had come back and therefore</p>
43e
(3)
Hotel Berkshire
15 EAST OHIO STREET
CHICAGO
<p>we should look for another place! Of course this was evident hooey she simply didn't want us for very silly reasons. Therefore, we have taken the 2<underline>nd</underline> place, for it is just as lovely and not as old-fashioned. Besides, we will probably get gree transportation much of the time, for everyone there drives to the Loop, and we have been told that we may ride too.</p>
<p>Friday night we received a call about a job, but it is not in a very good place, and besides is for only one girl. Shortly after this call, we called the Countess <unclear/> on a sudden hunch. Sylvia was out for dinner at her aunt's, so when the Countess asked us to come see her then, only Doris and I could accept. We were like two year</p>
(4)
<p>olds when we boarded the IC wtih 11<cent/> fare and rode over miles of track out of Kemlark St. where she has her studio. When we arrived we were even more thrilled, because we found the Countess to be such a human, intelligent, marvelous person. She talked over our whole life with us, gave us some marvelous advice, adn and address of a dancer of great influence in New York who might influence something here in Chicago - a card of hers with a note on it about us too. She showed us her marvelous ivory miniatures and talked about her husband pioneering work in the line of Scienc and sanity - a basic for a future sane world rather than animalistic as it is today. This was indeed an inspiring visit. We shall never forget it or her. She has so lovely to us - siad she'd be eager to hear of our latest <unclear/>! We'll see her again with Sylvia. The latter was here when we returned and was she excited!</p>
<p>Friday afternoon we also visited the Frost Club (a club for girls) but no <unclear>vacanies</unclear> were</p>