<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
156 Fink Collection 167
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
DEC 19
3 -PM
1939
M.O.
Mrs. O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
St Louis
County
Mo.
168
Monday
(Dec. 18, 1939)
Dearest Enid adn Ollie and Alice:
<p>It is so fine for me to be thinking of you 3 together - and that you have gotten adjusted. Please do write me as soon as you can, Alice; For your dear letter, Enid, many thanks.</p>
<p>I was received here much as I expected, but I felt there was something decidedly wrong, when Amama embraced me <underline>very</underline> warmly - and told me at once what I could do, since she and Maxine dovetailed so perfectly and were going to continue till she left__ We happened to speak of you Alice and that unleased torrents. I immediately told Amama what is what - and to make a long story short - we got into a <underline>mess</underline>, I</p>
169
<p><unclear>mean</unclear> are <underline>outrageous</underline> one__ This is all I need tell you, expecting that Amamma has gone to Kansas City and that I expect never to see her again. I surely made every thing plain - and the fine thing about it all is that Daddy and I are absolutely together this time down to the smalles detail. Daddy told her that I was essentially right, that he was all for me, and that he always would be even if I were wrong!__</p>
<p>So you see the blessing that has come out of it all for me_ Amama had been underhanded and a real sanke in her attitude, while I was with you children, and had tried to win Maxine with flattery against me, - so you can immagine what a lovely feeling there was when I arrived!! But she did <underline>not</underline> succeed in <underline>any</underline> detail - so all is fine now - and we are united more than ever.</p>
170
<p>I feel absolutely cold - and I see clearly. I have not the slightest feeling of pity or affection or anything else when I think of her - as though she ahd never been related to me - just <underline>nothing</underline>.</p>
<p>Too bad? No - but <underline>strange</underline>.</p>
<p>So you will probably never entertain her in your home Enid - I expect never to see her again. This certainly is the end. Some day I'll tell you mroe - but there is no use in writing it.</p>
<p>I love all you dear, dear children and I know that you will always love your own devoted.</p>
Mama,
Mother.