<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
123
31-32
After..........days, return to 
Neihardt 
........................................
........................................
BRANSON, MISSOURI. 
BRANSON MAR28 3-PM 1935 MO. 
UNITEDSTAT <FIGURE/> 3CENT
Miss Enid Neihardt 
Hotel Somerset 
150 West 47th St. 
New York City 
Suite #118

124
Branson, March 28'35
Dear Enot:
That was a dear and beautifully written letter; beautiful because it was simply true and out of the deep place in you that is wise without knowledge of its wisdom all that you say is essentially what all seers in all countries and ages have said & shall continue to say, with relatively few at any time to believe them. 
Everything is going finely here. Mama is working happily, & the Messiah will be much as I dreamed it long ago.
I enclose two self-explanation letters. No doubt there will be others. Be sure to see Lacham before long. He is planning a trip West. You'll like Guiterman. Too bad Masson is gone - too bad for us, I mean. He had become a very bright spirit. 
I don't think of any rare books I really want very much, but perhaps you could find by chance some of my early firsts - or maybe a "Black Elk Speaks." 

125
you ask about Lucy Long. An appalling fellow! His scheme reveals pitiful ignorance at best, & since he is taken for a radical, he tends to discredit those who really understand the world - muddle. He might, with the right break, go far - much too far. The people are pitiable & so easily fooled. As yet they have light in him. Johnson & Laughlin, viewed as from a height of time, of <del/> no more ^significance than Lucy. 
We are moving rapidly toward Busman's dictatorship, virtual Fascism. It has to be that way before anything really countrymen can be attempted - after Fascination the floundering of the present administration is tragi-comic. It too, must be so. The whole in RA <del/> notion was from the beginning a choas of contradictions inherent in the social scheme ^that the administration was compelled to try to save, never has these been such a Babel as now. This is not pessimism. The world is not dying - only one of its colossal follies! 

126
Both optimism & pessimism are foolish. Only understanding matters - seeing what as & must be. 
I have no illusions as to the alleged " wisdom & goodness of the masses, nor of the present ruling clans. And I can hate neither, and I am far form feeling gloomy. 
Tell Amama I'll keep on sending books. I think six have been sent. Love to her & to you. 
Dad. 
Many thanks for the cheese figs etc. Bully! It was dear of you to do that. 