<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
[1938] 
32 Petri Collection 48
Branson, Mo. Oct 24 [23] (Sunday)
Dearest Girls: 
Even though we were well prepared for the great news, Hiddy, we were none the less thrilled. It's prefectly bully! You are now a rich lady and can assume a "from up down" attitude toward people, with the <unclear/> graciously but haughty tilted. Can you manage a frosty accent too? Congratulations, Old Lady! We're no end proud of you. 
We're a bit up-stage ourselves just now, with our Hudson Terraplane (automatic shift, clutch, etc) Boy! she's a pippin, and did I ever do a job of buying! Mama will max lyrical about the car in her next better, so I'll stick to prose. 
Sig and I had a marvelous time at Wayne. He played at <del>two</del> 3 public programs & definitely added to the tradition. (My kids don't let the old man down!) His playing was exquisite. I spoke seven times in two days - full periods. It was, apparently, an overwhelming success. (There's considerable talk about my holding audiences. had two 
(over) 

49
-2-
high school assemblies - one in the new city auditorium. They didn't move. I seem to have gained power, somehow. If so, I know the source of it. 
We stayed at Jim Brittain's new home. Lovely time. It was all lovely, & all the old-timer's flocked to us. Happy experience. I heard much of you, Hiddy; and all were delighted tohear of your success and of your singing. Anderson and I clicked magically, and are friends from now on. I'm so glad he's the right man, as he undoubtedly is. Miss Geisler was at all public performances & came to me twice - so dear and so genuinely moved. I want to write her, so please send her first name to me at once. Also, please give me <del/> Miss <unclear/>'s first name. I must write her, as she had Sig and we at her home for lunch - pheasants! Don't delay, please. Both names. Brock, among many wished to be remembered. Everybody did. 

50
Allen Burke at Bancroft insisted upon entertaining us at his home on our return trip. Called in old-timers, & we had a pleasant evening. But Bancroft is a sad place. it is dying - almost dead; and the people have been cruelly hit by the depression as well as by "the fury of the wind of days". They seem to be waiting apathetically. Sad, sad! 
I'll be at "Jed" again tomorrow. have two major lyrics in mind to be done after "Jed". The <del/> one recently concieved will be called "a litany of Beautiful things". It will really be a sequence, each part a separate flight, dealing with some phase of visible or invisible beauty for which to give thanks. Easy to write, and it will be all syrup. Golly, golly! One flight will be about gems. There may be as many as so flights - so marvelous is the world seen large! 
(over) 

51
4-
Alice, I want to hear from you about dancing when you have time for a genuine unburdening. I believe, - profoundly. <del/> I told folks that you walk like a leopard! <del/> A compliment to the leopard, I should say. 
No more now; but I want those names right away please. 
Alice, no doubt you rec'd the 12 which from Wayne, so I'm not sending today once Mama sent for less week. Do you need soemthing extra? Let me know. 
Endless love to a couple of really great Gals: 
Dad 
Big reception at Neihardt Hall as a farewell! 