<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
102 
Fink Collection March 12
25
Neihardt Branson MO. 
BRANSON MAR 13 7-AM 1935 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESP <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Miss Enid Neihardt. 
Suite 118. 
Hotel Somerset.
150 West 47th St 
New York City 

103
March 12th 35
Dearest Enid:
Yes dearie send Hilda you know suit and the pink dress - Am glad you can use the other things - You must not even think of sending me a suit precious girlie mine - I'll get any thing I want or need you may be sure of that. You are very fortunate to have your job and Amama and you must please not misunderstand my attitude. I am so grateful you are where you are and have what you have - but I feel your experience has been for ma-nuscript work and that you might be transferred to such a position - where most 

104
<unclear/> York stenos have not had the opportunity for your kind of experience. Indeed I am not thinking you are too good for your present job - God knows not - When you are through with your teeth, which was also a grand thing to be able to do - you will know what you most need to do next. I am so glad you have Eatna Insurance - is it the kind you can get a sum of money for after a given number of years, if you should so wish to do? I remember Amama telling me of a working girls In surance policy which I always con-sidered wonderful, and wished you might some day be able to have. - You have not been seeing any of the embroi-

105
dery design stores have you? You remem-ber we used to talk of what lovely things you might be able to make if you ever got a job in the city.- It is so fine that you have been to the <unclear/> - I never went to any but the Metropolitan when in New York! I am glad you saw "my" studio Bldg! You know it was there that I received the present of that drawing that now hang on our wall here of the young woman lean-ing forward gazes <del>weigh</del> away applaud down! I told you about the artist who later broke the Bank at Monte Carlo giving it to me! I'm sorry Uncle Offocar did not de-cide to settle in New York, City - but he doubtless has very good reasons.-I am 

106
also sorry about Dick - too sorry to say any thing! - I am so glad to know you will have an other sweater, and that an orange colored one - I always loved you in a sweater - Alice is to graduate from Gram-mar school this Spring - and you know the fuss they make! She will wear a white dress and shoes, and she wants me to make her dress, and put lots of ruffles on it! Sig had to walk across the Railraod bridge to work today and yesterday as we are poured - and MacQuerter's camp is clear under water! The water is over the floor of Hullands querage and so Sig is working at Pembertons. Daddy helped Sig to make 

107
a good deal on his car - He got his payments cut in two, and a very good Oldsmo-bill in place of the Wyllis 8. Theya re stay-ing with us until they can make a move over to an adorable little cottage - on the heights over Hollister - Close behind where Dr Charlotte Martins cottage was, do you recall it? There is a stove founda-tion and a good stone cistern, piped in to a cute convenient kitchen. There is a good sized living room, a nice little bedroom with big clothes closet - a large screened in porch-with a heavy honey sickle vine over hanging! They have a bit of the prettiest of Ozark woodsey scenery for a yard - and a view clear across the new bridge - I'd like to move in there my self! It will cost them only $6.00 a month!! I hope they can buy it 

108
Daddy was all shot - but he is a great deal better now and loads well too.
I am getting fat! I eat a lot and have not had a real head ache for almost 4 months. 
Hilda wrote a dandy letter not-long ago - I am so grateful she is well and so enthusiastic over her studies. 
Yes dear we will do as we said about Omaha - I feel that will work out if you want it to. 
Loads of Love to you and to my own dearest Mommie as well 
from 
Mama., 