<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
112
Fink Collection 
Jan 10th 39 12
My dear dear Enid - 
What beautiful eyes or ties(!) for Daddy you did make - they are exquisite and just in time for his next trip! He has them to wear with his new suit - and so will look as elegant as you please - and Hilda sent beautiful hanky's too! Max will go with them to Emporia, Kansas on the next trip in about 3 weeks. Then I'll go to Boonville and St Louis, and I'd like to have my lower teeth out and stay with teh girls till that is done - and then stay with you a bit - I'd so love to!
Tell me how you liked the picture of my baby and me? May be my head there, would go in your locket? I believe it is a good picture 
Daddy is doing swell work one 

13
Jed and having lots of fun with his gem - tools. Sig remade the whole table yesterday as it was not large enough and not strong enough for those powerful machines - you should see it now - 
I am having trouble with the sleeve on Dad's coat - I need a better pattern than his old zipper coat sleeve, and have not been able to make a better one as yet However here's hoping!-
It is so warm here we let the furnace go out - and we fear the fruit will be killed again - The blue birds and cardinals are about, and it is heaven-ly weather. Wish you were here - maybe you will be before too long, as Dad is flirting with the idea of buying part of Cantwell's <unclear/> our place some day! 

14
Ollie could build a little Home there and run a chicken farm or some thing - wouldn't that be marvelous? There is such a lovely view there to say nothing of a valley with walnut trees and good posture land, if it were planted in Alfalfa or something! 
Mrs Cantwell wants to keep the Spring - and she is having Grandma's cleaned up so you wouldn't know the place - Thank Good-ness! She and I bring over the fence and had a grand talk the other day! I like her so much, and her girls. 
"We all" have been picking up the rocks and piling them in little pile especially Joanie and I - lots of fun - we may have dinner in our "Park" today if Dad will do the cooking!! 
Love to Ollie and you, my own 
Enid girlie, from Mother. Mama. 