<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20 McDonald Collection 47
Branson, Mo., Oct. 27, '25
Dear Lulu:-
Congratulations! Mama has just forwarded your note in which you announce you^r success in the Federation short story contest. hurrah for us! that's corking, and I'm deeply tickled. Hereafter, however, when you have a short story that you like, for goodness' sake don't fool with it in local contests. Get after the big magazines with it. This is bully, for a starter, and is extremely encouraging; for some excellent stuff surely must have been entered in a state like Minnesota. Still, it would not surprise me in the least if you should yet do something big. The success in the Limerick contest tickles me too. It's another straw in the wind. But aim higher hereafter. 
I've jst returned from a lecture trip. Gave my lectures on POETIC VAINES at the University. You'll want ot know how they were recieved, and won't mind my telling you a few things. 
Well, here goes. Dr. Hartley S. Alexander, head of the Dept. of Philos-ophy, formerly president of the American Philosophical Assn., took me to his house for a talk, and asked if I'd be willing to accept a chair of Poetic^s in the Dept. of Philosophy. (I was brought there by the English Dept.!) Alexander wanted my permision to urge that I be brought there very soon in his dept. I know that there is a quarrel between his dept. and that of English. I hinted at this, and he said: That's so. But I don't care how you come. May I then urge that the English Dept. bring you at an early date? 
Dean L.A. Sherman, under whose wing I went to lecture this time, assured me with a glowing face that I had made a very deep 

48
impression, and that it was a big success. Prof. Scott, ranking professor in the English Dept. stated that he had been in the University twenty years, and that in his opinion my lectures were the "most significant" that he had heard there in his time. It went like that. I needn't tell you other stuff. I suppose I shall be called for next year. I'm not eager. But if they give me light work and pay me a full professor's salary, as of course, they would, leaving me plenty of time to work, I'd probably go. Alexander asked if I'd rather have a department to myself, and I said I preferrd to be under the wing 33gf of one of the^existing departments. A bunch of intellectuals came down from Omaha to hear. The book, POETIC VALUES, will be out very soon. In ways it's my biggest. Judge Vingonhaler, who heard me at Lincoln (he's a scholar and has read everything) wrote Mona in high glee, that "after forty years in the wilderness John has come out with the new law". Judge was excited, and he loves me as I love him. But he is Scotch and hard head.
Those lectures cost me more than anything I ever did. I did not want to write them. I fought against them from first to last. I seemed driven and it was sometimes terrible; sometimes it was like a big cool wind blowing through me. But I did not want to do a word of the stuff. It was very strange, and made me feel old and hurt for months. As it is, the book now appeering is only the front porch to what I msut say yet - sometime. It depends on waht the public does with this book. If I had to go ahead, I'd be glad enough, I suppose. 
Though I want to write poetry and nothing else. 
By the way, The WARS is taking hold far better than any of my other books ever did. More of that later. 
Love to all four of you there. 
And hurrah again! 
Jno. 