<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
3
Fink Collection 
14
2129 So Water 
Wichita, Kansas 
WICHI JUL 19 4 PM KANS. 
Mrs. O. F. Fink 
Branson 
Mo. 
58 

2930 Water. 
Wichita, Monday 
4
July 19th 37 
Dearest Enid and Ruth:
Daddy seemed to enjoy driv ing and said he was not tired, so kept go ing to Wichita where we arrived around seven P.M. We went to a nice Hotel - Cafe' where we had a wonderful dinner consisting of fruit juice Chicken giblets rice, peas, potatoes, salad bread and butter and ice cream for 25 cents - (Can you believe it?) The air is marvelous here, and we had a thunder shower last night with cyclonic wind - slept fine and this morning I washed out 4 shirts, my dress and slip, and Daddy's underwear and Pajamas. All <del>are</del> these are now hang ing in the sunny back yard where there is a love by shade tree and lots of grass. Maxie has a love by <unclear/>, keeps it very neat and clean, and babies are perfect in every way. Joan, from the back, could be you 24 years ago! She is a darling and seems to remember us - making up with her Grandpa first. Now she plays with the big ball he brought her, wears my locket, and goes 

5
about as big and happy as can be. She talks quite a bit and is very gentle and loving - Sig has had a good run of business selling 4 Pianos in as many days! He and Max both look very well and are so dear. 
When we arrived about 8 o'clock Sig and Max with Joan between them on the Porch swing, were a picture of beautiful home life. Elaine was busy in bed "being good" - you cannot imagine a sweeter, letter baby. She smiles and kicks and laughs and if you pick her up she crows with satis-faction. 
Daddy is all dressed <del>in</del> clean and has gone out with Sig to interview the news paper man for Ollie. Oh Enid, if you could just be here! This is a clean, up and alive place, where there is no smoke, no lack of employment, no rotten city atmosphere. Must close for today - Hope Ruth is happy and that you are the same. Loads of love - Mama. 