<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 157
[c June 18, 1941]
Wednesday 
Afternoon.
Eny dear;
<p>Tea being over I feel strong to belabor with pen in hand write a belated answer to your last fine letter.</p>
<p>The wubs and I are glad you liKed "Baby Lamb" even tho it wasn't much. Still if it conveyed to you the love we have for you two and baby buntin' then our small efforts are well repaid. I only wish it could have been something more.</p>
<p>I Know you must have much worK on hand. Wish I could be there awhile and assist in the painting and monKeying around that taKes so much thought and time. I Know Ol must be so tired after all the clamor of town &amp; P-D expansion.</p>
<p>Went to Jane Mitchell's shower which was held at Opal Parnells last Friday evening. It was exclusive &amp; very nice. Mom gave her <strike/> on of the Chinese prints. Of course it was through me but after all I ha no extra money to buy Jane an expensive gift and it was certainly a breaK for me as well as Jane, I feel. Still, it was nice.</p>
<p>marie's baby's name is Richard George after the two grandfathers. What a name! They'll call him Dickie I guess. And he'll probably be impossible as most Dickies' I have Known! My gosh listen to me carry on. I certainly have no right to do so!</p>
<p>I have a very bad cold and as a result am fussy &amp; cross &amp; feel liKe Hell. Nearly grannie time too.</p>
<p>Isn't it swell about Hil and Albert?</p>
<p>I just finished a wool crocheted rug. You remember that old grey winter coat of mine? I cut it up and added a couple of other <strike>color</strike>colors and now tis done out. I'm glad to be this before its so hot. Now I'm going to finish a silK stocKing for Marie as I can't buy her anything</p>
158
<p>and fell she would liKe it finished.</p>
<p>the babies are fine and today have nearly run me for a bug hunting!</p>
<p>I guess I can write again later as I have now to answer Mare &amp; Write Dad Melton.</p>
Lots &amp; lots of love to you three,
Ma. &amp; wubs