<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
32
[July 13, 1936]
Monday 
170
Dearest One: 
Your good letter made me once more feel ashamed of my - self for adding to your worries - you surely are taking care of me in a marvelous way and I have real comfort and wonder ful care. My foolish head is as usual not sufficient - that is all. So don't feel worried for me, only I do want to talk to you - and when i do it on paper it does not quite give the right mean-ing. I should be using these long hours of inactivity to grow spiri-tually. I wish I knew just how to proceed, maybe God will show me if I am sufficiently recep-tive! I feel tha tyou are <unclear/>

171
the hard end of this, not I.-Darling please consider this next week, (the one that began yesterday), as the last week in which to send $42.00 for Virginia - because I no longer need such expect care. You see I can do everything with my own hands now, and Hilda and Alice are more than enough help. Dr Mitchel came yesterday and said I positively must keep my leg on a level with my body still all the swelling has left my lower leg and foot. He said what I now had was Flebitis, re-sulting from Erysipelas - and Time is the only cure. So I feel it sil-ly to have an expert, expensive nurse to just wait with me for maybe 4 to 5 weeks more, <del>or</del> 

172
3
when the children are so ready to do for me what I need. Besides I know if this dreadful expense stops I shall worry less - it "gets my goat" whenever I cannot force it out of my mind - so if you will let us have $25.00 extra week after this one instead of $42.00 that will help us do quite a num ber of little but necessary things far more important to me than nursing. Included in these little things will be the work in the garden, the mattress is coming and while she insists on staying down at the Hotel, I feel that if she sees we really have an extra good bed, she may change her mind and stay here. John 

173 
4
when I think of how good you are and the children are to me and then compare with it my mo-thers life, haunted with the feeling among all of her own that she is not wanted - I feel it is coming to her to feel perfectly welcome here now with me - and god knows she is so; how about you? 
Burris Jenkins gave a five salt yesterday AM on "Don't be silly - there was a part in which be took down St. Vincent Millot - How she did deserve it. To think that "they" ever gave her the Golden Scroll makes me sick.  
And this brings me up to the important part of this letter the Award! I have not yet seen the Medal - out there 

174 5. 
is the notice in the Post Office of a package which may be the medal - I am crazy to see it. The letter is here - and I read and re-read it - John dear you of all the pacts listed have over and over again merited it. But when one reaches the top the only assoriates one can have must be inferiors because there is only one sop-and in Poetry that top is you - How well I know. 
Mrs. Harine was just here and I did love to read her that grand letter! 
Must quit now 
Loads and loads of Love to my ownly Man. 
from Mona. 
over 

175
Dearest, the bird looks are just fine and I enjoy them thoroughly - Unfortunately the Mullberries are all eaten off and so my strange birds are not returning - but I remember them pretty well and have identified a number Mrs Miser wants me to look up a certain bird for her - They are going to have an Audubon Souch here, beginning Aug. 4th Alice's birthday. But I'll probably not be able to go to the meeting - Is it not terrible what irrevocable harm fuus do? They did good while there were wild animals, but now Great God! 
Love from me Love for you! Enid V.N. 
