<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
116
Rates $1.50 up Most Modern Hotel in Central Missouri 
Seminole Hotel
The best place to live - Isn't either! 
Fulton, Missouri 
Mon. 10-17-'32.
My sweetheart-
Just rec'd your letter from Miss Burr at Fulton. you dear girl, - nobody in this world means more to me than you! Your sweetness & true - ness is impossible for me to credit (merit rather) too highly! 
there was a place on the sched. which was too close to a next place & this woudl leave out necessity of mailing to St. Charles!
So close to eachother you know! 
Left St. Charles this A.Sn. & am in Fulton this A.M. Also! 

117
Rates $1.50 up Most Modern Hotel in Central Missouri 
Seminole Hotel 
The best place to live 
Fulton, Missouri 
-2-
you can never tell where I am going to be one hour to the next'n! C? 
Sure am going to have a lot of hard work in the next two wks., but honey I'm feeling excellent physically! Have to fix up the Auburn water pump by installing a new pump shaft! 
The shaft is worn & causes "wear in excess" on the packing! 
Sounds "greeky" ?? I-bet-U! Anyway this has to be remedied at K.C. by M.M's boy friend! 

118
Rates $1.50 up Most Modern in Central Missouri 
Seminole Hotel 
The best place to live
Fulton, Missouri 
-3-
"M.M." better tell "S.N." to be good boy & fix it! Sweet, loving girl - I am terribly unhappy without my sweetheart along! It won't always be this way - 'cause we'll not be separated always! What did we get that divorce for anyway? Ha! Ha! You are away & so am I; nevertheless our love for eachother is true & honest!
Our mutual tho'ts are the strong point holding us together!
I'll always love my dear girl, & she may feel safe at all times in feeling that the more girls I see - the more I'll 

119
Rates $1.50 up Most Modern Hotel in Central Missouri 
Seminole Hotel 
The best place to live 
Fulton, Missouri 
-4-
love her! Speaking of you, & no one else! I'm glad that you & Enid have had a good time or two together! Here's for more of them 'til I get back! It will then be up to "us" ^ahem!! to once more think up things to do! Eh? Must close, and look forward to your next letter - & in the meantime read the two which I have rec'd! 
Always know that I love you dear! It means happiness in life for me - the fact tha tyou love me! 
Always Love,
Your Sig. 

120
SEMINOLE HOTEL 
FULTON, MISSOURI 
FULTON, MO OCT17 5-PM 1932 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, 
Missouri. 