<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
39 Neihardt Collection 
150
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON JUL10 PM 1936
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Mr. John Neihardt 
5544 Pershing Ave 
301 Ilene Apartm. 
St. Louis
Mo. 
just had a wonderful rain still raining! It rained a little last nite toes. 

3. 
[July 9, 1936] 
151
Darling:
I did not get my yesterdays letter mailed so am continuing today Last night Alice took me out into our garden, all around the place and how to you suppose? In the wheel barrow! The other girls just laughed themselves half sick and Dandy went along quite deligh-ted. Oh Darling it seemed so won derful! All things that have deep roots have grown remarkably - The Redbud you petted, which we enjoyed so a year ago in the Spring has spread out astonishingly the Wall nut is very big. It shades the entire back so that the South point of our Star is no good for flowers. So I am having the Gol-den Glow, which was all brown from drought, moved to the flower bed at the back - Woudl it not be grand if it still flowered this year? Our Jubilee is bearing fruit and is quite a big tree. Is that not great? The grasshop-pers are after our shrubs but the pest has not gotten to be as bad here as other places. The Tree of Hea-ven that Mother and I too wanted to cut down once is marvelous, and 

4
152
it thrives in this hot dry weather and looks as green as does our Psuedo-grape, and Trumpet vine. The Matrimony vine is wrapped in a dream to deep to be affected by heat or lack of water - What a strong climber it is! The St. John's wort has almost entirely died, but Mr Deeberry trimmed it up and it has a chance to live, but it will not be pretty, we should replace it by some oth-er shrub. The red Spirea I placed in the North West of the circle is also struggling to make good - but the rest of the circle is also struggling to make good - but the rest of the circle is doing well. I saw a little Gold finch in the Mulberry tree this early morning. It loves lettuce that was gone to seed, and you remember we had some lettuce planted in the South West corner of the star - so the little yellow finch decided he'd stay around! He is so cheery and pretty. The Cactus you planted is doing well - and the <del/> other one you and Sigurd brought several years ago is also O.K. Cannas are all but one. dead. If we should stay here we coudl put in <unclear/> and a good swimming Pool - and then we'll be in Heaven Mrs. Albert Parmel has just returned 

5
153
from an extensive trip with her family (<del/> Mr stayed home!!) and she was all over the South West, West, and North West. I asked her waht she liked best; she said Long Beach, Col., but she thought that was mostly because she had many friends there; when she came back this Ozark country pleased her more than anything she had seen because of its intimate beauty! The woman who took care of Max has been very seriously ill, and has moved over, to Farsy the to her Mother in Laws! I gave her all the clothes our children had out-grown when she came over here last Spring before I got "down"- the Coffelts have sold their few belongings and have you to Cali fornia by train. How can such people afford such things.?- Dr Carlis gave a really fine talk over the Radio, on Western Rail-raods - you would have called it a good talk - very well <del>gw</del> spoken Hilda was quite thrilled. 
I am getting well fast, and I believe you'll approve of your girl even though she can't compete with Lelah etc!! 
Darling I love you just you - Always your girl 
Mona. 