<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
103
In next letter I'll not be so rushed and say more you know how hard it is to think when pushed! 
No hard luck - 'cept water pump leakin' our water away! 
S.N. 
Thursday
Oct. 13th '32
Rolla Missouri.
Sweetheart-
Have been thinking of you constantly, & am missing my fine girl more all the time! 
Last nite - the 8:55 date was certainly not for-gotten.
I was sitting in a restaurant & listen-ing to "Ky-B-X" giving the exact time! 
Not a bite was eaten 'til time to "sign off" 

104
-2-
at 9:05 P.M. 
It was a hard day for us in Springfield-you know how the women's clubs get people to spend a whole afternoon in the entertaining them! 
So that's what made us "fagged out"!
Stopped in for a few minutes at Sutton's & had an unusually remarkable reading from the psychic! She is surely the most unusual one I've been to 

105
-3-
I have a number of things I wish to talk to you about! Nothing but good, & very interesting! Seems "too good" (so we used to say)! 
I had to take it so slowly form Spr. to Rolla to keep from arriving to early; so just happened to run across a "66" Chrysler in trouble! I couldn't (at first) convince the Dutch - man of being able to fix him up - so 

106
-4-
I bet him a carton of cigars against a carton of cigs that I'd fix it!
I got it in shape for him & drove him a-round for a while! It was strange how happy & convinced he was after seein' his Chrysler do "56" all the way up a long grade! The fellow wanted to give me the money equivalent of a carton of Chester-fields, but I took $.25 instead! 

107
-5-
The poor fellow was out of job & I could see that he had made a bet too large for his own good! WEll, so much for this commonplace subject! 
I am going to play again tonite; & with my sweet girl always with me (in tho't at least)- I'm sure to do well! Please take care of yourself, dear girl - you know - you might fall off of 

108
-6-
the front porch & be in a more danger-ous situation than I'm in while driving so much! C? Ha! Ha! Eh??! "Big teaser" - wish you could tease me now! I love my sweet girl & nothing can make me think any other way about it! 
Mrs. Sutton should have you a letter soon in answer to yours! She promised me she would! 
I'm so looking for-ward to getting a 

-7-
letter from you that at time I have an awful heartache! As soon as I get to St. Louis I'll write you about something good I foudn out! Dad is genuinely pleased over yours & my association with eachother, & this is quite im-portant in certain ways! Is it not? I've had great pleasure in "high-hallin'" the girls involved in the many receptions & will continue to have fun that way! 
Always Love, 
Your Sig. 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

109
ROLLA M.O. OCT13 3-PM 1932
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, 
Missouri. 