<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
326 Fink Collection 84
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
JUN26
3 -PM
1942
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mrs O.F. Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
<underline>Overland</underline>
St. Louis County
Mo.
85
Precious Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your dear letter was so much enjoyed by Amama and me, and I want to thank you for it as well as for all the dear care you have been giving our Daddy. I have written him to Purdue Uni. as he asked me to do. A card from Kirksville tells of his usual <underline>real</underline> success there. Bless his heart! how wondeful he is, isn't he? To talk with Amama and hear all the tales of what other men call "living" makes me appreciate <underline>my</underline> dear man all the more. We here are eager for his home coming. Mammie seems better - if we can just help her to turn over</p>
86
June 1942  SWITZERLAND Editions Novos S. A., Lausanne
SATURDAY    Sunrise   SUNDAY     Sunset       MONDAY    58
20         4:35 a.m.    21      8:28 p.m.       22
<figure>Neuchatel, Closter of the Collegiale Eidenbenz, B.</figure>
87
<p>a <underline>new</underline>leaf in her book of Life, she will yet be happy and well.</p>
<p>Alice is in St Louis (by the time this arrives) and I do <underline>so hope</underline> you will find a way to go and see her dance, but if you cannot do that you may have her spend a night with you and get a <underline>good look</underline> at her, afterwards sharing your experience with me by letter. I am so deeply grateful for all you dear children, that I no longer <underline>can cry</underline> with the heartache of being away from you, one and all. I <underline>mean</underline> this <underline>every</underline> word. Hug and Kiss the most dear and lovely grandson anyone ever had for his Nanny and Know always how deeply I love and admire Ollie and you.</p>
Your Mama - Mother.
88
June 1942  SWITZERLAND Editions Novos S. A., Lausanne
Tuesday    WEDNESDAY     THURSDAY    59
23           24           25
<figure>Stormy morning. Glacier du Trient seen from Finhaut (Valais) A. Brandt, L.</figure>