<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
151 Fink Collection 124
October 29, 1939
Hotel 
Broadhiew 
RAY DAVIS, MANAGER
Galesburg
ILLINOIS
Special 
Delivery
GALESBURG ILL.
OCT 29
9 PM
1939
Oct 28 '39
Mrs. Jno. G. Neihardt
5406 Delmar Blvd,
St. Louis,
MO.
% Hilda Neihardt
Hotel Clubs.
<underline>NOTICE</underline>
LETTERS MAILED IN HOTEL ENVELOPES
IF NOT DELEVIRED WILL BE SENT TO
THE DEAD LETTER OFFICE UNLESS
THE WRITER GIVES A RETURN ADDRESS
IF NOT DELIVERED IN _ DAYS RETURN TO
J. G. Neihardt
Branson,
MO,
125
Hotel 
Broadhiew 
RAY DAVIS, MANAGER
Galesburg
ILLINOIS
SAME MANAGEMENT
HOTEL PARKSIDE
KEWANEE
HOTEL NEWCOMB
QUINCY
Sat. Eve.
Precious Girl:
<p>We just arrived from Mount St Joseph, Kentucky, where we had a divine time at St. Joseph Academy. I'll tell you about it later.</p>
<p>I've just rec'd your letters. Had to coax the post office authorities to get the letters, as they close here at 1 P.M.</p>
<p>Of course I want you here. We're already looking for a kitchenette apartment, and if anything of the sort can be had in a town of 20000, I'll get it. We <underline>could</underline> stay at a hotel if you wouldn't get too darned bored. But I prefer the kitcheneeter &amp; honest home meals.</p>
<p>Your misunderstood my denial to Noble, I disclaimed it as <underline>my</underline> doing, &amp; he understood. It really was astonishing. Within 15 minutes at the most he just <unclear>willed</unclear> into <underline>deep sleep</underline>. After an hour he 'woke &amp; called me</p>
126
Hotel 
Broadhiew 
RAY DAVIS, MANAGER
Galesburg
ILLINOIS
SAME MANAGEMENT
HOTEL PARKSIDE
KEWANEE
HOTEL NEWCOMB
QUINCY
-2-
<p>telling me he felt <underline>so much</underline> better, &amp; saying "You did it"! Then I said: "You'll sleep again". He did; and in another hourwoke, &amp; seemed well except for his ghastly exhausted look. He was up with us all afternoon &amp; late into the evening - and he started a day early for California. I <underline>believe</underline> thoroughly.</p>
<p>It was wonderful to be at a Mount St. Joseph - a beautiful <underline>still</underline> lovely peace in the Green River Hills far from a town of any size. The affair was an epochal event (!) for the girls &amp; sisters. What a people they are! And how they claim me! The girls crowded around the dear sweet &amp; wise mother Superior &amp; said, "O can't you keep him here!" And she told me "This will</p>
127
-3-
<p>be a glory to us hereafter".</p>
<p>Sig played &amp; played &amp; I read &amp; <underline>read</underline> lyrics &amp; talked, &amp; it was a joy to us all while it lasted. I was exhausted before I went there, &amp; had been for several days. Evansville was terribly hot &amp; wet. Anyway 40 minutes before a crowd bleeds me white. I <underline>do</underline> recuperate quickly after I have a chance to stand still and rest. We've done 4500 miles in 32 days, &amp; there've been so many hard talks.</p>
<p>I should learn early in the week about a possible apartment.</p>
<p>This is done in a hurry. I'll write more <strike>later</strike> tomorrow.</p>
Endless love to all there, the gals &amp; Oddie &amp; You
Jno.
<p>I rec'd Enat's letter &amp; will write</p>