<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
196
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
St. Louis - At Apt. 
July 24, '36
Dearest Mama:-
Did you receive Amama all intact? I hope so; I sent her carefully packed in a Greyhound bus. Bet you were happy to see her; I was, as well as Dad. She's the same old Amama; and I'll say she hasn't changed any if she hasn't become younger. 
I am very happy thinking about coming hoem to be there awhile and to see you again as well as Hil and Al; and to see Amama some more. I am planning ot go for a visit with Sig & Max in Louisville during the last week or two before we go to work again in September. But, Hil and I are planning on painting Branson in all pretty colors while I'm there. Also, I have a lot ot chat with you about. I shall also enjoy talking with some of the old friends there. 
Glad you like the quilt. I thought it would be beautiful. Just heard from Mrs. Wilson that she is starting 

2
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
on Hil's & Lache's gift! I truly hope the kids will have many a joyful sleep under that quilt and that each joy will be as bright as the colors are in it! I didn't say this to Mrs. Wilson. 
I'm looking forward to many things now that I think about it more - and the vacation time draws nearer. Sleeping under the stars will be a great inspiration to me and beneficial as well. I want a good coat of tan before I leave; especially, do I desire an evenly tanned back to stick out of my formal! I hope Hil & I can use my formal in Branson. Be a dandy time to initiate it! You might just like to see it on me even tho' we don't use it there. 
Hot yesterday and today - nearing the plus 100o mark again. 
Mrs. Behymer is in Barnes Hospital with gallstones, Mama! He used to ask after you so often while you were in Springfield. He's a fine man. We're so sorry he had to have this; but we think he'll pull thru okay. 

197
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
3
Think we'll come down week from tomorrow. I'm packing the winter things, and we're going to store them in a storage house here in the city until September. 
Won't it be nice to be in either Webster Grover as University City? Bet-ter for Al, better for us all. 
Looks a bit like rain. Hear you had rain Sunday. Good. 
Be seeing you, Mama! 
Love to all, as well as Amama. 
Loads of love to you, 
Mama, from 
Your loving daughter, 
Enid 
<figure/> 

198
After Five Days, Return to 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
N.E. Corner Twelfth Blvd, and Olive St. 
ST. LOUIS, MO. 
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 1 1936 JUL 26 830 PM 
<figure/> 
Neihardt 
Mrs. J.G. Neihardt 
Branson 
Taney Co Missouri 