<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
157a
M
Mount Saint Joseph College,
Maple Mount, Kentucky.
Nov. 22, 1939.
Dear Sigurd:
<p>The mail of yesterday carried a few copies of our school publication, "The Mount," which I hope you will like. I will be returning the cut of your father in a few days. I want to thank you for the privilege of having you and your father represented in this issue. This paper will reach thirty-five of the leading Catholic schools of the country ranging from New York to California; these do not belong to us and of course it will reach our forty or more schools. I tried very hard to get you a few engagements while I was in Cincinnati, Ohio on a recent business trip. All seemed very interested. I think that I owe this to you because of your kindess to us but more than that the culture and inspiration that you give to students. Your father is one of the most wonderful men that I have ever met. He is an inspiration in my life that I will ever be grateful for.</p>
<p>The day that you were here I invited the seventh and eighth grade teacher of our Laboratory School to bring her little boys and girls over; they came and when the lecture was finished they ran over to the school to get the world book to see if your father was <sic>emntioned</sic> in there. They were very happy and enthusiastic on finding that he was. Then they asked Sister to read them some of your poetry; she came to me and I gave her my favorite so far, "The Song of Hugh Glass." It is a little over their heads</p>
157b
<p>so she is reading it and telling it to them in their own language. They are delighted. My class, the Seniors are demanding that they be allowed to study your father's poetry and you know how happy I am to make him better known. I hope that you tell him for me that I want him to take care of his health and to give to the world much more of the beautiful.</p>
<p>I read the nicest article the other day that made me think of you and Dr. It was entitled "The Poet's Aren't Sissies," and it was very beautiful. The author was Austin J. App, Ph.D. It began with David, the first poet and reached down through the ages. I enjoyed it so much that I think that I will read it again.</p>
<p>Sigurd, Have you ever heard Msgr. Fulton J. Sheen? He spoke here recently and he is atune with the finest feelings of life. I suppose you have heard him by radio but you loose half in not coming in contact with his personality.</p>
<p>The school is running along as usual, with many things to do. We had a class play with my class last Sunday and have been requested to repeat it in Owensboro on Monday of next week. This will be good preparation for the Thanksgiving holidays.</p>
<p>If there is anything that I can ever do to help you or your father please do not hesitate to call on me. My prayers shall be for your success and I have a hope that someday that you will come again and be our guests. If you are ever in this vicinity remember that "WELCOME" is written on our door step.</p>
<p>I admired very much the thought at the end of your letter, Sigurd, and I too feel that you are called to be his staff until "The Song of Jed Smith" is finished. Do watch over him and the devotion lavished on him will be rewarded not only here but hearafter. You indeed have ability coupled with sincerity and honesty that it is a pleasure to know that you are a real, real man in every sense of the word.</p>
<p>Let me hear of your work, your bookings, your hopes and your success, whenever you can. I will ever be interested in you for I feel that the future holds <sic>mush</sic> in store for you. Keep your face ever toward the better things of life, keep your heart free from everything that is base and low, keep your eyes ever toward THE MASTER, who rewards all we do even to the giving of a glass of cold water in His name.</p>
<p>God bless you, God keep you, God guide you, is my wihs and prayer for you each day.</p>
In Christ,
<signed>Sister M. Josephine</signed>