<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
23 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 5
Jan. first 1941.
Dearest Children
<p>Your good visit here has made us so glad and grateful. May you be able soon to come again!</p>
<p>Joanie has left an awful ache and emptiness - but it was right for her to return with you Maxie - and I do thank you for letting me Keep her. When it gets warm may be you can bring both Wubs down for another visit? In the mean while we are planning soon to drive up - depending</p>
6
<p>on what results we get from the books. Please tell me what you need most for the Wubs that I can be making, will you? I want now to think of nothing but the bust, and I should be able to finish it shortly.</p>
<p>Yesterday after you left, Daddy and I together did the dishes then he took all the <strike>every</strike> things off of the Xmas Tree<strike>e</strike> and I packed them all away to be ready for Xmas 1941 - Where will we then be? - Next we took all of Joan's toys upstairs and I put them in the closet where they will rest till she want them again. Please tell Joanie that Nannie was joking when she said she would get an other little girl - Nannie could never</p>
7
<p>do that.</p>
<p>I am sending the little bedroom shoes - did you forget them?</p>
<p>I did not get to say half of all I wanted to, to each one of you But the main thing is for us all to continue, and Know that our plan will some day workout. Hilda, your voice seemed more perfect than ever - and I <underline>Know</underline> there <underline>never was</underline> a <underline>finer</underline> one.</p>
<p>Alice, what stikes me every time I see you after an absence is that your figure has improved - and that your whole personality sparkles with an inner certainty -Keep it up darling!</p>
<p>Maxie I am so happy</p>
8
<p>that you are reading Daddy's lyrics - some day maybe you will do so in Public - That would be the ideal thing!</p>
<p>Sigurd, I am thrilled beyond expression with the feeling that you will never again waver away from Music - Please let me hear how things develop for your recital with Hilda - You two <underline>should never</underline> fail to realize that each one of you possesse, what the other requires to make an immediate public appeal. Of course you Know this already.</p>
<p>I am still hoping we will be able to sell here in the Spring - The last agent we saw in Springfield seemed to think we had a good thing. He often comes to Branson it seems, just to eat dinner and see the scenery.</p>
Love to you all from
Mom-Nannie
