<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
264 Fink Collection 73
BRANSON
FEB6
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
74
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Sat. P.M.
Dear Oddie and Enot:
<p>By gosh! Those were lovely letters! Got some real sleep last night, <strike/> thanks to an electric pad, &amp; today, for the first time, that sacro - iliac joint<strike/> <underline>feels</underline> as though it is really healing. So I ought to be getting out of this trap during the next week. It's slow, but I feel sure now. It's not the pain, but the actual mechanical crippling, that I've cared about. The pain was all right in a queer-crazy way, that might not be so crazy either. I have <underline>not</underline> been unhappy. Mama has been an angel &amp; it surely made her happy to keep me, I hate being waited on and jumped around for; but since it <underline>did</underline> make her much happier, it must have been good for her.</p>
75
-2-
<p>Still, I'll be damned it I like to see her doing everything. No boy to get anywhere. We've been very cozy - even during this sudden drop of temperature. Don't worry any more now. We've been truly happy together. I hate to lose time now, but that too may prove a good thing.</p>
<p>Floyd Mitchell, the Los Angeles agent, is eager to book me out there for next season, &amp; probably this summer. He is <underline>the</underline> agent out there; and often inquiring around he said he got much more encouragement then he expected. We're dealing now. Mama &amp; I should have a wow of a time in Calif. <strike/> Might stay all winter with engagements strung along.</p>
<p>Ollie, I'm grateful for the offer. But as soon as I can sit up 7 hrs I can drive too. I'll come back fast as soon as the</p>
76
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>joint is fairly healed. My general health has been better than usual, &amp; there's no systemic trouble to prolong the sciatic nonsense.</p>
<p>Gillespie wants us to have his place out south on 65. <strike/> He'd do almost anyway. It's a burden to him. We'll be at the ranch with them in early April. <strike>If</strike> he should make a ridiculously generous offer, involving, our place here, I might fall. He spen $30000, on the property. It is 6 miles beyond Hollister.</p>
<p>Nowadays you can't sell a gold brick for 30 cents a pound!</p>
<p>My Gawd, Ollie! Don't you think gehovah must be busting a gut with laughter, these days? An <underline>idiot couldn't</underline> invent so gorgeously silly a spectacle. But it's quite</p>
(over)
77
<p>all right with Gaki. Everything going as doped out some years back; and far be it from me to oppose the inevitable.</p>
Endless love from Nanny &amp; me
Dad
<p>That joke hurt my back &amp; leg, Ollie!!</p>
Sunday A.M.
<p>Much better this A.M. Dressed for first time, but must be careful. I'll get out of the trap this week sure.</p>
Dad