<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
COPY 
23a
1910
1-21-10.
Soldier's National Home 
Levenworth Kan. 
Mr. Jonas Neihardt, Coal City Ind. 
Dear Bro: I rec'd your welcome message yesterday. Was glad to know that you were yet living and fairly well. Can scarsely expect for an old soldier to be altogether well and sound can we? Now bro: I shall ask of you a favor; when I went ot the service I gave my (swore to a lie) age 12 1/2 years younger than I was, by my two discharges I would really have to be 74 years old before I would draw old age pension which I should draw at 62. I was born in Williams Co O., on July 16th 1853. I wish for you to take the Old Family Bible and one or two witnesses and go before Justice of the Peace, and draw an affidavit, and have it acknowledged by same -- his Seal placed thereon. Please insert place of birth, date, State, County, and town, and my parents names. 
Kindly do this at your leisure and inform me of the cost, which I will foward by postal order. 
Ero: give me David Grim's address. Also bro. Jacob's if yet alive and too, I want Sister Phoebe's address.
I intend to return to the coast states, in early spring. sorry to inform you that I shall not be able to visit you. It is imossible financially for me to visit the many relatives as I should like to! had not the Rich-Man's Panic struck me Oc. 18, 07, I probably would be worth $30,000. Was engaged in buying and selling Real estate, on the installment plan for 5 years in Seattle Wn. and also workign the greater portion of the time at good wages: $2.75 per day, meals 10c. Some of my property increased about 500 per cent while sleeping, and was very fortunate in buying at the right time and place. Been too much of a Plunger, and there-by have gone down seaveral times; though I have seen men of my temperament make millions! So their you are and I am here, and expect to try again some time. 
I devote about 7 hours per day in the Library which is a good one, and a good place to be. 
My children do not know that I am here. However, I am reading my son John Greenleaf Neihardt's articles in magazines; he built himself a boat and installed therein a Gasoline engine at Ft. Benton Mon., and is on a 4,000 mi trip down the two great arteries o the Continent and writing while he glides merrily along! he has sold his press. In the magazines he is called The Nebraska Poet! 
My regards to all. 
Note 
copied 1972 from xeroxed copy of the original hand-written letter. John Neihardt's father spelled his own name without the "d."
(signed) Nicholas N. Neihardt. 
2
