<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
1
Enid Darling:
<p>Your good letter was so welcome, and I am so grateful you are doing so normally and even better than that! Yes Darling I do so want to be with you at the right time. Daddy and I both would love to be at your Home doing what ever could help while you are at the hospital. We have heard nothing for a long time from Mitchel, which makes us feel worried, naturally. Although, Daddy is contracted for September. It is one of those things that Keep one guessing.</p>
<p>Hilda said, while here, she had intended calling you before leaving and she forgot in the rush. She has had a lot of things on her mind, dear girl, so please do not hold it against her. She always says how much she enjoys your Home and your wonderful goodness. She certainly has not taken your advice amiss - of that I am sure.</p>
<p>I have a lovely sea nymph - coffee table decoration - about finished, and Hilda wants me to have the Camark Pottery quote a price on putting it out for her to try and sell in St Louis through gift shops. I do so pray it may be successful.</p>
<p>I have finished the Lullaby and Daddy brought the glass home for it today Maxie is putting the last touches on it for me in the form of some red leaves blowing across the last stanza. You'll have to appreciate the good intention on this, my first piece of its' Kind! The baby looks to me like Mona Lisa - but may be she is to be only in my heart? We'll see!</p>
<p>Certainly there never was a</p>
2
<p>baby more wanted or more loved than this one that you are bringing into this strange yet wonderful World!</p>
<p>Dr and Mrs Plank were here Monday and Tuesday, and we did so enjoy them. I could be very fond of Mrs Plank - there is nothing untrue about her - she is just a dear, fine person! She told me of her private troubles in her first marriage. it seems her husband deserted her for a <underline>rich</underline> woman! A millionairess or so!! She took care of her one child by working at jobs - so she never learned housekeeping - and now she wants us to teach her to bake bread, can vegetables and fruits etc! She may come back here a little later to stay, while Dr Plank goes on his yearly tramp with his youngest son. She is a nice friend for you, and how much she would appreciate <underline>you</underline>, Enid!</p>
<p>Your glad's must be lovely - at present we have not so many flowers - the Hollyhocks and Poppies are gone - and the other things have had a dreadful dry spell to contend with. But last night we had a glorious rain.</p>
<p>We have no more news - but hope for some each day!</p>
<p>I'll keep the Lullaby till someone comes with a car - maybe Sigurd. He always has a wonderful time at your Home, and he dearly loves you too.</p>
<p>Ollie is so good to be doing all that painting. I'm sure the Sunroom will be a very charming nursery.</p>
<p>What do you still need for your "Wub" Maxie says to tell you to use paper diapers entirely!!</p>
Loads of love to my own dearest Enid and to her best of men
from your devoted
Mama Mother.
3
Neihardt
Branson, Mo
BRANSON
JUL11
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs O.F Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo. St Louis County