<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- pages 81 and 82 are missing -->
78
Nov. 5, 1941
Dear Ollie:
<p>I want you to know about this. I've rather discouraged any review, urging that the P-D has already done handsomely by me. As for using Rolf's name, I've opposed that vigorously. <underline>I</underline> don't want any more reviews in St. Louis. Don't think it matters at all.</p>
<p>Pettings and kisses for old Nei! How is the old duffer?</p>
<p>Bless his darling face &amp; eyes and everything!</p>
Dad.
79
MIRROR-15 EMS
Stirring Story of Jed Smith
Completes the Neihardt Cycle
"The Song of Jed Smith," by John G. Neihardt. (Macmillan Co., New York.)
<p>"A Poet," says Paul Engle, "cannot repudiate his age." But it is no repudiation of one's age to read the implications of that age in terms of its antecedents. The major work of John G. Neihardt is a care in proof.</p>
<p>Thirty years of Mr. Neihardt's thought, experience, observation and study have gone into his "Epic Cycle of the West," a celebration in heroic verse of the era of vigorous American expansion and exploration beyond the Mississippi. The cycle of five "songs" is a stirring yet dignified evocation of the dynamic past, and illustrates both in lusty colloquialism and noble figure the quality Wordsworth expressed when he declared that "poetry is the breath and finer spirit of all knowledge....The poet binds together by passion and knowledge the vast empire of human society."</p>
<p>It became Mr. Neihardt's conviction in early life that the opening of the Western wilderness to civilization, through the mighty labors of explorers and colonizers, trappers and traders, had in it the true epic quality, "the stuff of sagas." These men, he felt, were direct spiritual descendants of all the heros acclaimed by bards and scalds since the dawn of literature, descendants of Achilles and Hector, of Aeneas, of Roland, of Sigurd and the knights of Arthur's court.</p>
<p>Like those heroes, the Western men opened an epoch; they stood upon a "water-shed of history." But unlike them, the pioneers of American left records whereby fact can be gleaned from clustering legend, thus making the poet's function one of narration and interpretation rather than fictionizing or embroidery of heroic myths. Mr. Neihardt has scrupulously consulted the original sources, and has traveled intensively over the routes followed by his heroes, in order to capture both the setting and the spirit of their careers.</p>
<p>"The Song of Jed Smith," last in order of publication, is the third in chronological order of the cycle. Its central figure, Jedediah Strong Smith (1798-1829), led the first party of white men overland to the Pacific, from St. Louis to "the Mission of the Padres," now Los Angeles. He was the first to penetrate the desert from the Sierras to Great Salt Lake, and explored the Northwest as well. His story is told here by three trappers, camped at Henry's Fork and spending the night in talk, feasting on buffalo meat and passing 'round a jug of "Taos lightning."</p>
<p>For the first time in the cycle, the greater part of this long narrative poem is done in the vernacular. The writer here has set himself a difficult task. He has all but discarded the vast vocabulary of formal verse, and has restricted himself to the limited if expressive word store of the plainsman, broadened only by the fact that one of his speaking characters, Evans, is a man of some education.</p>
<p>It is a feat of versatility that Mr. Neihardt has been able to avoid both banality and bathos. If poetic imagery suffers to some extent from his device, there is a gain in homely color and realism. Certainly there are clear-cut if</p>
80
<p>poetically unconventional pictures in such lines as "the snow horse-deep and getting deeper," and "far peaks looking like a broken saw."</p>
<p>From the affectionate reminiscences of his friends emerge the dramatic story and stalwart figure of Jed Smith. The men recall his bold, calmly confident leadership in the long treks across deserts, badlands and mountain passes. Scarcely believers themselves, they respect his faith and his reliance on a well-thumbed leather-backed Bible ("that looked like a worn-out boottop") in moments of crisis, which were many. Their conversation evokes the thirst and hunger and weariness of those long marches, their awe at nature's weird magnificence, their constant urge to press on, "to have a look at where the canyon led."</p>
<p>The climax is Evans' story of pilgrimage to the spot "somewhere along the Cimarrone," where Jed, trapped by Comanches, went down, "fighting all alone...with twenty yelling devils." The tragic closing note, beside the dying fire, the old friends mourning anew, the dog howling dolefully, is impressive in its Homeric grief for a dead hero. The gallery of American lore, and the pages of American literature, have been enriched by this cycle's virile and sensitive and lofty rendering of the pioneer epoch.</p>
ALVIN R. ROLFS.
Lafayette, Ind.

