<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
8
Petri Collection 
13
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
"Of Making Many Books" 
<figure/> JOHN G. NEIHARDT <figure/> 
pm Branson Dec 10 1933
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
December 10 
1 9 3 3 
Dear Hiddy: 
That was a bully letter. 
I am sure you were headed in the right direction, even though you could not clearly see your way, in your comment on Cralle's attitudes. 
What he says of proof is essentially sophistry. The conception of proof involves a definite conception of truth. His statement reveals no definition of the term truth. If it be supposed that somehow there is a universally valid truth, then he is right becaus no man can know such truth. But all the truth we can have, being limited as we are, is of a relative nature--relative to human experience. Such truth can be proved; for it is a matter of abiding relation-ships in human experience. 
The value of Spengler's Decline of the West does not depend upon the provable validity of the thesis he elaborates, but upon the light that is generated in the intellectual process of elaborating the thesis. I told Cralle this when I urged that he read the work. Just to follow a powerful and richly furnished mind in a great intellectual adventure is an extremely valuable experience. 
As for his limitation of interest to the period in which he and his immediate offspring shall live, he is fundamentally mistaken, and the mistake grows out of the individualistic conception of life which is central in our present time-mood. To discuss social problems from the viewpoint of individualism involves an obvious contradiction! In discussing social problems 

14
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
"Of Making Many Books" 
<figure/> JOHN G. NEIHARDT <figure/> 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
-2-
the individual must be regarded as merely a transient mani-festation of the continuing social stream. The race endures, not the individual. Social problems are therefore precisely time problems; and the individualist is hopelessly provincial in the time sense. Wisdom of any sort emerges only when the self is lost in the greatest thing the self can concieve, and no one can be wise in his approach to social problems so long as he is unable to feel the continuing life of the race as being, in the last analysis, all that can give the slightest significance to his own brief fussing about on this planet. 
But Cralle is quite able to raise great questions, and he is therefore an excellent teacher for you. 
The Post-Dispatch is bent on having me there to write editorials. I have replied that everything depends upon the liberality of the offer they can make. 
The State College at Moorhead, Minnesota, which is one with Fargo, N. D., has offered me $200.00 for alecture on January 17, and will help me get other engagements. The Auburn is now being re-ducoed. 
Alice and I got a big duck on the Boswell pond yesterday! 
Love always, 
Dad 
After 5 days, return to
J.C. Neihardt 
................
BRANSON, MO. 
BRANSON DEC 10 4-PM 1933 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Miss Hilda Neihardt 
767 East Elm Street 
Springfield, Missouri 