<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
36 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 48
1940
[e. Aug 11, 1940]
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
'41
Sunday Morning
Dear Sig and Max:
<p>Many thanks for the phone call last night. It was characteristically good of you to be worried. It may well be, Sig, that you did get something direct from me when I was above. The mood may have gotten over without the proper interpretion, which very commonly happens when such communications occur.</p>
<p>I'm hanging on to $30, hoping to get a decision form the bank tomorrow. One can't guess how the fog shapes may turn over in dark skulls.</p>
(over)
49
-2-
<p>If I can't land here, I'll try Union National, in Springfield, altho' it might not look good if my home bank should refuse. I don't seem to be able to do a good job of worrying at all, somwhow. One way or another will be possible. I'm getting on slowly but surely with the work.</p>
<p>Yesterday afternoon 'Laine waded up to her neck with one in Roark. That's her first spell of daring. Joan still holds out, but she will dare a bit one of these days, I'm sure.</p>
<p>Swimming has put me in really excellent shape and I've come to realize that I'll have what</p>
50
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>it may take for a desert trip thatthe Home Mountains when the time comes. I wish, Sig, that you Ollie and I could have the adventure together! May be we can.</p>
<p>It's perfectly bully, the way you are doing in your job, Sig. Cool weather &amp; the new home in the fall will boost the piano practice.</p>
<p>Max, Old Lady, it's good you can't hear what we say about you. Perfectly awful, because we don't like yoou much. They very idea! We do too. We do not! <underline>We - do - too</underline>!</p>
(over)
51
-4-
<p>Dr. Katt says he is so glad he wasn't nominated for the presidenvy after all. He'd rather sleep on his back in the cool green grass.</p>
<p>Seems to be another big rain coming now. Radio said fair and warm over Sunday.</p>
<p><unclear/> world! We're <underline>so</underline> close to all that really maters, and yet can't quite touch it.</p>
<p>I'll let you know whether or not I get the coconuts.</p>
Endless love to Old Hiddy &amp; you two
Dad,