<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
203 Finn Collection 10
Neihardt
Albuquerque N.M.
Gen Del.
ALBUQUERQUE
JAN 6
2 PM 
1940
N.MEX.
Miss Alice Neihardt, 
% Mrs O.F. FInk
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland
Mo.
St Louis County
11
Albuquerque
N.M.
Jan 6th 40
Darling Alice:
<p>Yes dear, your good letter to Branson reached us here, also your latest one, for both of which, many thanks.</p>
<p>We are still remaining here in Albuquerque although the fact is that Daddy does not feel the slightest bit better than he always does. At first, the light dry air seemed to <sic>stimmulate</sic> but now it no longer does that and Daddy has all of his characteristic troubles. We moved from the Aztec Court to 66 Court as we found a very nice one room affair</p>
12
<p>here with toliet bath and Kitchentte for $5.00 per week, can you believe it? Our meals and extras come to $5.00 per week too. Daddy is actually writing on Jed every morning, and I am holding my breath for fear he will say "I don't feel right and cannot go ahead!" But this hasn't yet happened.</p>
<p>The weather here is always mild, excepting when the sand storms happen, which is not often. If one want, light air and lots of Sun, I suppose this is fine - but I don't see what there is to brag about. Nothing grows that is not ir</p>
13
<p>rigated. The Mountains and the desert and the sky - all are wonderful - and I could be happy here if Daddy really seemed any better, but he most certainly does not.</p>
<p>We may run down to El Paso soon - I think we are too far North for what we are looking for. Please continue to write us to Gen. Del. Albuquerque. The city itself is very fine - good stores etc. We went to a <sic>moovy</sic> this afternoon "Ninotchka" adn thoroughly enjoyed it every minute. We both like Greta Garbo very much - I am so glad you have been</p>
14
<p>having some fun, and that Hilda has been so generous to you, and that Enid has been such a good Mother to you - She is taking my place so much better than I could take it, were I there with you! Also Enid says you are really a help to her and I am so glad and grateful all'round.</p>
<p>I believe Ollie is getting a Kick out of you Alice, he writes <underline>such funny</underline> letters, that Daddy and I laugh and laugh about! For a minture I really feared he was telling the truth about your</p>
15
<p>New Years' escapade - but I am hoping and praying he was just joking!</p>
<p>You certainly have everything well planned, and will have to be extremely careful if you make that money go as far as you expect it to do. We both appreciate your help, all of you dear, good children.</p>
<p>If Daddy only continues to get along with Jed that is all I ask of Fate. No one can guess what a long, hard pull that Cycle has been____</p>
Loads of Love, Alice darling
from Dad and Mama
16
<p>PS.
Please find out from the Art-place across the street from you on Enclid, if the Ozark baby was sold, or given to <unclear>Madaine Casan</unclear>, will you dear? The arrangement I made with them was that they should take it to Madame if they did not sell it before Xmas. Don't neglect this please.
M.</p>