<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
13 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 13
Winter, 1940.
Dear Mama
<p>I want you to be here. I have some nice new shoes, and they are brown and have laces. They feel good and warm. I gave Mama Daisy your letter. Tommy was sick in bed from vassination, so Nanny thought I had better not stay there today. Mom Daisy told us that Kathie had chicken pocks so I cannot play with her yet.</p>
<p>Maxie, I held Joanie's hand to write you the above, and now she is tired of writing and is watching Gaki in the work shop.</p>
<p>We were so thrilled to find lovely green vegetables in the bread box - So many thanks for them. We used one <sic>carot</sic> last night for supper, and green beans today noon. They are marvelous.</p>
<p>Joanie is fine and very</p>
14
<p>good and happy, as she is busy every moment. Last night just before going to sleep she wanted you so badly, but she got over the homesick feeling in a short time and fell asleep, sleeping quietly all night. She is so proud of her new shoes - and the girl at the store gave her a red balloon - so she ahs been playing with it almost constantly and has not yet broken it.</p>
<p>She has the rollaway bed in our bedroom - as you suggested and is as snug as can be. In the morning she gets into her dark red corduroy robe and her house shoes, and goes down stairs to dress in the warm. So she is comfortable. She says quite often "How quiet it is here, Nannie!" She plays a lot with George Kat who seems much pleased and purrs contentedly to her de-</p>
15
<p>light. So all'round you have nothing to worry about here.</p>
<p>I wish Sigurd felt more happy - It makes me sick at heart to think of him worrying so much but I can blame myself for his doing so - as I have worried so much <underline>unn</underline>ecessarily. We are <underline>too</underline> serious.</p>
<p>As for Hilda - Well I can only say I feel all of her heartaches as though they were mine - also to no avail.</p>
<p>Alice is surely going to mature very soon, and I have asked Enid to get the necessary things and give them to you to Keep safely somewhere for Alice, so that she is not taken by surprise. Please Maxie keep watching - and be sure to tell her she <underline>must</underline> stay at home for <underline>3</underline> days without fail. Tell her from <underline>me</underline>. Will you?</p>
16
<p>You would please your old Mom, by sending a pattern with long sleeves, so that I can make Joanie the proper clothes for every day. I shall <underline>love</underline> to</p>
<p>Mom Daisy and Mrs Cantwell and Mrs Miser all think Joanie has grown so much. They also think she is too pale and thin. So Nannie feels she has quite <unclear>a</unclear> duty on her hands!</p>
<p>Gaki just now has taken Joanie for a walk - and she seemed so tickeled. Little by little she will take <underline>longer</underline> walk<cutoff/> They should help her.</p>
<p>Well Maxie I must close this heart to heart talk by saying once mroe how intensely grateful I am for you, just <underline>you</underline></p>
Love in endlessness
Mom.