<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
50c
Monday
Dear Mom &amp; Dad;
<p>ThanKs for those last good letters. Yes Dad - I have the Ames letter ready to type tomorrow. SIg had to taKe a trip to Fayette &amp; will by to land Central College for a lecture. He is also contacting them as well as the Colloege at Fulton (Wm Woods) for a position in the piano department. Every weeK he will maKe one contact wither in Mo. or Ill. for this purpose as well as trying to land lectures. he had a lead at Wm woods - we'll let you Know how it is when he returns.</p>
<p>Miss Bamer (she doesn't speel it that way but I don't Know how its properly spelled!) was here for dinner this evening. It was so nice seeing her &amp; we had a good visit.</p>
<P>Last evening we had Alberts sisters and their husbands over as a farwell gesture for Louise's busband, Rudolph, who leaves for the Army Wednesday. Poor Kid, she was too near tears all evening. he plays an accordian so we had him record some numbers &amp; dedicate them to Louise. We had a nice evening.</P>
50d
2.
<p>Nice letter from Alice today - she got extra line worK with the show troupe of 16 line girls and was thrilled to pieces for the extra money as well as the extra experience.</p>
<p>Was out at Enids Saturday to attend Baby Nei's birthday party and had loads of fun. He is such an adorable child and I'll declare - he looKs just liKe the picture of the Neihardt Kids - Alice or Enid or Hilda at the toddling stage, I'm recalling the one where Eny was hiding her head against you Mom - becuase she was too shy to have her picture taKen. He's a real Neihardt adn certainly fits his name! Bless his bones! Joan &amp; Elaine had a wonderful time. Francis was there too and they enjoyed playing with him. He was very nice to them considering his great age - which, at time, weighs heavily upon him! I told him Joan was going to Dozier School this year - by way of conversation you Know &amp; he replied "Oh, I'm too interested in a little Brunette to notice anyone else!" Later he got Ollie off in a corner &amp;
 asKed him how old Joan was - if she could read or write. Ollie said Yes - she could. Francis then said "Does she Know anything about Enistein?" and Ollie</p>
50e
3.
<p>said - yes he supposed Dad Neihardt had told her about Enistein - so Francis thought a bit and then said, "Well, I guess she's worth playing with them."</p>
<p>Albert &amp; Hilda have taKen Miss Bamer back to her hotel this eveing &amp; are meeting the bus to see if Amama arrived.</p>
<p>Mom, Joan's hair is nearly long enough to braid decently now. I am worKing with it - oil treatments &amp; brushing it to maKe it grow faster. She looKs quite grown up all braided up. MaKes me thinK of a little gazell, she's so tall and dewey eyed.</p>
<p>Haven't heard from Mom Daisy. Do you Know if Marie is there yet?</p>
<p>Its been too hot here.</p>
<p>Let me Know when you plan to come up so I can send you money for shipping the bed before you come.</p>
<p>Guess there's not much more to gossip about. Any new's from Boonville? We hope for it to be good when it comes.</p>
<p>Heaps of love from us all. The Wubs send Kisses and hugs to you both dear Nanny &amp; Gaki.</p>
Maxie &amp; Sigs wubs.
50f
Wed.
Dear Mom &amp; Dad;
<p>Before I foret I'll answer some of the questions you asKed in your last letter. Ames was written about a weeK ago - the folder was sent to Boodin at the same time. I have written others - about ten colleges but no answer as yet. I'll write more soon.</p>
<p>I've bene so busy getting the wubs in school. Yesterday we registered which tooK until noon as the schools are very crowded. Joan was put in the first section of grade two. Elaine, of course, was put in the afternoon class of Kindergarden.</p>
<p>Joan is very happy in her room <strike>and outside of</strike> the first few hours - <strike> in which</strike> she was hard to put to be brave - bless ehr little heart. But today is much easier for her as she has friends now.</p>
<p>Elaine had no trouble yesterday but she shed a tear or two today</p>
2
<p>when I left her. Dear little girl. I taKe Joan at 8:45 mornings and return for her at 12:00. We lunch and they both return at 1:00 to stay until 3:15. I have eight trips to maKe. In between I do my houseworK. But its fun and will be more so for them when they get used to it. They are such good babies. Its so quiet here now. I was really more afraid for Joan then I was Elaine but Joan put on such a brave front and even tho she pucKued a time or two she never did breaK down. But Elaine did. She had made such brave statements, as "Why, I wouldn't cry," and "Mama - why does Joan feel sad?" in her stormy little way. But she was the one to cry.
<p>MaaKe your trip near one of our pay-days. Just following the 1st of a month of the 15th of a month for we have our own surplus of these times.</p>
3.
<p>I don't Know whether to say I'm glad or sorry about Kemper. I suppose its for the best. Anyway its what you want and strive for that matters I guess. I don't Know very much such things - but its my believe that everything happenes for a reason.</p>
    <p>Thanks for suggesting that I send Jed to Pat. I would never have thot of it and I was so glad to send her something that was of value to me.</p>
<p>I must be shop now.Hil &amp; I go together. I rec'd the baby booKs - thanKs so much for I really needed the birth certificates. And was so happy to see my booKs again. </p>
<p>Glad Katie will have George. The Wubs thinKs its a swell idea.</p>
<p>We all wish &amp; wish we could see GaKi's bust now, Mom. I Know it must be wonderful. I'm so happy about it. The Dream too must be a beauty from the account we had of it from Amama.</p>
<p>Must go. Heaps of love to you both. I don't Know yet what to do about the bed. I can't send fo rit until the 15th but will then I guess if I can raKe up the money.</p>
Love,
Sig, Max &amp; wubs.
<p>Amama says the bust does every thing but breathe!</p>
50g
<strike>Hawthorn Coat Company
688 Arcade Bldg.
812 Olive St.</strike>
St. Louis, Mo.
SAINT LOUIS, MO 6
SEP 1
6-PM
1942
<stamp>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
ARMY AND NAVY
FOR DEFENSE
POSTAGE 2 CENTS</stamp>
<stamp>UNITED STAES OF AMERICA 
INDUSTRY AGRICUTLRUE
FOR DEFENSE
POSTAGE 1 CENT</stamp>
Dr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Missouri
Box 167
S.V. Neihardt
5833 Bartmer
St. Louis, Mo.
<p>Have sent the folder to Boodin.</p>