<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
33
16
Monday. 
Feb. 4th,,35. 
My own dear, dear Enid.
Your wonderful surprise came to day to make me feel so happy and proud and grateful! How dear of you to spend some of your very first pay checkque on your old Mother! I have been wishing and wishing for amid meek note from you, and when this lovely box came with your dear handwriting on it I just kissed and kissed it! Oh girlie mine it is impossible for me to say the things that are deep down in my heart - but darling some day you will under-

34
stand how much I love you and how your thoughtful-ness touches that old sore spot that is my heart. 
I am so greatful that you are not here - for I have been in another one of those queer places that life has put me in since 25 years ago I came West. I can tell you about it and it won't hurt you, as it would do were you here - and yet it will keep you posted with home. 

35
Daddy left after Aunt Lu had been at Mother's for several days. One day before he left he came ot me on his way each from Mother's house and said "Mona Lulu is not patient with Mamma as you have been "I was so surprised I did not know what to reply - and he patted me on the back! After Daddy left i went in to Mothers' one day and she was all worked up and having a terrible cry - ing spell. She looked at Lu as though she could not stand her and said to me We must put her out - She does not love me - she hates me! No one 

36
could treat a mother like she treats me if she cared for her! I don't want her here, she tells you lies about me and makes you think I am crazy. Everything she tells you is a big lie - and I am not dying fast enough to suit her - She must go I cna find some one else to take care of me! etc. etc. Well I was so taken a back - that I did not know what to do. I petted Mother and told ehr Lu was just tired out - she had been with her day and night - on her feet all the time - and so she might 

37 
have been a bit cross - but she surely did not mean it! She had come all th way from Minnestoa to take care of her and she was doing <del>did</del> all one perosn could do to keep up her house. do the house work and take care of her deep her front r oom in nice or-der and hav e"things" look nice. Mother did quiet down, but said she wanted me there! So I todl her I'd spend teh night with her, so that Lu could get soem rest over at my house. Well Enid - that night I spend with Mother, with our Daddy's Mother! I'll never never forget! The things she said to 

38
me are worth more than all of her property. She said "Oh, Mona, Mona, why should this have come upon me? If I had only known! I wish I had known what Daddy siad was true-long ago! I said: Why Mother you have always insisted that John was not fair to your girls - and that the girls were so fine! "She said "yes, but if I had it to do over again, I'd right about face." Oh Mona, Mona I am so sorry! 
I tried to show her how good Lu was being - but she only re-heated you don't know how she treats me when we are alone - she 

39
does nto love me - she wants me to hurry and die, so she can get back to her family-" 
I said Mother she is doing the bet she can - and we must believe in teh good in people nothing else is real. <del>Sten</del> You must just be quiet now and rest and soon you will wake up and every thing will be alright - "She said: Oh Mona, Mona I alway knew you were that kind of a girl!" I asked her if she did not trust me. She said "I'd trust you to the ends of the Earth!" All the while she was stroking pain-fully but clearly. Then she 

40
added - "Mona I will come back to you - to you, because I know I can come to you! Not to "the girls" - and not to John, because what he calls "his growth" has come between us - but to you because you are "Earthly" enough so that I can come to you! 
I told her that I would be loading for her - and she would be Oh so welecome! 
Enid this means so much to me - and therefore I want you to know of it, now when it is all so fresh.

41
in my mind. The next day when I'd come to Mother she seemed more composed but when first she saw me she broke down and cried - and I told her everything was fine - and she must not cry or I coudl not see her again - so she just took my hand and said Oh Mona, Mona!-
Yesterday at about noon I thought she was going to pass away - she put her arm puainfully about my neck - and about Lu's and said our names - but she went into a state of coma, a sort of sleep - and did not  

42
waden till late in the after-noon. I was with her that night also - and in the morning we had to have the Dr give her an injection in the arm to make her quiet, as she seemed in pain and was very restless since midnight. How it is afternoon - and she is still sleeping adopted sleep. She does not look like her-self- but she has a strong heartbeat - and may just exist for many days or weeks. 
I believe she is trying to keep on thinking till 

43
John gets back.-
They say some times people turn against those nearest and dearest to them as the very last - but I believe that Mohter was just being herself in an exaggerated form, and that she could not stand being told what she might do and what not by one very like herself! In other words: Lu was tired and lossed Mohter a bit, and did things her way - and Mo-ther did not like it - also Lu exagerates what she does - never forgetting herself for one in-stant - always thinking my 

44
just look what trouble I am going to for you! She is that way - but wish it all she is good and efficient and very "thingy"!! You know what I mean! 
Miss Shattle was here just now to say that Mrs Gillespie was going to bring her baby very soon for me to see. Don't think "God" or "Something" is not on the job for us! - You have alrea-dy the proof of His Help, and I have had it over and 

45
over! If we do our very best - our very very best! he will look out for the rest - you need not worry! 
Loads of Love to my Mannie and to my own girlie form her old Mother-
Mama.
Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON FEB 5 7-AM 1935 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Miss Enid Neihardt . 
Suite 118
Hotel Somerset.
150 West 47th St. 
N.Y. New York City. 