<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
60
Again! Please 
excuse this stationary! Nothing better out in this suburb! What a "hick" town! 
S.M. 
Sat. Nite! 
Febr. 13th, '32. 
Dear Maxine,
Just back from St. Louis! 
Was s'posed to be doing some piano practice, out guess what happened! I trust you of course - to promise tha tyou'll not let this news out of your mind 'til after Dad & I have returned to Branson! You see, it's a big surprise & we don't want the folks to know anything at all about it til we get home, because 

61
-2-
they might think we've gone silly while in St. Louis! So don't tell anyone, please! 
Here's what we did: we left the place in Manchester (suburb of St. Louis) & went to Saint Louis for the day (Sat.) & were looking around at the Auto-Slaes places! I "spied" a gorgeous auburn "88" 8 cylinder (1930-model) sport sedan & went crazy over its looks! Dad saw what a great car it was, so out on the street we 

JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
Went with it for an airplane thrill of a ride! So we turned the Gardner in on this beautiful car! It is cream colored (two tone Duco) sport sedan with Brewster "V" Windshield It cannot be told from brand new by the most scrutinizing eye! Oh! I miss you so much that I can't explain it, my dear! I won't be happy 'til I see you! you are the dearest girl that ever was! 
I have wished for 

62
-3-
you more than you imagine! 
Every time i think of you, darling, I think more than ever of you! Oh! My dear you are the sweetest thought of my life! It is just how I feel at all times or I would not say it! 
I wished for you while at the gorgeous stage lighting at the Fox theatre in the world is right in St. L. (this new Fox). I hope you have been feeling better'n I have 
(over)

JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
because I've been sorta on the blink 'til today, but I feel keen now! Going to SD. Charles for Sun. nite lecture! Haven't seen a single person that I know in St. Louis except my old Webster Groves piano teacher! He hasn't changed a bit in 3 yrs. This letter is so silly sounding but I do miss you more'n you know! Hope your brother is better! I'll get a letter from you soon (Maybe St. Charles). 
Always with Love, 
Sigurd. 

63
SAINTLOUIS,MO FEB 14 830PM 1932 
AIR-MAIL <FIGURE/> SAVES TIME UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHSINGTON 2CENTS2
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 