<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
60d
Donato Guerra
Departamento 16
May 2, 1943.
Dear Mama and Daddy (if he is home now),
<p>it has now been several days since I last wrote you - in French. I am happy to hear from you soon. It seems so long since I received your letter - and I have received absolutely <hi rend="underline">no</hi> other letters from the U.S. than your one. I understand you are busy, but I do not see why someone else does not write. If you would only drop a few lines <hi rend="underline">often</hi>, I'd be <hi rend="underline">so</hi> happy, Mama dear.</p>
<p>It has been lovely here - with rain storms almost every day, however - for an hour or more. Several days have been actually cold and not, but for the main the weather has been all one could ask. The sky is a <hi rend="underline">light</hi>, never a tropical, blue, and frequently we are surrounded by a thin strata of fog, which hides the lovely mountains. It is all the more fascinating, therefore, to discover on a suhshiny morning that one <hi rend="underline">can</hi> see these.</p>
<p>The other day I had a most fascinating experience. Having gotten dressed to go see the American Consul (whom it seems had been transformed since the Countess had been here, and finding her was not the same man ,men-</p>
(2)
<p>tioned on our letter of introduction we decided not to go - That left us all dressed up with "no place to go" - that day, at least herefore I decided on a "happing" expedition (The (")indicate <hi rend="underline">ho</hi> intention to <hi rend="underline">buy</hi> only to <hi rend="underline">look</hi>) I took a bus to the Zoralo in downtown Mexico and there, last myself in the maze of little shops which border the lively, historical square of the old Cathedral and the Palace. I went up and down the little calles to search of "Jeyerirs"- jewelry shop, where I hoped to find some small gemstones afar Daddy. I had no luck till I sighted a small shop, a silver factory, and a smiling gentleman standing in the door. There I went at once and was told that the stones I desired would be secured for me. Don't say anything to Daddy - but I do hope to get some really nice things for him. Leaving that shopping district, I proceeded to the square, and bargained awhile at the many stands in the arcade. Wasn't in a buying mood, and besides most of the stores were closed by that time for siesta (noon to 4:00 daily). I found a little bookstore open and arranged for a Spanish</p>
60e
(3)
<p>to be secured for me that I may learn verbs in earnest. I was received there with many smiles, for they could see I was interested in learning the language of Mexico (como no?) In Spanish I was directed to the entrance of the Cathedral, which was soon to re-open. A storm was brewing, and great black clouds allowed the escape of scattered drops of rain - each of which seemed to seek out a flower on my lovely "chapeon verlet brun i la maman"! This I did not mind, however, for the terrible beauty of a storm bends itself perfectly to such a scene as an ancient Cathedral and any ancient Palace. While standing before this huge, wonderfully carved, historically - rich edifice, I <hi rend="underline">felt</hi> as dwarfed (in <hi rend="underline">various</hi> ways) as I actually was - and I was aroused from this train of thought only by the approach of a kindly, tall, keen-faced stranger, who informed me that he was a guide and desired to show me about. From that moment on I was in a trance. As the church was not yet open we went first to see the Palace. The guide spoke both fluent and highly descriptive English &amp; if with a bit of his original Spanish accent and furthermore, seemed to possess a soul. He explained in great detail each room in the Palace - the many offices</p>
(4)
<p>of Mexican rulers, the huge library (<unclear/> occupied by monks etc. Then we <unclear/> the staircase at the top of which oen may view at best advantage the huge murals of Diego Rivera, picturing the entire history of Mexico. these murals are unusually fine in that they actually encompass everything of importance in what they attempt to portray. The guide told me that the artist comes every morning (9:00 till 1:00) to work on the new murals and these I saw in their unfinished condition. Descending we walked through Carlota's Garden, and I learned many new and interesting highlights of the career of Mademeliano and Carlota in Mexico. In spite of or perhaps more because of the rain, I continued to enjoy my excursion. We braved the storm to dash across the street to the Cathedral - and how I longed for you, Mama, from then on! The immense, dim room that we entered exceeded in size and <unclear/> any I have ever imagined, of course you have seen the fine churches of Europe, but I do believe you too would have been <hi rend="underline">profoundly</hi> impressed. There we stood speechless, till the guide began as usual to impart his abundancy of knowledge, in his highly interesting and strangely <hi rend="underline">un</hi>-annoying manner.</p>
60f
(5)
<p>That room is 335 feet long, 167 feet wide, and 235 feet high, and it cost hundreds of lives as well as thousands of pesos to build. It was in construction for two hundred yeas. As our eyes grew more accustomed to darkness (semi) I could see more plainly. Ahead of us was a glorious altar rising to the foot above. It was ornamented by hundreds of carved figures all sprayed with <hi rend="underline">22</hi> carat gold, and in the center was a lovely painting of a Saint. This, I was told, was the Altar of Pardon. It was named so far a young Jew who, after having thrown into jail by the Inquisition, painted such a lovely picture that he was par-donned. From here we continued through the entire Cathedral. There were many other altars, each very, very beautiful in its own special way. Two huge organs, one from Spain, one from Italy rose majestically at the center of the one beautiful room; and this contrast of styling held good through same. At the extreme opposite end of the Cathedral, we came to the loveliest all all altars - on exact replica of the one in Sevilla Spain and ornate beyond words. In <unclear type="cut-off"/> with carved figures of various description (all of gold-gilt) were paintings by Mexico’s finest artists, all on religious subjects, of course. This altar covers the entire center of the back wall, and is three sided (indented). I shall never forget the feeling of intense admiration that fairly sweet  me off the little plain of daily - consciousness that we <unclear>hunsays</unclear> live on! To stand there and actually see that work</p>
(6)
<p>of love and devotion and <unclear>dear</unclear> for many was a great privilege. This feeling continued when we left the large <unclear>chiorche</unclear> and went into the <sic>adjoing</sic> monk's quarters (originally) where we were conducted through the one large room where are preserved the vestments of the priests altar cloths, Holy Figures, etc. - and mostly from the <unclear/> 16th and 7th centuries. The vestments and altars cloths, of Spanish, Italian, and Mexican origin are all gorgeously and artistically designed and woven of gold, silver, and colored threads. So masterly were the makers that the expressions are perfect on the faces of the figure solid wood, and a lovely little energy dressed and ornamented with rare jewels. Truly the loveliest painting of the Madonna and Child that I have every seen hung at one corner of the room and I stood long before it, with a feeling of something more then intense admiration, while the two guides discussed its perfection in Spanish. The latter surprised me greatly for I'd never heard such before among <hi rend="underline">guides</hi>. At the other side I was shown the figure of Christ, the Crucifixion, all in <hi rend="underline">perfect</hi> proportion, and with an expression truly unusually beautiful sorrowful and yet patient and <hi rend="underline">glorified</hi></p>
60g
(7)
<p>You can imagine how entranced I was and I boarded the bus and rode home to dinner. Doris said to me, as the details of my visit were being told, "You are beautiful with that Light in your eyes." God help me to feel that more often - for it is what I seek always, deep down inside.</p>
<p>We have been leading a busy life in <hi rend="underline">several</hi> ways - and a highly interesting one for me. At the theatre we live form 7:30 to 11:50 in the evening. After that and before that time we are free for rehearsals, housework, pleasure, or shopping.</p>
<p>I am continuing this letter with 11th of May and I do hope you'll forgive me my delay, Mama, I shall try to write all that has happened. A week ago yesterday, Sylvia and I went to Chapulteper Park with a fellow American Act at the theatre, the Tucker sisters and their mother. We visited the castle "Castilio de Maxumano" first of all, and had a guide explain everything to us. The day was clear enough to see <unclear>Papea tepetye</unclear> and I <unclear>tac ciuatl</unclear> - snow covered and partially veiled in clouds. Leaving the castle, we went for a beautiful walk through the same woods I had visited alone on a previous Sunday. The Tuckers are natives of Dallas and are sweet wholesome, appreciative people. We walked along are bord due "lago" Also, and had fresas con cremas. Returned happy and refreshed.</p>
(8)
<p>Tuesday we were to have had rehearsal for the new show at the <unclear/> but this was changed to Wednesday so we took advantage of our leisure by seeing "Fantasio." You <hi rend="underline">must</hi> see this if you get the chance (on a return run) for it is truly amazingly beautiful, artistic, and clever - all Walt Disney technicolor. Returned home at 6:00 for a delicious meal then walked to the theatre, arrived as usual at 7:30 (just as show was beginning) and made up for our usual two evening performances. You see we are on about an hour after the show begins, so have plenty of time.</p>
<p>Wednesday we rehearsed with orchestra before the first evening performance for our "Marin" dance - and this was received very well both by audience and fellow performers, later in the evening. Now, here comes a bit of news on the sad side. Doris hurt her knee on the stage one evening during performance of our "Jungle Dance." She managed to dance, however, several nights after the accident. Then she saw a very <unclear/> Dr. - friend of our apt. manager - who forbidden her to dance till further notice from him. As it happens, we have done the "Jungle" before without Doris but the "Sailor" or "Marin" is built for we three girls alone, without George so this presented a bit more of a problem. Not for long, however, for George took over Doris' part. You see, we two (Doris and I) are French sailors, and Sylvia is a little French wharf-maiden</p>
60h
(9)
<p>George is now replacing Doris as some sailor, which I am the other, or always. You can imagine how <unclear/> this is - and we have gotten much better applause since the change! Saturday evening, our manager of the apt. came to see us (He speaks French as well as Spanish and is truly cultivated) and like us so much he took his wife to see us next day. We are getting really fine publicity in all the papers too, which is marvelous for the act. I shall keep sending you this for you to place in the scrapbook, dear Mama.</p>
<p>Sunday, Mother's Day, we performed at Chapultepec Park in a large outdoor theatre, on a fine by stage. There were over 20,000 people present - and the performance was both good and varied, as well as several hours long. There were sketches done by Mexican motion picture stars, Spanish dancing, singers, and the only American pet present was the George Leon Dancers. We did our waltz and our entire Russian (sans Doris) and were given a marvelous reception by the audience. Several people offered to drive us home, and one gentleman invited us to Cuccnava, where he will show us all the sights via his own auto. We returned to Donato Guerra, ate lunch,</p>
(10)
<p>and left for the theatre for a Sunday <unclear/> at 4:15. After the matinee we took a taxi home for dinner. When we arrived there, someone was waiting for us in the living room. It was Max, and he announced that his brother was also in town, and they both wanted to come see us dance that night. We invited him to stay for supper, which he did - and afterwards we left for the Folies Berger. Max and his brother were waiting for me after the last performance, and took me thence on a round of night club thing. As before, we had an evening of absolute happiness - and something so good about it all, too relieve me. I can really appreciate true gentlemanliness and fineness now - and it is the element I love George and Max and his brother are <hi rend="underline">all</hi> gentlemen, and they shine as such I got home in the early morning, with a feeling of Something different than I usually feel after an evening of gaiety - something beautiful and <hi rend="underline">unsordid.</hi></p>
<p>Slept till 9:30, got up and did housework, my personal chores and then napped an hour. At 4:30, Max and his brother came to take me to the Olympis to see "Seis Dectinos" really a grand movie. At 7:30 we</p>
60i
(10)
<p>left for the theatre where Max left me. We did our two performances there, and afterwards went to the Bremen, a club in which we shall "double" for a week. Max and Heinz came to see us there, and we had a nice time together. We did our entire Russian; did our opening, then the trepal and chellegc as encores. Sylvia and I rode home with Max and Heinz, and had a jolly time joking and laughing in French. In fact, when with them I speak mostly French.</p>
<p>This day we arose at 1:30 in the afternoon, and, after housework, have been doing such things as ironing washing and I, writing you. Max and Heinz left today to return to there rancho, but Max shall return the 21st or 22nd.</p>
<p>This next week the show is to change again and we shall do an apache dance (which George shall arrange as a special favor for the show. It should be fun - rough and <unclear>trimph</unclear> as such dances are. We may triple at a second club later on.</p>
<p>I am looking about for gemstones for Daddy - and I want to know form you what you especially would like - oh please, Mama for you will make me very happy if you are</p>
(11)
<p>Is Daddy still in Chicago? What is Hilda doing now - anymore prospects? How is your job - and what of your government "travail"? How is Albert - and how is <hi rend="underline">his</hi> work. How are Eny and Ollie and Nei? (And <hi rend="underline">new</hi> one to be) And how are Sig and Max Joan and Elaine. Is Sig still going to Natal Brazil? Are the rest going to Branson? Is Amama there yet? Give my love to all - as always - and stranger than ever now that 2100 miles be between us.</p>
<p>Write me, dearest of Maman, and know how I love you - and how I appreciate you now <hi rend="underline">more</hi> than ever for I have seen more of the world. I love our life - its contacts, our dancing, our excitments - and still I feel you with me always - for you are a constant inspiration. That is simple truth.</p>
Loads of Love
Your Alice