<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.6.26-32">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper, June 3, 1925</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.6.26-32</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper</title>
                    <date when="1925-06-03">June 3, 1925</date>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Piper, Mildred</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Lulu</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Neihardt-Ballinger, Grace</term>
                    <term>Hubbard, Elbert, 1856-1915.</term>
                    <term>Neiahrdt, Alice</term>
                    <term>Perkins, Dorothy</term>
                    <term>Mitchel, Dr.</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Sioux City (Iowa)</term>
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Buffalo (N.Y.)</term>
                    <term>Grinnell (Iowa)</term>
                    <term>Minneapolis (Minn.)</term>
                    <term>Coal City (Ind.)</term>
                    <term>Canada</term>
                    <term>Niagara Falls (N.Y.)</term>
                    <term>Aurora (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Hastings (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Piper, Mildred</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4876523">Sioux City (Iowa)</placeName>
                    <date when="1925-06-03"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">27 26</note>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    #255 
                    Branson Mo.
                </ab> 
                
                <ab type="dateline">
                    June 3, 1925
                </ab> 
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    BRANSON JUN 3 1 PM M.O.
                </ab> 
                
                <ab type="address">
                    Miss Mildred Piper 
                    1921 West 7th St
                    Sioux City 
                    Iowa.
                </ab> 
                
                <note type="authorial">
                    Please forward.
                </note> 
                    
            </div1>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">27</note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Branson Mo. 
                        June 3-1925
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>My Dear little girl-</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>Maybe you have gotten the thots that have been going you-ward for a long time and if you have you are not surprised that no letter has gone your way for so long; I really dont' remember what Ihave told you of my winter's trip and I know you are just now finding out that I am home again I have not been well. For the last year and a half.</p>
                
                <p>people who reacted my house did not vacate until the 15th of April so stayed at John's until they went, Oh I wish I could have a talk with you, there are so many things that woudl be worth talking, but to write them seems impossible Mother was very sick with the Flu and has never recovered but is able to be about is all. She spoke of 4</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">28</note>
                
                <p>home shorter by two weeks than I had blamed, Had a lonely time in Buffalo and also in Cal city, was so busy in Grindle where my mother is living <del>visiting</del> with my sister. I was with mother 6 weeks and then went to Minneapolis to see Lulu and her family, spent three weeks there and then back to Grinnell again reaching home the 4th of April.</p>
                
                <note type="authorial">2</note> 
                
                <p>part of the time hardly able to be about at all I think I could compete with Ulyssus for wander-ings, found myself in Branson after a 7 1/2 month's absence, left here the last day of last any for Buffalo stayed with Grace until the 15th of Jan. and would have been there longer but for the illness of my mothe so hastened my visit there and also cut my visit in Coal City Enid. My girlhood</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">29</note>
                <note type="authorial">5</note>
                
                <p>she spoke of you so often and wants to be remembered to you always. Lulu and Grace both asked about you, I was so glad I had that lovely photo of you to show them and now it has a place of honor on my mantel and looks so sweet and friendly I have always been so glad you came into my life as you did and altho I seem to forget, don't believe it you are my girl always</p> 
                <p>chicken yard is just one big bank loaded with buds - then there are dozens of bush roses, loaded with blossoms oh how I wish you could see them, the yard is so pretty my garden is late but we have had peas and new potatoes since the first of May-then I must not forget to tell you about my strawberry bed - we had such beasts of strawberries every way.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">30</note>
                <note type="authorial">6</note>

                <p>I wished so many times when I was at the Library with Grace that you were there too, she likes her work so well and Buffalo is great place to live. The Lake there is so lovely I had several trips across the lake and was in Canada several times to Niagara falls - to East Aurora where Elbert Hubbard lived, was thru the shops They were wonderful to me, But the Branson Hills looked good to me</p> 

                <p>and little Alice was so glad to see her grandma - In fact they all acted glad to have me home - my yard is beautiful - the fence between John and me is covered for 50 ft or more with the Dorothy Perkins rose on the lattices on either side of the front porch the American Pillar is a mass clear to the roof on the fence on the East next to Dr. Mitchels, the fence clear back to the</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">31</note>
                <note type="authorial">9</note>
                
                <p>shortcake with Jersey cream-strawberry pie and just strawberries the children and I would pick a dishpan full at once, I canned a few. I msut tell you before I forget it that in April John was in Hastings-just over night I think and he said he was standing on the street talking to some one and the man said - "did you know that lady?" and</p> 

                <p>love from all of us to the tired little school teacher - how I wish you were going to be here with me this summer.</p> 
                <p>My bread is in the oven and needs attention I will says good bye to you with love
                    and best wishes to you and all of yours - please write soon and tell me all
                    about your self your plans for next year</p> <p>Alice M.
                        Neihardt</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.26-32"/>
                <note type="curatorial">32</note>
                <note type="authorial">10</note>
                
                <p>when he looked you had gone clear by He was not sure it <del>you</del> was you but said it was dark and he thot <del>it</del> she looked like you I was so disappointed and asked him why he did not follow you He laughed and said what if it had not been Miss Piper I would have been arrested for following a lady, Mona has not been very well for some</p> 

                <p><del/> time, but she keeps going, Enid and Sigurd are doing so well in their music, Sigurd reallly is wonderful, Enid is the good average I think we will live in Lincoln some of these times then you will think it your duty to show your self to us at least once a year, when you get home this letter will be there to greet you and it carries bushels</p>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>