<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
141 Fink Collection 37
<gap reason ="torn"/>
Neihardt
Branson,
Mo.

BUFFALO
AUG 17
11 AM
1939
S. DAK.

Mrs. O.F.Fink
9716 Hawthorne Ave
Overland, 
Mo.

Saint Louis
County.
38
Thursday A.M.
Buffalo, S.D.

Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie:
<p>While Daddy is putting a few ideas together on paper to be used in his talk Saturday I want to write to you and let you know how much you have been in our thoughts.</p>
<p>You already know this part of the West, Enid, and need non of my questionable descriptive powers; enought be it to say that much has been beautiful and invigorating to me. Especially the Black Hills. I think Rapid City a charming city and it reminds me a little of Baden-Baden in the Black Forest. Daddy want to see the Papermen there, and feel around for a possible job for you Ollie dear, thinking that you might both love it as we do. I wish we could have a cabin spotted within easy reach of Rapid City, where we all could spend next Summer - and then if you should be set - <unclear/> there, how wonderful that would be for the Neihardt clan! What do you both say?</p>
<p>Daddy says you will remember Buffalo as that funny little Western town with a hitching post for horses and a store etc on one side of the street! Well it has grown tremendously, being quite a place with no less than 3 garages a Hotel and what</p>
39
<p>not. We have spent two nights at their new cabin camp, paying only $1.00 per night.</p>
<p>Daddy is looking and feeling fine- Today we expect to go on to Bison - in plenty of time for the "doings" Saturday.</p>
<p>We stopped but a minute with Everetts at Sturgis but we expect to see them longer on the way Home. The son is making money hand over fist in a Cleaning and Stem Laundry Business of his own. He supplies no less than 15 C.C.C. Camps all around, to say nothing of all other trade. The father and mother help him all they can and he is surely hitting the ball. Daddy seems to really want to stop and visit on our way back so we probably will do so. I am more eager to find out things around and in Rapid City, thath may prove to be of value for Ollie and you as well as the rest of us.</p>
<p>It was truly cold last night. We slept under our blankets and comforter, and today we both feel fine. At first I was dizzy and could not get enough air into my system, but now I do not notice that any more.</p>
<p>I picked up a picture</p>
40
<p>of a love rider in an office here which reminded me of you, as I though you'd just love to have it on the wall somewhere. So I will send it to you with a dime for which please buy a frame for me. I could not send the glass very well or I would have bought it here for you.</p>
<p>This S.D. Pairie should be called the Neihardt Desert - as so much of his Poetry celebrates this part of S. Dak. don't you think so? I hope to see the Hugh Glass Monumnet on this trip too.</p>
<p>Day before yesterday we experienced a little miracle. In the midst of a burning hot dry sky a cloud gathered in the West, Lightening flashed out of it and the cloud moved over our heads, rained a hard rain for almost 5 minutes so that Daddy had to use the windshield wiper, then moved on into the East and dissolved - leaving the day as hot and the sky as clear as before. Daddy had prayed for rain the night before._ These experiences cannot all be coincidences, can they?</p>
<p>A nice balck &amp; white doggy has decided to sleep at our doorstep - quite a</p>
41
<p>la Neihardt, is it not?</p>
<p>I am hoping the flowers are continuing to bloom down home and that this trip will do something to help Daddy get into Jed Smith again when we get back. The trees will look goood to us when we get back there, and I am missing the family a lot.</p>
<p>Loving you both always.</p>
Your own devoted
Mama.
Mother