<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
60a
Madison, Wisconsin,
March 23, 1939.

Dearest Mama:
<p>I am stranded in Madison for a couple of days, owing to Carburetor trouble on the car. The United Motors Service Co. here had to order parts clear form St. Louis, form teh Carter Carburetor Company, manufacturers. Nothing serious, but a very handicapping delay.</p>
<p>I was very glad for your letters of late. I am sure that all will work out well for Alice. Somehow I have a hunch that it is only a matter of a short time until she'll be O.K. Isn't it fine that Mr. Fortunato has such an attitude towards her abilities.</p>
<p>I wish that you would write me, no letter then Sunday to EAU CLAIRE, WISCONSIN, general delivery. It does mean a great deal to me to hear from you, and to know how all goes with everyone.</p>
<p>I have been having a rather difficult time, owing to the fact that it is early yet to book 'On the spot'. But how in hell is a fellow going to hit a better time than right now when each institution seems to have its own pet time for arranging its coming years schedule. See? It's nothing to worry about tho', because I have contracted some nice ones already, and in the case of the others I've left 'em with their promise to contact me at a certain time. Of course we'll undergo delays, nevertheless the year to come will have a nice big income for us, ever tho' booking periods for various ones are scattered through the months. I got a swell summer engagement, two, in fact, for us at Carbondale, Ill., also Univ. of Illinois. Isn't that swell? Also I landed one for Nov. and several others, so I can't kick.</p>
<p>Dad had a marvelous success at Des. Moines, and I've written for a testimonial. This will enable me to land the one-day forum at Evansville, Indiana, for $125. near the Evansville, Ind. Teachers convention which I just contracted. Whoopee!</p>
<p>Always take it easy as possible.</p>
Give my love to Hil and Al, also Ol &amp; Eny.
Always you devoted - <signed>Sig.</signed>
Sigurd.