<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
p82- <strike>283</strike> Fink Collection 134
BRANSON
MAY28
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs O. F Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland, Mo.
St Louis County
<underline>Over</underline>
<p>Eny dear - will write soon thanks for your letter.</p>
135
Dearest Enid and Ollie
<p>Your dear birthday letter was so very welcome and added a great deal of my happiness. Letters from Hilda and Alice arrived with yours and Max had an extra dinner for Nannie too. Besides I did not have to wash the dishes but could feel like a lady! Joanie asked that I dress up in my pretty green and pink dress - which she remembered from <underline>last Summer</underline>! So I got it out of my dresser drawer and ironed it for the occasion. I like it ever better than I did last year, which is saying a lot, Enid dear.</p>
<p>No girlie please do not buy me a birthday gift as we</p>
136
2
<p>all must save money now.</p>
<p>Daddy had pictures taken of the bust today and it should be successful as they certainly took pains with it. I'll send you one as soon as possible.</p>
<p>I am looking forward to the time when I can make a little "Madonna" of you and your baby fro your mantlepiece. So when you come home here next Summer you can Know what too expect!</p>
<p>Marie is right now in the Springfield Hospital for her new baby, Maxie just heard. We had a little much needed rain last night - our poppies are about 3 inches to 4 inches high, Hollyhocks are as tall as I am, and cannas over one foot. Roses are marvelous -</p>
135
3
<p>the Mulberries are so big and juicy that the birds have not bothered with our cherries which we have enjoyed to the fullest this year. They are all gone now.</p>
<p>Daddy works around the place pulling weeds, trimming trees and things it is a joy to me.</p>
<p>But I'm hungry for my children once more and the place is dead without them. It is fine to have Max and the Wubs but I want more of you!</p>
<p>The nursery is a great event - and worthy of all your labor and artisitc en</p>
136
<p>deavors. So wonderful too about your wagon - I am so glad you are lucky - and trust your baby is making you so! Bleass it and you my darling!</p>
<p>Do you read your Stranger at the Gate? You should!</p>
Love in endlessness
from your devoted
Mama-
Mother