<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
36a
Branson, Mo.
August 16, 1939.

Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We recieved your cards from various points along the way, and were very glad to get there you must be having a lovely trip together; I certainly hope you are! I hope everything goes fine at Bison, as it undoubtedly will!</p>
<p>Hilda left Sunday afternoon at 1. 59 on the bus. It was a pity she had to leave so soon. I have only two more weeks myself, for I must be back by Sept. 2 for the tryouts Will you be back before that, or should I plan to go by bus?</p>
<p>We're having a swell time here I haven't had time to be bored one second! I practiced about an hr. &amp; 1/2 day</p>
-2-
<p>before yesterday, first on the bar and then in our front room last Sat. evening we had Lache over for a sandwich and beer supper - wonderful sandwiches, made with your bread, Mama!</p>
<p>Yesterday Max &amp; I washed and Sig got a superb elegant dinner for all of us. We had pork chops stuffed with dressing, mashed potatoes, gravy, spinach, tomatoes, and the most delicious butterscotch pie we've ever eaten! After dinner we rested awhile - Max sleot and I read "Strange Journey," which I like immensely. About 2:15 Helen, Mary Katerin Waltz, (aross the street) and I went swimming at the beach. We had a marvelous time swimming, and even ate a watermelon on the way back! Then we rode up</p>
-3-
<p>the hill with Mr. Miser <unclear/> a supper of swell sandwiches, Max &amp; went to the show (dime nite) with Helen and Margaret Waltz while Sig stayed with Joan and Elanie.</p>
<p>Sunday afternoon I went swimming with a group of girls. <crossed>and</crossed> We took a picinic supper with us, but got caught in a wind and rain-storm before we got to eat it. We found shelter, however, in the Hale's house (friends of Helen's from New York), where we dried off and waited for the storm to quit. Finally we started out again and ate our supper by the waters edge under the bridge. The sunset there was glorious!</p>
<p>I'm planning to call Georgia today and find out when we can go horse back riding together. As</p>
-4-
<p>I know where I can get a horse for nothing - or, as I intend, for very little. The horse belongs to a fellow working at Owen Boat Line whom I know well (from school in Branson) and who rides the horse very seldom, except at night. The horse is young, coal black with three white feet. He is a rather stocily built, though very well shaped little trot and gallop horse. I rode him down at the beach yesterday, and made arrangements to rent him sometime. Isn't that swell? Then I won't have to get one of Ronnie's poor starved creatures! This horse knows various tricks such as lying down with his head flat on the ground, raring</p>
36b
-5-
<p>up, etc. He was taught by the owner of Rex, the Wonder Horse who performed at the Owen Theatre sometime ago. Georgia has been sick recently because of something she ate at a picnic but I hope she'll be well soon now.</p>
<p>I'm going to practice again today.</p>
<p>I must close now. I'll be waiting for a card or letter from you.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice