<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
313 Fink Collection 95
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
NOV27
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
<underline>Overland</underline>
St Louis County
<underline>over</underline>
<p>Hello, Nei!
Come over &amp; play with me!
Gaki</p>
96
Nov 26th 41
Dearest Three:
<p>Your letters are so gratefully received and I am especially glad you, Ollie, have to write longhand - I do love a long hand letter, especially from a man! It sort of seems as though he really cared about you when he does not use the type writer!</p>
<p>The news about the bad reaching in O.K. which must have relieved your worry for which there was no need. Many thanks again. We asked the man how much it cost prepard, and he said $2.52 as near as I remember so You must Keep the three dollars we had Hilda pass on to you, and send me some of those tablets for fertilizing plants will you not? I do not recall the</p>
<margin>Hilda &amp; Alice <strike/></margin>
97
<p>name, but always think "B.O." and then laught to my self! </p>
<p>This may seem fantastic and foolish to you, but it means a great deal to your old Mother to have the opportunity to get out some of my little trinkets to see what money I can get out of them. We do so need to get ahold of something now, and I feel less miserably incapable if I can actually make a little money on my work.</p>
<p>I Know your time is full Enid with your precious baby, who is a remarkably good, fine specimen of boy hood right now. But when his Nanny gets ahold of him he will I hope be as generous to me as he was to his Gaki. The way things are go</p>
98
<p>ing fo rus, I believe Sigurd and Daddy will be travelling together soon again and I do believe I'll then have a good chance to go visiting you. In the mean while I am very grateful to Know that you <underline>want</underline> me to come. The Winter is a bad time in which to leave Home. One has ones ways of doing and being which are not so easy to make fit into other people's Homes. And you have not much extra space now. On the other hand here I have all the room there is! Our Wubs are so good and we would hate to do without them. Maxie is so good about selling my babies. She sold 6 which I donated to the Unitarian Bazaar - and then 5 more as orders for me, at $1.25 a piece. Now the thing <strike>I am</strike> we are getting out is a thing</p>
99
<p>that appeals to every one as a practical piece I will not explain it because I want it to be a complete surprise for my grandson and his parents on Xmas. As for the Harrison Baby, let me Know at once if you want a pink one or a pale blue one - the letter I am now doing and it is really prettier than the former - You may have it as I told Hilda "entirely free gratis"! The big piece (<unclear>Tranverci</unclear>) was called "stunning" by a man "in the business" in Kansas City and I was told where to send it to possibly sell. So <sic>holp</sic> your thumbs for me! Well I have little to tell excepting that I do love you devotedly and will visit you as soon as "practical"!</p>
Love in endlessness
your <underline>Mother</underline>
100
<p>P.S. You asked about Thanksgiving! The night before was Daddy's reading at the S of O. for the trcity Rotarious - so he and I were over there eating a Vension dinner and Mom Daisy was keeping the Wubs for me at home when the St Louis crowd arrived! When we got home it was after 11 o'clock. Albert had retired into the guest room where he always sleeps. Sig and Max had gotten together into Joanie's bed and Joanie and Elaine were snoozing in Elaines' in the back room! Hilda and Alice were hunting around for what not and having a big lark anticipating how we four were to sleep in one big bed! But we dispelled their doubts as we had our plans made, and Daddy and I slept in the warm front room very comfortably while Alice and Hilda were tucked into our big bed</p>
101
<p>under a new comforter I had been making and which I had not yet finished!</p>
<p>We four had a nice visit before going to sleep - and the next day we had such a good time preparing the wonderful things Hilda had brough - A delicious goose, and (<underline>not</underline> a gander!!) was it tender, and fat! (I have a jar of goose grease which has already served for sore throats and noses - and Oh how good it feels!) We had dressing and roasted browned potatoes, fresh whole wheat bread (with two loaves for Hilda and Alice to take back and one for Maxie) - cranberry sauce that still makes my mouth water - lettuce and a raw vegetable salad with shredded coconut in it - made by Alice - Afterwards coffee and pumpking pies - All the toasts were to the point, made with a bottle of lovely white wine. The one that must have made you concious of us was a toast to little Neihardt and his two dear parents.</p>
<p>This is all - It was marvelous to have all the dear dear Kids!</p>
