<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
158 Fink Colleciton 175
December 22, 1939
Neihardt
Branson,
Mo.
BRANSON
DEC23
3 -PM
1939
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis
County
176
Dec 22nd 39.
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your exquisite by beautiful housecoat was the one thing I was wishing for - only even my wildest desires did not picture or covet anything so rich and beautiful, as the particular one you sent me. Daddy is tickeled with with the supply of R.T. R. and we are taking your gifts along on our trip to Albaquerque. We are leaving tomorrow so Sigurd has been planning for us to do this, and Daddy cannot get in a proper state of mind here for the writing of Jed Smith - besides here I cannot help him, and if we go away I can do plenty. It is a great privilege to be the one who</p>
177
<p><unclear/> go with him - and I am looking forward eagerly and happily to his first lines. He used to read me every day what he wrote - ages ago when there was litte confusion in our lives - and now it is really wonderful that the time has come when we can again be quiet and united in his work.</p>
<p>Besides we want to look over Albuquerque for its possibilities as our future home, or homes. I have made up my mind definitely that this place won't do ever again - there have been too many injustices here - and besides the climate is not stimmulating for the best in <underline>any</underline> one. So I hope never again to be here more than a very short period at a time - after this when Dad goes I got too - I am not going to remain here ever again as a sort of attachment to the furniture etc! People and not things, thoughts are more real than anything else, and I am going</p>
178
<p><unclear/> he where we all can think constructively, and live happily. Daddy is so wonderful, and it is surprising how glad he is to start West tomorrow.</p>
<p>The children are swell too. Sig packed all our Kitchen things in a case he bought for that purpose and Maxie is doing all any busy little mother or daughter <underline>can</underline> do to help is get ready. Also Sig has been tuning up the car. So, when you read this, think of us very happy and on our way to the "<sic>Promissed</sic> Land"!</p>
<p>I am taking work with me, and do so hope. I'll find a chance fo rmy work there too. I'm sure there could be more and certainly not less chance than here.</p>
<p>I called on Mrs Parnell and told her we wanted to sell, she did not say much about buying, but she did spread the news Neihardts were leaving all over town - in less than half a day it got around to Melton's that we were going to</p>
179
<p>move to Albaquerque at once! Such are liitle towns.</p>
<p>I am so glad the girls are all with you Xmas, and I know you will be happy. Ollie dear, you surely made us all laugh with your funny letters. I think that one about the plea for 5 more towels was the funniest I ever read - I could not get over seeing the picture, and hearing all the noises!!</p>
<p>Wishing you a Merry Xmas and a very happy and successful New Year,</p>
I am always your devoted
Mom - Mother.