<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
55
Fink Collection 
19 
HOTEL WELLINGTON 
MAIL 
KANSAS FEB 8 830AM MO 
<FIGURE/> 
1935
Miss Enid Neihardt 
Somerset Hotel 
150 West 47th St. 
New York City 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH 
OMAHA, U.S.A. 
Suite #118
AIR 
NOTICE 
LETTERS MAILED IN HOTEL ENVELOPES IF NOT DELIVERED WILL BE SENT TO TEH DEAD LETTER OFFICE UNLESS THE WRITER GIVES A RETURN ADDRESS 
IF NOT DELIVERED IN 5 DAYS RETURN TO 
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo. 
<figure/> 

56
<figure/> H.B. PAYNE, PRESIDENT E.M. SLATER, VICE PRES. 
150 RESTFUL ROOMS AT REASONABLE RATES 
HOTEL WELLINGTON
ON DIRECT CAR LINES FROM ALL STATIONS 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH
OMAHA 
Wed. Night 
Dearest Enat:
Grandma went away at noon today. I was out at Blair, Neb., talking to a state school convention when she died, & the wire reached me a half hour later when I was at lunch. At first I planned to leave at once for Branson, but a second wire asked me to meet Aunty Lu <del>and</del> & at K.C. where the body will be cremated: Before I left Branson I made all arrangements with Whelchel for this - at Grandma's request. So it is best for me to meet Aunty Lu at K.C. instead of going ot Branson first, where I could do no good at all, as all was arranged there. 

57
<figure/> H.B. PAYNE, PRESIDENT E.M. SLATER, VICE PRES. 
150 RESTFUL ROOMS AT REASONABLE RATES 
HOTEL WELLINGTON
ON DIRECT CAR LINES FROM ALL STATIONS 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH
OMAHA 
-2-
When I reached the city, the papers had the news of Grandma's death on the front page. Strange! All the Profs., many students and even the hotel people knew & were like brothers. Enat, people are good deep down outside - very good, that's the human truth. If they seem otherwise, it is because of some pathetic misunderstanding of some sort. 
I shoudl be talking to a class in philosophy tonight - a picked group - but they let me off. I didn't ask to be let off. I could have talked well. I know Grandma is all right, & she should know that I know

58
<figure/> H.B. PAYNE, PRESIDENT E.M. SLATER, VICE PRES. 
150 RESTFUL ROOMS AT REASONABLE RATES 
HOTEL WELLINGTON
ON DIRECT CAR LINES FROM ALL STATIONS 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH
OMAHA 
-3-
Listen, Enot, old Lady! here is something for you. This evening Dr. Thompson, Dean of men at the U. of Omaha & my very old friend (we were together in our 20's) insisted on taking me to a show. He thought I'd better not sit around. He is a psychologist, & he understands. Well, just a half hour ago he said! "This daughter of yours in New York - does she want to stay there? "I said no, not necessarily. he then said he thought he'd be needing a secretary next year, & would be glad I have my daughter. This 

59
<figure/> H.B. PAYNE, PRESIDENT E.M. SLATER, VICE PRES. 
150 RESTFUL ROOMS AT REASONABLE RATES 
HOTEL WELLINGTON
ON DIRECT CAR LINES FROM ALL STATIONS 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH
OMAHA 
-5-
is in addition to the Presidents need of a Secretary next year. So, Enot, you are now going to school in New York, getting prestige & training for a good job out here. See? By gosh, <del>a</del> I'll land you a job here. The whole school is strange for your Dad, Enot. In spite of Grandma's going, your life is a happy one even now. Grandma was ripe fruit, <del/> and it is good to go when ripe. 
Feel hopeful & eager to learn, old Lady! The outlook is fine for you. 
I rec'd Amama's dear dear letter - good, great, 

60
<figure/> H.B. PAYNE, PRESIDENT E.M. SLATER, VICE PRES. 
150 RESTFUL ROOMS AT REASONABLE RATES 
HOTEL WELLINGTON
ON DIRECT CAR LINES FROM ALL STATIONS 
FARNAM AT EIGHTEENTH
OMAHA 
<unclear/> -5- 
gray pussy cat as she calls herself, I heard & felt her purr 1500 miles away, & was glad you are lucky, Enot, to have her, as of course you know as well as I do - or better. No more now - but endless love. 
Dad. 
Later 
Have just seen Dr. Thompson again. He has spoken to Dr. Sealock of you. Sealock was interested & sympathetic & said "I think we can do that <del/> a little later on". he is strong format a wonderful man. 
So be happy
Dad 