<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
262 Fink Collection 67
p.m. Jan 31, 1941
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Friday A.M.
Dear Oddie &amp; Enot:
<p>This is the 9th day I've been tied to this couch, but I'm gaining now and should be able to walk in a few days. I have had <underline>no</underline> cold at all, and my general health has been exceptionally good. What happened was as follows: I was feeling like a million dollars just before I stooped, with a little twist of the body, under the raised trunk lid of the car. I was merely picking up a bundle of twigs weighing no more than half pound. The twist caught something just to the left of the base of the spine where the the sciatic nerve comes out. The nerve was injured somehow &amp; the whole sciatic system across the hip &amp; down to the knee blazed with pain that kept up for three days &amp; nights. After that I could control the pain more or less by lying in a certain position</p>
(over)
68
-2-
<p>What I have is the equivalent of sciatic rheumatism but without the consitutional cause. It's just an injury - like breaking a leg. The pain has been very great, but I have felt no resentiment of it and no impatience, altho I shouldn't be stopped in my work <underline>now</underline>. I state this merely as a fact, &amp; don't take any credit for it or think it is in any way virtuous. It has just been so. I've had a feeling all along that the pain was good for me - especially in the nights.</p>
<p>When I can sit up any considerable length of time, we'll start for Overland. I could force my way through now if there were some considerable need involved. Mama has been an angel, and we've been happy</p>
<p>If someone would only say a- h- on a national hookup in a dark brown Oxford voice,</p>
69
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>I'd get well immediately!</p>
<p>Ollie, ain't it awful the way democracy and the American way of life are being threatened? I just feel awful about it. And civilization - there's another thing! And religion too! I'm so proud of the way we love everything that's good &amp; holy and hate everything that's naughty and unjust.</p>
<p><sic>Enot Penot</sic>, I think <underline>very</underline> often about what you are doing, and it gives me a joyous feeling. Gaki is crazy to hold that Wub &amp; feel it pissing its didy. Funny sweet little cuss! And I want to hear it bawl.</p>
<p>We've had no winter to mention. Same rain - no snow. This is really quite a winter resort, when you compare with other sections by radio reports.</p>
Endless love,
Dad.