<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
176 Fink Collection 104
Neihardt
Branson
Mo.
BRANSON
MAR29
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F.Fink
Miss Alice Neihardt
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St. Louis
County
105
Darling Enid and Alice,
<p>You must have had a very attractive Easter celebration - and even though snowy, we too had a pleasant time. The Wubs were overjoyed with their surprises and baby 'Laines ' delight was expressed in her dramatic manner too cute to witness. We surely are blessed with King "aunts" - who have always made a great share of our babies' happiness at every festivity. To you many, many thanks!</p>
<p>Our Men left this morning for Boonville without Max, who would have gone had she not caught a dreadful cold again. I am sick of calling a place "Home" in which the women are so cold trying to do their work, to say nothing of having to get up in the night to take</p>
106
<p>care of babies in a freezing cold bedroom. It just is silly. We have always had lovely living quaters - and nothing comfortable for the women to do house work in - adn now it is so much worse since we have no cookstove. This Winter has been one more nightmare of discomfort and now at 50 odd years I am sick of it - So there! Now I feel better!!</p>
<p>Jed Smith, thank God is grand and wonderful - it Keeps my spirit lifted up - but Oh, the <underline>Flesh</underline> is weak!</p>
<p>The children did something wonderful for me the other day! They decided to move out of my studio, and make their big bedroom into their office as well. The result is that Sig is more quiet of a morning when he does his office work - and I can do my work in my studio with good light. Daddy too has his corner there, adn the sewing maching another - so I can actually be comfortable when I make clothes, which</p>
107
<p>I think will be my main work from now on - because it <underline>really</underline> helps, and I love to do it. Max's jacket is the best tailored job I ever did I believe, pockets and all. She is so thrilled!---</p>
<p>The seeds came from Ma Perkins, and I Know it was a gift from you Enid darling for which my sincerest thanks. I'll plant them as soon as the present snow has subsided, leaving the ground in proper condition. I have the holes dug for the Cannas you sent, but will not put them in till it is really warm! My house plantings are growing beautifully - I already transplanted the morning Glories into an old boiler -- they are absurdly big! The Holly-hocks all have the 3rd leaf. The Phlox is doing well adn the snapdragons are swell.</p>
<p>I have thought a figure like the</p>
108
<p>sea nymph would be the lovely thing for <underline>your</underline> pool, how about it? I think Ollie and you would appreciate such a piece - and It would be lovely for a fish pool - but her right had would be <underline>forward</underline> making a dandy place to put the fish food each day. What do you think? Please Alice, tell me what you need in the way of clothes, that I could make for you and send. When Hilda is here I am planning to make her a whole lot of clothes - and there is <underline>no</underline> reason why I should not be allowed to make all of your things too. I Know I <underline>can</underline> and I <underline>want</underline> to.</p>
<p>We are planning for Max to go along with the men on their next little trip East - they are leaving here towards the end of April and will be gone one to two weeks - They <underline>really</underline> will go through St. Louis then - so I hope you can have them then for just <underline>one</underline> night maybe. <underline>Can</underline></p>
109
<p>you, do you think? Please be frank. I can send our two camp beds along if you could use them! I will Keep our Wubs here. Some pile of fun all 'round!</p>
<p>The Red C<unclear/> is swelling, our yellow jouquils are glorious; they nodded over the snow on Easter Sunday! The Forsythia too is showing yellow - I have no Weigelia at all Enid dear - I don't think you ever took one from here either. Mine died while we were in St. Louis. It had been gorgeous, and pink.</p>
<p>Must get to work again now loads of lvoe to you all from</p>
Mama
<p>P.S.1. Tell Ollie he had better be careful about making my hair whiter with his wild stories - I always won</p>
110
<p>der how much fact there is in them and then I worry over my girlies!</p>
<p>P.S.2.
Alice dearsest, your tales of all you are doign in the studio are intensely interesting to me as well as to Max - so please Keep on telling me all you are doing. Also please give me Madames' address, will you? I may want to have a chat with her someday - I do like her so much!-</p>
M.