<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
63a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, MO.
Jan. 30, 1941
Dearest mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>So glad you got a doctor, adn that it is going to probably be better very soon. As good going to probably be better very soon. As good as Dr. Mitchell is, I <underline>do</underline> wish an osteopath could get at Dad's back, tho', because it's a strain of some sort on a muscle which is causing the pressure on the sciatic nerve. An osteopath would correct that little twist &amp; things would improve faster, I think . Mrs. Harrison is so sorry about your having that kind of pain, Dad, &amp; she knows, thru experience, that this can be helped by an osteopath - sometimes even in one treatment. Helping Nature straighten the muscle sooner makes for quicker recovery, don't you think? Too bad, Dad, you have to have this terrific pain; but it'll all be over before many days! Know, <sic>tho'</sic>, that we're thinking of you!!</p>
<p>We have a good practical book here entitiled "Fifty Years A Country Doctor". He has devoted a chapter to Sciatic Nerve &amp; it is most informative. He says, "cautery (ironing, same thing) applied lightly but freely along the course of the nerve from spine down to the calf of the leg" has shown him best results. Of course this is painful &amp; many sensitive patients can't take it! But - this is</p>
2
<p>probably what you've been doing anyway.</p>
<p>I am enclosing Wright Howes' letter, Dad, as you might as well see it now as wait longer. If you want any letters written just dictate 'em to Mom &amp; I'll type them up &amp; send them out for you from here! Will you do that? We have plain envelopes, etc.</p>
<p>What do<strike>es</strike> you two eat? I do hope you don't sya to yourselves "Oh well we're alone, why should we bother to eat well?" Can't you have a little variety of vegetables? I guess you do have that tho'. If you don't, you "arter be spanked."</p>
<p>We surely hope to hear <underline>soon</underline> that you're starting up here <underline>soon</underline>! We're quite disappointed again, as we were sort of waiting for you to get ehre tomorrow (Friday). I guess Ol will go to town tomorrow &amp; buy a suit! I'm so delighted! I've been trying to get him to get a <underline>good</underline> one for ages!</p>
Loads of love, from us
to the dearest of parents.
always,
Enot &amp; Oddie
<p>Be seeing you sooner than you think I hope!!</p>
