<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 142
November 6, 1939
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
Monday Noon
Precious Mona:
<p>I've been wondering how you are getting along, whether or not you've had much suffering, and if the swelling has gone down. No doubt I'll hear from you tomorrow morning if not by some afternoon mail. I do hope you're all right and I believe you are. I'm <underline>so</underline> glad your mouth is fixed up at last, and you must have the other plate re-made as soon as possible.</p>
<p>I met with a sociology class this morning at 8. This P.M. at 4'10 I begin talking about and reading from teh Cycle. That will continue this week, and there will be several classes. Was at an informal</p>
(over)
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
143
2
<p>last evening. Nice people, of course. I gave only 3 lectures on Poetic Values. It was too stiff for them. Now I do fear I shouldn't givethe one on Literature Since 1912, as people here seem singly &amp; cozily fitted into the going world. That would leave me short two lectures for the last week.</p>
<p>I don't feel eager here, altho' I like all the people personally. It may be better after I get going on poetry. There <underline>is</underline> a feeling of everything being on the surface.</p>
<p>Caught a bad cold Friday night - how I don't know; but quinine - lots of it - checked the thing, and I'm all right, though it has gone yet.</p>
<p>I'm wondering about paying for the suit when it arrives. I have $52.50 left out of $87 when I came. Must pay the hotel weekly. Expenses are great, even tho' I have <underline>no</underline> chance for special or extravagant spending. I'm just staying alive. I don't know that they have evov<unclear/></p>
144
-3-
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
<p>to stake me for the suit payt. I could perhaps squeeze through here with what I have on hand, but I'd have nothing for the suit. If Sig can't send it, I may have to borrow from Hiddy until the 18th of the month.</p>
<p>God damn money.</p>
<p>But I do love you and all the others - endlessly,</p>
Jno.
<p>Rec'd a lovely letter from Sister Madeleva which I'll show to you when me meet.</p>
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER