<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
38
7 Neihardt Collection 
Sunday Evening 
31-2? 
Dear boy--
My letter writing has been shamefully neglected - I <unclear/> there has never been so many things to do an there are this spring But Things book lovely for the Extra work - Our gardens are full up, Mona has worked like a horse and things are in fine order there too. 
I had a card from Jane beginning "dear mother" and adding that he is coming thru Branson Monday (tomorrow) and wants to make me a visit, He surely has his gall and what I am to do has not yet occured to me, He and Frank are mak-ing the trip in a car together
I picked a big bowlful of radishes from my garden yesterday and my Early pease are full of blossom. The last two days have been so very hot following the 

39
old, and the gardens are needing rain which I hope the change of the moon will give us and it does looks much like a warm rain. 
School commencement is over, Alice, being quarrentined kept <unclear/> from going but I went with Mrs. Cantwell, there were two very good addresses. Men from the Springfield Normal. Mr <unclear/> gave out the diplomas and afterward announced that a new school building is to be built this summer ready to be occupied next Sept.-Hilda's Report card and Alice's too had nothing but E I should thank the teachers would tire of that letter all the time.-the girls give such good accounts of the doings I do hope the time will be as profitable as you had hoped for. When you come home you will not have to <unclear/>

40
2
<unclear/> come straight on 65-they  seem to be having some trouble to get the right away for the Roark bridge - They are expecting to go thru a process of condemning the property - and then go to work. - holding back the work and so many men waiting for work. 
a letter from Sigurd today said that Don had written to him. That he has been fired and is starting for home in the Dodge be hot. Poor kid his troubles are only beginning when he starts out in that car - Garner has really got six acres of al-falfa out and his melons planted. How I wished we could all be there when you have <unclear/>. Won't the girls Enjoy that? or at least they shoudl Howard came home yesterday but did not stop to see Mona, too bad!!
The "Whipporwill" is noisy tonight it sounds good to hear him. - I am reminded what 

41
<unclear/> father used to tell me - "When you hear the Whipoorwill you may go barefooted" and I used to hear him long before Grandpa did, 
We miss you so much, Indeed the place is actually hollow. It looks even more lonesome to see Alice around way thru and laid it down in disgust I'm sure his imagination is most wonder-ful - but why I should wade thru his disgusting filthy ideas was more than I can understand, - I know you will be disgusted with me but no more than I am with that writer - just have finished Sheila, Kay-Smith Shepherds in Sack Cloth - which is really a very human thing - am hunting for some thing once. - Don't know a good book when I see it and tha tis a good reason for one reading your criticisms, - I do hope boy that you are getting rested, I know it must have been a great stain to meet all those dates. We all love you John It seems foolish to tell you so often but we do. 
Mama