<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
24
199
16 Gramercy park New York, 21 July 1911
Dear old Cub;-
My, but you are the long time between drinks correspondent; still its all right. You could not help having me in mind often, because I have been sending thoughts out your way several times daily. 
I called on Mrs.M.last evening and had a jolly little visit. Am dining with her this evening. Davis came up to make himself known while I was there, and you would have enjoyed the Gab-fest that ensued. He seemed much impressed, and I think she is one of the best girls I have met in years; she is an under-study for Ellen Terry. 
Called on Kennerley the other day; he is just as boy-ish as ever, and is a good sort of publisher to have as he is just as enthusiastic as he is boyish. he is not afraid to try things. You will be glad to know that I am going to print a new edition of the Book Titles from Shakspere, there are now 350 titles, and this will be the final edition. Am making 800 copies on Holland paper, and the type distributed. It is to be one of the prettiest books ever turned out- I HOPE--
Jewett is out of, and with, John Lane. I do not know whether he has taken up anything else. He always asks after you when I see him, and so does Joe Bray. They are both among your admirers. Davis has promised to send to the magazine containing you Storm Rune, he is full of it. 
Of course it wil be a BOY! but is it quite fair to cumber him with a name he may not liek when he is older? The original Anne was a great man, I have tried to wear it honor-ably if not worthily, and can only say you have paid me a great compli-ment, there can be no answer to such a tender evidence of Love and Friend-ing but yes! I hope will she like it and use it to advantage for eighty years. 
Two Names are enough--Volney neihardt-- that looks good to me. With all good wishes, and LOVE to all
Continually yours
Dad
P.S. Am going away for a pair of weeks about August 12th. V.S.

25
After 5 days, return to THE PLAYERS 16 GRAMERCY PARK NEW YORK 
NEW YORK, N.Y. JUL 22
1230PM
1911
<figure/> U.S. POSTAGE TWO CENTS
Mr. JOHN G. NEIHARDT 
Bancroft
Nebraska 