<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
92
<underline>Friday, 1:30 P.M.</underline>
Precious Mona:
<p>I enclose Ottocars letter, together with once from Mildred &amp; one from Dawn, which you will note he wants returned. The check was enclosed, and I am depositing it. I am forwarding <unclear>Gawyine</unclear> letter without opening.</p>
<p>You should assure Octocar that the situation with Dawn is not at all tragic, as it might seem at a distance and that she is far from unhappy. I've just spoken to her about summer school in St. L. &amp; she is eager &amp; determined to push through.</p>
-2-
<p>The amtter of spending the summer in Calif. The present plan is an excellent one. Perhaps you can get in touch with the proper school authorities there (Supt. of Schools) &amp; get information as to Dawn's attending summer high school. Of course she will have to pay tuition. She seems sure there will be summer school. I don't know.</p>
<p>Dawy <underline>has</underline> improved - <underline>vastly</underline> for <underline>her</underline>.</p>
<p>I must be in Montgomery, W. Va, <underline>Next Thursday</underline>.</p>
-3-
<p><underline>May</underline> stop on the way there; may wait until return trip (about Apr. 15)</p>
<p>It's hot - like summer. The house <underline>gleams</underline> &amp; is in perfect order. I did all the dishes etc., &amp; Alice scrubbed the kitchen floor; then she &amp; Dawn straightened everything up on both floors. Looks spick &amp; spam &amp; sill stay so, I'm sure.</p>
<p>I'm glad I did not go along.</p>
-4-
<p>I need to get straightened up for the trip. I've been feeling st<unclear/>, &amp; the chest cold did something. But I'll be feeling swell very shortly. Take it easy, Mama, &amp; get to feeling <underline>calm.</underline> Everything will be better than we suspected - <underline>much better</underline>, I know.</p>
<p>Alice takes hold here in her old efficient way, &amp; she seems happy.</p>
<p>Rest yourself &amp; yet to feeling right.</p>
Endless love
to you &amp; all there.
Jno.
93
Box 305
<underline>Branson</underline>, MO
BRANSON
APR4
3 -PM
1947
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
SPECIAL DELIVERY
AT ANY
UNITED STATES
POST OFFICE
13 THIRTEEN CENTS 13</stamp>
<stamp>UNITED
STATES 
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mrs. Mona Neihardt,
9917 Denmison Ave.,
Overland
Missouri
<underline>SPECIAL 
DELIVERY
over</underline>
<p>Of course, if we're in Columbia Dawn would want to attend Summer school there - in case there is a summer session of the high school. Better <unclear/> about St. L. anyway</p>