<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
278 Fink Collection 118
Neihardt
Branson
Mo
BRANSON
MAY9
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland
Mo.
St. Louis
County
119
Branson
Friday noon
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>It was wonderful to get a glimpse of you "three" and to see the love and goodness of it all! The Home is <underline>so</underline> sweet and it is good to see you, Enid, waving a last goodbye to you, Ollie, looking back to get a last goog view of what is most dear to you before following up the same old duties and irksome routine of your "job" - It is all such a dear picture to Keep in my heart!</p>
<p>Alice wrote you <sic>Keept</sic> saying we should have stayed there longer - but I have</p>
120
<p>found that long visits seldome make for happiness.</p>
<p>We Know that if necessary, you'd be glad to have us stay with you, sharing your <underline>every</underline> thing with us - for this Knowledge we surely are grateful.</p>
<p>You are going to teach your babe a few things, dear children, but "it" is going to teach you far more!</p>
<p>I have found that we must do the best we can, and we must also love and live with people who do differently from us. Loving means nothing much, if we love only those near and dear to us who feel and think the way we do. Somehow or other we must learn to love our enemies, do good unto those who least "deserve" our love and good will, and learn to understand <underline>other</underline> ways <underline>other</underline> people too.</p>
121
<p>I'm only talking with you Enid and Ollie trying to share my experience with you - so please do not feel I am preaching or even trying to do so.</p>
<p>It is surprising how lovely your place has become in so short a time!</p>
<p>Maxie must have worked every minutehere cleaning up out doors as well as washing and ironing those 2 days. Every thing looks so wonderful.</p>
<p>We just ate on Dewey Bald - and wished for you all to be with us.</p>
<p>Hilda is wearing pants and standing on her head on the lawn! She'll gain a few pounds this week I hope.</p>
<p>The Bust is almost ready now to</p>
123
<p>cast!--- No news as yet from Mitchel excepting what you Know. Will Keep you posted!</p>
<p>Please tell me how your nursery progresses - I want to Know about <underline>
</underline> you make Enid dear. I gave Frankie your message. She is now looking for your letter.</p>
Loads of lve to my girlie and to her fine Ollie,
from Mama Mother