<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
30a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORAL DEPARTMENT
Jan. 10, 1940
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
<underline>Dearest</underline> Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>It's so nice to hear from you, Mom. It's always nice to get a letter when I'm at home alone, these days especially.</p>
<p>Glad to hear Dad, that you're getting a good start on Jed. That's certainly important - and here's hoping that when you do get the book finished Macmillans will do right by you in a big way! I'm going to be quite sore if they don't! You certainly do deserve a little peace of mind financially even tho' you have had it easier than many, many people.</p>
<p>Mom, day before yesterday, I was feeling so darn peppy that I fear I did a few things to many, so yesterday I layed around all day without doing a thing such as I'm doing today. Boy, does Alice come in handy! I didn't do much but wash out a few things. However, I learned a darn good lesson &amp; am feeling better today. It fools you - and then the next day you feel it. From now on, no <underline>work</underline> will I do! I was going over to Mrs. Harrison's today, but she is going to town, so i'll wait till tomorrow to go. She's going to have her sister down &amp; we three will have a nice visit, sewing &amp; gossiping! Anyway, I'll be sitting!! Maybe she'll want me to lunch!!</p>
2
<p>I ordered groceries for three days this a.m. It makes it easier to budget! I find it so. Alice <underline>should</underline> with care, get by till end of Feb. with her allowance. I fix her lunch each day - a sandwich, apple, cake &amp; a bottle of milk; so she doesn't have to buy that. However, she has been having to get a coupld things lately. But, we hope she can get by thru Feb. She thinks she can.</p>
<p>I'm having Alice get me some blue wool to match my wool I've started with on the baby blanket. I do hope there's a <underline>reason</underline> for making it. Do you think we'll have an heir or heiress to our <underline>millions</underline>?! Ol still wants a baby by next Xmas. So do I. My business now is to take life easy so I can become strong enough to have one. As soon as it gets less snowy, so we can get our car out we're going to see Dr. Finley to see if I can have a child. He thinks I'm okay, but wants to be sure before we try again. I personally, think I'm perfectly normal. I am trying my luck on resisting my temptation for smoking! I believe I'll be free of that bad habit before I start to having children. It's hard, tho' everyone smokes!!</p>
<p>Funny, Ol was saying that you two would finally decide Branson was the place! He says it really is lovely country all times of the year and everyplace isn't that way. Anyway, I guess Ozarks are about as weet as any country.</p>
<p>I do wish you could be located here! It's central for lectures, too. And teh county is a <underline>good</underline> property investment! We still intend to buy this place sooner or later. We hope, sooner!</p>
30b
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORAL DEPARTMENT
3
<p>Dad, what about the Edit. Dept.? Do you think you would still want to try being a puppet and write on the edit. page? Maybe that would be something to inquire about Old Bart Howard mgiht be the one to inquire of, don't you think?</p>
<p>My, you two skip around so fast that I can't keep up with you. Hil called up yesterday. She was worried about a pkg. she sent you, Dad, for your birthday to Aztec Court in Albuquerque. I guess it'll be forwarded; but if not, why dont' you drop the p.o. a card &amp; tell them to send it on to you? You'll probably have it before you get my letter, tho', anyway.</p>
<p>I'm glad you are happy about Al being here with us. We're so happy that we can help out that way a little, at least Al is sweet to have around, altho', I'll admitit times I have to tell her a few things, Mom. Like, she has a bad habit of throwing thing down everywhere! But, you'd be surprised how she has improved in the last couple weeks! I just ell her calmly, &amp; she is just grand about it. She now keeps her room neat &amp; hangs up all the clothes! Isn't that something? At first, she didnt' pay much attention when I'd suggest something; but then I got a little bit shrewder &amp; said. "Alice, I'll bet Madame Cassan doesn't believe in carelessness about <underline>her</underline> house. Did you notice a<underline>nything that wasn't neat</underline> when you were at her home</p>
4
<p>with the other girls the other day at the luncheon party?" She really took that - And do you know since then, I've had <underline>no more trouble</underline> with her regarding neatness! She may forget occassionally, but she'll get a gentle nudge to remind her from me in that case! Shows what the power of suggestion can do, doesn't it? That's my way of telling or teaching. Our kids are going to get it that way!! Ha, ha!!</p>
<p>I finished stuffing those little things for Elaine's birthday. They're really cute! A rooster, a kitty, &amp; a puppy!</p>
<p>I guess there's no more to say right now.</p>
<p>I'm going to have xhap suey tonite for dinner. In meantime I'm going to sit or sleep all day.</p>
<p>Write often!</p>
Loads of love to you both.
Always,
Enat
<p>Just got my 2 wks. laundry back. Was only 1\$.05 with shirts ironed!!</p>
-E.
<p>Ol will write again on of these days. It doesn't at home till about 7:30 at nites &amp; by time we eat it's bedtime. The snow hold of traffic is terribly!<p/>
    
