<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
375 Fink Collection 88
Neihardt,
?920/Blackstone,
S. Chicago, Ill.

68 CHICAGO
UN 2
330 PM
1943
ILL.

Mrs. O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, 
St. Louis County

89
Chicago, Ill.
June 2nd 43.

Darling Enid:
<p>Thanks for your dear letter and for the tea, which arrived O.K. I'll be careful of it as you said, dear. Amama has a dizzy spell today from an overdose of Aspirine (she thinks) and she is lying on the front room couch. The door to the porch is open wide, letting the breeze from the Lakeside in and she is quite comfortable. She asks me to give you much love and tell you that she so often thinks of you and your dear Ones - (She surely thinks a lot of you Enid girlie!) Also she says not to worry Ollie with the books. She is sending 4 stamps for her baby Nei's book - and also 25 cents for postage you may have been expending.</p>
<p>We here had a lot of fun over your change of names for our new baby - and</p>
90
2
<p>of course we heartily approve of every thing you say. We think Mona-Enid, not quite as pretty as Enid-Mona on account of the clashing of vowels in the former! We also like Michael, and Amama was already visualising "Little Mike" and though it so cute.</p>
<p>The only think that might not be just right about the idea would be the possibility of his wondering why you had named him after such a questionable hero as Daddy's Mike Fink. This is just in <hi rend="underline">my head</hi> and may not be any thing to even consider -</p>
<p>I have written to Mrs Cantwell, asking her to get the washer and bedpan packed and sent to you within the month, so I feel sure you'll be hearing from Camels' Express in due time.</p>
<p>Enid please tell me at what camp dear Jack is stationed here? I want</p>
91
3
<p>to contact the dear boy at once - so please tell me.</p>
<p>Alice arrives here tomorrow - and of course I am already seeing her in every fast approaching young girl I see as I look up and down the street here! We all can hardly wait!</p>
<p>Now I must give you some sad news. Daddy's eyes have come to a crisis, and offer trying to get glasses and failing we have had a very fine specialist here (recommended by Mr Aigler of St. Louis) look into his condition, <hi rend="underline">finding excellent vision but</hi> a very <hi rend="underline">serious</hi>, deeper trouble in the eyes. So this reading job on Esquire is <hi rend="underline">absolutely beside</hi> the point for him in fact we fear he will have</p>
92
4
<p>to do <hi rend="underline">no</hi> reading to speak of, for a long time. He and I should both of us take suitable jobs in Chicago - that to not interfere with his going along with whatever treatment is necessary for his dear eyes. - So we are looking forward to changes. The job in Kansas City is only for 3 months, Enid dear, so that is fine, but not anything to make our living in Branson possible. All this <hi rend="underline">does not</hi> change or interfere with my being with you on the 20th of July - so don't worry any about that. I am only telling you about everything, because I Know you are really interested.</p>
<p>Mrs Smith, the lady here who thinks I have a line chance with the Censoring Dep. tells me that I am needed since I Know German <hi rend="underline">script</hi>,</p>
93
<p>and can get the job if I try; she says they would let me off July 20th for several weeks, if I tell them the situation, and she feels I ought to apply now because another person is leaving from that Department. - However, I do not see how I can do so because of Amama being here - Yet that too may change - We are still in the midst of uncertainties.-</p>
<p>Now I want to tell you what you will want to hear: i.e. Mrs Seymour has you per Pullman to Oklahoma to speak as some Indian comention or so - and on her return I must remain in St. Louis at Hotel Statler over the weekend unless it so happens that Albert is arriving to Chicago in his car on Saturday in which case we hope she can go with him. <hi rend="underline">If</hi> Albert cannot</p>
94
<p>do this, then he will try to give her a good time in St Louis, taking her to place of interest, which she very much wants to see. So I want her to meet you and see your Husband, Home and Baby Nei and I feel sure you'll want to contact her, since you have written many a letter for Daddy in years gone by to the Seymours, and yet have never met her. Of course she could not meet Ollie unless she could be with you on Saturday, but she could noon might be O.K. with you, even tho she could not meet Ollie then. She is a very <hi rend="underline">sincere, fine person</hi> (very nervous at present owing to heart trouble) and very appreciative &amp; kind. She is the intellectual (type but with absolutely no "put on" or "show off". You as well as Ollie will like her, and she does so want to Know you, Enid, as she has now met all the other Neihardts. This has turned into a long letter. So will stop right here.</p>
Endless love,
Mama - Mother Nanny
<p>Kiss <hi rend="underline">my baby boy</hi>!</p>








