<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
19 Sigurd Neihardt Colleciton 1
1940
[July 6, 1940]
Saturday
Dearest Boy:
<p>Just a word from me too to tell you how remarkable I think your recent successes in business are. We often speak of the splendid way in which you are making good, and are very grateful for <underline>yo</underline>u. This will all appear different once you are practicing regularly again. We are all for your moving the Piano and hope that you will not meet with any more compaints about the "noise you make! If the other tenants are German, they will enjoy your Music even your exercises which are so soothing and beautiful to me. There can be such a thing as music in clay that disturbs no one, and that is what my present Sea nymph is to me. The surf forms are the left hand and accompaminent and the nymph is the theme - song! I hope to have it finished enough to show the big Rook wood Pottery at Cincinnati Ohio on our way back. We feel this trip is a success because never before has Daddy been able to go ahead with his work at the same time as he is now doing. He write every morning. ----I have been po</p>
2
<p>ing our car so that it looks more like a 1940 car. That is my job.- This is nice, quiet camp, the cheapest we have been able to live however is at $10.00 per week for cabin etc. But I can cook and wash so that we have to spend the minimum in other ways.</p>
<p>There is lots of fruit in this country and the land is tops. Trees are gorgeous, and the people are so friendly. -Daddy keeps looking for a word from Wake Forest - How strange they never responded! - We expect to go to Shippensburg Monday noon, take a room at the Hotel there = Hotel Morrison. telephone to the school in the afternoon letting them Know we are there - The affair is at night on Monday. Then we'll leave the following day for St Louis - But we will take at least 3 night as "we" msut write every morning! So you can count on seeing us towards the end of next week.</p>
Love unlimited to you our own and only dear dear Son,
from Mama.
