<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
319-320 Fink Collection 24
Return In Five Days To
<strike>SIGRUD</strike> NEIHARDT, <strike>Mgr.
"BOOKS OF THE DAY" </strike>
Branson, Missouri
BRANSON
FEB1
3 -PM
1942
M.O.
Miss Hilda Neihardt
Consulate of Switzerland
1012 Ambassador Bldg.
Saint Louis, Mo.
25
Sat evening
Darling Hilda and Alice:
<p>That is a wonderful picture of you three - I simply love it of all of you! Many thanks for sending it to us. You are right in what you said Hilda, about Alice - she surely looks prettier than ever - and you are looking simply lovely too! Albert could "belong" to the family by blood could he not? He surely looks like a brother!</p>
<p>Hilda it is customery I believe for bridesmaids to buy their own clothes, but for the bride to choose the color etc of their attire as well as to furnish their bouquets. The bridegroom furnishes the bride's bouquet. Do you want me to speak to Frankie. or will you write her yourself? I think that would be nicer. I too had thought of Frankie - I am so de</p>
26
2
<p>lighted that you are thinking of coming down soon - but I must ask you to be <underline>sure</underline> and bring plenty of blankets and comforters for all of you - as I am using all we have here. We have plenty of beds and pillows but no warm things. Our babies are not yet well - but they are better. Daddy and I are O.K.</p>
<p>I think Sig's plan to have records of his accompainments for you to study with, simply a <underline>wonderful</underline> way for you to do. That takes the place of your being able to play your own accompainments - and even better than that! I hope he does that at once. That would be the way for you Alice as well, not?</p>
<p>I have been rocking Baby Laine nearly all afternoon - now they are in bed all cozy and warm - and I do hope they are over the worst.</p>
<p>the Ladies Home Journal returned</p>
27
3
<p>the Childs' Prayer - I'd like to send it to the Woman's Home Companion - Can you tell me their address? <underline>Please do</underline>. I think it marvelous that you have so good an out look for the seed business. Hope it works out. I also hope the Nebraska trip works out with fair results for all of us. Daddy does <underline>so want</underline> to be able to pay you back the money we owe you before you get married Hilda. I am hoping too that Enid can come home for the wedding.</p>
<p>Mrs Mitchel is so pleased to hear you will be married here - she will help me a lot I know. We will have the announcements printed here so they do beautiful work and are reasonable in price at the Leader. But we must wait as we Know so little that is definite -</p>
28
4
<p>just as you say! If <underline>my</underline> wishes come true, We will Keep this place, improve it, and have money enough to be able to go and see you children whenever we want to , and visa versa! Mr Chase is so nice, and he and Daddy are friendlier now than ever - He would be nice to have for your wedding in case Dr Plank cannot come - but of course it would be nicest to have Dr Plank. Will you ask him some time? He would have to stay elsewhere over night as we will be full up with our own family.</p>
<p>Mrs Mitchel told me she got Jane's Wedding Cake at Lipman's in Springfield and it was a masterpiece, bt it cost her only $10.00 She mad the Punch and that was all she served - that sounds easy, doesn't it?</p>
29
5
<p>Alice darling - I have to guess at what you are doing and how you are feeling - but Hilda helps me!</p>
<p>Our babies are coughing upstairs I hope not for long - last night was pretty bad - <underline>not serious</underline> though! I do hope they will both be well when you come. - Do you like the new folder? I think it is simply beautiful.</p>
Love to you all in endlessness
from your devoted
Mama.