<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
13a
(1)
1419 North Dearborn
Chicago, Illinois
August 5, 1942
Dear Hilda, Albert, Sig, Max, Joan, Elaine,
<p>I really am very sorry that it's been so long since my last letter - but somehow or other I've just laxed a bit in the matter of correspondence Hil, and Max, I did so appreciate your letters - and your costume suggestion Max. It seems taht I may get at that dame sometime - and then you'll come in right handy! Hil, I received your letter yesterday, on my birthday with your much appreciated good wishes as well, Albert, and you can't know how touched I was by both. How ridiculous to say you <underline>wish</underline> you could do someting nice for me. How many billions of things have you already done? Furthermore, that letter was</p>
(2)
<p>exactly what I did want from <underline>you</underline> on my birthday <underline>my</underline> Hil! can you feel - just how <underline>special you</underline> are to <underline>me</underline>?</p>
<p>It is a lovely day this morning - bright blue sky, golden sunshine, the sound of a lawnmower cutting the lush green grass, and the feel of approaching fall already in the air.</p>
<p>Speaking of my birthday, I had a lovely one indeed. First of all, we arose at about 9:00, ate breakfast (With peaches on our cereal as a special treat), and cleaned our little abode. While Doris and Sylvia prepared breakfast, I shopped for the peaches, and upon my return, found a lovely gift and a card "To Alice"</p>
13b
(3)
<p>at my place. Those dear comrades of mine had bought me two prs. of lovely silk panties (one blue, one pink) and on the card had written "From your other 2/3 <underline>rds</underline>, Doris and Sylvia." Wasn't that dear? Oh! Yes, before I forget, I must tell you that I received two of those indescribable birthday letters from Daddy adn Mama, together with five-dollars the day before my birthday, just after our return from Benton Harbor. To continue, George came to say we were to rehearse at 2:30 at Gladys Hights! His Mother and Grandmother accompanied him and us to rehearsal, and watched</p>
(4)
<p>with great interst. We <unclear/> a marvelous rehearsal. First, the Sailor Number, which we did over several times till George saw fit to say it was good. (At <underline>least</underline> perfection always he says!) That is really an adorable number, and the costumes are lovely. Mrs. Carlson (G. Mother) said she saw them all completed - and they are beautiful. Next came "Dancing in the Dark." The pianist was a bit vague but we accomplished quite a bit anyway. I like it very much, and, being a sequel to our waltz it will be very effective. At last, we</p>
13c
(5)
<p>continued rehearsing by going into "Cappriccio Espagnol". Hil, George has given me the solo in this with him - and I <underline>love</underline> doing it! So much fire and wildness! Really, we all think George's choreography is better than that of the Ballet Russe - more intricate steps, heel beats, hard clapping, etc. THis will be a long suite of three numbers (as in Russian and Jungle), using Espana Cani as opening number, another Spanish number, and Capriccio Espagnol as closing number (the alborada) We are building more onto this each rehearsal. You should <underline>hear</underline> us working out heel</p>
(6)
<p>and toe rythms, after <unclear/> with hard clapping! "Stamp, rodoble, stamp, stamp, heel hell (last with devil-may-care- sholder movement)" Ah! The costumes are to be all manner of brillant colors - all but clashing. We worked about three hrs. straight - and could easily have continued, but it was late. While returning home in the jalope as Mrs. Carlson says, we asked them to come see us in the evening with cake - so, although Doris was very upset becasue she and Sylvia had planned to get the cake and decorate it, they did just that. We hurriedly</p>
13d
(7)
<p>prepared and ate dinner before their arrival - Eddie with us. It was then that I received your dear letter - and a beautiful telegram from Eny and Ollie and Nei. We had a grand evening together - made much nicer by the fuss and muss created by Syl and Dor in dishing out ice cream, decorating the cake, and burning their hands on the coffee pot. They always get <underline>so</underline> excited it's really very cute. Even Nenette came to our party (the white poodle) and ate ice cream and cake. To top all this off, Eddie came over at 10:00 (He ahd to go home to study as he's a student for
the</p>
(8)
<p>Signal Corps) bearing for me a 2 lb. box of delivious Ting Ling Chocolates. He is such a dear fine fellow - we ahve great times together. Such a gentleman - so much fune, and <underline>such</underline> a <underline>really</underline> artistic person. We finally got to bed around 1:00. What a day!</p>
<p>Now, I shall retrace my steps a few days. We left Chicago Friday morning at 6:00 for Benton Harbor - had a lovely trip there along Lake Michigan. We rehearsed at the theatre at 10:30 adn got settled at Mary's Hotel across the street, one of the establishmetns owned by the House of David, a religious organization</p>
13e
(9)
<p>for profit in business as well as soul. All the men wear beards and the whole population is vegetarian. It is a pleasing atmosphere - quiet and almost ancient as Doris said, she almsot expected to see Jesus Christ coming down the hall, among one of the many beards! Not sacriligous, just fact! We had three shows this first day, and four the next. Workign these numbers on a stage was most different from on a night club floor but we soon grew to enjoy it greatly. We had a lovely walk and sprint along the beach near Benton Harbor. Such beauty I cannot descrive to you - Oh Hil, how</p>
(10)
<p>you'd love it!</p>
<p>Money I have enough of now - but will not for so long! Don't worry we <underline>are</underline> going to win, but it is a struggle. M.CA is taking us over. You're a dear to worry - but <underline>don't</underline>. Just pray for us. Our costumes are all being gone over, and our new costumes and new numbers are developing.</p>
<p>Oh! I told all about Mac and Mexico! I somehow believe we <underline>are</underline> going there! What a thrill to see Max and all the horses and canyons adn animals! George says we shall go there.</p>
<p>Ask Sig if he can find out if there are any station wagons in St. Louis - and if so (used but in good shape) what makes, models, and prices. George</p>
13f
(11)
<p>is shopping for a car, for when we really step out, we must have a new car. Dates about here we'll take till then I'd <underline>greatly</underline> appreciate this as soon as at ll convement. Meanwhile, I'll ask about for you Sig - in the right places.</p>
<p>Loads of Love to all of you. Glad you are swimming lots. Nice you saw Julie too. Sylvia says Frieda is bashful You call her for she'd love to bicycle with you. Syl will tell Frieda also.</p>
<p>So gald about your swell progress.</p>
Loads of love,
Alice