<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
71l
1355 N. Dearborn
June 20, 1942.
Dear Mama and Amama,
<p>When did I write you last, Mama? It is sometimes a bit hard to remember when so many things are happening every minute! I've been thinking of you two, and how happy you must be together - and it makes my heart <underline>so</underline> full.</p>
<p>The last week in Detroit we spent in quite a flurry of business. Doris' knee was much improved, so with care she could manage to rehearse with us on the two new numbers in our repertoir, the sailor point ballet, and the modern, done to "Dancing in the Dark". George's Mother busied herself at adding underskirts to our Russian costumes, etc. - and was adorable to us. I believe I already told you of our picnic to River Rouge Park and our barefoot hike along the banks of that muddy though picturesque stream. What fun that was!</p>
<p>We left Detroit Monday morning at 11:00, after a lovely breakfast <unclear/> Madame Carson. That dear woman was much more serious than her usual bubbling self, for "He is going</p>
(2)
<p>away (George) and I don't like it - that is all." Even Nenette, the spoiled poodle, failed to receive her usual amount of petting, for the points of interest did not concern her! Our trip here to Chicago was truly lovely (How I do enjoy that word!) and we were as genuinely happy as a band of gypsies are said to be. The day was one of those glorious golden creations and the scenery was equally beautiful. We had a picnic lunch at a roadside table, and a flat tire just a little later, both of which added to our enjoyment. While the wheel was being attended to (something or other mysterious was done to it!) at a small garage, we three girls amused ourselves at such childhood games as rope-jumping and hop-scotch! By 8:00 o'clock Chicago time we were in Chicago and within fifteen minutes had secured oru rather Bohemian basement apartment - copy and comfortable. George lives only four blocks away with his dear Grandmother. She is the most cherubic looking person I've ever seen, and has been very nice to us on many occasions.</p>
71m
(3)
<p>You would both love her I'm sure and how she would adore speaking French with you! Her English is very broken, while her French comes out in torrents! Why, oh why didn't I begin learning French before high school days - when I had every opportunity? Kids are that way - aren't they? Playing was more important than anything else - and schoolwork took up what time was left. Now, however, I <underline>shall</underline> learn to converse in French (I have knowledge of grammar) and pester George's Grandmother every time I see her. It is tit for tat, however - for she asks us about English words.</p>
<p>We have now been in Chicago for almost a week, and have been accomplishing necessary rehearsing and costume-fitting during that time. I wrote Hilda concerning the A.G.V.A. trouble-strike to gain more money for its performers. That with Doris' knee trouble, and too, our need of a better <strike>manager</strike> agent (whcih we now have) has kept us from working more steadily. Getting started is always a difficult task, in anything, isn't it? However,</p>
(4)
<p><underline>many</underline> engagements are in the offing, and we have an audition Monday for a big agency representing the best in entertainment. We are to have pictures taken when we complete our costuming for new repertoireliy Maurice Seymour.</p>
<p>Now I have a big surprise for you. Our next engagement is in St. Louis! We are to work three days at the Riverview Country Club, June 26th, 27th, and 285h, remainin St. Louis till the following Thursday, and go then to Springfield Ill. for a week's engagement at the Gingham Inn, one of the two best places there. That will keep us one whole week in St. Louis. We will rehearse at Madame's probably, and will do things necessary and see people while in St. Louis, besides being at home again for awhile! Mama, I have no idea whether you can manage to see me, but if not, please don't feel badly, for we would really rather have you see us work (and that "goes" for all of those in St. Louis too) a little later in our career, when we have mroe repertoire, etc. All</p>
71n
(5)
<p>this has come as a great surprise to us as well as to you. Plans change <underline>so</underline> quickly in show business. That is what helps make it exciting. Oh! Mama this <underline>is</underline> living! It is what I love and what I need! I could never have imagined how marvelous the world was without this stimulation, this building, working in something I love. Our numbers are on such a high level (although not high brow) that the <underline>best</underline> places are teh ones who really appreciate them. They are armed for the best places in entertainment - for they are definitely miles removed from what is known as chorus or "line" work. With those numbers of our repertoire not yet costumed, we have quite a variety too - Russian, Jungle (native), pantomomic point "sailor" number, Viennese (ballroom type) waltz, modern, and, in the offing, Spanish and doll.</p>
<p>I am continuing at present on Sunday afternoon. We were on the beach all morning, sunning ourselves, swimming, and most of all, practicing. An amateur photographer took a lot of shots of us - both posed and action. If some come out he'll send them to us - so we're hoping they will</p>
(6)
<p>a Russian friend of Eddie's, Piotr, and Eddie were there at the beach when we arrived, and we had a grand time singing Russian and German songs and attempting to sculp in the sand. Now we're back in our apartment preparing dinner and feeling delightfully drowsy. This afternoon, as yesterday afternoon, we shall turn our front room into a studio and practice several hours.</p>
<p>Mama and Amama, I'd love to see you both, but if it would be absolutely inconvement, <underline>please</underline> don't think you need to see me this time - because such a thing is not necessary I just want to tell you in case you could come.</p>
<p>Please write me as soon as possible, for I'll be waiting to hear from you. We leave here this Thursday A.M. I have of course already written Hilda.</p>
<p>We heard from Snippy that Madame Cassan has had her operation and is O.K. but very nervous, and therefore must have no visitor's as yet. We shall see her if at all possible. Hope we can practice at her studio.</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alicia