<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
127 Finn Collection 103
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
Neihardt
Branson, Mo
BRANSON
JUN 1
3 --PM
1939
MO
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F. Fink.
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, Mo
St. Louis
County
104
Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie:
<p>Thanks for you dear note. I do appreciate your wanting the girls in July, but I don't think there can be any question of Alice being in St Louis then. It would be lovely for you to have Hilda there for the 2 weeks before the comes Home for her vacation, but <underline>we want</underline> Alice Home as soon as she can leave after graduation. It is so sweet of you to plan for me to go track with you - but those things always cost money as a general thing. We are doing everything we can to keep the good work go</p>
105
<p>ing and are very happy in that it <underline>is</underline> going and looks good - but we are not allowing ourselves any indulgences.</p>
<p>At first I felt miserable not to see Alice, but Alice and Hilda helped a lot in their attitude, and so I am now definitely plainning <underline>not</underline> to go. It has been had enough to have to be away from our baby this whole year - and I see no reason why we should have to endure this separation any longer, once her school is out and her dancing teacher gone. So please don't place to keep Alice.</p>
<p>I can't wait to see</p>
106
<p>you dear children here - it will be grand, and don't neglect that Springfield plan, will you! I don't expect an answer in a letter so I put "!" instead of "?", See ?!</p>
<p>Mrs Leonard and Tracy, who is completely will now, brought me a big jar of strawberry preserves and a big basket of strawberries! Tracy remembered you and was glad for the good news I gave him of you Enid.</p>
<p>They liked the trust but of course <underline>Mr</underline> Leonard is the man to please, and he is</p>
107
<p>in Kansas City.</p>
<p>I hope you will see this bust before it is taken away. I am quite proud of it.</p>
<p>Daddy is making something new in ivory and I wonder what it is?! Our cannas are <underline>up</underline>! The garden is swell and the lawns are gorgeous.</p>
<p>We need to paint badly, so I gear we are not so clean as you are.</p>
<p>There are 2 caramine-red water lilies blooming today and 3 white ones or pale pink ones rather.</p>
Loads of Love, always
form Mama_Mother