<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
149a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
June 9, 1941
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>I just talked with Hilda on the phone &amp; she says you are all so well-looking &amp; happy. She said they couldn't stay long, but that they had a wonderful time. Ol &amp; I were hoping you would come back with them &amp; stay with us awhile. Yes, we'll keep that bed upstairs, as you request, Mom. We want to finish the upstairs for the "family bedroom" &amp; fix a toilet upstairs, connected to downstairs one. So babies wouldn't have to come downstairs or wouldn't have to use "pots"! That, we think would really be a nice arrangement! Don't you? It wouldn't be so terribly much work to finish off the attic. We'd just love an arrangement of that sort; then, too, you &amp; Dad would feel you "had a place" in the joint!! The sunroom, <underline>then</underline>, would make a good study! However, now, it's a nursery or goin' to be, if we ever get time to get things out of there.</p>
<p>We went to Sears last Friday &amp; got our uphostery material for the wicker set. It's like the green you picked out &amp; priced for us only it's a lovely golden brown &amp; goes beautifully in this room. With colored pillows, it'll be so much nicer than cretonne, we think.</p>
2
<p>I washed the blue cretonne that was on the wicker set pillows &amp; made a cover for a seat we <strike>I</strike> amde out of the piano seat for the porch! Looks nice. We have to get some more ivory enamel before we can finish wicker set &amp; paint the nurservy linoleum. Yes, Mom, I'd surely <underline>love</underline> to have the "Lullaby" you mention to hang in the nursery! That'd be lovely. It looks as tho' my picture problem is all solved!!</p>
<p>Maybe the child will arrive early in August, but I note Dr. Finley has Aug. 30th down as the approximate date. Yes, of course, I swiould, &amp; Ol would, rather have you with me when it arrives, but if it can't be, that'll be all right too, as the other <unclear/> mighty important too!!</p>
<p>I'm so happy for Hilda! Haven't seen her lovely ring yet, but will Sat. The kids wants bring a picnic out here. Roast steak &amp; eat it on the porch. All I'm allowed to do, it seems, is to make ice tea!! Of course I do appreciate their sweetness, as I must be careful, now especailly! We'll have it buffet style. We'll have everything out on dining table &amp; everyone will take his &amp; then we'll sit on the porch. It'll be too dark &amp; buggy outside! I told Hilda she must begin picking up things here &amp; there for her "hope chest"! I'm going to make a place for her in my cedar chest. And I want to start on something fancy in a tablecloth &amp; napkins for her as soon as I can get all this baby busincess out of the way. I'm not finishing</p>
149b
3
<p>up the spreads for the crib. I have to inquire of Mande as to the size of it before I can't finish it.</p>
<p>I'm sleepy! Missed my nap yesterday! The "rabbit" is kicking me now &amp; wants me to tell you &amp; Grandpa that it love you already too!</p>
<p>Ol will write soon. He's <underline>so</underline> tired when he gets home - usually 7:30 and on Sunday 8:30! I hate to ask him to move furniture or paint, etc. even! We surely have lots to do. The trouble is that I can't do any of it myself &amp; it all falls on Ol now!! Ain't fair!</p>
<p>Wonder when Hil &amp; Albert will marry? I'm thrilled about it. Looks like "baby" was ordering itself <underline>another</underline> uncle, doesn't it? Hil will probably use these baby clothes &amp; things I have next!! Ha!</p>
Loads <sic>o'</sic> love &amp; <sic>wishin'</sic> you were here, always,
Enid
Enot
<p>Ol said he's in favor of naming, or at least calling the baby "Neihardt" if a boy. And not saying "John". "Nye" is a cute nickname!</p>
Eny
<p>Love to Max &amp; Wubs.</p>
149c
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO <underline>Fink</underline>
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS, MO.12
JUN10
1130 AM
1941
BUY U.S. SAVINGS
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER
<stamp>UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Dr. &amp; Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
<underline>Taney Co.</underline>