<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
240 Fink Collection 17
BRANSON
DEC3
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
MO.
<underline>St. Louis Co.</underline>
18
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Dec 3 40
Dear Enat and Ollie:
<p>We were glad for your letters, as always; and it's dear of you to plan for us as you've been doing. We could not feel right about being with you for more than a brief visit if your actual household expenses were increased. The household budget would have to stay the same, or we <sic>wouldnt</sic> stay. There would still be the debt of kindness, which could be paid only with kindness.</p>
<p>Enat, I have not been helping Sig, except by paying $20 commission on the Denver trip, which <underline>cleared</underline> me $230 even so; and $5 on the Taylor business. Sig &amp; Max have written</p>
19
-2-
<p>a great many letters for me, and I felt they should have some commission on the engagements landed. They did not ask it.</p>
<p>As for Hiddy, I don't think she has been milked. I have paid Alice's lessons <underline>in advance</underline> to March 1st, and have been &amp; am giving her $10 a month for incidental expenses. Her board cannot be much and Hiddy's total household expense under the present arrangement is <underline>little</underline> more than if she were alone. She has been able to pay off the debt she incurred while alone.</p>
<p>Something is brewing that may turn out very well for me. It looks good, as there is in<underline>flu</underline>ence in high places on my side. I'll tell about it later.</p>
<p>As for finishing my Cycle. Anyone who wouldn't do so in the same position of advantage would be a silly ass, obviously.</p>
20
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>Ollie, I'm grateful for the inquiries you made. I'm afraid it's a muddle-headed affair; but just on the off-chance, I'd be glad if you'd inquire at Jeff City, just as a good citizen grown curious. Will you? Then, with any-chance appearing, I might tackle the Washington gentlemen and get a rise out of him.</p>
<p>Anyway, we may be running up to see all of <sic>you'ns</sic> this month.</p>
Endless love
Dad