<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
184 Fink Collection 46
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
<strike>GOSHEN, IND.</strike>
MAY12
3 -PM
194-
M.O.
Mrs. O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
St Louis County Mo.
47
Sat. eve.
May 11, 1940
Dearest Enid:
<p>Your wonderful gifts are little by little being appreciated - I can hardly believe I have so many lovely things, and it takes time to get acquainted with them. Tomorrow, Sunday, I shall wear one of the<strike>m</strike> dresses as I must look beautiful and Ill get Maxie to turn up the hem! I love both dresses. That sweater is surely a master<unclear>ly</unclear> job, as you said; no old hand at Knitting could have turned out a more perfect job. I am so proud of it!</p>
<p>Hilda sent me marvelous hose - they are exquisite and I needed them as I believe every one does all the time!</p>
<p>Sigurd is get</p>
46
<p>ting lined up for going to St. Louis. He was terribly tired, as was Daddy - but in a different way. I think Sig feels O.K. now but Daddy has his usual trouble. Dear, dear Daddy, I do so wish he were in better health. Yet there does not seem to be anything to be alarmed about.</p>
<p>I do so hope he can get at Jed Smith shortly again - and that he can push through to the end without too many interruptions - I am expecting to go uo to St. Louis, when John and Sig have to go East in June and I do so look forward to being with you all then. I get so homesick for my darling girls each one! We had Mr</p>
49
3
<p>Bierig here looking over our lovely place and he said it was a most desirable place. Mr Sharp has a very fine property in Shrewbury Park St Louis which he will trade for our place here if we would take over the $3000 mortgage he has on his property which is valued at $6,800 right <underline>now</underline> in St Louis. It would have been a good thing to do while we had money up there - but now we don't want to assume such a debt. There will be other chances by fall I feel sure.</p>
<p>I am doing all I can to Keep this place as good looking as possible, and that in itself is enough to keep me busy. I'll have a lot more flowers than usually. I do feel that it is</p>
50
4
<p>going to be too much work after this year - so I hope we will sell. Meanwhile Daddy will get his Cycle done and then we can face the future with one less big burden, in fact we can look forward to it happily then - and we <underline>want</underline> to be near you children.</p>
<p>Enid, I have finished a costume for Alice, and have sent it to her to try on, and return to me for finishing and changing if necessary. Will you please fit it and work with pins where changes are necessary? I made lining and all, and am not so sure about the "gusset" and some other things being car<unclear/>, although</p>
51
5
<p>I followed directions as nearly as possible.</p>
<p>The pansies are adorable - and look as "perky" as possible in their Branson soil!</p>
<p>I have Zinnias and Marigolds up thick, as well as your Nasturtiums and Morning Glories - I do hope they'll do well. Lots of Phlox and Petunias are doing very well too - and Snap dragons! 3 Cannas are up! What fun all these blessed little people are for those who care!</p>
<p>This World would be so fine if we did not have to wrory ourselves to pieces!</p>
<p>How lucky we are too!</p>
52
6
<p>by comparison with families in Europe now!</p>
<p>This has been a perfectly beautiful day here - not too warm yet pleasant in the Sun.</p>
<p>Thanks so very much for all your own and your dear Man's goodness!</p>
<p>We are so often with you both in loving thought, and I hope before next Winter to be nearer you in fact.</p>
<p>Always your own grateful and devoted</p>
Mama - Mother.