<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.5.12-18">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Caroline D. Berg, March 12, 1924</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.5.12-18</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Caroline D. Berg</title>
                    <date when="1924-03-12">March 12, 1924</date>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Berg, Caroline D.</term>
                    <term>Carey, Delia Gage</term>
                    <term>Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917.</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>House, Julius T. (Julius Temple)</term>
                    <term>Ryskind, Mary House</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Nebraska</term>
                    <term>McCook (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Quest</term>
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
                    <term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                    <term>The Song of Three Friends</term>
                    <term>The Fool's Mother</term>
                    <term>A Bundle of Myrrh</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Berg, Caroline D.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1924-03-12"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">12</note>
                <note type="curatorial">
                    1 Berg Collection
                </note>

                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Branson Mo. March 12-1924
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>My Dear Mrs. Berg;</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>There are ^a number of things scattered thru the last 25 years that have marked time for me regarding my son, that are as high lights to a painting. Your sweet understand-ing letter adds still an other high light. It fills a place all its own among the pleasure things that have come to me.</p> 
                <p>I have read your letter very carefully twice. and ever-tho I know it is a sure sign of old age to reminice and very bad taste ^is inflict reminicences on others I shall indulge myself just a few minutes knowing you with your big understanding will forgive the offense.</p> 
                <p>You spoke of The "Unveiling," that was a great day for me, the greatest of all my life. Just because people were talking to me of the greatness of my sons a thing I had known many years and could talk it to no one but my dear friend Mrs. Carey who did understand, the rest simply smiled indulgently, But that does not matter now. After the "unveiling" a reception was held for me and I did not Even know it was a</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">13</note>
                
                <p>reception, Every one seemed eager to tell me how much they admired the work my son is doing. It was like wine to me, It was the one subject I could really talk upon I never had such a glorious time in all my life as I had in the hour following the unveiling. I thot it was all for John and for once I could talk with the rest for dind't I know it long before any of them there? So now do you see the cause of my remi-nicing and why I am inflicting you with the process of my mother mind? Then just in the right time to keep me heartened your beautiful letter comes.</p> 
                <p>I am happy that you felt you could go into detail and I am very grateful for the diciples you have <del>added</del> made for the Neihardt Spies.</p>
                <p>You are right about comparisons, Isn't it strange to you that Guest should be ever mentioned with John. Now that sounds snobbish but I am talking about the pact, not Neihardt The Standard is not Neihardt, but ^that which all the great ones have made, and it took all of them to make the standard we have in Neihardt I hope you understand that I take no credit to the name but to the work, and the work</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">14</note>
                
                <p>judging by the best in all the great ones must be the standard. John was a very lucky boy to have the field he has, so full of Epic Material So too is the world lucky that a man like John who so thoroughly understands all human emotions with his wonderful power of Expressing them, has the field.</p> 
                <p>It is enough to satisfy any mother, and it <del>does</del> is a great satisfaction. to me to say with the rest of you now, "His language is not ex-celled," "His descriptions unparalled," "His understanding divine," "a pact of rare ability" I notice with great elation that we worship at the same shrine, altho any of the Epics must and will have their devotees. "The Song of The Indian Wars" is the greatest thing he has done. he has grown since the writing ^of "The Song of Hugh Glass," and "The Song of Three Friends." I only hope he may live to finish the other two. "The Wars" will be finished this coming summer and next winter he will spend writing a series of lectures <del/> to be given at Lincoln University The following summer, The Epics are his great work of course, But I am looking forward</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">15</note>
                
                <p>to his lectures. His prose is so delightfully poetic. It sums too bad that there should be a break in The Epics. But he will give to the public something worth while, at the same time fortify himself financially.</p> 
                <p>I am so glad you like the dedication. of "The Quest," we all felt happy that he could apply that to his women, folks, but alas! There is a great army of such women I am happy to say.</p> 
                <p>I like most, "The Fools Mother" the dedication to "Bundle of Myrrh," That was written before he was married and I knew all of his "foolishnesses," if you will allow the plural, and he knew I was worried over them, I did not always keep the vision that he was to be a great pact. Yet he knew I was always there when he needed me.</p> 
                <p>I do indeed wish we might meet and talk on "our favorite subject" you notice it is not subjects, I think you will conclude by this letter that I need not have added that last. I am proud of John, yet I feel very humble indeed many worthy Mother's have had very different Experiences with their sons. I am proud of him not because he is the greatest pact, alone but (ov</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">16</note>
                
                <p>me is like best some likewise one of the very best sons and his bands, and he is supplemented most wonderfully, ^by his wife who is not only a good daughterinlaw but a good wife and mother with an understanding heart and a temperament fitted for the wife of a pact. She is not without talents of her own plays the violin very well has a beautiful voice and a sculptress of no mean ability having studied under the great Rodin. Yet the thing that is the closest to her heart is John's success. We have all been interested in you and your husband John's visit with you stands out as something very pleasant and I wish you might know his wife too. She read your letter with great interest.</p> 
                <p>Dr House is a fine critic, a good instructor and a very fine mane and he has a love for all the finer things, she all admire him very much. His daughter is with me this writer. She is the Primary teacher and a great success. I am very grateful that your letter reached the envelope instead of the flames and I assure you it was any thing but tedious. We all appreciate the interest you have in the Neihardts</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">17</note>
                
                <p>I really wonder some times if I am dreaming when I hear that girls and boys are studying Neihardt and his Epics. It is so wonderful to me. I hope you are not disgusted with the Extravagant adjectives I use. I don't know whta I would do with out them. John does not seem to need them in such profusion, but I have not learned the art of elimination, But as I said and that does not express my feelings it is wonderful. It has been such a short time since he was a little boy. It is only very recently that I have allowed him to be grown up. That, no doubt accounts for my surprises. If a message from me is wroth anything I would send <del>her tho</del> your niece this: The sincere respect and love he has always had for his work together with endless painstaking effort is what has counted most he has always kept his high ideals in the face of poverty. Nohting could make him sell himself fo reven "Pot boilers" and God knows he <del/> needed to. He had the vision when a very young boy, but he. paid the penalty while he was proving himself. "The Poets down" is a record of the</p> 
                <p>(over)</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.12-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">18</note>
                
                <p>poet boy. My Dear mrs. Berg: I think you will be very careful hereafter about getting me started, but I am not always so <unclear/> John is in Nebraska now. Is reading Tonight at McCook</p>
                <p>If you are not digusted with this and will at your leisure write again I should like very much to send you a letter to read that will tell you much of John. I am very glad ^you <del>did</del> used the stationary you did, it leaves me free to use. What I have without apology many thanks for your delightful <unclear/> letter;</p> 
                <closer><salute>With best wishes to you and yours, I am</salute> <signed>Alice M. Neihardt</signed></closer> 
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>