<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
I love my sweet girl & she loves me! This is the thing that makes happiness!! Love, Sig. 
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
162
Re See'n you Sweetheart! & soon!! Love, Sig 
HOTEL KEYSTONE
<FIGURE/> K 
POLAND, MERRELL & STEPHENS
LESSEES
C.B. STEPHENS, MGR. 
McCOOK, NEBRASKA 
10-"28"-'32, 
MCCook Nebraska. 
My sweet girl, 
I love you endlessly, as I've so many times said & you know I think it constantly! I was so overwhelmed with joy to receive on the last mail day another letter from you, dear! 
I say: "yes, I mean it" as answer to what you asked in that letter (regarding girls of your age smokin' & cuttin' up in general)! Sweetheart, for your 

163
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
<FIGURE/>
HOTEL KEYSTONE
    <FIGURE/> K 
    POLAND, MERRELL & STEPHENS
    LESSEES
    C.B. STEPHENS, MGR. 
    McCOOK, NEBRASKA 
-2-
own satisfaction, pride, & also for mine - just take it as gospel truth that you are not the kind of a girl that I run across even in this "high society" bunch, so called! You are the girl I love & I can love: no one else! Others can't compare!! I assume that this does not make you conceiled to tell you these things, because I know you see things in the way they are!! There is one girl <unclear/> who comes up to the tip top 

164
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
    <FIGURE/>
    HOTEL KEYSTONE
    <FIGURE/> K 
    POLAND, MERRELL & STEPHENS
    LESSEES
    C.B. STEPHENS, MGR. 
    McCOOK, NEBRASKA 
-3-
in sweetness, good sense, & decency - & she is & never will be any one but Maxine Melton! This may sound very complex in correspondence but I think you under-stand that I love you & care not to "fool" around with other girls! 
I have arrived at the place where I want a fine girl to love! I have her, & am satisfied & happy! 
It will always be just this way, & you'll never see the 
(over) 

time when you'll be reading or thinking over these statements with sadness or disgust! I am "plenty sore over H. Maxwell saying what he did - about my "Fulton" girls' concert! They asked me to stay over & play at following morning chapel & I did that & without "crowing to H. Maxwell" about it! 
That was uncalled for, & furthermore very untrue & mis-represented, by him! I will be so happy to get back to you, sweetheart! 
I'm quite tired, & need to come back! 
Always I love you, 
Your Sig. 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

165
After.........days, return to 
.........................................
.........................................
SN Branson, Mo. 
McCook, NEBR. 
MCCOOK OCT 27 9 PM NEBR. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE SPECIAL DELIVERY <FIGURE/> AT ANY UNITED STATES POST OFFICE 10TENCENTS10
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, 
Missouri 