<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
10a
<p>The chopsticks say, "John Neihardt" on one of them, <hi rend="underline">plus</hi> a prayer for good.</p>
1325 North Dearborn
Chicago, Illinois
January 7, 1943.
Dear Daddy,
<p>Tomorrow is your birthday, and I just want to write you a few lines to let you know that I am thinking of you, and wishing for you all the joy that should be yours. Oh! Daddy, you <hi rend="underline">are</hi> so deserving - not only because of your work - but also because of you yourself. I am no one to wise seeing that this may sound a bit silly - <hi rend="underline">my</hi> telling</p>
(2)
<p><hi rend="underline">you</hi> - but I do not mean it the way it may sound. It is just htat, on this occasion above all others, we have the chance to express ourselves concerning all the things you are - and what you mean to us.</p>
<p>The little remembrances seemed a trifle conserative to me, (although they're not <hi rend="underline">supposed</hi> to be) but it seems that simply raucous affairs are the only</p>
10b
(3)
<p>alternative now. Hope you will be tolerant of my queer selection.</p>
<p>Daddy, I haven't had a minute to spare or I would have tried of do something about the agents. As yet, I do not know who would be the ones to contact - but I shall do my best.</p>
<p>We are to be here several more weeks then we are to go to Mexico City for an early February opening. <hi rend="underline">So</hi> glad you are glad</p>
(4)
<p>about our coming trip. We shall feel very lucky indeed. Maybe I can look around a bit for gems, too! I hope so.</p>
<p>I have received several letters from Richard - he is a grand person. In his last, he mentioned very happily and modestly that you said a few good words about a sonnet of his. He also told of the grand time he had with all of you - and the fine dinner Eny prepareds</p>
10c
(5)
<p>We are working hard - love performances, and are getting really fine publicity and audience and house appreciation. Sylvias brother, Eddie, a real lover of ballet, came to see us with a very nice friend of his the other evening and both were actually <hi rend="underline">struck</hi> with our work - Eddie with the Jungle, especially, and Jim with all, especially the Russian. Eddie is very critical - and he actually raved - so we were made very glad indeed. I am hoping</p>
(6)
<p>you can see us soon when we do pestice to our dances - and when we have proper effects (<hi rend="underline">all</hi> of which were lacking when you saw us). We <hi rend="underline">have</hi>, in all seriousness improved <hi rend="underline">greatly</hi>. It seems that the agents are becoming every favorable toward us. More things are cooking <hi rend="underline">good</hi> things indeed, and I shall tell you of those when they become a reality.</p>
<p>Daddy, I want you</p>
10d
(7)
<p>to know always how I love, admire, and appreciate you - and to realize that I shall ever feel indebted to you - yes, much more than as in a mere daughter to father appreciation. For it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> your teachings (that of the belief in good, the faith in our Great Spirit - and <hi rend="underline">always</hi> the gratitude for blessings received) that carry me through an occasional weak moment - and make all others <hi rend="underline">gloriously strong.</hi></p>
(8)
<p>I shall pray for waht you now desire so unselfishly - and believe - yes, <hi rend="underline">know</hi>, that all <hi rend="underline">will</hi> be as it <hi rend="underline">should</hi> be.</p>
<p>So much for my fancy expression of the thoughts we all hold for you, dear Daddy. Excuse my jabber - and <hi rend="underline">\</hi> that you are very dear to us - and to all who have anything to do with you - but most of <hi rend="underline">all</hi>, to your own, who love and appreciate their Daddy more than words can say.</p>
Loads of love,
your Alice