<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
371 Fink Collection 62
<unclear/>
4920 Blackstone
Chicago, Ill.

13 CHICAGO 
MAY 17
5 PM
1943
ILL.

Mrs. O. F. Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo. St. Louis County
63
Darling Children:
<p>We are in our "home" across the street from Seymours' and like some things about it - others <hi rend="underline">not</hi>. We have a hunch that we may find someplace more suitable - and move - but for the present we are here.</p>
<p>The air in Chicago is simply wonderful, and the wind which is very common is pleasing to me, because I love to feel the clean, strong, bracing sweep of it, reminding me of the Ocean. The lake is lovely and also reminds of my childhood days.</p>
<p>Daddy is certainly looking well and liking his connection with Esquire. He is being given the power to <hi rend="underline">turn down</hi> manuscripts already, but Mr Ginrich decides out of the bunch of <hi rend="underline">possible</hi> ones, which shall be used. I think that they are already trusting Daddy with a lot of power therefore, don't you? And it cer-</p>
64
<p>-tainly looks as though he could just about have things his own way, if he remains with Esquire and I believe he will do so.</p>
<p>He had to have an occulist put drops in his eyes last Saturday in order to properly test his eys for new glasses - and this experience has cost him plenty - prices are high and anyway specialists are expensive any where! But I hope the result will be fine, and that Daddy will really see perfectly with his new glasses, which he hopes to receive Tuesday afternoon. He has found the Osteopath a very fine friend of the St. Louis Osteopath and that trouble is taken care of for him; so we think he'll need but one treatment a week, until he is completely well.</p>
<p>We all went to dinner last Saturday at the "Friends of American Literature" annual affair - to which Daddy was invited. We sat at a differ-</p>
65
<p>-ent table, while Daddy was one of the honored guests at the Speaker's table. We paid for the privilege - and are glad we did, but the affair was certainly not worth going to, excepting that we learned to see and meet some more or less important people of Chicago, and them <hi rend="underline">we were</hi> present, which is more than being away off somewhere else! Daddy did not speak at all, although he was given the opportunity to do so. He felt the entire thing too "piffling" and we were glad he did not try to speak of truly serious things in an atmosphere of "<unclear/>" and superficiality. We are going to join the organization that gave Daddy a yearly award for the "Song of the Messiah," remember Enid? "Friends of American Writers" - it evidently is a more genuine group than the "Friends of American Literature" to which we went Saturday night. This latter group was formerly led</p>
66
<p>by Harriet Monroe, and that speaks for itself, not?</p>
<p>Yesterday we saw "The Hall of Man" with Malvina Hoffman's wonderful sculpture - which is even greater and more wonderful than I had expected it to be - in the "Field Museum."</p>
<p>I am going to see everything great in Chicago, little by little.</p>
<p>I already like it very much - since one <hi rend="underline">must</hi> live in a big City.</p>
<p>We are hoping to hear from Branson soon; Daddy has written Mrs Cantwell, and if the M.D. does buy our place we will be going to Branson to pack, (Amama going on to Hot Springs maybe) and then Daddy and I will be buying that farm!! WE are interested in Michigan possibilities, not more than 100 miles away maybe. There are <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> possibilities there. We hope Albert will be transferred up here -and then after</p>
67
<p>that - maybe you children will want to consider having a home on "our" Michigan Farm? Who can - say or Know <hi rend="underline">any</hi> thing?</p>
<p>I'd be glad to sell our Branson Home in exchange for such a happy possibility!</p>
<p>We talk every day to our precious Baby Nei in his dear picture - and we long to hear from you all three -</p>
Endless love as always
form your devoted
Mama - Nanny
Mother
