<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
133a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
May 27, 1941.
<p>Ol will write very soon.</p>
Dearest Dad:-
<p>It was so nice to have a letter from you, as we haven't had "'ery a 'un" for one long spell! No, there isn't a lot to say, but it's nice to keep in touch by writing. The trouble usually with letters is that one often gets the wrong idea of what the other is trying to say! Ain't it so? I'm sure non of us ever means anything wrong! We don't mean no harm!" Ha!</p>
<p>Gee, Dad, that jewelry sounds perfectly beautiful!! We can hardly wait to see 'em! "When are you'unds a - comin' up <sic>agin</sic>?"</p>
<p>The place is nice this year - with the blue grass almost knee high &amp; about to seed! 'S funny people think short grass so charming? We love that wild 'n <sic>woolly</sic> tall stuff, don't you? But, we're going to cut it soon, so we can see the flower beds from a short distance! We put in a couple little box-elder trees, Dad. Found 'em in Harrison's hedge! One is quite pert; the other dreadfully sad! We'll get one anyhow <sic>mebbe</sic>, &amp; that's 'nuff. Hil &amp; Al &amp; Sig just talk &amp; rave about the home! But it is wonderfuller than ever! <sic>Mebbe</sic> we'll get down next summer with the "bunny"! Wouldn't that be fun?!</p>
2
<p>Its mama is going to pull all its hair our - one by one, tho', just because it's so athletic! Ha! It must be <underline>some</underline> kid judging from the power of its rights &amp; lefts with feet &amp; hands, etc. I tell neighbors that I'm gonna do that &amp; they get so mad at me!! Ha!</p>
<p>Yes, Dad, the hedge is doing handsomely &amp; we're <underline>so</underline> delighted. This fall we wnat to set it out. It'll always be a dear memory when it's big &amp; tall &amp; blooming! The fact that you cut each one of the millions of shoorts just for us. Then, you'll have to be chief supervisor of the trimming when it gets to that stage.</p>
<p>Jackes had some hedge clippers, which Ol borrowed, &amp; he is repairing the handle which is off - doing it on the lathe. Ol really enjoys that outfit, Dad! You couldn't have done anything nicer if you'd tho't &amp; tho't &amp; tho't! In the next winter, he'll get more chance to work on it. Summer keeps him in the yard so much. And, then, too, he's been painting things lately in his spare time. We hope to have the wicker set adorning &amp; glorifying our living room very soon. I'm putting a removable  cover on the big chair and will have similar cretonne to cover the seats of the wicker set &amp; the ottoman part of the big chair with. Mom, won't this be nice?</p>
133b
3
<p>Dad, that folder is most intriguing in get-up! Makes one read it <underline>all</underline> right away at sight! On the last column of the inside of folder; I just noted "Nie" instead of "Nei" in "Neihardt As A Speaker". but of course, you got it no doubt. And, I like that picture, but it may not be right. However, there's something about it I love. We're so anxious to see at least a picture of the bust. It must be perfect from all we hear from Al, Hil &amp; Sig &amp; everyone who's seen it! It'd be grand if they could slip in that picture of the bust in place of the one now on the foler, wouldn't it? Could they?</p>
<p>Hope we see you soon.</p>
Loads o ' love to you &amp; Mom &amp; plenty to Max &amp; Wubs,
always,
<underline>Enot
P.S.</underline>
<p>Mona John is kickin' a few hard ones - his or her way of sendin' a <underline>lot</underline> o' love to Nanny &amp; Gaki! It's a darlin' babe - it's really surprising good, considering what it must be up against this warm weather! Ha!</p>
<p>Doesn't this so called patriotic propaganda in everything get you?!! <underline>It does us</underline>! - Enot</p>

