<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
3
Jan. 28, 1927
CHRISTODORA HOUSE 
147 AVENUE B. NEW YORK, N.Y. 
TELEPHONE ALGONQUIN 8400
<del>Dec 24, 1928</del>
Monday 
Dear Mama:
I thought of you last night at the dinner at the Biltmore Hotel and wished you were there. It would have given you a big kick. The brilliant crowd of diners filled the huge & gorgeous dining room. There were famous men & women from both England & America. I was the guest of honor & sat at the right hand of the President of the Society. The guest table was raised <del/> four feet above the floor. I as honor guest, did the closing stunt, & it was a big success. I held a big reception afterward - people crowded up - famous, many of them..

4
-2-
Ernest Rhys editor of Everyman's Library, a fine old British scholar, was by me. Mrs Corinne Roosevelt Robinson came up & said: "I am Theodore Roosevelt's sister, & I want to say that you two should have <unclear/> each other. He was fond of your poetry & introduced your work to me." Later she said: "I'm sure he is with you." 
Old Edwin <unclear/> rushed up tome, cooking like, a god from Olympus, & said: "Is this John Neihardt! Well you're the one man in America I want to meet". Mrs. Markhams said: "you made them all love you." and some other famous person said: "you had them in your vest pocket every minute." 

5
-3-
CHRISTODORA HOUSE
147 AVENUE B. NEW YORK, N.Y. 
TELEPHONE ALGONQUIN 8400 
It was really a triumph, & I met many who have cared for my work for years. I was surprised at the strong undercurrent of reputation I have. I am to read over WOR Friday A.m at 10 or thereabouts-just a short reading-maybe you can get me. It doesn't matter, though, unless it's easy to pick me up. 
The President of the National Society for American Speech spoke very enthusiastically about my enunciation & <unclear/> & the way I manipulated my syllables, that's her specialty. 
Lennox Robinson, head of the Dublin Theater, was near me at the guest table. Leonora Speyer was at my right. 

6
4
Beyond her was written Bynner etc etc. On the other side Rhys, Robert Underwood Johnsons, forms Golding, Joseph Auslander, Edwin <unclear/>, <del>etc etc.</del>
Mrs. Corrine Roosevelt Robinson etc etc. 
This p.m. I am to meet a bunch of people here at this house, which is under the direction of Anna Hempstead Branch, Josephine Peabody was formerly head here. 
Leonora Speyer. given reception tomorrow evening for me at her house. Big guns will be present. Wednesday a.m. I read at the world org. astoria Friday night at the University Club etc. 

7
-5-
CHRISTODORA HOUSE 
147 AVENUE B. NEW YORK, N.Y.
TELEPHONE ALGONQUIN 8400
All this seems fine, but I'd rather be with you in Branson. Very much neither. I'm to lunch with <unclear/> tomorrow. He wrote me that sooner or later, when there is a vacancy, I'd be considered for a <unclear/> on the Macmillan staff.
I can't see yet, have anything much will come of this, but it seemed the thing to do. 
Oh I wish I could spend some weeks resting with you & watching the spring come on that clean beautiful, quiet country! Maybe I can. 
Endless love,
Jno. 
