<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
729 Fink Collection 79
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your good letters always mean so very much to us - so many thanks for them. The trip was the most perfect one we have ever had. Daddy's <unclear/> is almost uncanny and every one old or young seems to get a feeling similar to a revival only there are no hysterics. I believe Daddy has still a long way to go in this World adn that his mission is a very religious one. He has found the way to turn egotism into most effective altruism - losing himself in the transition. It is surely a great privilege to be his wife and is becoming more a pleasure than a hardship.-</p>
<p>I am sending you some pictures that you will love, as they are the best we have ever had of "Home". <strike> I may send them to Southwood since Maxie wants to plan a celebration for you on your birthday there.</strike></p>
80
<p>I think your present to Enid of the Home and also the mattress are very big and wonderful birthday gifts. God bless you Ollie for all your goodness and sweetness to our girlies who I Know is most deserving and very appreciative of you - as are we here too.</p>
<p>Yesterday I washed and then used the soap suds to clean our darling car. Afterwards I simonized it and it looks lovely indeed. Simonizing brings out the blue color.</p>
<p>Today we are going to call on Mrs Shmitt. Daddy and I enjoy going visiting together. Yesterday we went to<unclear/> Daisy and Sunday to Lunds.</p>
<p>These is a sweet song-birdie just out side the front window in the Wisteria vine sending you some sort of message of love! Our flowers are simply marvelous - What a riot of color now! The blue morning-glories against the red yellow <sic>bronzie</sic> tones of the hills are a joy to see! The yellow marigolds, blue ageratum white and pink</p>
81
<p>baby-zinnias are like a meadow of flowers all about our pool-baby. SO you must immagine the colors in the pictures I am sending. Will send the pool picture a little later on.</p>
<p>I swell the apple pie I am baking in our grand new oven - wish you both were to eat it with us two. Daddy is going to make my Kitchen cabinet into a seat for two with table so that we can eat on in the nice, warm, bright Kitchen. Please say something, encouraging about this when you write, as I'm having a hard time to get Daddy to "want to" - You understand, Enid! Once it is made he'll enjoy it as much as I will!</p>
<p>the bust is so good that I feel certain all my training and all my disappointment in that direction were worthwhile. The best thing about it is Daddy's pleasure in it!</p>
<p>Enid darling, don't worry about the way you are doing or feeling inside, try to forget it all, and you'll be in the family-way and O.K. I don't doubt you are</p>
82
<p>conscious of this yourself, but I thought I might be able to help you a little by mentioning this.</p>
<p>Always love to you both and wishing you more and more happiness with every year you live together -</p>
Your devoted Mama-
Mother