<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
188 Fink Collection 6
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
MORRISON'S 
HOTEL AND RESTAURANT
SHIPPENSBURG, PA.
SHIPPENSBURG, PA.
JUL8
5 -PM
1940
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St. Louis
County
7
MORRISON'S
Hotel and Restaurant
Banquets and Parties
Shippensburg, Pa.
Monday 1940
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your good letters have been much enjoyed. We are waiting in Shippensbug now for this evening's affair at the Auditorium of the College. We have been spending 10 days waiting in Chambersburg and so we are mighty glad to be moving once more. It eats up one's funds to have to stick at tourist camps even though</p>
8
2
<p>we do our own work. But it has been a nice rest during which "we" got ahead on Jed very well! This town is most fascinating - but sleepy and not at all thrilling like the West. Everything is perfect. The people are Kind, the Homes are lovely - farms are so clean and the crops are tops. One sees not a blemish on the lanscape - no dumps no dirt or refuse anywhere. There are many old fashioned severe fronts on good houses, with marvelous gardens seen only through the gateways. I never saw such</p>
9
3
MORRISON'S
Hotel and Restaurant
Banquets and Parties
Shippensburg, Pa.
___19__
<p>blue grass on laws since I came away from the East. And the many Kinds of foliage trees are like pictures of perfect specimens! Daddy and I have eaten our fill of wild raspberries and cherries bordering Highways!</p>
<p>Tomorrow we start West and you may know how eager we are to see you dear children. But we are not driving</p>
10
<p>the mornings because Dad writes till 10 - and we hope you will allow Daddy to continue doing so when we are with you in St Louis, so as not to break the spell. He sits in his car and puts a sheet over the top hanging over the windows where disagreeable light comes in - and there he feels contented and able to write or plan what he is going to write. If he may do this in your backyard be will be less in a hurry to get back to Branson.</p>
<p>I hope to show my sea nymph at the Rookwood Pottery in Cincinnati Ohio. - Loving you</p>
11
MORRISON'S
Hotel and Restaurant
Banquets and Parties
Shippensburg, Pa.
___19__
<p>all so deeply, and hoping to be with you by Friday anyway -</p>
Your devoted
Dad and Mom.