<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
58a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
(1)
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
February 6. 1940.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I'm really sorry that I didn't acknowledge the receipt of the $10 traveler's check. I simply forgot to say anything about it I guess, for I have written you since I received it. I've been sick since last Tuesday, so that is why I haven't written you very lately. I <underline>have</underline> thought of you often though. As I'm up and about now again, I'm writing to you now.</p>
<p>Yesterday I went to the morning class again, my first class since last Tuesday evening. I didn't go through all the class though, as Madame thought I ought to be very careful, and I'm not very strong yet.</p>
(2)
<p>After that I came home, had some soupd and went to sleep for about 2 (1/2) hrs. Then I dressed, Ollie returned and we had dinner. I went to bed again at 10:00 after doing dishes and reading paper. This morning I got up at 9:00, so I'm getting a lot of rest now. This evening I'm going to take class but I'm not going to attempt practicing yet today.</p>
<p>It was wonderful to be at Hil's while I was sick. I think it took a burden off Eny and also made it possible for Ollie and her to be alone together for awhile. Hil and Millie took wonderful care of me. I stayed in bed Wed. and Thurs. adn got up Fri. but didn't go outside 'till Sunday. I began reading "Madame Curie" by Eve Curie her, daughter. It's marvelous! I had to leave my copy</p>
58b
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
(3)
<p>of it at Margaret's however, for it belongs to her! Therefore, I won't be able to finish the book 'till she returns and I can request it from her. Right now she may still be with her Mother at home. If was her absence that made it possible for me to stay at Hotel Clubs, for I slept in her bed. Wasn't that nice? By the way, I expect Hil's already told you that I had the grippe. I expect I'll be rather weak from it for some time to come so I'll have to get back into harness gradually.</p>
<p>I just finished writing up on my diary. I've been keeping my new <strike>years</strike> one <underline>every</underline> evening, but I didn't have it while</p>
(4)
<p>at Hil's. My old one is completely done - 5 yrs. I'll admit I'm about the only one who could read most of it, but that is perhaps as good a way as any for keeping it a secret! The new one is being written legibly, however.</p>
<p>Yes, Madame does have the baby. I explained everything concerning that to you in a previous letter, Mama, but evidently it was teh one that wasn't sent or have I already told you this?</p>
<p>Nothing much reamins to be said now.</p>
<p>Elaine and Joan or Joan and Elaine, rather, must, be adorable now Gee! I'd love to see them! Give them love in gobs from their auntie Alice.</p>
Loads of love to Everyone,
to you, to Sig and Max, 
adn to the wubs,
from Alice
<note>sentences below are in margin of letter</note>
<p>P.S. Daddy, if in some of your lecture time, you could pick out some books for me I'd be delighted!</p>