<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
3 Berg Collection 
[Spring 1924]
22
Dear Mrs. Berg:-
The Pender Republic came as usual today and it made me think of you just because it is ^from your town. The urge to write to you grows upon me and here I am as you see. 
I think I must tell you why I am a patron of <del>the</del> your paper, It might be of interest to you. Some 10 years ago I was selling the Spiritual corset. Pender being one of "my <unclear/>" I put an ad in the Pender Republic and they sent me a copy showing that they had been faithful to the order. Well they kept sending the paper, I wrote them I did not want it but they kept right on never missing a week except when we moved to Branson. There was one week I did not received it 

23
<unclear/> we left Bancroft I thot now they will discontinue, but not so, they sent it right on, there has been nothing financially for them I have never paid a cent. & They have never sent me a bill, jshould you believe me when I tell you that now the paper is the first I open. In it, when ever John is in that part of the country is always a very sensible write up of him. When he was in Pender they gave him valuable space. So I always look for that paper. Many of the names are familiar. I am able in a way to keep up with you an Mrs. Day & others and since our correspondence I look for your name always. 
I hoep this narrative will not be tiresome, but you have proven yourself a good sport have my perpetration;
How I wish you could be here today 

2
24
The day is a perfect one, The sky is so blue and the grass and trees so green and the birds are singing as tho they had been Divinely authorized, oh such masses of roses, this is arose country what ever else it may be. I have been in my house thru years. The first year there was practically nothing growing, infact great heaps of rocks on every side of me, ceiling & to from the rock the Masons used for my house. besides piles that were made blasting for the cistern and for holes to plant my trees. Oh dear it is yet an awful night mare. Well I started out to tell you about my roses. I planted all the fall of the first year here really I planted almost all winter, and as a result I have roses Every where on the <unclear/> between John and me is a fence literally covered 

25
climbing roses besides bushes planted three feet out making almost a solid bank. on the East I have wild roses on the same kind of a fence as on the West. They have not bloomed yet but soon will be a profusion of Wild roses in front of them I have monthly roses that are just cuttings two years old and they are loaded too, against the house on the East there are more roses a big bush at each window three of them, and filled in between with Christan <unclear/> and this ^is a great Country for them too, I have had beautiful ones and they look promising for this year. But the prettiest ^thing is the Dorothy Parkins on a lattice on eihter side of my porch against the house and our hanging the big window they grow riotously, are climbing along 

3
26
The roof of my house and when they bloom I shall be tempted to just stay out and enjoy them. Oh Mrs. Berg; what a pact nature is. I wonder why every one doesn't see it and enjoy it. Have you ever enjoyed the Early mornings just after the break of day and before the Sun has hardly made pink enough, where it will rise, to make one think it is the sun, the mocking birds after a long night of mimicry gorwing suddenly quiet the quail taking up its hotel and oh I might go on and on with all the different waking things have you ever had that experience? That lovely softness over everything thing, makes me feel that I am very close to God indeed I wonder if I am not a part of <del/> God, and <unclear/> times I am filled with "God and I dreamed the vast dream together." 

27
arcy. I am just rambling on and not getting the things you might like to hear about told. First we are all will ago or much better. My trouble was humerioce for which I had quite a serious operatic and it is only now that I am really getting well altho I have been home since the middle of Feb. Mona has quite gained her strength and has her house cleaning nearly all done. Mine is yet most of it to do as I did not want to do painting while Mary is here and <unclear/> closes this week. The children are having such loads of fun this after noon. At donkey strayed in to us from the country and Sigurd took him in cleaned him up and made a bridle for him and this afternoon Hilda and Alice & are riding all over the pasture bare backed it is fun to see them so happy over that ugly ani-mal. Sigurd has a sweetheart he very seriously informed us and which 

4
28
we all take in good part. She is a very nice little thing. She is studying music too and is very ambitious a year older than Sigurd but he says that does not make any difference to him. She tells Sigurd she will have nothing to do with a boy who swears or keeps bad company. So we are just winking at each other while we note the change in her "<unclear/> bromel." now maybe I have not spelled that right these children are a problem each different with different tasks and temperaments all bright as tacks and wide awake. Sigurd is making wonderful strides in his music, practices so well, Enid takes violin with her mother, they play simple things together. surprising by well, Hilda is at the head of her class all of them a year older than she. Her teacher says she is a joy in school. Alice the last, and sweetest and best and that is saying word

29
in you know, because nothing but superlatives was ever used by Grandma about the other three. Will she says she thinks she will marry Grandma, none of the rest ever loved me that much. She is a little picture, I'll tell you! Virigy my Extravagance, I'll have daddy take a snap of them and send you one. 
John will finish the Indian Wars in a few weeks and oh how glad we will be. He goes to Nebraska in July and when he comes home I hope he will be free from any obcession for a little while. I'm no End grateful for your interest in and good wishes for us all. It is mighty sweet of you and we all send thanks to you, hoping for a real acquaintance some time in the near future. My best wishes to you and Dr. Berg oh I almost forgot to <unclear/> the note of appreciation form Mr. <unclear/>. It is safely at away with the rest of the <unclear/> that may be value after we are all passed away, thanks for your good letter and may I please have an other one? Alice M. Neihardt 

30
P.S. John just tells me that the University has Neihardt day at Morton Park has Neihardt day at Morton Park Sterling J. Morton's old homes July the 11th and I wonder if you have seen or purchased the combination of "Hugh Glass" and Three Friends pub. in the modern reader's series? If not I should like to give you an auto-graphed copy of one. - 
The only good you will see in this letter is that I have written enough to - last quite a while. 
I want to tell you too that Monda is getitng ready to do some <unclear/> -ing, I think, of my baby Alice, and that I have a daughter who graduates from the Governer Librarian shool ^Buffalo the 7th of June. How I would like to be there. She has a good position in the Pub. Library of Duff  

31
<unclear/> and I'm powerfully happy about it Dear Mrs. Berg I'm so glad you appreciated the letter and thankyouf or its safe return sometime it will add much to a volume of Neihardt's letters. I have recently read the letters of Mark Twain and also the letters of Swerrburn and sometime ago a volume of <unclear/>'s letters I find nothing so wonderful as the one I sent you. Yes I am paid over and over again, I wish I might have heard your talk on Neihardt I am sure it <del>would</del> was <del/> same and just sometimes even tho all that has been said is true but does not ring tru like the real admirer, you know what I mean just getting into The "Band Wagon" Thank you so much for your loyalty now I'm giving to seal this upright for fear I may think of something else to say. Everybody send best wishes to you and yours. Most Sincerely
Alice M. Neiahrdt 