<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
54
Branson
Sep 3rd 
'42
Darling Enid and Ollie:
<p>By this time you will have seen Amama and she will have told you about us here - I hope she feels able to go ahead with her decision to be happy in N.Y.C. but I do not feel sure at all. SHe seemed quite natural before she left here, although she is not as strong by any means as 10 years ago. Also she seemed quite happy most of the time. Certainly she had "more for her moeny" than she has in N.Y. but somehow she seemed to feel she wanted "city conveniness" above all else - so she will have to find out - till some day it will be too tale! - <underline>Too bad</underline>! I would not be surprised if O.J. went before <undelrine>she</underline> goes on - and that would be awful for her. he does not look at all strong to me in his picture - and that young wife of his means destruction instead of conservation. Thirty years between them! It is a scream and about as crazy as every thing else poor Amama's mind is filled with back there. ---</p>
2
55
<p>will be for you two fine, dear parents later on! When young we build our memory walls that later on surround us - and how wise to make good memories for our old age!</p>
<p>I cannot see ahead very far but I can tell you that Daddy and I are plannig to be with you a week after this next week end, if that is convenient for you. We have 10 pounds of sugar to bring along, minus what we usee now each day which is very litter. Please tdll me if you'd like a lovely new Alarm clock? You see we have $80.00 in Poll Parrot</p>
3
<p>moeny and we <underline>are going</underline> to get something for <underline>you</underline> with it, so you might as well tell us the truth as we might bring you soemthing you did not care for. How would you like a <underline>heavy</underline> bathroom rug? Well made cotton ones they have, that do not muss up. Their alluminim ware is about gone, but would you like silver ware, spoons or so? <underline>Please</underline> tell me at once. Would you like a new coffee pot?--</p>
<p>I am on the baby's outfit at last - so sorry I could not do it sooner.</p>
<p>The MacArthur pictures</p>
4
56
<p>have helped me a lot and I may be able to "land" somethign will let you Know as soon as <underline>I</underline> Know something.</p>
<p>Daddy's bust is cast adn in the front room.</p>
<p>Our rose and pink Zinnias are a sight adn pale blue morning glories too - just beautiful! The whole flower and blue - wonderful!</p>
<p>It is good to Know you want us and Im eager to be with you-</p>
Loads of Love to the finest little Home in all the World -
your devoted Mama- 
Mother.
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON 
SEP3
3 -PM
1942
MO.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr &amp; Mrs. O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis County.