<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
100a
(1)
March 17, 1940
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Dear Mama,
<p>I was so glad to get your two swell letters. I appreciate your talk of proportious. I shall think about all you said - I can see what you mean.</p>
<p><sic>Joannie</sic> and Elaine must be adorable. they are such different personalities, aren't they? Baby 'Laine must be wanting to play the 'Bylin - hope she really does - I know she will, too. I think <sic>Joannie</sic> does have dancing ability. Maybe she'll want to take it up some day.</p>
<p>Hil was here today for dinner. We talked about the apt., and all four of us decided we should not get an apt. till May 1st after Hil's vacation. Eny and Ollie seem to think it's O.K. for me to stay here till then - they're swell to me!</p>
<p>As to money matters, I now have only about $1.50 left. I need to buy a new pr. of toe shoes, so whenever you and daddy can send it I'll be glad for a little cash. I'll give Hil the bill from Madame.</p>
<p>I'm feeling very well, not at all "let down", as you say after my shots have been discontinued. In fact, I'm feeling and looking better than have been for a long time. I feel swell!</p>
<p>Never feel that <strike>I'm</strike> having a hard time here - on the contrary, I'm having a marvelous life - I love my work and feel I'm advancing in it, and I have a marvelous time at home on Sundays, etc.</p>
<p>The garden must be progressing wonderfully. Today Eny and Ollie worked outside all day. It was glorious - perfect for St. Patrick's Day.</p>
<p>This morning I went riding from 9:30 to 11:30 on Nancy from next door. I rode clear out A<unclear/> to St Charles Rock Rd. Had glorious time. On the gorgeous sky, the wonderful fields, the sparkling air. Really it and a swell little horse under me!?</p>
(2)
<p>was marvelous!</p>
<p>Surely I can use my blue suit.</p>
<p>Saturday I had a swell lesson, I did some arabesque releves (holding balances) so well that Madame said with the amount of lessons I've had, she didn't see how I did it. She said it was because I used my mind!</p>
<p>I must wash some costumes now, so I can have clean ones tomorrow!</p>
Loads of love to All,
Alice
<p>Ollie thinks the violin you mention is (1/2) size, and that no smaller ones are made. He says he has spoken about it to Francis, who wants to give it back as soon as possible. So Ollie will get it soon. He'll see if any smaller is obtainable.</p>
<p>I'm enclosing an article which Ollie wants you all to read.</p>