<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
22
October 15, 1930
Blair, Neb. 
Saturday Morning 
Dearest Mama: 
We decided, after all, not to stop in Omaha, and so came on down here on the way to Wayne. I wrote you last evening sitting in the car, and my hand was still shaky from the Peru stunt.! I feel very happy while I'm before a crowd, because a sort of tenderness develops in the place, and fills it. But always, whenI'm asked to write autographs afterwards, I can hardly guide a pen. For this reason, we must get more money for appearances and have them separated by a day or so, It isn't as though I felt tenseness or any anxiety. I feel perfectly at case; but 
-2-
that stuff begins <del/> pouring out of me - What it is, I don't know, but it is powerful and it <unclear/> me. Always did. I do believe, just the same, that the expenditure results in a renewal after a rest. 
That must have been a no good note I wrote; but I love you, dear lovely Lady. I'm hoping that you are letting loose and resting. You must. 
I'll mail a check to Alice today, for fear you might not. If you do, then she'll just have a week's allowance ahead. . 
I do wish I were, working on "Jed". I was in the swim when I stopped; but I'll get back easily I think. When I get that finished, I'll just 

23
-3-
let some lyrics happen, while I float. There must be some pretty good ones somewhere in me, because I've felt them. But wouldn't it be funny if, later, I'd do one more S'ong for the Cycle? I hope not; but there could be another still, I care more for being and saying than for writing, and perhaps I'll go that way altogether. Something does take hold of me & do the talking. It flows so easily and smoothly, and people don't move. Kind of queer, and it makes me deeply happy and kind. Awfully queer! 

-5-
24
state of development. Sig and I don't even feel any function of any kind. He's grown up now, and we're less father and son than two men who believe the same things. I'm so glad. 
Grandan is awful mad at Joan for not writing at least one love letter. Does that little boy stick around there? Dog on him! May he get the measles! And a very mild case of whooping cough, maybe! And a spanking! Kisses all over Baby Laine's face, and puttings for old George! But I'm mad at old Joan. Love to Maxie. 
Endless love to you, Mona. 
Jno. 
