<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Just can't say all I feel when writing letters to you! I love you 
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
155
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS FIREPROOF, MODERN <FIGURE/> HEADQUARTERS KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
HOTEL FORT KEARNEY
JOHN A. HENRY, PROP.
CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS
MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
KEARNEY, NEB.
10-27-'32
Kearney Neb. 
My own sweetheart,
Just awoke from a few hours (two) rest after the all nite's drive from Lincoln over here!
Almost went to sleep at times, but averaged around 57 m.p.h. or over! Marvelous roads, you know, & had to use the cut-out to stay awake on! C? This was a nite-man ina  way, 'cause I was so awfully sick thru the whole nite, but am well as 

156
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
FIREPROOF, MODERN
<FIGURE/> 
HEADQUARTERS
KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
<FIGURE/> HOTEL <FIGURE/>
FORT KEARNEY
JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS 
MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
KEARNEY, NEB. 
-2- 
can be this morning! These trips are a con-siderable nerve strain & cause thereby - lots of "system" disorder! We've been in the same boat - I note from your letter which I rec'd! 
You sweet girl, I'm so sorry that you had this sickspell!
Take care of yourself! I think that we both know what it's like to overwork & get sick over it all! 
Don't we, dear? 

157
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
FIREPROOF, MODERN
    <FIGURE/> 
    HEADQUARTERS
    KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
    <FIGURE/> HOTEL <FIGURE/>
    FORT KEARNEY
    JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
    CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
    CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS 
    MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
    KEARNEY, NEB. 
-3-
Dad is out to his lecture (it is 10:50 A.M.) & I have the privilege of sleeping if I can - but I'll not do it! I care too much about my darlin' girl to want - to sleep when I have such a sweet & loving letter to read & answer! It is so wonderful, my dear girl, - tohave your love! Because you are the sweetest girl I've ever known & I love you more all the time! 

158
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
FIREPROOF, MODERN
    <FIGURE/> 
    HEADQUARTERS
    KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
    <FIGURE/> HOTEL <FIGURE/>
    FORT KEARNEY
    JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
    CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
    CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS 
    MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
    KEARNEY, NEB. 
-4-
Just one more place to make & hurrah! the trip will be a - bout over!! 
Oh, it will be so wonderful to be with you again, sweet girl! I am thrilled with the news of our bridge being in use! Fine!! Just wait'll "we" drive over it (ahem!!!) (you & I)!! I have so many things to tell you, & you know how it is - it would take a 

159
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
FIREPROOF, MODERN
    <FIGURE/> 
    HEADQUARTERS
    KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
    <FIGURE/> HOTEL <FIGURE/>
    FORT KEARNEY
    JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
    CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
    CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS 
    MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
    KEARNEY, NEB. 
-5-
m.s. to even start! I have never in all my days, seen a bldg. so huge & marvelously deluxe as this Neb. state Capitol bldg. It is $10,000,000 in cost & covers nearly 3 1/2 acres of land, with a tower 125 or so feet high! Statue on top of dome! It simply takes one's breath away to look at this uncanny structure! The interior is a 

160
"GENUINE HOSPITALITY" 
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
FIREPROOF, MODERN
    <FIGURE/> 
    HEADQUARTERS
    KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
    <FIGURE/> HOTEL <FIGURE/>
    FORT KEARNEY
    JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
    CENTRALLY LOCATED BETTER BEDS 
    CHOICE SAMPLE ROOMS 
    MODERN COFFEE SHOP 
    KEARNEY, NEB. 
-6-
king's palace in every detail, & to the ex-tent that a person could hardly exagg-erate its beauty! We'll see it together, jsut you "hold-on"! I don't know why not! I must close, & soon I'll be on to Mc-Cook where I'll receive another letter from the only girl that I love & who means everything to me! 
Always I love you, 
-Sig. 

<figure/> L <figure/> 
FORT ARNEY
161 
JOHN A. HENRY, PROP. 
KEARNEY, NEB. 
<FIGURE/> 
NEW & FIREPROOF
100 ROOMS - 60 BATHS 
HEADQUARTERS 
KEARNEY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1932 WASHINGTON 1932 1CENT1 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1932 WASHINGTON 1932 1CENT1 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1932 WASHINGTON 1932 1CENT1 
KEARNEY OCT 27 1932 130 PM NEBR. 
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson,
Missouri 
Taney County. 