<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI>
54d
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
April 5, 1943
(el cinco Abril)
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Now at last we have arrived in "el parsiso del universo," Mexico City, and, form what we've already seen, we can well believe and agree with quotation. Above this, everything seems like a dream - yes, a glorious one, which has set us down in a land as beautiful as it</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(2)
<p>is strange and fascinating.</p>
<p>We left Nuevo Laredo on the 1:30 A.M. bus Sunday, for we were detained there several days longer than I thought when I wrote you last. Had one grand trip here, travelling very rapidly in a comfortable bus through some of the most beautiful (la mas <hi rend="underline">ermosa</hi>) country it has been my privilege to see. How you would love it! First of all, we rode over flat sagebrush plains, then, at six A.M. arrived in Monterrey. Here we breakfasted (desayuno) on Jugo de</p>
54e
(3)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>Narange, pan dulce, y cafe con leche, took a walk about the city in the dusky morning, and finally reboarded the bus at 7:00 bound for parts South. Monterrey seemed most interesting from what we saw - filled with native stands of all kinds and having nice boulevards and monuments. As the sun arose we again entered mountains, this time much higher</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(4)
<p>ones than those preceding Monterrey. These were covered with dry brush (seared by the sun, although it is never hot there), and some greener grass. Every so often one passed a lovely little creek which seemed a gross contradiction to the general appearance of the land. Between stretches of real mountains, high and rugged, and a bit God-forsaken in a glorious sort of way, we travelled for miles on high mesas, seeing in the distance the huge, blue form of a lone butte. Just such country must</p>
54f
(5)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>Hugh Glass have crawled over - endless, and lone, and, though God forsaken, still very full of God! A little later we began getting glimpses of rugged mountains veiled in filmy cloud. With the sun shining on these full force they looked like mountains of solid iron, dressed in soft cotton. If one did not know it was real, it would be hard to believe such was not the skillful</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(6)
<p>work of a scenic director! I sat part of the way with a Mexican Senor who was "muy amable" and seemed to take great pleasure in conversing with me ("all in Spanish too!) about the beauties of Mexico. Strange as it may seem, I understood him almost completely, for what I didn't understand, he managed somehow to explain in another way. He knew only a very few words in English as I in Spanish)</p>
<p>Finally the mountains flattened out into high, plain-country, and we</p>
54g
(9)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>drove for miles over this country, stopping frequently for refreshment in interesting little towns full of bright-eyed people. IN one restaurant, I went in alone to order lemon soda. When I asked for "la cuenta" I was informed by the Senorita that a certain Senor (muy bonito!) there had already asked to pay my bill! I could do nothing but answer "Gracias, Senor," and he responded with a smile and bow! Leaving the</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(10)
<p>plains, we entered around suppertime a range of mountains which were so different from the first ones that it was hard to realize they were both in the same country. Instead of seared brush, (or even greener trees with tall white blooms, such as followed the seared land), we now saw truly tropical trees and verdure of every description grading on the sides of high mountains. As in the preceding ones, there were many little adole huts with thatched roofs, adorable little hurr-</p>
54h
(9)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>os, vacas (cows), and fine strong vallors (horses), but, in addition there were the beauties of <hi rend="underline">green</hi> things and many blossoms. For the first time we saw many bananas (green ones) growing, papayas, and some kind of pink flowers which decorated many trees more beautifully than any blossoms I have ever seen. These mountains at times looked</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(10)
<p>a bit like I imagine part of Switzerland must be - not the tropical part, but the greeness of the pastures inhabited by sleek cows, the thatched huts - oh! es <hi rend="underline">muy</hi> bonito, muy ermoso, as one says here! We had lunch in a small town, in a nice restaurant, <hi rend="underline">truly</hi> Mexican. I ate "una ensalada de fruta," consisting of papaya, platina, and tororja (grapefruit) papaya, bananas, and. it was there that a certain gentleman spoke to us en francais, and we</p>
54i
(11)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>found it most enjoyable speaking with him about the land of our new adventure, as well as of Europe where he had lived previously.</p>
<p>At last we emerged from the mountains and <hi rend="underline">hurtled</hi> for several hours over more or less flat country till we reached <hi rend="underline">Mexico City</hi> at 6:05 A.M. this morning. We came directly to Hotel Coliseo, which had been reco-</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(12)
<p>mmended to us by several people in Laredo. Besides, we have already assumed temporary ownership of a charming apt. - simply lovely in fact, and large. There we shall be able to cook (which will be a great convenience and saving as well as healthful measure for us to take), and we shall have much room for relaxation. Our address there I shall give you. Write me: Donato Guerra 14, Apt. 16, Mexico D.F.</p>
<p>Now I must tell you of our plans here concerning work. George went out first thing this morning to see about that, and returned at 1:15 to tell us all</p>
54j
(13)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>about it. As the Folies Bergire will not open for 19 days, we are to await its opening (all our expenses paid!). Besides, El Patio is being redecorated, and we are to open there when it opens! Therefore, we are going to rehearse, see things, and get acclimatized in these next nineteen days. We visited El Patio yesterday, and were very pleasantly impressed</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(14)
<p>with its quaintness, and beauty, even though it is now in the midst of repairs. Very oriental in appearance, with winding stairways (I should say <hi rend="underline">Moonish</hi> which is <hi rend="underline">Spanish</hi> as well) turrets, and balconies this club has actually little room for customers, who, being a chosen few <hi rend="underline">really</hi> pay for their privilege. My, it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> a lovely place! We are going to rehearse new numbers as well as old.</p>
<p>I will send our address on a card. Want to send this out now. Oh! yes, we are to have new music <hi rend="underline">composed</hi> for part of our</p>
54K
15
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>dances, at the Folies Bergere Teatre! George went there last night and returned to say that the scenic director was all Hollywood could desire in the way of quaintness. The composer creates music wherever needed, for too well-known music is never used there.</p>
<p>Yesterday, upon arriving here, we went to had for three or four hours, being really sleepy from back of sleep <hi rend="underline">and</hi> the altitude as well. Upon awaking at 1:15, we heard</p>
Un Lugar de Distincion y de Negocios
An Address of Distinction and Business
(16)
<p>George's knock on our door. He had come to tell us about the plans <unclear/> at. We then dressed and went out to lunch, the three of us. Tried a Mexican Restaurant where we were forced to order en Espanol. It is gradually soaking in, faster for us who know French. As for the latter, we speak it so much it is becoming almost as natural as English. After eating we met George and his Grandmother. Hailing a taxi, we rode to our new apartment, which we found to be near El Patio (only a block) and near on albarotes too (grocery store)! I shall tell you more about our</p>
54L
(17)
<figure type="symbol"/>
Gran Hotel Coliseo
BOLIVAR 28
MEXICO, D.F.
<p>nwe home when we move there.</p>
<p>I also shall see about getting the little gems, Daddy - and also shall <unclear/> the papers for you. How you would <hi rend="underline">love</hi> it <sic>hear</sic> - all of you!</p>
<p>I have some lovely photos of the Palacio del Bellos Artes for we visited it yesterday. My <hi rend="underline">what</hi> a gorgeous place! Our guide spoke only Spanish and described every</p>
(18)
<p>thing to us thusly Oh! How I wished for you! Huge, beautiful, rich beyond description is this palace, and the paintings are <hi rend="underline">really</hi> unusually fine - <hi rend="underline">original</hi> too. The auditorium. There is like over Muir And - only more beautiful, Watched the nature ballet rehearsing. It is here that the Ballet Russa and Caravan perform. How we'd love to dance there!</p>
<p>Must close now</p>
Loads of Love,
dear ones,
Your Alice
</TEI>

