<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
2
32
April 17-1924
My Dear Mrs. Berg; 
your second good letter reached me long ago, much too long to fit with the promise I made you. 
When I tell you we have had a hospital first at John's then at my house and again at John's which I assure you kept Mona and I busy in turn ^you will understand why I have no Mona is now recovering from a very wicked attack of the flies and I feel as tho I could never feel ambitious again. But our weather is fine. The Hills are beautiful, the water will soon be warm enough to swim and soon we will have forgotten this winter's measles, whooping cough flue and hospitals, Isn't it fine that there are so many highlight in the world? And <unclear/> necessary and even beautiful are the shadows 
I remember Mrs. Masters; They were both so lovely to me and I found her a great admirer of John's work

33
<unclear/> of course made me very happy, I feel very much interested in your nieces and I know you are too. I think time will take care of all the school-boards. Many of them have already <del>have</del> been converted. I don't feel so impatient as I used to. I am more prone to think why hurry? There is plenty of time and there will always be plenty of young people. So much has come to John at such an early age and I have been permitted to enjoy so much, that I am happy about things first as they are. Dear lady; I did not mena to criticize you when I spoke of "Three Friends" and "Indian Wars" and espeically of his prose, of course I knew you would appreciate the best army place and I can understand perfectly the effect "Hugh Glass" had on you and I'm so happy it is that way. It opened up a new vista to me too I was pleased to have you mention Dr Buis in connection

34
<unclear/> John's work. I have never met Dr Buis, but have met his wife in a business way and she was so sweet to me. She said she did not need the corset I was selling "but own't you come in and rest?" That gave me heart and I have always remembered her. "It was the cup of cold water," That so few people have time to offer. Remember me to miss Buyer she is an other I have great reason to remember with pleasure. Dear Mrs. Ronk! I am happy that she remembered me. When you see her tell her as much. 
You do John's women folks great honor Thank you so much, I only hope it is all united. 
Have you never had "Man Song" or "Bundle of Myrrh?" I should be glad to send you my copies for a while. I think there are a number of things. Very good indeed not inclu in "The quest" I think the lines you 

35
fer to however can be found in "the nest." They are the dedication to "Bundle of Myrrh" and included in "The quest," 
I notice your list in complete the chances are you know his poetry much better than does his mother, but that only makes me happy too. 
I should like to tell you all about the children, a subject upon which I could write volumes, the next best thing after their father is his children and sometime I shall ful more like it than I do tonight. You wrote listening <del>to</del> over the Radio and I am writing between coughing convulsions ^to which I hope you will be kind enough to <unclear/> this undignified looking letter. 
Jno, to tell you the recel truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth I get homesick Nebraska's big corn fields altho the Hills are beautiful here and I have a very pretty stone bungalo close to John yet I htink maybe I was two old to transplant. Don't think I am unhappy tho. I am enclosing "The letter" you were take good care of it and return it your container 
Most sincerely Alice M. Neihardt 