<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
343 Fink Collection 14
Box 167 
<underline>Branson</underline>, Mo.

BRANSON
AUG 8
3 -PM
1942
M.O.

Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Rink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland, 
MO.
(St. Louis Co.)
15
Saturday
Dear Ollie &amp; Enot:
<p>Thanks for good letters - and more.</p>
<p>I think your reading of Hitch's letter is about right, altho he may have a little better figure in mind. We'll know soon, At any rate, if they really want me, I'll go. A couple of lectures each day would be excessive. I suggested two courses and a weekly open forum. No doubt there will be some outside lectures, as you say. I think your view is pretty close to possiblities. Rolfs wants me to "canvas teh university field thoroughly" before accepting of an offer is made. But the "<unclear>canvssy</unclear>" can continue even from Boonville - quietly.</p>
-2-
<p>What you say of the proposed study interests me a lot. You can, and I think will, do it.  Before hearing from you, I had given Rolfs permission to go ahead, and the man is going at his reading background like one obsessed. He should not be stopped, and what he may do can in no way hinder you. Whatever he writes, yours will be very different; and he will do a lot of hard spade-work that will help you. You will stand on whatever hill he may build.</p>
<p>It would make a nice pattern if I could be at Kemper, sell here, and buy that farm.</p>
16
-3-
<p>You may remember that I made a passing remark about "ironies". I see that there just aren't any at all, and can't be.</p>
<p>This has been, and still is, a good summer. I've felt stronger &amp; more steadily than every, that sort of blossoming happiness i've mentioned. There has been so much that once would, have seemed compelling reason for the exact opposite. It isn't at all a matter of "forbearance" (a silly word); it is not negative at all, but joyously <underline>positive</underline>. If it requires self-conscious effort, it is no good at all. It has nothing to do with doctrine or preachment, and</p>
-4-
<p>there is no way to get at it by taking thought. <underline>And it works</underline>, which is what matters.</p>
<p>Those are good articles, as usual, that you enclosed! Some day - not too late - you will get the satisfaction you need, and deserve, by doing a work in which ou profoundly believe. A farm might help to bring that day for you.</p>
<p>the enclosed is a second letter from Dr. Steguer, Prof. of Lit. at Howard, whose "Remembering Laughter" received the Atlantic Prize in 1937. He had asked permission to use a rather long passage from Jed - describing taht vast country. It's for his forthcoming book, "Mormon Country."</p>
17
-5-
<p>We're glad you will get pictures of MacArthur. A profile is desirable, along with other views, and <underline>reporductions</underline> will be good enough. Mona is eager to start on the little bust.</p>
<p>I'll bet Nei is <underline>not</underline> a bad boy! I bet he's a good boy - <underline>such a good</underline>! The precious darling little cuss! Hot do! Bang! All damn! Mama pick it up and Nei thrown it down! Swell game! I'm afraid he ahs been needing our teeth, from what you say.</p>
<p>We're getting perfect tomatoes from $1 a crate now. They'll drop in price soon.</p>
(over)
18
-6-
<p>SO this is page six! I dont' think I can fill it unlesss I write awful big.</p>
Love to all three,
Dad Gaki
<p>I hope the poor fellow who wants to "save" the world may have a chance to try! I'm afraid he'll be surprised! Saved from being this world! (This isn't cynicism.)</p>