<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
56h
May 6, 1942
Wednesday
1425 North Dearborn
Dear Daddy and Mama,
Eny, Ollie, and Nei
<p>I just receieved the letter with enclosed check, Daddy, and want to thank you greatly for both. It will really not be long till I can stand on my own.</p>
<p>I'm so glad about the Seymours. We're invited to the Bookfellow tea this Sunday.</p>
<p>Perhaps my last letter sounded quite muddled for indeed things were a bit mixed up then. Here is an account of how things stand now. First of all, Pryor and Leon are no longer connected, but our services are to be used</p>
(2)
<p>by both. Leon is ready to start us, so he will use us first. He <underline>does</underline> have bookings already - the first one in Detroit two wks. hence. You must understand that an act such as ours, consisting of three girls and a boy doing four numbers which are quite difficult and filled with "tricks", takes a great deal of rehearsing before it is presentable. We are working hard several hours a day now in order to be ready in two weeks for our opening in <strike>Chicago</strike> Detroit. We are to be fitted</p>
56i
(3)
<p>sometime soon for the costumes (which Leon already has in his possession) and our shoes will be ordered likewise. No, <strike>they</strike> we have much more, as we see it tahn a mere hope of being booked. Leon has already talked to his agent from New York, who is booking us in Detroit. You see, Leon and his dancers (previous to us) have paved the way for our bookings. Leon has been in active dancing for some years and has been very successful. He is young, very smart of course, but so far at least, we believe</p>
(4)
<p>he will be fair to the "waiting period" <strike>Dear Mme.</strike> should not be so long now. Whenever we are not being booked for George Leon, we shall be used by Pryor in the numbers I have already told you about (plus others we'll learn) I hope we may work into this with Pryor after several - maybe many bookings with Leon, for of course I <underline>love</underline> the cassical ideas of Pryor. Our present work will be with Leon alone,</p>
56j
(5)
<p>doing character numbers with lots of public appeal - and it is <underline>marvelous</underline> experience in the art of selling yourself, besides being <underline>real</underline> dancing. We are doing a Russian (with one boy) which is <underline>very</underline> cute, flashy and humorous, a gypsy danced by us three alone, and a "challenge" (consisting of tricks done alternately by the boy and us girls) as our first number. This we have learned and will busy ourselves to perfect. We have also begun</p>
(6)
<p><strike>We've had some delightful social <unclear/> person</strike> a "Jungle" dance, done in imitation of Haiti natives to real voodoo rythms. These character dances use many classical ballet steps in a characterized fashion, but they are vastly different to calssic ballet in stype and of course, technique too. In the Russian number we do a large variety of typical Russian steps and tricks, such as the "Cozatski," heel clicks, fouettes, and "wind the clocks." The last trick is the leg from the back around</p>
56k
(7)
<p>side and front, then jumping over it, the supporting leg being bent as far as possible - hands on the floor. You can see from this that besides using our acquired technique and developing artistry, this work also requires the learning of strenuous feats (audience appeal) Our thigh muscles are so sore we can barely walk upstairs - and going downstairs is in itself a feat! We'll get over this in a week however adn be O.K. from then on. We all feel that this is a grand oppor</p>
(8)
<p>tunity and we do believe it is right to hold on till we get our first pay check - in some manner or other - don't you?</p>
<p>We placed an ad in the paper (Tribune) for room and board for the three of us in return for evening work and companionship to an elderly lady - or someone else possibly. This was done in the period of uncertainty. Now, however, we have decided that we have little time for other work in view of rehearsing, etc., and furthermore our ansers have thus far been for only one girl per place</p>
56l
(9)
<p>We feel we need to be together with so much to plan and decide about. Besides all this, who would want us for only two wks.? In view of these things, we have taken this cozy apt. - quite reasonable yet roomy and very clean and pretty. (In comparison to anything else we've found in all our romings, this is tops in economy and value!) We pay $4 apiece per wk. rent and about $2 per wk. groceries. It is <undelrine>such</underline> a happiness to eat good food again - enough green vegetables, etc.; especially after two weeks of restaurant and boarding house meals.</p>
(10)
<p>What do you think of this? If we should have to stay here longer than 2 wks. - then I must get extra work - even though I haven't really time for it. As it is I shall spend only about $6 per. wk. for living - $1.20 or so carfare. If you think I <underline>should</underline> get something for these two wks. I'll do so of course.</p>
<p>We're having <underline>such</underline> marvelous experiences - such as <underline>new</underline> thrills. Now we're working hard in work we love - and all we want now is to begin earning soon!</p>
<p><underline>Please</underline> write soon.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
