<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
5 
Neihardt Collection 
19
ABSOLUTELY FIREPROOF 
<FIGURE/> Comstock Hotel 
FRANK F. DUNLAP 
PROPR. 
Thursday, 8 a.m. 
MOORHEAD, MINN. Jan 18 '34
Dear Ones:
Had a fine time yesterday in Minneapolis's. Everybody well there. Went to see A. J. Russell at the Journal. He, Neil & I had lunch together at Shicks. It was bully to feel old Russell again, & he was as glad as I. You will remember that my old boyhood pal, "Dick" Medical Sciences at the Minnesota University and one of the most distinguished <del>in</del> men in the medical world. Yesterday Mrs. Scammon called Lulu (after a deuce of a time tracing her) and invited all of us to <del/> dinner Sunday evening. It will be great to see old Dick again Good Lord! It will be hard to call him Doctor! I think I won't do it. Then Teena will have us to the Ritzy place of Minneapolis for another. 

20 
(2) 
ABSOLUTELY FIREPROOF 
<FIGURE/> Comstock Hotel 
FRANK F. DUNLAP 
PROPR. 
MOORHEAD, MINN._______________________
eating Saturday evening. My coming to Moorhead was in the Minneapolis papers. 
Last evening Lulu, the two boys & I went to the Orpheum to want for my 10:50 train to Moorhead - the saw & heard Kate Smith in person. Mona, she is a moose and sings like a lark with a powerful but clear & sweet & flexible voice. This seems impossible, I know But that noise we heard was certainly not Kate Smith. Everybody seems to love her - big fat, active thing with a warm heart. A bit coarse in action, but a wonderful voice. 
I had a good night. Got here at 7:30 a.m. It's not cold here - just a bit nippy, although <del>I am</del> is is as far North as Duluth. This is the country where Mrs. Holsen grew up. The Red River is close. 

21
(3) 
ABSOLUTELY FIREPROOF 
<FIGURE/> Comstock Hotel 
FRANK F. DUNLAP 
PROPR. 
MOORHEAD, MINN._______________________
Have just seen a Prof. from the College. Very nice & very cordial It's to be quite an affair, & has been armourred in the Fargo daily as "the oustanding event" of the <unclear/> season. I remarked that much would defend upon the quality of the rest of it! 
By Donald & I are really good friends. He & I both know it without trying. They weren't that we drive up here in the answer & on up into the North Woods. We may, too. 
I love this dry snappy air. It gives <unclear/> & is not at all hard to stand. Minneapolis was about the same as here. Snow all the way worth of Des Moines. 
Endless love for all
four of you
Jno. 
Dad. 