<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
51L
Wednesday, March 24, 
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Today I am at home with a bit of a sickspell due to a cold, so I can take time to chat with you. I have several very nice things to tell you.</p>
<p>Today is glorious as every day in Laredo with the exception of two or three has been. As I write I can look out of my window and see a sky of light blue filled with large fleecy clouds, and, on the horizon, a cluster</p>
(2)
<p>of three giant palms gently swaying in the breeze and glistening in the brilliant sunshine. Yes, it is truly very lovely.</p>
<p>Now I must tell you some news. We have been dancing at the Victory Club, as I told you already, and shall dance there again Saturday evening. Mr. Cole liked us very much, as did the audience too. Officers are fine people to perform for; you have found it so, haven't you Daddy? In <hi rend="underline">any</hi> capacity, for they are truly</p>
51m
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>appreciative, as a whole! Next, we may perform at several other affairs here soon. If we'd only made these contacts sooner we could have been working all this time we've been waiting; it takes <hi rend="underline">action</hi> I've found, to accomplish. All these engagements are through <hi rend="underline">one</hi> of my acquaintances. Now, here is the best bit of news - nothing very definite as yet, but hope, anyway. George received word from Philadelphia that as soon as</p>
(4)
<p>he gets his draft-release extension card, he will be awarded with a re-entry permit! That should not take long now, so we hope to be able to go to Mexico quite soon. His case has evidently been thoroughly examined now, and this decision has been reached. George has never had trouble in receiving these extensions (His last only recently expired), so we do not think this will take long to secure. However, we may take another engagement</p>
51n
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>which M.C.A. hopes to get for us soon in Texas before going to Mexico, as this will give our Mexican agent time to arrange matters for us there. Once in Mexico we want to remain for six months if we can. Pray for us - as I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> you have been doing. Living is becoming very high here and is much lower in Mexico. How grand to be dancing <hi rend="underline">exclusively</hi> again. Incidentally, I believe Truman is the cause of this action</p>
(6)
<p>Every day at the Hotel I see the Immigration Official; in fact, we are good friends now. Day before yesterday, he told me to send George up to his office, that he would wire Washington. He should have an answer on that soon too.</p>
<p>I meet <hi rend="underline">many</hi> people from Chicago and St. Louis, and we talk of those towns. I am continually being asked where I hail from, etc. Yesterday I made $4.26 in tips alone - quite good, n'est-ce-pas? I can begin to pay my debt now. they are not huge, but I have a few.</p>
51o
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>How do you like your new home by now? Is Amama coming to live with you? How are you feeling, Daddy? Have you been seeing a <hi rend="underline">good</hi> Dr.? I certainly hope you are much better. tonight I want to go to chapel and into the Garden afterwards - and I always pray for you and mama. That is the place where I can feel the most secluded from certain influences which pervade this atmosphere - soldiers, a bit of over-gaiety, etc.</p>
(8)
<p>A very fine gentleman from Chicago, whom I see every day at work and who has become very friendly with me wants to take some pictures of me posed around cactus etc. out on these Texas plains. One of these days I'm going out riding with him for that purpose. He is a camera fiend too. I'll send the pictures when they're ready. My "Boss" at the Hotel, Christine wants me to have some pictures taken too, so I'll buy coupons form her - and it's hard to refuse one's employer so it seems I'll have to have lots of pictures!</p>
Loads of Love, dear ones,
your Alicia


