<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
107a
6/14/40
Overland, Mo.
9917 Emerson.
Dearest Mama:
<p>Thanks for your very fine letter. I'm glad to know about that new bust of Dad you are to make, &amp; I'm certain it will be one of your very best accomplishments.</p>
<p>You surely should not be sad about having missed Alice's recital. Both Hil &amp; Enid, also Ollie, were disappointed, not in Alice, but in the fact that it was a ridiculously inadequate appearance for her. To see her dance any other time is better, they tell me</p>
over
-2-
<p>She simply wasn't displayed is what I gather. Al is industrious as the usualy thing. She's going to go places with all that determination, I am sure. She &amp; Hil are both lovely girls.</p>
<p>Max will explain to you what I've written as I my stability in this job I have. Like <underline>all</underline> other jobs it is no certainty of permanence, but I can say from all indications to date that I shall most likely become reasonably sure of staying on steady duty. I am working harder than I've ever worked in my life, physically &amp; mentally, <underline>but</underline> I am in fine health apparently.</p>
(inside)
-3-
<p>For God sake do not take, it amiss when I don't write to you or to Dad! You simply would not believe it if I were to tell you truthfully of how I come home late at <sic>nite</sic> <underline>staggering</underline> with fatigue. Ask Enid, she'll tell you it is true. Then the following morning I go in to Hil's ap't, try to write letters, &amp; other times I am forced to attend Co. sales meetings at downtown hotels, tehn be back on teh job at noon 'til 10:00 o'clock that <sic>nite</sic> again.</p>
-4-
<p>If I didn't work like a slave, on my toes every minute while on duty then I'd get canned. Big corporatiosn like this demand two-men's work out of each fellow, thereby increasing their profits. I've found out things that I do not like, <underline>but</underline> I shall continue applying myself in my very best ability. Then if it all flops - I'll not be at fault.</p>
<p>I am hopeful tho', of course.</p>
<p>Please write me again, for I <underline>do</underline> want your letters.</p>
Endless love,
Sig.
107b
S.Neihardt
9917 Emerson,
Overland, MO.
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 5
JUN14
12 -M
1940
BUY U.S. SAVINGS 
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER

<stamp>UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>

Mrs. John Neihardt,
Branson,
Missouri.