<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.5.22-31">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Caroline D. Berg, 1924</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.5.22-31</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Caroline D. Berg</title>
                    <date when="1924">1924</date>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Berg, Caroline D.</term>
                    <term>Day</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Ryskind, Mary House</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Morton, J. Sterling (Julius Sterling), 1832-1902</term>
                    <term>Twain, Mark, 1835-1910</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Pender (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Buffalo (N.Y.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Pender Times</term>
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
                    <term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Berg, Caroline D.</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5074969">Pender (Neb.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1924"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">22</note>
                <note type="curatorial">
                    3 Berg Collection
                    [Spring 1924]
                </note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mrs. Berg:-</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>The Pender Republic came as usual today and it made me think of you just because it is from your
                town. The urge to write to you grows upon me and here I am as you see.</p>
                <p>I think I must tell you why I am a patron of your paper, It might be of interest to you. Some 10
                years ago I was selling the Spirits corset.</p> 
                <p>Pender being one of "my towns" I put an ad in the Pender Republic and they sent me a copy showing
                that they had been faitful to the order. Well they kept sending the paper, I wrote them I did not
                want it but they kept right on never missing a week except when we moved to Branson. There was one
                week I did not revieve it.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">23</note>
                
                <p>When we left Bancroft I thot now they will discontinue, but not so, they sent it right on, there has
                been nothing financially for them I have never paid a cent. They have never set me a bill. Would you
                believe me when I tell you that now the paper is the first I open. In it, when ever John is in that
                part of the country is always a very sensible write up of him. When he was in Pender they gave him
                valuable space. So I always look for that paper. Many of the names are familiar. I am able in a way
                to keep up with you and Mrs. Day &amp; others And since out correspondence I look for your name always.</p>
                <p>I hope this narrative will not be tiresome, but you have proven your self a good sport hebce my
                perpetration.</p>
                <p>How I wish you could be here today</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">24</note>
                <note type="authorial">2</note>
                
                <p>the day is a perfect one. The sky is so blue and the grass and trees so green and the birds are
                singing as tho they had been Divinely authorized. Oh sweet masses of roses, this is a rose country
                what ever else it may be. I have been in my hourse three years. The first year there was practically
                nothing growing, in fact great heaps of rocks on every side of me, cullings from the rock the Masons
                used for my house. Besides piles that were made blasting for the cistern and for holes to plant my
                trees oh dear it is yet an awful night mare. Well I started out to tell you about my roses. I
                planted all the fall of the first year here really I planted almost all winter, and as a result I
                have roses every where on the <unclear/> John and me is a fence literally covered</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">25</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> climbing toses besides bushes planted three feet out making almost a solid bank. On the
                East I have wid roses on the same kind of a fence as on the west. They have not bloomed yet but
                soon will be a profusion of wild roses. In fron of them I have monthly roses that are just cuttings
                two years old and they are loaded too, against the house on the East there are more. Roses a big
                bush at each window three of them, and filled in between with Christian themes and this ^is a great
                country for them too, I have had beautiful ones and they look promising for this year. But the
                prittiest ^thing is the Dorithy Perkins on a lattice on either side of my porch against the house
                and our hanging the big window. They grow riotously, are climbing along</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">26</note>
                <note type="authorial">3</note>
                
                <p>the roof of my house and when they bloom I shall be tempted to just stay out and enjoy them. Oh Mrs.
                Berg; what a poet nature is. I wonder why every one doesn't see it and enjoy it. Have you ever
                enjoyed the early mornings just after the break of day and before the Sun has hardly made pink
                enough, where it will rise, to make on think it is the Sun, the mocking birds after a long night of
                mimicry growing sudden by quick the grease taking up its note? and oh I might go on and on with all
                the different waking things have you ever had that experience? That lovely softness over every
                thing. Makes me full that I am very close to God indeed I wonder if I am not a part of God, and many
                times I am filled with "God and I dreamed the vast dream together."</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">27</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> I am just rambling on and not getting the things you might like to hear about told. First
                we are all <unclear/> or much better. My trouble was hemmeroids for which I had quite a serious
                operation and it is only now that I am really getting well altho I have been home sinde the middle
                of Feb. Mona has her house cleaning nearly all done. <unclear/> is yet most of it to do as I did not
                want to do painting while Mary is here and <unclear/> closes this week. The children are having such
                loads of fun this after noon. Our donkey strayed in to us from the country and Sigurd took him in
                cleaned him up and made a bridle for him and this afternoon Hilda and Alice 3 are riding all over
                the pasture bare backed it is fun to see them so happy over that ugly ani-mal. Sigurd has a
                sweetheart he very seriously informed us and which</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">28</note>
                <note type="authorial">4</note>
                
                <p>we all take in good part. She is a very nice little thing. She is studying music too and and is very
                ambitious a year older than Sigurd but he says that does not make any difference to him. She tells
                Sigurd she will have nothing to do with a boy who swears or keeps bad company. So we are just
                winking at each other while we note the change in her "Beau formal". Now maybe I have not spilled
                that right these children are a problem each different with different tastes and temperaments all
                bright as tucks and wide awake. Sigurd is making wonderful strides in his music practices so well,
                Enid takes violin with her mother, they play simple things together. Surprisingly well, Hilda is at
                the head of her class all of them a year older than she. Her teacher says she is a joy in school
                Alice the last and sweetest and best and that is saying more</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">29</note>
                
                <p>than you know, because nothing but superlative was ever used by Gransma about the other three. Still
                she says she thinks she will marry Grandma, none of the rest ever loved me that much.
                She is a little picture, I'll tell you! <unclear/> my extravagance; I'll have daddy take a
                <unclear/> of them and sewed you one.</p> 
                <p>John will finish the Indian Wars in a few weeks and oh how glad we will be. He goes to Nebraska in
                July and when he comes home I hope he will be free from any obsession for a little while I'm no end
                grateful for your interest in and good wishes for us all. It is mightly sweet of you and we all send
                thanks to you, hoping for a real acquaintance sometime in the near future. My best wishes to you and
                Dr. Berg. Oh I almost forgot to mention the note of appreciation from Mr. Wilton. Tis sadly but away
                with the rest of the things that may be of value after we are all parsed away thanks for your good
                letter and may I please have an other one?</p> <closer><signed>Alice M. Neihardt.</signed></closer>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">30</note>
                
                <postscript><p>P.S. John just tells me that the University has Neihardt day at Morton Park Sterling J Morton's old
                home July the 11th and I wonder if you have seen or purchased the combination of "Hugh Glass" and
                Three Friends pub. in the modern reader's series? If not I should ike to give you an <unclear/> copy
                of one. -</p>
                <p>The only good you will see in this letter is that I have written enough to last quite a while. 
                I want to tell you too that Mona is getting readt to do some <unclear/>, I think , of my baby Alice.
                and that I have a daughter who graduates from the Grosvener Librg man school ^Buffalo N.Y. the 10th
                of June. How I would like to be there she has a good position in the Pub Library of Buff</p></postscript>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.5.22-31"/>
                <note type="curatorial">31</note>
                
                <postscript><p>and I'm powerfully happy about it Dear Mrs. Berg I'm so glad you appreciated the letter and thank
                you for its safe return sometime it will add much to a volume of Neihardt's letters. I hve recently
                read the letters of Mark Twain and also the letters of Swurburn and Some time ago a volume of
                Whitter's letters I find nothing so wonderful as the one I sent you. Yes I am paid over and over
                again, I wish I might have heard your talk on Neihardt I am sure it was sane and just sometimes even
                tho all that has been said is true but does not ring tru like the real admirer, you know what I mean
                just getting into the "band wagon" Thank you so much for your loyalty.</p>
                <p>Now I'm going to seal this up right for fear I mat think of some thing else to say. Every lady sends
                best wishes to you and yours. Most sincerely,</p>
                <p>Alice M. Neihardt</p></postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>