<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Thompson Collection 46
[Aug 20, 1939]
Sunday
Bison So. Dak.

Darling Alice:
<p>Your dear letter made me so happy. I feel sure we will be home the end of August, so that we can get you off to the Bus. As for your clothes, please look them over and have a definite idea as to what you need right away. The rest should wait.</p>
<p>Yesterday was one of the loveliest experiences of our life. To see such big results of Daddy's work after 30 years since he first talked over his plan to write the Epic Cycle with me, is a great Dream come true.- It seems but yesterday that Daddy first told me they story of Hugh Glass, and my saying: "Oh John <underline>you must</underline> make that man <underline>live</underline> you <underline>must</underline> write about him! That was before he had even thought of the Cycle!</p>
<p>Now Hugh Glass is the mythical God-Man of this country. The Parade started with an impersonation of Hugh Glass well in the lead and it is a matter of much discussion hereabouts, where or not Hugh really crawled that great crawl!----</p>
<p>At a little after 5 o'clock when we woke up, a mighty Prairie wind had swept the town clean and a hard cold rain fell, making us glad because again Daddy's Prayer had been answered - The first rain anyone ever remembered to have fallen in August hereabouts! It rained so hard that</p>
47
<p>we began to fear the day would be spoiled, and most of the Town was upset, for every Man and woman had worked hard for this great event _ They had needed rain for months, and now rain came on the <underline>one</underline> day when it would ruin their business! But at about 9 o'clock the rain stopped - as much as a miracle so had been its appearance almost - The thirsty ground sucked up all the moisture, and the day remained clear and dry, but with an umbrella over the Sun, making it absolutely perfect for the celebration! There was no dust, and the usual white glare was subdued!</p>
<p>Cars, cars, cars arrived from long and short distances and the town was full to overflowing. The Parade was truly wonderful showing all stages of Prayers that had been mage in So. Dak. The Old Stage Coach had been brought clear from Spearfish - There was the covered wagon and the team of Oxen, then old engines, old cars, and then new ones and an airplane - Lots of Floats and things you should see, but I cannot describe in an interesting way - Then the dedication of the School house in which Daddy gave a fine talk - you Know <underline>his Kind</underline> - and then after telling a lot of the historic facts of this country he finished with a marvelous Indian Prayer. It was grand - Then the monument was unveiled _ and </p>
48
<p>and after that there was the banquet. The Old timers told tales, all the violins and guitars etc made music - and Daddy read two lyrics._ I sat beside the man who had been longest in this country - he came here in 1890 - when it was all open Prairie - and a saddle horse was all one needed!</p>
<p>There was a horse race which we missed in the afternoon - I forgot to tell you about the class band that came from a North Dakota town looking simply swell - consisting of girls and young men and having a little girl to lead them, who was most attractive - but needed some more training of the sort you could have given her Alice, but she was cute and clever. Miss Virginia Fitch<crossed>Hickey</crossed>, age 15.<p/> 
<p><underline>Later</underline> Everyone has been so good to us. Since starting this letter I have more to tell, for yesterday, Unday Mr &amp; Mrs Jackson and Mr &amp; Mrs Bierman, and old Mr <unclear>Jennewein</unclear> (He is the man who impersonated Hugh Glass) and his daughter, all took us through miles and miles of Prairie to show us a few of its wonders.</p>
<p>We, luckily did not have to take our car. We went over the most dreadful roads you could think of saw a hug heap of Buffalo bones beside the Grand River, where herds of there great animals must have stompeded and fallen to meet their death. It is believed they probably were forced by a prairie</p>
49
<p>fire to sun, and arriving at the world's end, jumped over - and there are the remains for us to wonder about! Then we drove to Daddy's Hugh Glass monument which he built as an altar to "<unclear>Rowrage</unclear>" rather than to Hugh. It is very simple and grand, on a point over looking a most beautiful Prairie scene, with the Spring where Hugh Glass awoke to find himself deserted. A big portion of the Grand River and a few ranches are a part of the view. It is most beautiful. Then we went more miles and yet more across the open Prairie and over terrible reads to an excavated Redwood tree, which has been unearthed 75 feet long and then it goes on into the hil for maybe 75 more feet. It is the <underline>biggest</underline> Known petrified tree.__ We had a swell Picnic too, and by the time we returned to Bison the Stars were brilliant - and the end of a perfect day had come.</p>
<p>This is early Monday morning Daddy is shaving and I am thinking of you dearest ones at Home - Soon we will be on our way to Sturgis, and so I'll say goodbye till I write again.</p>
<p>Loving our wee babies and Sigurd and Maxie bushels and bushels, and a heart full of love to my own Baby</p>
I am always 
your devoted
Mama.