<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
108
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Lock Haven
June 25th 40
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>The wonderful formal outfit simply stuns your old Mother! How is it possible that you, Ollie dear, should have wanted Enid to make me such an exquisite gift? And how could you, Enid girlie, have done such a lovely job? You may be sure Daddy will buy me the evening gloves you speak of, and I already have black potent leather sandals - so I will be dressed beautifully from my skin out! You are a wizard with your fingers Enid, and Ollies and your own heart cannot be beat</p>
109
2
<p>en in this or any other world! I am thrilled and will treasure this gift until I am able to wear it and never cut it down, because it is altogether too adorable. I have the rose <sic>quatz</sic> necklack along too, which you suggested I should wear with it. How altogether perfect!! To misquote Daddy:"Your love clings beautiful about me" Bless your dear hearts - adn many many thanks to both you darling children.--</p>
<p>I have just cleaned up in our little cabin. Daddy is in his private study, the car, writing. We had a wonderful breakfast and I have teh dishes washed and dinner planned: asparagus, tomatoes, new potatoes adn strawberries! - and now have time to write you adn Maxie this morning.</p>
<p>We are in a quiet retreat till Wednesday afternoon, getting well rested from the trip. The affair here is in the morning. So I shall wear my white suit. I have a shiny balck hat and the sandals I mentioned already - and the lovely bag you</p>
110
3
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>made me a year or so ago. So I feel I will be properly dressed. We may be invited somewhere for eveing, but I doubt it. We will be at a good Hotel here for one night before the affair, because Daddy feels he should be able to telephone from a good address, which is of course the proper thing to do when you are being paid $100.00 for a convocation <strike>address</strike> talk. This will be Thursday AM - after which we go to Shippensburg, Pa. for a similar affair. We will spend about a week in some quiet place, where Daddy can write and where we hope to get a weekly rate. So far we</p>
111
4
<p>have had to pay $1,50 per night._ Speaking of expense brings me to your question Enid as to what I had in mind when I asked if you were still of the same opinion about your present Home. I was just asking for information. People many times are enthusiastic about a place and then have a different view after spending the year around in it. I thought from your letters last winter that you were rather disgusted at having to buy so much coal and I wondered if Ollie, you, might be thinking the house was partly to blame?-- </p>
<p>Besides this old Mother of yours has been getting more and more communistic I suppose! <underline>I think</underline> (please believe me when I say that this has not been discussed much here) it is too bad for you children to spend $35.00 per month, Hilda and Alice $35.00 and Sigurd about to spend at least $20.00 to</p>
112
5
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>$30.00 for a roof over your heads, when you might all go in with Daddy and me this Fall if we sell our place in Branson. If this should come to pass, could we not buy a wonderful old Home with sufficient grounds about it for those of us who want to farm and garden a bit to be able to do so for the common good? Daddy would buy the place with the idea that you children should pay him say $20.00 per month, making $60.00 between the three job holders. That would be less than you would pay any other place,</p>
113
6
<p>and you <strike>were to have</strike> should have your own apartments, Sig and Max <underline>their</underline> own, and the girls and Daddy and I, <underline>our</underline> own private apartment in this one common Home. Then if you did not like it, you could give us notice and we could rent to some one else. This property, the Neihardt Home, would be your property some day to be divided into <underline>4 equal</underline> parts, when both Daddy and I are gone.</p>
<p>You see I am thinking on paper, and trying to make our common dream come true, and it is all for you to consider and turn down if it does not appeal to you both as being in your in</p>
114
7
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>terest as well as in ours. I do love to express what is in my mind and heart - and do not want to influence you against you own good judgement. We can talk all this over when we see you soon.</p>
<p>Of all the country I have seen, this Pa. is by far the most beautiful, I love the <sic>Alegheny</sic> mountains. They are bigger than the Ozarks! and are <underline>so</underline> fertile and not so rocky. The people too are not so queer. They take you for granted and do not eye you <sic>ascance</sic></p>
115
8
<p>as the mid-Western folk do, or the hillbilly people. In other words I feel at home in the East. We are in Centre Conuty where Daddy's grandfather was born, and we are having fun looking up relatives! When I took my suit to the cleaner's here the young woman said, "There is a d in <underline>your</underline> name" so I said: "why, is there none in <underline>yours</underline>?! She said I meant to say There are a lot of Neiharts here, but they leave out the d before the t at the end!" We passed a Barber by the name <underline>Neigh</underline>thart at Belle Fonte. Daddy went in and the old woman said "We have a family Bible and the name in it is speleed with a "gh" in it. So Daddy asked her to show it to him,</p>
116
9
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>which she did, finding to her surprise that the name was <underline>not</underline> spelled with a gh but simply Nei - was that not funny? This man's name is <underline>John L.</underline> and could easily be a cousin of Daddy's father.</p>
<p>We both love this country. We are right beside the Susquehanna river - There is a long quiet green lawn beside our cabin where no one cames or can see - so we have a very private and lovely place to be. The great, wooded mountains rise up on our So. whiel the river flows on the No. of us. The locusts are making</p>
117
10
<p>their queer, deep, whining sort of sounds and we can hear the passing cars on High way 120 but nothing bothers us.</p>
<p>Daddy just came in to read the lines he has written on this trip - and I'm you they are great and wonderful indeed - so convincing, so simple! God <underline>what</underline> a Poet he <underline>is</underline> - and a Life's work you will be coping one of these days Enid darling!</p>
<p>I'll get dinner started now - and then write my other letter.</p>
<p>Oceans of love to you two, and to my one and only <strike/> dear Sigurd.</p>
from your grateful and devoted
Mother - Mama.
194 Fink Collection 118
June 25, 1940
BRANSON.
OCT22
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs O. F Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo. St. Louis County