<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.2.36-40">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, November 18, 1921</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.2.36-40</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1921-11-18">November 18, 1921</date>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Sterling, George, 1869-1926</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler </term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>San Fransisco (Calif.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5391959">San Fransisco (Calif.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1921-11-18"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.36-40"/>
                <note type="curatorial">36</note>
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Friday, Nov 18th 21
                        Branson Mo.
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>My own and only, dear, beautiful precious Husband!</salute>
                    
                </opener>
                
                <p>Oh! how you are winning out, and I with you! It comes over me with such
                    the members certainly that I want to cry it out gracefully, joy only to all the world-until I remember that the silly world does not count, and then I want to say it to you, just so you, darling, we are all very well and happy, and a number of things have occured since your hearing that I mgith tell you often but they all seem so unimportant compared with the things you are now doing, the thoughts you are thinking</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.36-40"/>
                <note type="curatorial">37</note>
                
                <p>-that when I sit down to tell you how much I love you and the things that really count, I simply forget everything else! So I don't doubt my letters are not conveying much news to you! - I hope you are having a lovely time with G. S. and that you are not admiring sooner my of his girls, no, not any one of them!!!</p>
                <p>Before I forget darling, be sure to write mo-ther a letter addressed "dear mama"
                    so alas, she feels it is for her. She has been so upset because you have not done that! We have not had a bit of trouble; we are both so anxious to do right, that we are both so anxious so do rights, that we are having newfully careful! So don't get anything out of these lines but just exactly what I am saying, will you, dear?</p> 
                <p>Sigurd came home from</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.36-40"/>
                <note type="curatorial">38</note>
                
                <p>school crying and utterly miserable! He said, "Oh how I wish my mama did not
                    rhyme so easy! They all call me "Pig" and I just can't stand it! Poor is she
                    man! I told him I understood and that you would too, he will just have to learn to get along with the roughnecks himself-he could not expect mama to stand up for him-because that would not help him in the long run! He</p> 
                <p>must be the lesser fighter and meet the boys on that plane! I am so glad I am not young any more! What a beastly world it is for most of us, and how lucky we are when we are married properly!</p>
                <p>We are all planning to go to the the play at the Church tomorrow night-Alice, Hilda, Grandma and I. Sigurd will en-joy his trip somewhat: it is so thrilling</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.36-40"/>
                <note type="curatorial">39</note>
                
                <p>to be dressed up and blacked! Enid is delighted with the dress and cap I made for
                    the occasion; and Hilda has a new pink dress to wear that I just finished so she
                    feels "in it" too. Mother has been sailoring a beautiful little boat for Enid. Alice will go on a pillow with her little sky blue comforter over her-and will doubtless have a good sleep on my lap!</p> 
                <p>Yes dear, everything is quiet and beautiful, inside and out here - and all thanks to you dearest one! I know you will take care of yourself and I know that I cannot lose you, because you are really mine, not just because we are married, but because I believe in you and can do my part to supplement you. Yesterday I made a manger for Mrs. Bessie-and she told me it was the Jersey man and not the White Face!</p> <closer><salute>worlds of Love from your</salute> <signed>Mona.</signed></closer>
            </div1>
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.36-40"/>
                <note type="curatorial">36</note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    BRANSON 
                    NOV
                    19
                    AM
                    1921
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    Dr. J. G. Neihardt
                    of. Geo. Sterling 
                    The Bohemian Club.
                    San Francisco. 
                    Cal.
                </ab> 
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>