<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.6.34-39">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, August 20, 1925</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.6.34-39</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1925-08-20">August 20, 1925</date>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>6 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>House, Julius T. (Julius Temple)</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Lewis</term>
                    <term>Buffington, Effie</term>
                    <term>Greg</term>
                    <term>Chas</term>
                    <term>Charlie</term>
                    <term>House, Flora M.</term>
                    <term>Mason</term>
                    <term>Conn, Ulysses Sylvester</term>
                    <term>Weeks</term>
                    <term>Perryman</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Omaha (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Arcadia (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5081454">Wayne (Neb.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1925-08-20"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">34</note>
                <note type="curatorial">
                    18 McDonald Collection.
                    
                    [August 20, 1925]
                </note>
                
                <fw type="authorial">
                    STATE NORMAL SCHOOL AND TEACHERS COLLEGE
                    U.S. CONN, PRESIDENT
                    WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
                    DEPARTMENT OF ENGLISH AND SOCIOLOGY
                    DIRECTOR OF IN ABBENTIA
                    JULIUS T. HOUSE
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <salute>My Dear Ones:-</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>This is the morning after but I have no dark brown taste - It was a wonderful day my day boy but because of you - the ceremonies were all that could be desired several people and among them^the governor-said to me it is the most sincere thing I ever witnessed and the monument is just right beautiful in its ruggedness as was expressed typical of the man" oh I never was so full of happiness I did not know that one person could contain so <del>much</del> happiness. Dr House was everywhere and a regular dynamo, oh how I wish I could be home with you this</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">35</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> there are so many things to tell you - the Judge came for me at the
                    Hotel yesterday <unclear/> (Wednesday) in a pouring rain, we had breakfast and
                    got into the waiting cab and were soon on our way to Wayne the clouds lifted and
                    by the time we arrived the sun was shining as tho there never had been a cloud -
                    Prof Lewis met us- The Judge was taken to Dr. House and I stopped at Crossland's to have dinner with Martha &amp; Chas and Mrs. Greg and Effie Buffington, they had noticed from Lincoln the day before to be present at the unveiling, dinner over Charlie took us all over to the park where there had alread been parked, cars on two sides of the park and Every body in <unclear/> out I was besieged from Every side</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">36</note>
                
                <fw type="authorial">
                    STATE NORMAL SCHOOL AND TEACHERS COLLEGE
                    U.S. CONN, PRESIDENT
                    WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
                    DEPARTMENT OF ENGLISH AND SOCIOLOGY
                    DIRECTOR OF IN ABBENTIA
                    JULIUS T. HOUSE
                </fw>
                <note type="authorial">2</note>
                
                <p>I did not realize that I knew so many people, Mrs. Berg was there and I have promised to give her a day on my way home Miss Nell Porena and the <unclear/> girls were over from Bancroft - well the time came Dr has told you who took part and again I did the unveiling I think I will soon be authority on such things - really everything was so harm, <unclear/> and so many happy faces all around me - Dr said now when you have unveiled the monument then you may say what you want to - well what I had planned to say all left me but I am sure what I did say was much better; and when it was all over</p> 
                <p>My bob is taken all right - lots of compliments for it</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">37</note>
                
                <p>was just swamped with hand shakings and congratulations. I sat down beside the Judge and he patted me on the shoulder and said bully Dr. Said I had a notion to hug you - It was half past five when Mr. Lewis took Mrs. House and me I to the Boyd hotel to a Banquet for all the Speakers and myself included I was seated at the head of the table Pres. Conf at my left and the Governor at ^my right - I told him and the chancellor what your message was to them and I have tried to make Dr House and the judge feel how grateful we are, really John you can never never have a more loyal friend than Dr House and never again will I doubt him and I hope you will not ever. either, after the banquet the judge and I were taken to Dr House's</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">38</note>
                
                <fw type="authorial">
                    STATE NORMAL SCHOOL AND TEACHERS COLLEGE
                    U.S. CONN, PRESIDENT
                    WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
                    DEPARTMENT OF ENGLISH AND SOCIOLOGY
                    DIRECTOR OF IN ABBENTIA
                    JULIUS T. HOUSE
                </fw>
                <note type="authorial">3</note>
                
                <p>we all had a wonderful visit on the front porch and at 9:30 we all went to bed - This morning is beautiful we have had breakfast the Judge is headed for Omaha the Dr. gone to school - chas is coming to take me and my baggage to Mason's and I will do all my visiting from there Mrs. House is pucking and <unclear/> back tomorrow morning to pack Mrs. Houses' dishes they leave here Monday next, I think i will stay here a short time at least so many have insisted that I visit them, tonight go with the Houses to Pres. Com's for dinner today noon to Jack cherries for lunch with chas and</p> 
                <p>Mrs. House has been perfectly lovely-</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.34-39"/>
                <note type="curatorial">39</note>
                
                <p>artha-that is as far ahead as I know I now. Oh boy the speeches were all as lovely I just wish I could tell them all to you Mrs. Weeks made a wonderful speech Mrs. Perryman told them have she knows you are a brave man and related the drive to Arcadia the crowd cheered long. Next best times the News paper man from Lincoln, I have just ratted on dear people but it is really <unclear/> to torn the heads of some people lent it only makes me very happy to know that all same thru you - Jones of the University was very good I had a nice <unclear/> with him and he is looking forward to meeting you love to all the children to my baby and to you to Mona</p>
                <closer><signed>Mama</signed></closer> 
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>