<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
79a
9716 Hawthorne 
Overland
Mo. 
Mon. A. M. 
Dearest Mom, Dad as well as Sister, Brother & Precious Nieces:
Even though it might have been a little crowded around here, I want to write now and tell you in writing, which is more lasting htan just mere words, that I love all of you more than you can know and that I miss you all tremendously. It has all been sort of like a dream. It was all so sudden and so fleeting a visit it seems. I'm sure Ol feels the same way. We looked forward to your coming and both hated to see you go just as much as we like dot see you come. You must consider when thinking of us that we have become rather old-maidish, being alone so much. So if we did anything to offend any of you it was not meant at all in the way it might have seemed. I think it wouldn't take long before it would be perfectly natural for us to ahve you all right here iwth us: You know how that is. I believe Hilda and Alice are very very lonesome too now, and we'll all have to get together right away and talk about all of you and hope that it won't be long before we're together again. Mom, that one day we had together menat more to me than you'll ever realize, for I have been, even tho' I am not very demonstrative, so very very lonely for you and am right this minute. I feel that you should be here with Ol and me for a spell soon. Don't you think it could be arranged? It would be good for you too to take it easy for a few days. We love to have Sig and Max and the kids just any time they can come. I'm sure they know that. Dad knows without 

79b
-2-
my saying anything that we want him to come any time and that we both get a great deal out of having him to talk to. If you want my opinion, I say that I wish I had a couple of kids as dear and lovely as Sig and Max have. It is, in a way, what makes life worth living. Of course there's another side too, but the greater side is the young side, for they are the emblem of life. I hope we'll have one anyway. Nuff said on this. 
Max, I found your skirt, lipstick and white pencil here. I found one of Dad's armlets. Mom, I'm so sorry, but I forgot to see tha tyou got the goose grease, crab apples and that loaf of bread. No doubt it's too late to send the bread, so Ol and I will enjoy it! But I'll send the things all to you today. The kids' kaleidescope and little wagon are here, and I'll bring them down when we come. I wish we would be able to come down sooner than Xmas. I'll see what Ol thinks about it. 
I'm going to get at my clothes right away, Mom, and perhaps I'll even have a skirt made when I come down! 
Oh, yes, there's a blanket here of yours too, Mom, and we'll see that that comes down when we come as well. Is that all right, or do you need is sooner? 
There's no news now of course, but I did want to write you, as I'm feeling dreadfully lonely for all of you. 
Give Joanie & Elaine big kisses for Unka Oddie & Aunt Neenie, won't you? All of my love to you, Mom, and to you,Dad, and big kisses to Sig & Max. We'll be seeing you, probably sooner than we think, as I'm anxious to be with you more. 
Always, 
Enid 
Enot
Neenie 
P.S. This probably sounds; but it's not!! 
Dad, I cancelled your dental appointment, told the Dr. you'd be back in Feb., as you weren't well now.

79c
Fink 
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI 
SAINT LOUIS, MO 4 1938 NOV28 730PM
Dr. & Mrs. John G. Neihardt 
Branson 
Missouri 
Taney Co. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
SILVER JUBILEE PARCEL ANYWHERE TO 