<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
65 Neihardt Collection 34
August 16, 1939

Buffalo, S.D. Wed. A.M.
Aug. 16, '39
Dear Ones:
<p>We came up here yesterday, 100 miles due north of the Black Hills. Saw Everetts a few minutes at Sturgis, and arranged to stop with them on the way back. Mama will then get an eyeful of the mountains.</p>
<p>Yesterday in blazing white daylight, no-cloud in sight, we crossed the vast flat land over which Crook retreated to Deadwood form the Battle of Slim Buttes, with Crazy Horse snapping at his heels.</p>
<p>There was nowhere any sign that man had ever been on the planet. Most places the ground was nearly bare. Mama got the feel of vastness, sure enough. And the queer buttes, like something belonging to the moon!</p>
-2-
<p>The night before, at our camp 20 miles east of Rapid City, I "went out into the pasture" at night, and did what I do. When we left Sturgis for here, the day was a white glare, and remained so all the way, except for the following weird incident: We were <unclear>fowling</unclear> along the lonely dirt road, when we noticed <underline>filmy</underline> cloud <underline>forming</underline> west of us. It thickened as it approached us, seeming definitely to follow as we travelled at about 50 miles per hour. Then <underline>thin rain</underline> streaks appeared between it &amp; the earth, and sharp lightning flashed downward through <underline>clear</underline> sky. The cloud was small and we could see sunlight far around us as it came over</p>
35
-3-
<p>us. Then there was a violent burst of wind and for five or six minutes a darking rain. It's aim was perfect for we were apparently right in the middle of it. There were several calps of glorious thunder. It was over in a short while, &amp; thereafter there was the burning white day all afternoon. The night was perfectly clear and this morning is <unclear>flaming</unclear> white. This is the most striking experience of the sort I've ever had. Mama was it least as much impressed as I.</p>
<p>Yesterday we drove over to the Slim Buttes (27 miles) and <unclear>pesticated</unclear> around awhile. I walked over 2 miles down hill &amp; back up at a fast</p>
-4-
<p>gait, and didn't sweat - didn't even perspire! Didn't even get short-winded.</p>
<p>Seems queer. This was the hottest part of the day, from 4 to 5 P.M.</p>
<p>Golly, the dryness here, and the whiteness of the light!</p>
<p>This is a queer little place, in the middle of a virtual desert, far from a railroad. The people want to rise &amp; last night I sat on the sidewalk with some men, &amp; we gassed in the starlight.</p>
<p>No more now. I must make up my spill for the <unclear>dougs</unclear> Saturday.</p>
<p>(Incidentally, Everett told me the kids up here study my stuff in school. But I haven't told my name, &amp; will not.)</p>
(over)
<note>sentence below in margin of letter</note>
Endless love, Dad. (no mail at Sturgis)
36
<p>I checked our gas mileage at Rapid City. Our average was 20.4 miles to the gallon. I hadn't been travelling at 45 m.p.h. either, as you'd probably guess!</p>
<p>This place is 1200 miles from Branson. Bison is 75 miles east. We monkeyed around Rapid, Sturgis, and Newell yesterday.</p>
Dad