<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20 Thompson Collection 35
Overland, Friday Noon, Feb 12.
[1943]
Precious Alice:
<p>Your dear, very dear and brave letter, mailed on the 10th, are in a very tight place and Mama &amp; I have been troubled because we haven't been able to help. Who knows? Even the enclosed may help a little. O I do rejoice in your spirit and your courage! Alice, we do feel so deeply how fine you are, and we are absolutely sure of you and your future. It is fine that you can get the K.C. engagement there - and you will get other to tide you over. And <hi rend="underline"> this too</hi>, you will rejoice to remember. It is truly an adventure, and if you can just eat &amp; be sheltered, anything else is merely a lark. But <hi rend="underline"> how have</hi> you all kept going?</p>
<p>I rec'd a letter from Sen. Truman, saying the matter was being taken up with the State Dept. on <hi rend="underline"> Feb. 4th</hi>! Golly! That is already 8 days ago!</p>
<p place="margin">Affectionate thought for your comrades, including Grandma,</p>
36
-2-
<p>Can you still have the Mexico City engagement if George can get his re-entry permit? I judge that you can, and we do <hi rend="underline"> so</hi> want you to <hi rend="strike_through">do the</hi> get to Mexico City.</p>
<p>There seems to be <hi rend="underline"> some</hi> chance for me on The Chicago Daily News. The head man wrote me, saying he had long known me by reputation &amp; would look things over to see if he could place me - that he'd write again. But -</p>
<p>Something is going to work out most certainly. We <hi rend="underline"> are</hi> being tried, precious Girl!</p>
<p>Amama is leaving about now, &amp; Mama has not come back yet. How she <hi rend="underline"> will</hi> eat your letter.</p>
<p>It is great to be brave <hi rend="underline"> and</hi> sweet as you are, Alice. It is truly great.</p>
Endless love
Dad
<p>Yes, I remember so much too. <hi rend="underline"> Wonderful</hi>!</p>
<p palce="margin"> I'm getting over the trouble, &amp; am <hi rend="underline"> so</hi> glad.</p>







