<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
157 Fink Collection 171
Neihardt
Branson,
<underline>MO.</underline>
BRANSON
DEC21
3 -PM
1939
M.O.
Mr. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
172
This Afternoon, Missouri.
Dear Ollie:
<p>That was a lovely letter, and I do adore Christmas sentiment. How happy our dear Jesus must be with so much adoration! However, I'll bet he didn't but a return ticket.</p>
<p>I was just about to write you - had in fact written the address and date above - when yours &amp; Enat's letter arrived. I was getting ready to say simply that I sincerely appreciate your having Alice there; that I know such kindness &amp; keep are not to be paid for; and that you will let Alice pay enough per week or month to compensate at least for the extra expense. <underline>That</underline> is <underline>not</underline> in any way paying you for having her; it is only holding your actual budget to where it was before. Please say yes &amp; be accurate in telling me what that is.</p>
<p>Mama came back here, saw what Mrs. <unclear>Martmsen</unclear> had been up to, adn kicked the fat-assed serpent out forever. It was utterly <unclear>magnolient</unclear>, inquestionable just, and should have happened</p>
<note>sentences below are in the margin of letter</note>
<p>Alice was the casus belli. "Divide &amp; rule" was fundamental in the viper's strategy; but there was a <underline>solid front here</underline> after the hellion was <underline>scotched</underline>.</p>
173
-2-
<p>thirty years ago. "Better late than never", as Mahomet remarked to George Washingtopn while crossing the Rubicon at Fifth Avenue and Lindell on the first voyage to America in 1610 just after the Treaty of Westphalia, if you remember. Hiddy may show you Mama's account of the war, with my commentary. You like history, I know.</p>
<p>Incidentally <underline>I had been good as pie</underline> (damned hypocrite by intention!) But I'm still a bit out of my head. Mama is as cold about it all as a block of ice. The <underline>person</underline> (?) was not in the least wounded - just triumphantly delighted. <underline>This is just so</underline>. The departure eventuated, not to say happened, took place and decidedly came to pass, on Monday morning. By God, it even transpired, if you want further assurance. What I mean, the poisonous fat ass vamossed, and won't be back until Jesus returns in His glory, which is <underline>some</underline> time, if I know my homo <underline>sap</underline> rightly.</p>
<p>Incidentally, I wish to God I were a better laugher.</p>
174
-3-
<underline>Second Spastic Attack</underline>
<p>Your second letter with check just arrived. You're a heluva good <unclear/>, and wider other circumstances. I'd actually accept that five by way of giving you happiness. But, really, our plans are so different now, and all are agreed - including Hiddy who phoned this morning - that there's no point to our going to St. Louis or the girls coming home. We see each other quite often, and Chirstmas has no meaning whatever for any of us. So that's out. Mama &amp; I may spend six weeks in Albuquerque. We're not addition to the stimulating change, good for work, we could do some careful research in the matters of a new home there, with you &amp; Enat in mind too. The kids here think we should go and are eager that we should. We'd be back Feb 18th, &amp; we'd pass your way shortly after that. You'll hear further about this within a day or so.</p>
<p>Love to old Enat Peanut (naughty girl!) and to poor Old Lady Alice. (Can she sit up &amp; take a bite or two of solid food?) And love to you.</p>
Dad