<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
1 envelope 10 or German <unclear/> 
6a
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
Jan 12 24
Dear Mama: 
I dreamed about you last night & awoke fearing you. Might be rich. Don't get sick, please, - not till I get home anyway. Take the best of care of yourself. What a cold time you must be having. 10 below! Good heavens! It's may here night & day - wonderful. 
I have been at Bruminstool's home most of two days meeting old Indian fighters - one of them fought on the Little Big Horn. Five old men! One was Colonel Wheeler who owned the pony Crazy Horse rode in the Custer Fight. I know just how that pony looked! 

6b
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-3- 
This is a monster tour now - such growth! Over a million here & it's still growing like a boom town. One can ride twenty miles or more in the city & not twice! The trines took me for a drive through Topango Canyon & down along the sea night before last. Took bunch along & couldn't find a place to eat it, so brought it back & ate it. in their room! This evening I have to be with the Bookfellows here - Los Angeles branch. Don't want to go at all, but got roped in like a simpleton. Have been dad <unclear/> social engagements with fair success. 

6c
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-3- 
Tomorrow I am to eat dinner at a home where Tully hangs out - a rich family of refuted intellectuals, dawn 'evr. One youngster of the family actually makes 700 a week so intellectual! I may find a way out. Why did I get roped in? Then I've got ot eat a dinner Monday evening Jan 14th. 
But I'm keeping in a pretty far state of mind this trip. It will be fine to be back in Branson with everybody I love close by. Mama, it's wonderful that we can all be together!! I got a tremendous lot of stuff from Bruminstool. He has everything about the Indian Wars & knows everybody who knows anything. He's 

6d
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-4- 
a dera man, & his wife is, I believe, a pretty genuine Christian. I sincerely like them when they're that. She says <del/> grace & you feel that she actually thinks God is eager to hear. Bully! I could almost say "Amen." 
no suit yet! What a note! Maybe it will reach me by Monday. i need it, but can well through as I am, and shall not worry. 
I understand that the Ebell Club is pretty well received. Of course it is the Club of a big town & feels important; but I am told that their brams don't give them a raging headache. All right! I'll read lyrics & the drama & go after them for effect, not for the purpose of communicating my 

6e
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-5-
big idea of the Cycle. Too bad. 
I'm not blue at all and certainly <del/> not homesick, tho' that's the only place I want to be every minute I'm awake. I love you and so do the others. You should see what the wubs write about you. Before I left home - ,del/ two or three days - Enid said to me when I was alone with her: "Isn't <del/> Grandma awfully nice when we aren't having trouble!" 
Mona says you an all happy together. 
Jno 

