<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 81
October 9, 1939
Jackson, Monday Noon

Precious Mona:
<p>It was bully to hear from you &amp; to receive all that mail today. It seemed too long between time. I'm delighted with what you've done upstairs. I'll bet it's beautiful. Won't it be perfectly bully if the Junior Chambers of Commerce has you do that job! I'd be tickled stiff, and I've a strong feeling it will work out. $200 is small enought, but it's money, and the satisfaction should be great. I'll help you cast, with a captial C! No doubt your old trouble was in your glasses. Couldn't be anything else. Sig &amp; I have talked about you teeth, &amp; it's good to know you'll have the bad ones out. I wonder if Macmillan could get you a good plate -? But maybe the fellow down south is better. You mustn't be <unclear>devilled</unclear> too long. If we can just get our noses, eyes &amp; teeth fixed up - not to mentioninterstines, guts &amp; gizzards - we'll be as good as new!</p>
<p>Yes, I read all of Hitlers speech - 1 1/2 pages of solid print in, a New Orleans paper. Very sane, I'm sure. But I can't help hoping that there will be no peace now. This society must go through the catastrophe before fundamental social reform will be possible. The U.S. will go in, and no doubt has long since secretly a greed to do so! Daladier spoke to the Deputies for a half hour about the U.S., and what he said was kept from the press. He knew, and I suspect he said openly what he knew. But this too</p>
82
<p>is a part of the pattern. The U.S. should go in, for by doing so the will hasten the necessary process. We here will be the last of the great nations to reform, which will doubtless mean some phase of Fascist organization here during, and perhaps for long after, the European catastrophe. Russia's games is in no way concerned with the success of a great German Empire- but solid with Communism, the overthrow of Capitalism. Of this now goes through with the present apparent line up Russia's plan will win in the <unclear/> that revolution will destroy capitalism in Western Europe.</p>
<p>It is surely significant that everywhere we've been - 1500 miles - everyone of high or low degree, from loafers at filling stations to progessors is <underline>definitely</underline> for going over and "stopping Hitler". So gaki, is right again. (Brag, brag!). I'll not dare give any answers at Know. Already the Truth is semi-offically outlawed.</p>
<p>There is <underline>no</underline> <unclear/> in the above. <underline>We</underline> personally need not be greatly hurt and I will even work with a Fascist regime if I can get the chance. I am no evenly of the inevitable.</p>
<p>Lovely weather here today - just heavenly. We are well and hope you are all sick! We do not. You aren't either. The very idea!</p>
Endless love, corpulent Old Lady!
Jno.