<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
198 Fink Collection 30
Enclosed with Dec 13 1940
[Dec. 14, 1940]
Saturday
Dearest Children:
<p>Your good letters made us happy today. As for Xmas - we are planning nothing - and will stay here quietly - grateful that our darling children are so fine, and that we have eachother and our work and our home. So many real blessings in a world like this one!</p>
<p>If Sigurd can do so he will come after Joan in time for Xmas and also get the Xmas things of which we have two sets. But if he cannot sensibly do so we will have a Xmas</p>
<p>tree etc for our Joanie down here. Please don't tell me Joan and Elaine are spoiled! They have been learning ugly boy ways at the St Louis Apt - which is too bad - but they will get over that and who can avoid rough necks and their disagreeable ways? Sooner or later we all <strike>do so</strike> meet them and learn to dislike instead of immitate them. Our babies certainly were not spoiled when they left home here a year ago - and now that we have Joanie with us we are impressed with her premature desire to do right - and her ability to do so - So please reconsider your hasty judgement, Enid, and</p>
32
<p>remember that you will have a lot to put up with, with your own babies before they will be as perfect as you now expect them to be. You see Nannie is not taking <underline>any</underline> criticism of Joan and Elaine - because criticising is far too easy - <underline>building</underline> is much harder. If you left <underline>your</underline> baby with me some day I'd not allow any body on Earth to criticise him or her. I'd appreciate helpful, constructive suggestions and love - more and more love - there never yet was <underline>too much</underline> of that in the raising of babies <underline>I</underline> say. Spoiling a child means</p>
33
<p>something very different. <underline>I</underline> don't think you children ever were spoiled. You respected what was worthy of respect and you had a very good idea of the entire range of human values. You had very little in the way of material things such as clothes, toys etc. - but you always had <underline>enough</underline>. So that is that.</p>
<p>I dreamed about you last night, and awoke with the feeling that you Enid might make unhappiness for yourself by worrying about whether you would have a baby or not. Please darling do not do so. First of all you have a dear good husband, and that in a world in which you could so easily have been out of luck with youe man! To worry over not having a baby is silly</p>
34
<p>in a world that is <underline>full</underline> of babies that no one cares for. You could so easily adopt a baby and have all the happiness of one of your own <underline>without</underline> having to go through the worry and maybe the danger of bringing one into the world. Believe me it is not <underline>necessarily</underline> a blessing for you and Ollie. It possible darling, accept whatever come gratefully - because you are already <underline>so</underline> lucky - See what I am trying to say, darling?</p>
<p>I need ink - so will stop here for today.</p>
<p>Will surely bring the mattress you asked for when we come - I</p>
35
<p>believe in February probably - also the motor etc etc -</p>
Love in endlessness
Mother.
Mom