<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
291 Fink Collection 161
Neihardt
Branson Mo
BRANSON
JUN27
13-PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs Enid Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
St Louis County Mo.
162
1
Friday
Darling Enid
<p>So long it seems since we last heard from you, yet I am quite sure <underline>I</underline> owe you a letter. There is no news but we are having really hot weather now. The hollyhocks have gone and poppies are gorgeous. Cannas and roses are blooming profusely as well as nasturtiums and zinnias and marigolds. What a beautiful thing is a Gardern.</p>
<p>You are getting eager to be relieved soon of your precious burden from the womb to the arms where you will love to carry it.</p>
<p>I never Knew of any</p>
163
2
<p>mother who could feel the babies arms moving - but you may be right. I my self can remember only the motion of the limbs in a general way. You do realize, don't you Darling, that I can come to you if you need me? From now until we go to California? We do so want everything to work out fo rthe best. Daddy does need to have that lecutre business work out. At the same time I do so want to be with you when you want or need me. I am eager to know how the baby room is progressing?</p>
<p>Daddy's work for your and for Ollie is simply marvelous. He has been having to wait for the materials for finishing.-</p>
162
3
<p>Hilda seems to be upset lately. I am so sorry!</p>
<p>We here all like Albert very much. Hilda has to make her own decisious - and she cannot blame me for anything she may do, for I have told her I shall love her more and more, no matter what she mad do - and I shall not "advise" her <underline>ever</underline>.</p>
<p>Enid w have taken the <underline>best of care</underline> of your Weigelias, but neither one came to life - In fact I believe they were dead when they sold them in St Louis. Don't worry about this, but I do want you to Know so you do</p>
163
4
<p>not buy more stuff from them.</p>
<p>Joanie sits up on the front room couch and crochets so earnestly - she is a darling!</p>
<p>Gaki takes them swimming and they love it now</p>
<p>I am making my self two dresses - one white percale with red dots after your housedress pattern - and the other sort of an invention! It is rose with white.</p>
<p>We baked and washed today. Max washed and I baked. Daddy is such good help with the house work!</p>
Loads of love to you all three
from
Mama Mother