<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
314 Fink Collection 88
After.....days, return to
<underline>Box 167</underline>
BRANSON, MISSOURI.
BRANSON
NOV23
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
89
Sunday A.M.
Dear Ones - Three, count 'Em!
<p>We had a happy time on Thanksgiving - a gang of us, all trying to live a month or two together in one day! We thought and talked of you, and drank some Santerne to you in concert, wishing you were present to make the day perfect. Nei, the old cuss, got into the conversation, and the three girls went on about how darling and beautiful he is! Hiddy said I ought to see him <underline>now</underline>.</p>
<p>The folks have the walnuts for Nei. He'll probably need a hammer to crack them, as they say he's not yet very well fixed for teeth. Why not yet him plates?</p>
<p>Enot, you can be certain that Mama really wants</p>
(over)
90
-2-
<p>to go up there &amp; see Him, but it just <underline>can't</underline> be done now. Max would have stayed this time, but that would have defeated necessary plans both here &amp; there. Be sure that there's only deep affection for you there in this house. We must not have any unhappy thoughts of each other. Life itself isn't worth that much. You're so fortunate, Enot!</p>
<p>I've just heard from a press -clipping bureau that they have 70 clippings on Jed; so I've sent for them and subscribed for more. Naturally, most of thse well be more or less perfunctary, but form what I hear indirectly, there'll be enough good ones. <underline>I</underline> wish I didn't <underline>need</underline> the clippings.</p>
<p>The University of Michigan has just asked me to judge their Hopwood Poetry</p>
91
-3-
<p>Contest this year. only, "five or six" manuscripts will be submitted, they say, and they'll pay me $75. I've judged a number of state &amp; national contests, as well as for institutions, but I never heard of paying judges! It seems a good idea, and I'm willing to run for president of something or other on that platform - providing Doctor Geo. katt is nominated for vice-president! I do hope Doc and Nei can meet &amp; get acquainted before too Cong. They'd have a lot in common, I know.</p>
<p>As you see, there's not much news.</p>
Love always!
Dad
<p>The Washington Post article was a whale!</p>