<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- page 2 has German, please proofread -->


67
Saturday afternoon
May 25, 1940
Dearest Mutti!
<p>On this gray afteroon I am thinking especially of you, for tomorrow will be your birthday - another milestone in your career of dearness and fineness. I want you to know I shall be thinking of you on this <unclear>your</unclear> very <unclear>own</unclear> day and wishing I might be with you, to give you in person my wishes for many, many more happy returns of the day. You are just simply very <underline>very</underline> favorite Mother!</p>
68
2
<p>the other day I received, to my great surprise, a letter from Betty. She had just then (April 8) recived the Xmas card I sent her on December 8. I'll let you read her letter when you are here, if you so wish.</p>
<p>Today I worked "overtime" at the office until <unclear>nearly</unclear> one! That will show you how nice it is for me there now, for I used never to leave before one!</p>
<p>Millie was over last evening for the first time. We were so happy to see her once more. she is surely a dear girl. She is going to have break just with us tomorrow (<unclear>Sunday</unclear>) morning. Don't you think that will be fun? She said for me to give you her best regards. She always asks how you are. Betty also asked how all of you are.</p>
<p>Among other things, though she could not say much for fear I a <unclear/> destroying the lecture, Betty said. "Hilda, wir erlebt man sovill zitgt. Weist du, Deutschland ist wirklill ein grosses Reich, auf das wan stolz sein Naun. Man versteht das</p>
67
3
<p>alles mint, lui man hier selbit mal gelebt hat. Dices ist line ireizniwalk Zeit. Kien Bruder Fredl, ist auch dentscher foldat. Ya, wihr will ich uisht scliuiben, ihu werdit ja in den Zeitmagen leoeu." She would be able to tell us so much that would be interesting. I really envy her, experiencing <unclear/> she is so much.</p>
<p>Alice is dancing now, as usual. I do not know what time she will get home. This rehearsing for the recital is lots of work. her recital is lots of work. Her recital is June 10. I do not know if she has told you yet. I am eager to see it, and I do</p>
69
4
<p>hope that you and Daddy will be here then. How about it?</p>
<p>Thursday evening Max was here for dinner. Sigurd played several things afterwards, and Max was quite impressed. Afterwards Max and I went to Faust park Highlands adn rode the roller-coaster, among other things. It was fun.</p>
<p>This is about all the news then is to give you. Anyway, this is a intended primarily to be a Birthday Letter for you, dearest Mother of them all. I love you more than ever I can say.</p>
70
5
<p>I am sure you will have a very happy day. Perhaps next year we shall all be forgotten on your Birthday, and in that case it will be a birthday for all of us.</p>
<p>Again, Happy, Happiest Birthday and my dearest, deepest love,</p>
Hilda
$