<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
197-<strike>198</strike> Fink Collection 23
BRANSON
DEC<cutoff/>
3-PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON, MISSOURI
Larry <unclear>Le Suar</unclear>
24
Here, This Evening, 1940
Dear Oddie and Enot:
<p>Two fine letters!</p>
<p>You've got it right, Ollie, about the nature of the work I'm doing; and you stated it expertly. Mine are not the meticulous labors of a self-concious stylist. I despise that sort of thing. What I'm always working for in itself is what matters. Aesthitic diddling makes me sick. I'm concerned with men and horses and the desert - <underline>and</underline> the human spirit in the midst of mystery.</p>
<p>I'm close to the end of the desert crossing, and after that there's a brief part. Already, at the same time I am working on the crossing, another part of me is actually working on the final passage of the whole narrative. It's like two people collaborating sometimes.</p>
<p>I get up about 5:30 and work till around 11. then work on a crystal-jad-white sapphire ring. The ring is about finished.</p>
<p>I'm looking forward to being up there when it's right to go. I'm eager to fit up that workshop for you, Ollie. That will be fun, &amp; we can make a corker. Fine that you have the power saw.</p>
(over)
25
<p>Enat peanut, I hope you'll be willing to take letters for me now &amp; then when we're there. I'll be going after various things. Want very much to get into some sort of defense work adn have done something in that direction already.</p>
<p>Lovely long rain here, but not really cold - just invigorating.</p>
<p>Enat, how's the knife cover coming on? When it's ready, let me have it. The knife should make a Xmas journey, if we dont' go.</p>
Endless love
Dad.
<p>P.S.:
I'm still listening eagerly for that Oxford voice on the radio saying you know what. No luck yet, but surely some time I'll hear it. If I ever get rich, I'll buy radio time and yell it myself just when all the boys are busiest selling their stuff amidst yodling, strumming, the bellawing of bassos and the screaming of sopranos!</p>
<note>text below are within margin of letter</note>
<p>I've sent Hilda some letters that she will pass on to <sic>you'ns</sic>. Send <sic>'em</sic> back.</p>
<p>Joan is so very lady, good and wise and so darned intelligent. It's good for her to be alone here. She is no trouble at all, and she's a big help!</p>