<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
16 McDonald Collection 
40
Branson, Mo., Aug. 29, '24.
Dear Folks:-
You must not htink that I didn't care to see you when I went to Mankato. that would be too funny for words. I was lonesome there, and knew I would be so before I went. I had thought, before I knew my schedule, that I'd nun up for at least a brief visit. Then when I learned that there was only one day for me at Mankato, it didn't occur to me to suggest that any of you should come down to see me. I thought that would be a nuisance. 
I shall be on the raod again in October (late) and November. Perhaps I shall be up that way again. 
I'd love to see every one of the four of you. 
THE SONG OF THE INDIAN WARS is finished and sent on to Macmillans. Allen True's drawings are half done and the half in N. Y. He's working on the full page drawings now. It should be a very beautiful book. It's a limited edition, you know, and I don't know how many copies I'll have. I doubt if they'll give me six. If they do, I'll remember my own first, of course. It looks as though the edition would be taken before published. I haven't heard the approximate price - something around five, I suppose, maybe more. 
But there'll be a trade edition shortly after the deluxe. That will contain all the drawings but will be much less magnoliatious, so to speak. 
here's some real news. Last night Dynamite, alias Barney Google, got into the apple pulp from our cider press. There must have been forty pounds of it. He ate it all. I supposed he'd have colic, but he didn't turn a hair. he's a hill-billy. Bessie, the Jersey cow, is a dear little lady. She kisses 

41
-2-
her uncle at milking time. It's an awful experience to be kissed passionately by a cow! She takes the hide off. 
Lots of love, 
John 
Worked four years and four months on The Wars. I'll bet your boys will suit up and call it a book! By Donald will like at the now I'm off for two more years. on the Song of the messiah (those Dance Religion T Wounded Knee)
John 