<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
7
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
11 P.M. 
Jan 14 24
Dearest Ones:
[Branson, Mo.] 
I won the Ebell Club inquestionably, and had a fine reception with tea afterward. Crowds of ladies came up and cooed - many from Nebraska and Iowa who coed especially hard for being from the middle West. I had been scared by stones I heard. They didn't like Yeats and they laughed at Kreyenborg and left him in bunches of a dozen. Every notable in the country & out of it has appeared before Ebell. Beautiful club house - packed. I'm so glad I won. They called me back from behind the wings. Darn them! 
<del/> Then I was taken out to the Goldwyn studies & had pictures together with Jim Tully & Rupert Hughes the novelist & movie man (Hughes makes $250,000 a year, & is therefore a very great artist!!"

8
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-2-
all right! Time will take care of him and his 250000 chips. Time is my friend and I remember this often when I need a friend. After that I went to dinner at the Westlake School for Girls-a fasionable school. They were dressed to hill at 100 yards. I had not had tiem to dress, but didn't care. Why should I? My nakedness was concealed. They made me read in a huge drawing room afterward & I did. Wanted more & more. And after the girls were sent to bed the older guests wanted another session. 
But Douglas, a composer - a genius by the way - slipped us over to his house. and gave me a drink that wasn't soft. Golly! but it helped me a lot. Then we talked a half hour - delightful family-and he brought me to the Hotel. Miss De Laguna 

9
G.A. HART 
D.H. HART  
<figure/> NEW HOTEL Rosslyn HART BROS. PROPRIETORS
AMERICAN AND EUROPEAN PLAN 
RATES MODERATE
HART BROS. MILLION DOLLAR POPULAR PRICE 
NEW HOTEL ROSSLYN 
COR. MAIN AND FIFTH STS. 
FREE BUS TO AND FROM HOTEL 
LOS ANGELES, CAL.  
-3-
started me home in her <unclear/>, but Douglas & his wife told the chauffeur to slip back to teh school without an asking a noise; that theyd see Neihardt house. Funny! Don't worry. I didn't swallow more than the equivalent of a good glass of wine, and I needed it. 
Well, I'm going to bed. I wired today! 
Received such dear letters from all of you. How I love those letters. 
Kindest thoughts to our Mary. I'm glad she's back with you. and I'm glad your cold spell blew over. I've been in may ever since I got over the Divide. 
Love 
Jno 
Daddy. 