<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20 Neihardt 
pm. June 29, 1936 
97 
<figure/> 
HOTEL ELDRIDGE, LAWRENCE KANSAS
HOTEL STATS, KANSAS CITY, MO. 
PEROSNAL DIRECTION OF W.G. HUTTSON 
HOTEL STATS 
12th and Wynadotte Kansas City, Mo. 
Dearest Neihardt:When I think how much you've been doing for me the last mouth or so, I wonder how I can ever been <unclear/> of it - either to you or the children. And to think that there are weeks yet that I'll need the <unclear/>-. And all this money that was supposed to be to write "Jed into with is being Well to keep the same old girl going. And you, dear, need a summer suit badly I remember your saying before there was any sign of were having to go to the <unclear/> that
Letter in Hilda's handwriting Just little after hours seen Illness 
In the Service of Hospitality 

98
you thought that now you could afford to get one, <unclear/> to wear and for my mental relief, We still owed the night nurse He, and she let me have the be you, which would have cost $2.50, for $2. Mis A. sent her the money out of hers. <unclear/> the agent $1.50 for necessary things for me to come home with out of her own money. Hilda had good screen doors put on our house, & if you could see the newly painted place now you wouldn't be disappointed in your home. It really is very neat and lovely. We painter did a good job of painting, another front really looks finished, I want to tell you about the dress you save me. It is the loveliest thing I've had in years but I don't believe I'll wear it until next year - maybe. 

99
-2-
    <figure/> 
    HOTEL ELDRIDGE, LAWRENCE KANSAS
    HOTEL STATS, KANSAS CITY, MO. 
    PEROSNAL DIRECTION OF W.G. HUTTSON 
    HOTEL STATS 
    12th and Wynadotte Kansas City, Mo. 
the children have been so good. Everything is so con-venient and so well-kept. Hilda's meals are so delicious that, I eat big Farmer's meals for dinner. Mat means I'm going to get well quickly and I'm not going to try to burn anything. It's so wonderful to be at home. It makes me so grateful to you that I have such a lovely home. I marvel how you keep hitting the ball with your beautiful graze. Won't forget that your letters are just eaten up. And Enid's are always a blessing too. I <unclear/> not to use that <unclear/> for the mattress, but to use it for 
I'm the Silliest of Hospitality 

100 
expenses already on hand, After all I can visit a little longer to have our matress or fixed up. Hilda is writing this for me, so my conscience can be a little cleaner. She been a month since I've been able to write to you, but you know I've thought of you every day. All I want now is to live, to be worth all your sand-ness, 
Mona
<figure/> 
G. Neihardt 
Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON JUN 29 7-AM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Mr. John Neihardt 
5544 Pershing St. Louis 
Mo. 
<figure/> 