<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
174 Fink Collection 81
Feb. 27th 40.
Enid darling:
<p>Your cute animals arrived exactly on Elaine's birthday and surely you would have been rewarded for your effort and work had you seen the delight in her eyes as she grabbed all three and hugged them up close with her chubby arms scarcely able to get around them altogether! The rest of us think they are surely wonderfully well done - <underline>most especially</underline> the crowing rooster - all we needed was Ollie to be there to crow for him! Max will</p>
82
<p>write you - but I wanted to let you Know how happy you made us right away - and Max has a big job of new folders and letters to get off no later than <underline>March first</underline>.</p>
<p>Our Men are well and enjoying beautiful weather etc. we hear.</p>
<p>Mrs. Spurlock is still on the job trying to get that fountain figure for me. She asked me today if I would make a small model of it for her to carry around to show and said that <underline>then</underline> she <underline>Knew</underline>she could put if over! I'll probably do that. If I do make "Maggie at the Well" from the Shepherd of the Hills, I'm going to make <underline>you</underline> as I remember you when you were <underline>here</underline>! My bowl is</p>
83
<p>getting beautiful - It will be a gorgeous piece of pottery for all of you children's homes at the very least.</p>
<p>Max is sending the yarn information to you.</p>
<p>She and I are just about getting over the excitements of the Men getting off and Elaine's birthday.</p>
<p>Today we washed i.e. Max washed and I hung out and scrubbed Dads work bench and the furnace room - What a mess!! Now Im getting after some housecleaning etc - and also am distributing the Fertilizer with Joanie's help - So Ollie has been prunning shrubs! Good for him - Daddy will do that too when he returns, he did some before he</p>
84
<p>left.</p>
<p>I am so eager for my seeds to arrive! Our Japonica already shows signs of rising sap - the buds are swelling - I don't Know where it got the nerve in all this cold weather!</p>
<p>Our fish are quite active too. I have a number of shrubs to move - Will hire a man right soon now.</p>
<p>Hilda write she so wants to have Alice with her again. May she remain with you Enid dear until in April or May? That would be swell. Loads of Love to you dear and to my son who does not write to his Mother who loves him</p>
Devotedly Mama.