<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
19
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
HOTEL K KEYSTONE 
POLAND & MERRELL 
LESSESS 
McCOOK, NEBR. 
Friday a.m.
mch 14'24
Dearest Ones: 
I got here last night at 1:30 and slept until 8:30 this morning, so I'm feeling bully. 
There was no snow at Falls City, and the weather was spring - like - maple buds pretty well developed but sometime from being out. It snowed here last night and is snowing today - a thin warm snow, next thing to rain. I'll leave here tomorrow (Saturday) at 12:30 and reach Fairmont at 7:35. That is only 40 miles south of Osceola. ^Will Read at Fairmont Sunday night in a church. All the churches will close & came over. to hear the poet. Monday might I'll be at Osceola, & then I'll hit for Omaha. Ralston on Tuesday night & Council Bluffs Wednesday A.M. at 10.30 then I'll take the 4 P.M. Burlington
<figure/>

20
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
HOTEL K KEYSTONE 
POLAND & MERRELL 
LESSESS 
McCOOK, NEBR. 
-2-
and reach Branson Thursday. It looks like something over $100 clear for this trip - not so bad. Might be considerably more, could easily be $150. I was talking to the editor of The Falls City Daily about the Julian oil business, and he said that we've got 'em for infringement. A certain portion of a given work can be used legally - but not the whole. I do hope we can loud for damages in excess of the minimum. 
I hope you are all feeling better by now & that Mona got Mrs. Robertson. 
I have a strenuous time from now on - Sun, Mon., Tues, nights straight and Wed. morning. But I feel normal - not at all strained yet. Caught a cold on the way to K.C. there is no sleeper 
<figure/>

21
FIREPROOF EUROPEAN PLAN 
HOTEL K KEYSTONE 
POLAND & MERRELL 
LESSESS 
McCOOK, NEBR. 
-3-
now; and the coach was draughty. But I doped up with <unclear/> - <unclear/> & the cold stopped, Slept in a hotel that first night - with farmer. 
I'm going to spend most of my time today are the University poetry contest. They sent me the 20 best poems received. 10,000 students to compete, and yet there's not a notable thing in the bunch! One little thing in the bunch! One little thing is so good - a sort of Sara Teasdale lyric - short & sweet. One pretensious poem is so vague I don't know what it's about. The others are almost nothing. Lots of love to my Six
Jno 
Daddy. 
<figure/> 