<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
8 Fink Collection 
54-55
WAYNE, NEBR JUN 22 4-PM 1935 
Enid, Hilda & Alice Neihardt 
Branson
Missouri 
Taney Co. 

9
Mama missed this I was flabbergasted & a bit sad. I wanted her there. 
Saturday A.M. 
Dearest Girls:
I've thought about you a lot altho' I havne't written, and even now I can't feel much like writing a real letter. But I love you all dearly. 
It has been & still is fine to be here. Yesterday at 9:30 I read 50 minutes - and talked - from the Messiah - It was teh first time I had ever worked out a well formed Messiah program. The auditorium was full, & wont' of the balcony 10:45 convocation was devoted to reminences & tributes to Dr. & Mrs. Conn, I was, of course, asked to speak. Didn't know what I was to say, but it seems the thing came on well 

10
-2-
formed from the response. The Governor thought he could not get here for the main speech today - Jubilee Day; & come asked me to wake the speech in lpace fo the Gov. This morning I began thinking it out & was about ready with it when news came that the Gov. could come after all! Was I relieved! I'll have to talk anyway, it's not hard when I get up there. Someday else seems to be talking. But. I'm glad conn can have the Gov. for his triumph Mrs. Conn said, when it seemed the Gov. wouldn't come, that there'd be a better speech; but that's not the point. (over) 

11
-3-
The Day is perfect - cool & clear. The parade this A.M. was bully - very long & in every way fine. Mama & I had a car to ourselves behind <unclear/> at the head of the procession with the bond playing!
Met Mary Lu yesterday, Hiddy a dear bird, sure enough. She said (referring to my spiel at convocation):"Now I know where Hilda got her gift for speaking!" 
Enot, it looks as tho' something might come to you either at Lincoln or her. Looks very promising. 
I do love you girls - you dear things! Mama & I are having a <unclear/> you time. Bully! We're happy. Endless love,
Dad. 

12
NEBRASKA STATE TEACHERS COLLEGE 
U.S. CONN, PRESIDENT
WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
EXECUTIVE SECRETARY
ELVA B. MILLER 
Dear Hiddy:
You & <unclear/> for having the dentist do your work is good. Yes, I know you want to help. I don't like the nerve fo a man who will take a human being's time & attention for $3.50 a week. Try it awhile, & go ahead with the teeth of the man seems to knwo what to do. 
Endless love 
Dad 
