<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
70a
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
ASSISTED BY
SIGURD NEIHARDT, PIANIST
BRANSON, MISSOURI
Saturday April 15
1939
Dear Mama:
<p>We all are getting to be 'early birds' around here. Dad gets up before 6:00 &amp; makes coffee. Then I come down about 6:30. Then Max at 7:00. It is fine soft weather down here. Really quite enjoyable. The place is very well cleaned up, including ozark bed, pool-garden, under the bushes &amp; hedge etc. (Dad had done all this by himself)</p>
<p>Things look encouraging for our business. However there is a vast amount of work in writing for all the information - then writing carefully planned letters to the proper persons. I'm working <underline>thoroughly</underline>, <underline>every</underline> accredited institution of higher learning in Indiana <underline>and</underline> Illinois. Looks like a very splendid October &amp; November will develop. Quite a lot is <underline>contracted</underline> already, &amp; the ones not yet 'contracted' <underline>will</underline> do so from now clear on down through September. For good measure &amp; to <underline>be sure</underline> about our having a sufficiently good year - I am also working the west.</p>
<p>Dad is now <underline>writing</underline> each morning &amp; going along very fast with Jed Smith. I have also thoroughly memorized two new piano numbers.</p>
(over)
<p>Just in last few days I landed another summer engagement for Dad - for first week of June, the Northern Normal &amp; Industrial School, Aberdeen South Dakota. Am now trying to get Moorhead, Minnesota &amp; Brookings South Dakota to consider <underline>having</underline> us while up in that country.</p>
<p>I'm hoping that you will be coming home soon. We leave for Lincoln, Nebraska - next Monday - a week, April 24th.</p>
<p>Perhaps Hilda &amp; Alice will soon be feeling lots better. All of that trouble must have been hell on all of you.</p>
<p>Take care of yourself please. Anytime you phone us from Springfield we'll be there on an hour's notice (or few minutes longer). I suggest that you find out from the Bus ticket office in St Louis as to <underline>when</underline> your bus arrives Springfield. Then write us about it, so we can be there waiting for you.</p>
Always love for you
&amp; Hilda &amp; Alice,
Sig, Max, &amp; the 
two "<underline>fat-rabbits</underline>".