<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 45
HAROLD E. HEIN
CHAIRMAN OF THE BOARD & TRUST OFFICER
NINA THOMPSON
VICE PRESIDENT
EVERETT E. REES
VICE PRESIDENT
HENRY E. LEY
PRESIDENT
T. L. <unclear>ARMBROSTER</unclear>
CASHIER
<gap reason="cut off"/>
ASSISTANT CASHIER
BEVERLY ANN ETTER
ASSISTANT CASHIER
SNB
The State of National Bank
and Trust Company
ESTABLISHED 1892
WAYNE, NEBRASKA 68787
December 14, 1968

Mr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>Just a note right now to tell you I received your letter and how pleased I was to hear from you and know that you are back in Nebraska again.</p>
<p>The loan you speak of may have been small but I think Dad was as proud of it as any line of credit he ever set up. I am sure he made it because he believed in you and this was the type of thing he enjoyed most.</p>
<p>Under ordinary circumstances, I would have to tell you that there would be no possibility that the record was still in existence. However, until after the turn of the century, there was no such thing as a posting machine and all of the records were kept by hand on what was called the Boston Ledgers. We have quite a few and perhaps all of them stashed away in the vault in the basement and I think it is possible that this record may still be in existence. I have located the ledgers but have not yet had time to go through them. If you will be patient with me until after the first of the year, I will get to this and do my best to find the information you want. Whether I find it or not, I will report to you at a later date.</p>
<p>My daily habits are not the same here as they were when I was in Lincoln. At that time, I kept pretty good track of your programs but I have not seen you now for at least several months. I did enjoy them when they were a regular part of the</p>
<p>Holiday Greetings</p>
Page 46
The State National Bank and Trust Company
Mr. John G. Neihardt
December 14, 1968 
Page 2
<p>Educational Television Programs.</p>
<p>I hope that you will be coming up to Wayne in the near future. If you should be considering it and would have use for trans-portation, let me know, as I can always figure out a half a days work in Lincoln and would enjoy your company up and back any time that you might wish to make the trip. Best regards and Merry Christmas.</p>
Very truly yours,
<signed>Henry</signed>
Henry E. Ley
bae