<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
39
For WASTEBASKET!!!... But you might skim lightly first. 
THE ARTHUR C. KEMBLES, ORE HILL, LAKEVILLE, CONNECTICUT 06039
March 15, 1973
Dear John Neihardt,
Ever tell the little lady with the beautiful, beautiful script the story I think of as a second-cousin companion piece to Black Elk's eagle? ... Meaning how Manabozo got so fed up with shivering one winter night he climbed a frozen moonbeam to the cloudland where the Manitous were sleeping sung around their campfire -- stole a firebrand and was creeping away with it, but sneezed on the smoke and woke the Manitous -- then ran so fast to keep out of their clutches, he stumbled into a hole in the cloud and fell yelling bloody murder, down, down, down -- then how his pal, the eagle, flew to the rescue  so that Mama-bozo, still clutching his brand, landed conveniently astride the eagle's back and rode him on down to the Jeebway village where they hailed him as the great hero for bringing his people the fire of the Manitous which woudl keep them warm all through the bitterest winter cold ever after. 
The factual human stories that link us with the immortals and our own destiny also have elements of intriging mystery -- such as a wealth of "impossible" coincidences. And both of you might be mildly interested to know that right across the road from our remodeled cowbarn here is a charming little old house built by a fellow who may have played at least a minor role in the labyrinthine pattern which led Henry Schoolcraft to his monumental labors of love in recording Jeeway lore in the Upper Lakes. 
This was Ethan Allen. Ethan was a chum of Henry's father, Colonel Lawrence Schoolcraft, who served with him in capturing Ticonderoga. Ethan grew up in the iron mining boom here, was a partner in building the first big iron works in 1762. And one of his dreams was exploring and exploiting all such natural resources. He evidently infected Lawrence an dhis boy in turn. Right after the war Lawrence set up a glassworks just over the Hudson near the Helderburg -- the first major industrial project of our new republic. There young Henry served an apprenticeship as a glassmaker -- then when still in his teens wrote a pair of manuals on min-ing and metallurgy -- and began a series of explorations for natural resources that took him down through the Ohio valley, up the Mississippi to the Dubuque-Galena lead mines, and on down the river to New Orleans.
Unbelievable as it may seem. not long after he'd 
1

40
-2-
turned twenty-four, Henry worked up a comprehensive program of laws and guidelines for orderly, economical development of our national resources with such help as he could get from others and put it o ver with the goverment. He spearheaded the plan for some years with surveys, negotiations with Indians, miners, and politi-cians -- in the process becoming increasingly absorbed in Indian affairs and Indian lore until he married a Joebway and settled down as Indian Agent at the Mack-inac crossraods of the Great Lakes Indian world. 
Ethan, Lawrence, and Henry must have become fairly well acquainted with our Indians around here in their early years as, in a more intensive way, you did out in the Plains. Ethan evolved a philosophy that was practically a religion with him of the "natural man" and his trust in the inspriation and guidance of in-stincts and mystique of wild nature -- part Unitari-anism part boyhood exposure to the rugged unspoiled wilderness around his dad's farm just south of here -- and part, it seems reasonable to guess, from the friendly Mohegans still lingering in the Housatonic Valley flanked by several ranges on both east and west which were for-midable enough to serve as some protection from the war-minded Mohawks and Pequots. In his late years Ethan, for all his lack of schooling, wrote up his maverick for all his lack of schooling, wrote up his maverick "religion" in a book which became known as Ethan's Bible. 
As Ethan's second marriage was to a cousin of his chum Lawrence, it seems probable he played "Dutch Uncle" to henry and influenced him slant on Indians as he also did on his fascination with natural resources. 
Isn't this a parallel with your early bent for mechanics? And isn't it the same phenomenon as John Muir's boyhood inventions and aborted career as a fac-tory master mechanic and pioneer in "work simplification"? ... Sometime (not NOW!) I'd sure like to know what you make of this curious riddle.... Could it be that in some forgotten round of mortality, you men developed your mechanical talents to the place where it cropped up naturally from the subconscious -- then said to your-selves, "Hey, wait a minute! I've already had enough of that stuff -- it's time for an about face into un-explored territory!" 
I myself come from clans on both sides of the family who were builders of ships, mills, and machinery. But I was emotionally turned off in childhood by table talk on science, math, and assorted technology -- so much so that I was a technical dunce in school. Yet I think I recognize a carry-over in a compulsive interest in put-ting together observations and experiences with common denominators like jig-saw pieces to see what the picture can tell me about the fundamentals of human nature and 

41
-3-
facts of life here and hereafter -- the "long view" as I think of it. That obsession has paid off two ways in a life of wonderfully zany and diverse adventures -- and in a rather thorough-going education of a kind I wouldn't trade with anyone I've ever known, even through print. 
Before signing off, I'll give you a sample that ties in with your own story -- if I can squeeze it into capsule. When you were working on The Far West when she was bringing back Reno's wounded, was there a woman aboard by the name of Dousman -- the mother of a young officer killed with Custer? 
By a one-in-a-million chance I turned up at Villa Louis (believe they called it at Prairie du Chien the very morning the granddaughter came to inspect the place -- first time she'd seen it since her childhood vists there when her grandmother was alive. She had inherited the place, but had avoided it because of a "complex". She was in a tizzy becuse Reno's regiment had been us-ing it as a repository for all their menorabiliam as had the Dousman family for fur <del/> trading records and the famous elephant edition of Audubon's pictures which Audubon had sold them himself -- and the whole rich historical treasure had been stolen form a locked book-case while the place was being used as a boys school. 
This will be damn hard to believe. But I was able to tell her what had become of them. Just weeks before, I'd received a catalogue from a dealer in rare books which was a complete listing of all the items. Later I sent her the Catalgue. She put it into the hands of here Mnneapolis attorney who, as she wrote me, got it all back and stashed it safely in some museum-library. 
Mrs. Whatever-Her-Name was so gratified that morning at my hopeful news, that she told me everything she knew ab out her grandmother's eerie adventure and its conse-quences. She was visiting kinfolk in St. Louis at the time of the Custer debacle. An old Indian friend of the trader came to her with a report of the battle and its results -- this a week or more before the news came through white sources. The Indian said eh got it from his people's "grapevine" which he refused to explain. But she believed him and set off immediately, traveling most of the way by horseback. She found Reno's men on the battlefield trying to sort out the dead. As I got the tale, she was the first white person to appear. She found the men badly demoralized. And despite her trauma over her son, she pitched in to help tend the wounded and to cheer the soldiers every way she could. All identification she could find of her son was a piece of torn shirt in which she believed she recognized her own stitching. 

42
-4-
Reno's men responded to her as you might expect. They idolized her and tagged her "Our Littlew Mother of the Seventh Cavarry". When she finally left, perhaps on your steamer, she invitated the whole command to a reunion when they could arrange the leave at her Prairie du Chien estate. Not only did they come en mass. jThey made it an  annual affair and kept return-ing for an encampment on the grounds. My lady, then likely in her fifties, remembered those encampments, their feasts and songfests vividly. 
in one of my umpteen book mss. -- believe I called it Impossible? -- I've spelled it out and owuld gladly pass it along in case it's worth a paragraph in your autobiographical series.... My point, however, is that this is only one of a half dozen parallel cases of primitive communication I came onto here and there. Two were in Haiti, both from first-hand sources. And in one case I got eye-witness description of one end of a "telephone" conversation between a black   girl in a state of trance (who neverthe less could talk back) and what was presumably the bocour in her native village some twenty miles away, telling her that her father was dying. Obviously  controlled telepathy, implying the boucour could tune in when she was in normal sleep. 
Another case was a first-hand witness of the Pen-obs ot Indians in Maine who used the sound-conducting surface of lakes and rive3r to send a messsage around 15-18 miles and get a pinpoint answer which was verified a few hours later. Still another was of regular one-way mental radio by which a mother kept picking up specific problems of her three daughters married to lighthouse keepers at different lights. As the mail boats came at only three-week intervals most of the year, it cut the communication interval in nearly half. 
Again, afraid I'm terriby gabby. I have soem little things I might like you to take a look at some time by way of introducing you as to what kind of a so-and-so I turned out to be. But not for now -- or for anytime until you may happen to be enough free from pressures to waste an hour on amusement. 
Can well appreciate the strain on those recording chores! Delighted, though, that we'll sometime have the treat of hearing your voice for hte first time -- and discovering your personal intepretation of your superb poetry. .... The closest I ever came to this kind of thing was when osme friends pulled a surprise one me by making a four double-record recording of a swatch of one of my childhood books -- an adventure with an old Jeebway woman on Lake Huron when I was six. They got a young Broadway actor who did a fine job. 
My very warmest!!!
Sandy 