<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 25
University of Missouri
COLUMBIA
65201
INSTRUCTIONAL TELEVISION
Office of the Director
409 Jesse Hall
Phone 449-8121
401 3.p.m
South_
October 22, 1968
Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I enjoyed your letter of October 17 very much..At the present time, I have not had further word from Eastern Ken-tucky University regarding the loan of video tapes from your Epic America series. I do appreciate hearing from you regarding this matter and will certainly send along a copy of all correspondence with Kentucky relating to this matter.</p>
<p>I will look forward with great anticipation to visit-ing with you when you return to Columbia.</p>
Sincerely,
<signed>Don R. Mitchell</signed>
Don R. Mitchell
Associate Director
DRM/rm
<unclear>Grifetch</unclear>
Page 26
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
October 17, 1968

Mr. John Schweitzer
English Department
University of Missouri
Columbia, Missouri 65201

Dear John:

<p>Eastern Kentucky University wants to borrow my "Epic America" tape, as I think you must know by now as there has been some correspondence.xxxx Also Syracuse University wants to obtain the "Twilight of the Sioux" tape. Since you know as much about those tapes as I do, I wish you could find time to meet with Don R. Mitchell, Associate Director of Instructional Television, and do what you can to clarify the matter. I have just written Mitchell, giving permission to loan the "Epic America" tape.</p>
<p>I think of you often, John, and always with the old warmth of heart. I have been doing a number of things for quite a while and have been kept really busy. At the same time I have been working on my autobiography, The Old Man Remembers, and I am happy about it. John, its going to be quite a book.</p
<p>I am getting a bit eager to see you again and to find out how things go. Give my kind regards to any one in the English Department who would care for them. And be sure that you have my kindest thoughts always which you may share with your lady. And do hug the youngster for me.</p>
M.M.Y-
Speeling of Switzer?
Page 27
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
October 17, 1968

Mr. Don R. Mitchell
Associate Director of Instructional Television
University of Missouri
Columbia, Missouri 65201

Dear Mr. Mitchell:       (English 279)
<p>I understand that Eastern Kentucky University has written you about my television course "Epic America" and that it is necessary for me to give permission before you can loan the tapes. <crossed>x I hereby give you permission to loan any of my tv</crossed></p>

<p>I am glad to give my permission.</p>
<p>I am wondering if the people at Eatern Kentucky University know about my "Twilight of the Sioux".</p>
<p>I am told that my old friend and assistant John Schweitzer will take this matter up with you.</p>
<p>When I xxx return to Columbia I shall want to meet you.</p>
With all kinds thoughts