<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 31
SOUTHWEST MISSOURI
STATE COLLEGE
SPRINGFIELD
 
Ans. 3/15/71
dictated

1111 East Normal
Springfield, Mo,
March 8, 1971

Dear Mr. Neihardt,
<p>I am deeply sorry the Missouri's Writers has not been sent to you. I left it up to my Editor but he has been very busy working on her Ph.D. and that accounts for the delay.</p>
<p>I hope you like the book</p>
SOUTHWEST MISSOURI
STATE COLLEGE
SPRINGFIELD
<p>of Teachers of English Literary Landmarks Committe I have to send in material concerning literary landmarks which are already established in Missouri.</p>
<p>That brings me to my question concerning you. Is there any house in Missouri where you have lived that has an especial significance. Is the house still standing in Branson where you lived?</p>
<p>I shall enclose a format</p>
Page 32
<p>We hope to publish a second edition soon if we can come out financially solvent on the first edition. We have not sold enough copies as yet to pay the printer.</p>
<p>If you know of any one who would like another copy send $1 to me and I'll see that you get one.</p>
<p>I got a pamphlet advertising your record and plan to order one.</p>
<p>Your picture celebrating your 89th birthday was in the Springfield paper. I chipped it for my files.</p>
<p>I am on the National Council to fill out if you have any information.</p>
<p>I hope you are in good health and that your eyes are better.</p>
Sincerely,
Martha B. Williams
and mail to home address
1111 East Normal 
Springfield, Mo.
65508
Page 33
Suggested entry format
Sample cards
1 Indianapolis                              Indiana
2 523 Lockerbie Street
James Whitcomb Riley's home 1893-1916
<p>3 This one and a half story Victorian brick house, trimmed with stone, was the home (though he was the paying quest of Major and Mrs. Charles L. Holstein; he shared the household expenses and many items in the house were purchased by him) of "Indiana's best loved poet" during his mature writing and lecturing career. The house is furnished with the items which were in the house when Riley died there, July 22, 1926. Includes personal <unclear/>, <unclear/>.</p>
<p>4It was purchased in 1916 by a group of Riley's friends (including Booth Tarkington, George Ade, and Meredith Nichalson, among others) and deeded in 1921 to the James Whitcomb Riley Memorial Association, which maintains it. open-to-the-<unclear/>.5Open daily to the except Monday 10-4 Tuesday through Saturday; 12-4 Saturday.</p>
use both sides of the card if you wish
<p>6 See booklet "The Lockerbie Street Home of James Whitcomb Riley" obtainable at the house or from The James Whitcomb Riley Memorial Association, 129 East Market Street, Indianapolis. Also Dorothy Russo A Bibliography of James Whitcomb Riley, Marcus Dickey Youth...and Mature Years of James Whitcomb Riley, Jeannette C. Nolen James Whitcomb Riley (juvenile fictionalized biography), R. E. Bant, compiler, Indiana Authors and Their Books, Riley The Lockerbie Book. The best edition of Riley's works is the Memorial edition, 1916 10 volumes.</p>
<p>Picture best cards and slides are available at the home. See also Indiana literary map (out of print) and map: Indianapolis; A City of Cheerful Yesterdays (Greater Information, Inc., c/o The Mayor)
7 Other Riley sites: Indianapolis, Crown Hill Cemetery, Plainfield, Indiana, his birhtplace and boyhood home, <unclear/> <unclear/> courthouse laim theme, Riley Hospital for Children, Indianapolis, Ill <note>text becomes illegible at this point</note></p>
cards may be handwritten or done on slips of paper

Give as much of the following information as possible, leaving blank space for any unavailable:
1.Town (or nearest twon)         state
  Addess or location of site
2.Designation of site (such as:)
A. Birthplace of author, date
B. Name, inclusive dates/residence
C. Grave, description and inscription of monument
D. Scene of writing
E. Monument or statue, sculptor, date or erection
F. Plaque or marker, inscription
3.What else is to be seen:
  Furnishings, pictures, manuscripts, books, <underline>etc.</underline>
4.Ownership (Name of organisation or private)
5.Days and hours it may be viewed and arrangements,
  if any, necessary (private sites without this 
  information are assumed to be close to viewing)
6.Significance as a literary landmark -- if not
  already covered by above items
7.Bibliography: (May be cross reference to another rather than repeat)
A. Source of further information about the site
B. Publications about the site (or reference to it)
C. Publications about the author
D. Author's writings other than those mentioned above
E. Pictures, maps, slides available (and source[s])
8.Cross reference to other sites connected with the author

Feel free to add any pertinent information which may be appropriate to the uniqueness of the site.
Repeat items 1 and 2 at top of second card and "continue" 
Inquire at Post office about manuscript rate for sending cards.
Picutres, booklets, brochures, or maps might have items 1 and 2 lightly pencilled on them if the connection is not otherwise readily apparent.

If in doubt, include. Include <unclear/> if the information for only <unclear/> and <unclear/> available.