<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
11
Hilda N. Petri 
ATTORNEY AT LAW 
110 NORTH EIGHTH STREET - COLUMBIA, MISSOURI 65201
P.O. BOX 1096 PHONE (314)F 449-2929
January 22, 1973
Dear Gaki:
I am back at work this morning, but i'm not very brilliant! 
I have just talked to Dr. Brownlee, director of the State Historical Society, concerning your manuscripts. I am sending you a copy of the letter that I have written to Marie Vogt about it. She wrote me, because they need to be able to show property that they will have as a part of their investment in the proposed building. You know more about this than I do. 
Dr. Brownlee said that if it were anyone but you, his answer would be a flat "no!" However, he did discuss the whole matter with me, and I am certainly glad that I went to him first and not to someone else. It was Dr. Brownlee's feeling that affection for you on the part of himself and others here might make some kind of an agreement possible. He suggested that possibly copies or micro-films could be made for this organization, and the originals go to the Nebraska museum. In the course of our dicussion, Dr. Brownlee stated that he thought that you were among the top American writers, and he felt that in a few years you would probably be considered number one. He said that your manuscripts will become tremendously valuable and sought after. 
Dr. Brownlee's suggestion <del>that</del> was that the president of the university should be consulted directly. I would suggest that you write a letter to Dr. Brice Ratchford, President, University of Missouri. You might tell him something about the purposed museum and say that you would hope that some kind of an agreement could be worked out. I think that you probably feel, as I do, a little reluctant to demand the return of the documents to you. Of course, this could not be done very easily, since there is a binding contract. However, a very nice letter to Dr. Ratchford from you, telling aobut the museum, expressing your appreciation to Missouri State Historical Society and Western Manuscripts, and suggesting that perhaps some kind of an arrangement coudl be worked out so that neither would be completely shut out, would be a good answer. 
2

12
Page 2
January 22, 1973
John G. Neihardt
If you can write such a letter, please send it to me, and I will take the matter up with Dr. Ratchford.
This is the biggest item of news right now. I am going to try to catch up with my work, and I will try to get something done on this too. 
Much love to you as always.
Hilda 