<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 56
December 29, 1968
Dear John,
<p>I am sorry to be so long delayed writing you, but it has not been possible to write sooner. My father died in November We went to Texas for the burial and there were a good many arrangements to make before and after; I had to miss school, and catching up the work before this term ended was all but overpowering. I simply couldn't write about it for a while; I had never been close to the various stages of death before, and I felt like somebody else for a while except when I could work on the book--then I felt like <underline>me</underline>. So I did work on the book, and I knew you would understand; it was keeping in touch with you in a way, and leaning on your strength, too. I kept thinking of things you have said and written, specially "Envoi," and a line form one of Alice's letter to you ran through my head. She said, "We don't believe in death, do we?" I don't either, but the exhaustion of all the preceded and the emotions running against each other shut me off. It was peaceful at the end; my father was in a coma for two weeks, and then our humane doctor stopped the treatment--it was getting no response and prolonging something far short of life. But my father kept his dignity to the end--he was a per-son even in the coma, and I think I wanted that more than anything else for him. He would have hated the oxygen mask and suction and glass bottle part if he had known. His friends had not forgotten him in the little Texas community; they had practiced his favorite hymns, and the whole servide was ready when we got there.</p>
<p>I have good news of the book. With any kind of luck I will have the man-uscript all ready for you when you are able to hear it after the surgery, and THIS IS THE YEAR IT SEES PRINT--if the publisher still wants it. It's a good book; the revisions are tightening the structure and doing more for all your writing--and for your ethos, good man! All the heavy revision is done and a</p>
Page 57
<p>good bit of the lighter. I have been working like a beaver on it all through vacation; Bower left on the 23rd to spend Christmas with Chrley's family, since he is in Viet Nam. Martha and Stewart were there too, and we agreed that I should stay here with the house to myself and concentrate on Neihardt, John G. It was lovely, actually; I worked as late as I wanted to without disturbing anyone, and I feel good about the chapters.</p>
<p>I shall be thinking about you during the surgery--and before and after. I am sure it will be as easy and successful as the last, but you might this time <underline>lie down</underline> in the hospital bed and rest up for all the biography listening. I want you to hear it through once without thinking about comments or suggestions. Just get the whole picture, and then hear it through for notes to me. Can do? Some of the things you think aren't there <underline>are</underline> there further on, and I think you will be impressed with yourself hearing your life straight through.</p>
<p>More news: this year I plan to come to see you. It won't be until the work is done, probably this summer, but I have made up my mind, which is not wishy-washy, that I am coming out to Nebraska for long enough to have a visit, if possible for the annual do.</p>
<p>I am writing Mrs. Young also, to thank her personally for all the things she sends me, and for her general kindness. I am glad to ahve all articles, notes, comments, sidelights, and pictures. I am very happy for you, John; it's really wonderful that all this can happen. If anyone in the world deserves to stand center stage and have the laurel fall in piles around him, it's you. I am cheering lustily form the far West--that overtone in all the applause you can't quite identify if me!</p>
<p>More later--I will now be able to write to you as I wish I could have all along. And I have a new appreciation for all the wise words you have said and written.</p>
<p>Regards to all the family, and my special deepest, finest love to you.</p>
<signed>Lucile</signed>