<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 25
September 26, 1970

Dear John,
<p>I've been slow answering your letters because all week we have been advising, tooling up for fall term, and it has been uphill all the way because the academic requirements have all been changed, and also none of the students had their transcripts. and evry day has been a series of crises. It is over now so here's a letter, written with shaky fingers from all the turmoil of the week. I feel sorry for students; the whole world is confusion for them.</p>
<p>John, I do love you, and you are worrying for nothing about the errors still in the manuscript. I wrote you, remember, that to get the manuscript in I didn't try to clean them all up--it would have meant retyping a good many pages and a month or so delay; I have all the notes and lists of changes to make but I didn't intend to ink them in. The manuscript is about to go through my final editing, with suggestions from Bower, too--he has never yet read it, and he's good on fine stylistic points. So the big clean-up is still to be done, and I've got it all down--the Willa Cather also, but I would like to have the article Florence found. The trouble was that I had not been able to document that point, so I just took out all mention in the manuscript to save an unfinished footnote. I <underline>don't</underline> question you as a witness; you're the best source.</p>
<p>I hope the press will send me the new books of yours; I want to show <underline>When the Tree Flowered</underline> to our professor of mythology and folk lore. He knows <underline>Black Elk</underline> and knows about you, but he hadn't seen <underline>Tree</underline>, and I don't want to lend my copy. I'm getting selfish about my copies of your books.</p>
<p>I'm glad you had the visit in Columbia. Did you get out to Skyrim at all? Alice was going to write me some news about psychic experiences, and I hope she will have time. Everything happened so fast in Nebraska that we didn't have time to talk very much. Tell me too about the recording. Is it all finished, or are you still cutting records?</p>
<p><underline>Much </underline>love form us all. I wish Nebraska were closer. Seeing you is like Base.</p>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
