<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 32a
Written and the <unclear/> mailed <unclear/>
December 18, 1969
Dear, <underline>dear</underline> John,
<p>Yes, I will say something to you---THE BOOK IS FINISHED!!!!!! I am working on the Bibliography, but here is the last chapter, and do send the letter. I can still write it into the Laurel Decade before it is typed if I can have it right away, and if not, I can edit it in on the final round.</p>
<p>I have not yet written Mr. Nicholl, but here is the nitty-gritty on publishing; I decided to do nothing till I had a manuscript. I feel committed to send it to Nebraska Press but they have never sent me a contract, though Mr. Nicholl said once he would, and I will not sign it unless it is the right kind of contract. Bower will give it his eagle eye; he knows a great deal about what a contract should and should not say, and he is as vitally concerned for you and the book as I am. In Bower's opinion, I ought to contact some Random House and Holt about the manuscript; I do not want to deal with Macmillan because we had some experience with them on Bower's speech text and the anthology that included your version of Spotted Tail's speech, and we were not at all happy with their general procedures. Holt is publishing the Oregon Curriculm that I tangled with so long, and I know some of the editors. One of them--the Language Arts Editor in the textbook division--will be in Oregon right after Christmas, and I will talk with him about it. Bower will be in New York after Christmas, and will see editors there. I'll keep you informed, truly. Now that the writing is done, and the bibliography will be finished this week I can write <underline>to</underline> you again. It's been a one-way communicaiton, and I don't mean just that you wrote more than I did; I talked to you and thought about and with you all the time, but you couldn't tell. I'm terribly sorry, because I miss you most awfully, but to get my whole mind on the book I have had to let everything possible go--too many things like classes and a granddaughter's needs and papers to grade <underline>had</underline> to divert me.</p>
<p>I know I have been stubborn about this book. Even Bower now and then thought I was not moving it fast enough, but now that it's finished I'm glad I did it this way--I wanted it right, and I mean most of all right in saying what I really wanted to say. I think I do know a lot about you, and I wasn't willing to release any chapter till right down to the sentence and the word it said what I deeply thought. In fact, I wanted the book to be <underline>you</underline>, not some biographer skimming you and missing the real point. The <underline>ethos</underline> of you and of your work was the point. I hope you will like the last chapter--my life blood is in it, and I think it <underline>is</underline> you as Mona used to say a good bust was. This is my portrait, and it's our work--yours and mine.</p>
<p>About the last chapter: If there are errors I will try to beat the typist to them, but we can redo pages if necessary. I have tried to be very careful, but some of the sources are newspapers, and alas, they are often wrong. The contruction of this chapter was more difficult than I anticipated because it had to jump around in time; I couldn't do a chronological treatment and point the emphasis properly.</p>
<p>I wish I could tell you what doing this book has really meant to me, but it's far beyond the level of words. I think what I feel most strongly is the miracle of what you are in what you say and do. After all, anybody can <underline>say</underline> that the principles you illuminate are real and live-on-able, but you did it. That reads like a simple sentence, but it isn't. Even the word <underline>love</underline> doesn't quite cover what I feel about you, unless it's Plato's divine love, and even Plato couldn't match you for living his ideal.</p>
Page 32b
<p>I wish my little granddaughter could meet you. She is a darling child, and she has never been really loved before; what the feel of love has done for her is astonishing; It seems to have quickened all her perceptions, even made her prettier. She has a good mind, too; she has been too preoccupied with trying to think herself out to find it yet, but she misses nothing. She makes me grieve for all the children who have to try to hold a footing on ground  shifting under them--the world must be full of them, without anyone to come to the rescue. You would liek young Martha(she's a Martha too, after Aunt Martha); she calls Bower Estavlishment, and brings home grasshoppers to show me, and talks to the squirrels in the yard.</p>
<p>I am laying deep plots to get out to see you again, perhaps in the summer, though I will be teaching until August. What are your plans, and what is in the books for the Annual Neihardt Day? Also, do you know anything andout Mrs. Vogt? I will write to her if she is able to get letters; she was very ill the last I heard.</p>
<p>Please give my love to the Youngs and to Frances. As soon as I get bhe Bibliography typed up I'll write, but it's a big job. You have absolutely no idea how much has been daid and written about you; the problem is going to be to keep it within printable proportions.</p>
<p>As for you, young man Neihardt, I hope you are taking care of yourself, with Mrs. Young's guidance, in flu weather. Are you going to Columbia for Christmas? Martha, Stewart, Susan and I are holding the fort here, since Bower leaves on the 26th. He will have the day with us, but then he has to take out. We will all be thinking about you, and I hope you feel a special wave of love from the West coming at you. If you go to Columbia, do give my love to all the family. I hope to hear from Enid, Ollie, Alice and anyone else about the manuscipt I sent Hilda. It didn't have the last chapter, and if you want to send your copy on to them, make your comments with page keys and I can read them with my own copy. I will send you one copy of the whole book when it is all typed; about it, you may have some corrections, especially in the footnotes, which you have never seen in final form. They were so marked up I didn't try to enclose them.</p>
<p>Love and love, to the little French accented Jacquot too! And now try me on answering letters!</p>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
MERRY CHRISTMAS!!