<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 31
c/o Wadsworth
Magnolia Star Route
Nederland, Colorado
18 November, 1968

Dear Dr. Neihardt,

<p>After a summer in the mountains I have finally disovered my direction. As I imagine is the case with most revelation, this one presented itself in a completely unsuspected manner though its message was one I had been expecting in some obscure way for some time.</p>
<p>It seems that the American dream has alywas been to produce the best living for the greatest number through intelligent utilization of the land. Unfortunately, somewhere along the line, our fore-fathers adopted the false equation "comfort equals materialism" and they usurped rather than settled this country. Only now is the present generation facing the fact that true comfort is emotional rather than material and it comes only form some type of religious grace, even if that be secularized.</p>
<p>As the present generation broadens its horizons, it is only a matter of time before we produce a religion which will be a syn-thesis of Christian, Oriental, and native Indian thought. Indeed such a religious spirit is beginning to spread though as yet it lacks focus. It is my opinion that when such a religious movement overcomes the inertia of our present culture, a new renaissance will follow of itself.  Art will present a new iconography; in literature poetry will become gospel and satire will record the impact of the new ethic; and science will again become the fountain of cosmology.</p>
<p>Naturally I hope to be able to contribute to this new literature, but my major concern at the present is to introduce your artistic and religious principles to as many of my contemporaries as possible. Whether such a study would serve as my master's thesis has become of scondary importance to me; I am more interested in communicaiton. As I have mentioned to you previously, your lectures on poetic values form the most acceptable handbook of aesthetics for our time; refute the "comfort equals materialism" formual without resorting to offensive sentimentality. And your portraits of Black Elk and Eagle Voice are essential to any full understanding of Indian religious ideals.</p>
<p>I am sure you recognize all this as enthusiasm rather than flattery; yet this very enthusiasm itself makes, in a direct inverse proportion, letters an unsatisfactory vehicle for an exchange of ideas. If it is convenient with you, I would like very much the chance to meet with you during the first week of December, for one or two days if possible.</p>
<p>Give my best regards to Mr. and Mrs. Young; and I shall be looking forward to hearing from you soon.</p>
Sincerely, Walt Black