<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 2
EXCELLENCE IN NEW DIMENSIONS
century of service
isu
1870-1970

INDIANA STATE UNIVERSITY TERRE HAUTE, INDIANA 47809
DEPARTMENT OF HUMANITIES

January 4, 1971

Professor John G. Neihardt
Route #7
Columbia, Missouri

Dear Professor Niehardt:
<p>I teach religion, as a dimension of human culture, in the Humanities Department as Indiana State. I teach general courses in world religions and the history of western religions, and my specialty which is the history of religion in American culture. (I did my Ph.D. work under Sidney E. Mead at the University of Iowa.)</p>
<p>The former director of the University of Iowa's School of Religion (now chairman of the Religion Department at the University of California at Santa Barbara), Prof. Robert S. Michalesen, introduced me to <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>. It was love at first reading, for him and for me. (Michaelsen's wife is from the Black Hills area in South Dakota and first heard of the work through his wife's family.) Michaelsen recalled his first reading by saying that he ended the work thoroughly absorbed in the Oglala Sioux world view and Black Elk's encompassing mind and heart; and he was literally in tears. My own first--as well as successive--reading(s) proved similar. And it has become, without question, the most appreciated and valued text I assign to students. In fact, it is one of the few books my students do not re-sell to the bookstore. (Which I trust as one of the few genuine student compliments!)</p>
<p>Over the semesters I have been using this work as a text, it has generated many questions which I've not been qualified to answer. And I have longed to be able to sit down with you as the narrator of this superb book and talk with you about them. Recently I located your address and decided I would express my appreciation to you for the work, and request a possible interview with you sometime in the near future if you're willing to grant such an interview. Would your health/and/or interest be acceptable to granting such a discussion in Columbia? If so, I should like to propose two possible dates to be considered for such an interview: (1) Thursday, Feb. 4, and (2) Fri., Feb. 5. Are either of these acceptable to you?</p>
<p>If either of there are possible, I'd like to suggest that we lunch together at a restaurant with a quiet, relaxing atmosphere and an attractive cuisine. Since I am not familiar with restaurants in the area, I would be glad to abide by your suggestion.</p>
<p>But in any case, I'm most appreciative of your book and would be honored to make your acquaintance and have audience with you regarding the questions and sympathetic concerns students have raised about the loveable, warm and gigantic man to who you've introduced us. Black Elk</p>
Page 3
<p>is a most engaging and respectable human being. Intensely human. And you must be so yourself to have transmitted Black Elk's story to us so sympathetically and movingly.</p>
<p>I will look forward to hearing from you regarding both the possibility of an extended interview with you and in terms of the particular dates I've suggested. If these dates are unacceptable, I should be glad to recieve your suggestions of times more conenient for you.</p>
<p>Thank you for considering this request. All good wishes and deep respect.</p>
Very sincerely,
Edward A. Warner
Edward A. Warner
Assistant Professor of Humanities
                    (and Religion)
<p>P.S. I have accidently made the acquaintance of an ISU co-ed from the Rapid City area with an Indian heritage who had know Ben Black Elk, Adam Two-Two, and Rosie Little Moon. She was able to supply me with general information about the present condition of the Oglalas at the Pine Ridge Reservation, but knew little specifically about Black Elk that was not discussed in your work. (Her name, in case you'd be interested, is Terry Bighcart.)</p>