<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 16
THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA
IOWA CITY, IOWA 52240

Department of English

August 23, 1970

Dr. John G. Neihardt
c/o Mrs. Julius D. Young
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebraska

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I received Mrs. Young's letter Friday. Please thank her for it. And I understand the conditions which prevent you from answering personally.</p>
<p>Would it be possible for me to meet you in Columbia while you are there in early September? I could arrange to be there any time between September 1 and 10, though the 2nd, 3rd, or 4th would be best. What I would like would be to spend a few hours looking at the Black Elk manuscripts and then have a few hours in which to ask you about them, followed by another oppotunity to study the papers in greater detail and in the light of your advice and memories. Perhaps it would be possible to tape our conversation. What would you think? It would be very helpful and convenient to me, at any rate, to have that exact record of what you said. Will your daughter Enid be in Columbia too?</p>
<p>Yes, I am indeed serious xx about/your wonderful work with Black Elk! I have read quite a few books like <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>--in being Indian autobiographies or "life histories" taken down and edited by other people--and to my mind it is far and away from the best. I would send you a copy of my essay on it, but the essay is still in its third revision and won't be finished for several more days. After that it will be a few more days while I get one of the secretaries here to type it.</p>
<p>I am sorry to hear of your accident but glad to know of your continuing vigor and energy. Congratulations on your 89th birthday and, as I interpret from your list of honors, the 3rd Neihardt Day, on the other side of the calender. You are like "Grandmother," the Queen of England, in have two birthdays, real and ceremonial, and especially strong in having one xxx for the North and the pipe and one for the South and the tree!</p>
Sincerely,
<signed>Robert f. Sayre</signed>
Robert F. Sayre
1033 Woodlawn St
IOWA city, Iowa
52240