<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
5
ans. 1-18-73
MISS MABEL BUCKNER 
20 MILLER DRIVE 
<del/>
COLUMBIA, MISSOURI 65201
January 15, 1973
Dear Dr. Neihardt,
It takes incredible temerity for me to write a letter to America's greatest living poet but I can't resist the impulse to try to tell you how much I enjoyed ALL IS BUT A BEGINNING. 
When I read the lines," hold fast, hold fast, there is more...." and turned to find they were really the last-there was no more- I felt deep regret and hoped the lines might be a promise of another volume soon. 
Your book has everything to make it great: humor that may cause a smile, a chuckle, or a spontaneous laugh; poignancy that brings a tears; and beauty that causes one to rered a phrase or a paragraph several times to savor the poetic flow of the words and the aptness of the choice. To me, it is magic. 
My acquaintance with Dr. Neihardt goes back many years to my teaching days at Christian( now Columbia) College when each year you came to read your poems to our 350 students. I recall that your beloved Mona sat on the front row, enraptured and attentive as if she were hearing hte poems for the first time and she would say, "Daddy, read the Easter poem," or"Read the poem about our daughter." And I would think, "Thank you, Mrs. Neihardt, they're the ones I want to hear too tho I suspect I would have had the same feeling about any that she suggested.
I recall that fifteen or more years ago I refused to make apointments with any of my students during the one o'clock hour that your Cycle of the West was being broadcast over KMDUTV. 
Now my great nephew at Missouri University is taking the same course as you recorded it on tape and enjoying it as I and so many hundred listeners did earlier.
I was told by a University of Missouri student in the days that you were giving the course in person that no second hand books were ever available, for all students kept their copies no matter how great their financial needs.  
You have brought great joy to many and are now adding to this number by giving us ALL IS BUT A BEGINNING. May we take this as a promise of more to come! 
Very sincerely yours,
Mabel a Buckner. 
(Miss) Mabel A. Buckner 
2
