<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 28
THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA
IOWA CITY, IOWA 52240
FOUNDED 1847

Department of English

October 3, 1970 

Dr. John G. Neihardt
c/o Mr. & Mrs. Julius D. Young
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I want to thank you and Mrs. Young for your prompt answers to my recent letter and your acknowledgement of the copy of the <underline>Iowa Review</underline>. I hope you like the <underline></underline>Review.</p>
<p>Would it be possible for you to authorize Mrs. Prewitt to send me a Xerox copy of the transcript immediately? Unless I can show it to Merle Brown and the editorial staff of the <underline>Review</underline>, I can, after all, give you no assurance that they will publish it, that is, publish the portion with Black Elk's description of the Vision. Moreover, if I should come to Columbia again, I would like to have had the chance to read it over more carefully beforehadn. Then I would be in better position to discuss it with you.</p>
<p>Any conditions you wish to set on a copy being sent to me I will naturally honor. As I told you in my last letter, I would greatly appreciate having a copy for my own instruction and to improve my presentation of <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline> to my classes, but those wishes must definitely come second to your wishes. So should you wish the Xerox copy returned to you or the Library after my showing it to Professor Brown, I will gladly do that. It would be treated with the traditional confidence of material sent to (or shown to) an editor. Then if further deliberations and preparations are necessary--as they well may be, though I hope not complicated ones--I will be more than happy to accept your invitation for another visit to Columbia.</p>
<p>As I said before, I think this little project could do a great deal xxxxxxx in directing a new audience towards <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline> and Indian experience and culture. What I want, as a scholar, is intelligent appreciation of the Indian way. Learning what I have from your book and from my friend Chuck Storm, I want other people to learn too. And learn <underline>from</underline>, not just <underline>about</underline>. So I think we are on the right road, the "red road". But if you would rather wait until, say, after the publication of my essay on "Vision and Experience in <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>," then I will be glad to hold off on this project. I have been meaning, you know, to send you a copy of the essay, but it is still not in final form.</p>
Page 29
-2-
<p>Perhaps you could also have some one in Lincoln draw copies of my books <underline>The Examined Self</underline> and <underline>Vachel Lindsay: Adventures, Rhymes, and Designs</underline> from the University of Nebraska library; and ask Mrs. Young to read you a little from them. Our acquaintance has been hindered, I think, by our not knowing enough of each other's writing, your very, very extensive writing and my so far very limited publication; And it is, I needn't add, a part of the Indian way to be thorough about getting acquainted!</p>
<p>So please do not think that I am trying to rush you on this little project regarding the Iowa Review. From our own perspectives there is simply no need for it. But reread the conversations I would like to do, as I said, and show them to Merle Brown I would have to do before he could make a decision about publishing the description of the Vision.</p>
Very sincerely,
<signed>Robert f. Sayre</signed>
Robert F. Sayre

Page 30
THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA
IOWA CITY, IOWA 52240
FOUNDED 1847

Department of English

March 19, 1971

Mrs. Hilda Petri
511 Guitar Building
Columbia, Missouri 65201

Dear Mrs. Petri:
<p>I have been meaning for two months or more to answer your letter of December 15 containing your very informative memories of the actual taking of the material from Black Elk and his friends which your father used in <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>. The letter has been on my deak; I have re-read it often; and I have been trying to do what you so wisely recommended in the last paragraph, thinking and dreaming myself back into the situation there in South Dakota nearly forty years ago.</p>
<p>And so, though I have naturally had all the normal distractions and obligations, I haven't forgotten.</p>
<p>I have also wanted to wait in order to send you an offprint of the essay on <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>--and will send one as soon as I get some. (They seem extraordinarily delayed.)</p>
<p>And so, I want you to know how much I appreciate your having written that letter, and having taken the time to make it so vivid and thoughtful. The account you give seems very real and very convincing. And I could see immediately, as soon as I read it, that you had said the kinds of things which your father must have wanted to say when we met last September. He couldn't say all that he needed to. And what a complicated process the original occasion was! I want you to know that I had imagined some of these complications, and so was trying to be as alert and sensitive as possible; but I am also quite ready to confess that on other xxxx points, like Ben Black Elk's facility as a translator, I was way off. For in the 1960 Preface to the book your father said Ben "had attended Carlisle for a year or two," and I took that to mean his English woudl have been very good, or what  is officially called "college level." But I now know, form learning something more about Indian "colleges" and the language conflicts seriously. I still know no more about the colleges and schools supports what you say--this is what I mean. Previously, alas, I had just assumed, well, that Ben's English was a good as Jim Thorp's football!</p>
Page 31
-2-
<p>But I won't prolong this account of my old illusions. I don't know how many I had (or have)--I'd like to think, like anyone else--that they are few adn insignificant; but I also know the traps in <underline>that</underline> illusion. And so I won't go on simply because, when all is said and done, few people are interested in other people's errors.</p>
<p>More to the point is to say that I appreciate your truth, and also appreciate your sense that the project I proposed last fall is ill-advised. I had had reservations about it--despite my apparent forwardness in proposing it--because xx it obviously made your father uncomfortable. I couldn't see why very clearly and didn't think it should make him uncomfortable. That's why I tried to explain it and worked so hard on it. I thought publishing "the transcript" of the conversations would do honor to him and increase knowledge--knowledge of Black Elk and his visions and knowledge of Dr. Neihardt's work. But on the basis of what you have written I can now realize that the process xx or history is probably too complicated for all but a limited number of people to understand. Matters of literary and artistic "influence" or "attribution" are always complex and often become painfully controversial; and in this case there are factors people have even less experience and awareness of, for this is very unusual case indeed. In the case of Boswell's life of Samuel Johnson, for instance, there is a running debate even yet over how much Boswell "made up," how much he edited out, and how much he took straight from Johnson's mouth; and much of that debate is just plain silly, but it goes on. And so it is easy to imagine the double and triple silliness which might rage here over translation, transcription, and whatnot. Better to let sleeping dogs lie (and not get up and makex lies!)</p>
<p>Nevertheless, your father has wanted his papers saved, and I think he has been wise and considerate of future readers and scholars in this wish. I also think that the project I proposed won't say now whether I would then like to undertake it, though you can see my concern about it. My respect and affection for your father, and for you, is greater than I can express. Likewise, my awareness of American Indian culture, what it has endured, and what it has to offer to future generations, grows as I grow. Just now I am working on an index and bibliography of Thoreau's reading on Indians. It is not generally known but in the last 10 years of his life Thoreau copied down over 2,000 pages of notes and quotations xx from over 200 books and articles on the Indians of the Americas. His notebooks are an encyclopedia, in effect, of all a European-American could know at that time, the 1850s. And such care bespeaks, I think, Thorau's vision--not just scholarship but vision--and a vision we are now coming to value, 120 years later.</p>
<p>This, I believe, was also part of your father's vision. And what Thoreau would have give to have been there with you all 40 years ago!</p>
<p>And so , thanks once mroe for your wonderful letter. Being</p>
Page 32
-3-
<p>now occupied with Thoreau, and other themes and subjects, too, like the utopia book which I will start this summer, I will not be writing again soon, except to send an offprint of my piece on <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>. That essay, which has been out for about three weeks now, has been very nicely received, and I had a letter from your father this week xxx which was, well, beautiful. This whole experience has been beautiful, despite my illusions and follies, and I want you to know that though I am sorry for the concern I xxxxxxx have incidentally caused him and you and your sister Enid, I am also grateful for your help and my education!</p>
Very sincerely,
<underline>Robert f. Sayre</underline>
Robert F. Sayre