<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 43
SOUTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY
BROOKINGS, SOUTH DAKOTA 57006
College of Arts and Science
ENGLISH DEPARTMENT
December 4, 1968

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I apologize for waking you out of your nap this afternoon, but I understand you were about ready to get up anyhow. I called, as I explained, to ask you if you could come here to deliver two or three lectures on evenings of your choice during the period from July 7 to July 29. We would, of course, be happy to have you attend the whole period of the Program, giving additional lectures if you wished. I called to inquire particularly what your fee would be per lecture so that we could enter that figure into our applicaiton for a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities. It is certain that unless we get such a grant to fund our Program, we will not be able to present the rather ambitious cultural program we are planning.</p>
<p>As soon as I can get some definite information in brochure form on the specific program, I will send it to you, but we must gather all the probable costs of the summer program before we can prepare a request for the government grant. For this reason we need information about costs now, and until we can find out whether the government will fund the program, we can't prepare an accurate brochure.</p>
<p>Please excuse this hasty note. I write to corrobrate my afternoon's telephone call. I remember that you can't be absolutely sure you will be fit following your January operation, but I think we can be certain enough that if you are willing to come in July, you will be able.</p>
<p>I have since my last letter read <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>, and it is a beautiful book about a noble man who must be one of the most poetic of failures in recent times; at least he thought of himself as a failure, but I hear his voice in all the Indians who are now belatedly speaking out for Indian Power. Mr. Martin sends his regards, and I add my own, hoping you will have a very happy holiday season and a very good 1969.</p>
Sincerely,
<signed>Jack W. Marken</signed>
Jack W. Marken
Head, Dept. of English
JWM/ril
<p>A land-grant university serving South Dakotans through Teaching-Research-Extension</p>