<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 15a
<bold>National Society Daughters of the American Revolution</bold>
MRS. WILLIAM HENRY SULLIVAN, JR., PRESIDENT GENERAL
<symbol>DAUGHTERS OF THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION</symbol>

MISS DOROTHY D. DRENNAN, VICE CHAIRMAN
120 NORTH MADISON
TAYLORVILLE, ILLINOIS 62568
NORTH CENTRAL DIVISION

PROGRAM COMMITTEE
MISS LAURA DICKERSON, NATIONAL CHAIRMAN
135 FALMOUTH STREET
WILLIAMSTOWN, KENTUCKY 41097

March 3, 1969
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>At long last the Christian County History is printed! I am enclosing photostatic copies of pages 97 and 98 whereupon you will find "Prairie Poet Lauraeate of America". It is in the section of the book entitled Christian County Celebrities and is found in the second part of the book pertain-ing to the last fifty years of history of the county.</p>
<p>We are very proud to have included your biography together with your two selections"
Hymn Before Birth and 
April Theology
These I did not photostate.</p>
<p>Other celebrities who gained national prominence included in this section are: Geophysicist- Leason Adams, Space Scientist-David Aldrich, Foreign Executive, James Hugh Angleton; Olympic Gold Medal Winner, Ronald Bontemps; Founder of Boys State, Harold Card; Music Industrialist, David Carroll; Chairman of the Republican National Committee, Thomas H. Carter; Medical Director, Donald Casely; Sculpton, Leonard Crunelle; Labor Arbitrator, Walter Daykin; Postmaster General, Jesse Donaldson;Big League Coach, Charles D ressen; Apostle-Re-organized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints, Cecil Ettinger; Ecnomist, Edward Garrett; National Commander American Legion, Edward Hayes; Mr. C. I. O., Alan Haywood; Supreme Court Justice, Harry Hershey; (Poet Neihardt) Nobel Prize Winner, Edward Purcell; Folklorist, Franz Rickaby; Composer, Thomas Rickaby; Supreme Court Justice, James B. Ricks; President of Union Carbide and Carbon, Jesse Ricks; Author, Vincent Sheean; Dime-Novel Hero, <crosse>Henry</crossed>Richard Tanner ("Diamond Dick") Automotice Engineer, Col. Jesse Vincent; Inventor, John Wahl; Crop-Breeder, Dr. Charles R. Weber; Blackhawk War General, Whiteside; Violinist, Florian Zabach; Commderal Artist, John Zwinak;</p>
<p>These I name so that you may know what company you keep!  It has been an outstanding experience in my work as editor to have made your acquaintance, I shall treasure it. Thank you and Mrs. Yound so very much!</p>
Sincerely,
Dorothy D. Drennan