<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 51
New Market, Iowa
Box 223
December 19, 1968

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I had much difficulty in contacting you by phone this evening, but it was well worth the effort as it was a rewarding experience talking with you. I felt flattered that you should remember me of fourteen years ago, and I would like to relate to you that I have prepeatedly used your work for speech contests over all these years, in-variably realizing high success.</p>
<p>I am at present doing an extensive paper as a Master's work at Maryville and have chosen A CYCLE OF THE WEST as my choice of Epic.</p>
Page 52
<p>I know that you are very busy and I do not wish to impose upon you, but it would be a great asset to me if you should see fit to write me a few lines as to your feelings of your work, as was understood in our phone conversation.</p>
<p>I would not ask you to write an extensive letter, as I do not wish to impose upon your generous disposition, but I feel that a few lines concerning A CYCLE OF THE WEST as an Epic would serve as a definate assest to this paper which is so important to me.</p>
<p>In closing, I would like to say that nothing would please me more than meeting you in person as I have read and re-read your work with never-ending joy.</p>
<p>While my paper is due within the near future, I feel that the instructor will make allowances for the time element required for your reply.</p>
<p>Thanking you in advance for whatever you may see fit to write me, I express my deep gratitude and appreciation for your time and effort envolved.</p>
Yours Most Sincerely
Max D. Carpenter
Page 53
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
December 31, 1968

Mr. Max Carpenter 
New Market, Iowa

Dear Mr. Carpenter:
<p>It was good to talk to you by phone, and I was glad to receive your letter.</p>
<p>Naturally I am greatly interested in your writing a dissertation on my work. In this letter I will answer your specific questions, and later on, if you need me, you may call on me.</p>
<p>You asked for some general statement about my <underline>Cycle of</underline> the West. Here is a paragraph that you may want to quote from me:</p>
<p>The <underline>"Cycle"</underline> celebrates the greatness of the human spirit in conflict with the forces of nature and the tragic whimsies of Fate. This is true generally of all epics, for it expresses the characteristic epic mood. The five Songs are bound together by this dominant theme, surely the greatest theme in the world.</p>
<p>You asked why the stories were chosen for the various songs. In each case I was seeking a dramatic representation of the epic spirit in keeping with the time and locality.</p>
<p>You will note that there are three progressions in the <underline>"Cycle</underline>". First, the geographical progression, from the Missouri River to the Pacific Ocean. Second, the historical progression from the spring of 1822 until the Battle of Wounded Knee in December, 1890. Third, the spiritual progression from the basic level of mere physical courage to the highest spiritual comcep-tion of man's relation to man and to the divine.</p>
Page 54
<p>It has been said that this is the only epic that ends on a high spiritual note. There is something to consider in the statement, properly understood. At the end of the<underline> Song of the Messiah</underline> we have the spiritually defeated marching off with guidons flying and the victors lying dead under the snow. They were the victors because they had seen the highest vision of man's relaiton to the human and the divine, and they had given everything of this world as a result.</p>
With kind thoughts,
John G. Neihardt
<p>P.S. I suggest that you make the most of the Introduction to the school edition of <underline>The Songs of Three Friends and Hugh Glass</underline>, published together. It will give you my theory of the epic.</p>