<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
ans 1/17/73
1-4-73
1
Dear Dr. Neihardt, Myrtle, J.D. & (of course) Joquot:
I meant to get a holiday greeting off to the Lincoln branch of my Nebraska friends, but flu interfered. For heaven's sake, Myrtle--protect our Gaki. Don't let anyone near him who might possibly have been exposed to this awful English flu. I am hale and hearty--and thought I'd die! Bone-crushing aches and pains and a 103<figure/> temperature for 36 straight hours. And my case was one of the light ones: ehere are people here whose high temps last 5 and 6 and 7 days! Please protect our friend! He's too valuable.
It has been unseasonably rainy around here. Then on New Year's Day the sun came out--shocking us all--and the temperatures hit the 50's and60's. Today it is a bit more like it: cold and crisp. Still no sign of snow in Manhattan, though. We all keep waiting for it because when it snows it is truly lovely here for a few brief moments (before the air pollution settles on the snow and the 500,000 dogs come out and <del/> do their duties on it).
I am looking forward with bated breath to the February Neihardt piece in Saturday Review. Cross your fingers that the editors haven't gotten hold of it and "edited" it beyond measure.
The Neihardt Christmas card was very special--thank you so much. Your daughter did such a fine job of capturing the Tree of Life. 
I have been relatively busy back here. My agent called and I have a piece <del/> coming out in the Febr. or March <del/> Ladies' Home Journal. I did the <del/> copy editing on my book (which will be out in April) and am working on two magazine pieces right now. It keeps me busy and pays the rent--but I'll sure never get rich at this! 
I'm still hoping for a spring and summer at home in my <del/> beloved Nebraska. Just hope everything works that way! 
Please excuse this frightful typing. My historic old apartment in this historic old house--has historic old heating. And the heat never quite makes it up to my apartment. Fortunately I ahve an electric typewriter which can take over somewhat--but still my fingers get so cold they get jammed up periodically! 
WELL__just wanted to wish you all well. And warn you against this flu. It is so awful and Gaki really should cut down on his visitor til this thing blows over. (Aren't I terrible--doing all my long distance fussing and worrying!) 
Take care, all of you. Hope to see you in <del/> the Spring. 
Love and peace,
Katie 
1