<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 1
THE PLAIN DEALER
OHIO'S LARGEST MORNING AND SUNDAY NEWSPAPER
1801 SUPERIOR AVE.
CLEVELAND, OHIO 44114
PUBLISHED BY
THE 
FOREST CITY
PUBLISHING COMPANY
CLEVELAND, OHIO 44114
At Home,
July 5, 1968
Dr. John G. Neihardt
English Department
University of Missouri 
Columbia, Missouri
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>I run a question-and-answer column for the Sunday Plain Dealer's <unclear>roto</unclear> maga-zine. Recently an item appeared which <unclear>bestirred</unclear> a dozen or readers who identified for me your poem "Let Me Live Out My Years."</p>
<p>I thought you might like to know that some of the readers sent me copies of your poem, and stated that it was a favorite of theirs. I now number it among my favorites, too, and feel rather stupid that I didn't know it before.
Would you be willing ot autograph the enclosed copy? I'd like to frame it for my den. All the best, with my deepest thanks and appreciation. John Huth Jr. </p>
Page 2
Let Me Live Out My Years
<lg><l>Let me live out my years in heat of blood!</l>
<l>Let me die drunken with the dreamer's wine!</l>
<l>Let me not see this soul-house built of mud</l>
<l>Go toppling to the dust - vacant shrine!</l>

<l>Let me go quickly, like a candle light</l>
<l>Snuffed out just at the heydey of its glow!</l>
<l>Give me high noon - and let it then be night!</l>
<l>Thus would I go.</l>

<l>And grant that when I face the grisly Thing,</l>
<l>My song may trumet down the gray Perhaps!</l>
<l>Let me be as a tune-swept fiddlestring</l>
<l>That feels the Master Melody - and snap!</l></lg>

John G. Neihardt
(1881 - )
Now You Know
June 2, 1968 = PLAIN DEALER, CLEVE. O.
<p>Q. Hotel Auditorium's dining room more than 20 years ago had a wall plaque of which this was a part: "Like a candlelight snuffed out in the heyday  of its glow, Thus would I go." What was the rest, and who wrote it? -J.R.P., Mentor</p>
<p>A. We've hunted for the anser for many months, without getting a candlepower glimmer. And Charles E. Borcher, the hotel's resident manager, says he doesn't know, either, adding that Mary Gergely, a waitress there 30 years, recalls there was such a quotation. It was removed when the Chalet Room was remodeled 14 years ago.</p>

<p>"LET ME GO QUICKLY-" A poem, once displayed in Hotel Auditorium's Chalet Room and sought by a reader in the June 2 NYK has been identified as part of John G. Neihardt's "Let Me Live Out My Years." from "A Bundle of Myrrh" (1907) and reprinted in his "Collected Poems" (1927).</p> JUNE 26, '68
<p>Lincoln Cahn, Geneva, recalls that the wall plaque at the hotel used the title "The Prayer of Youth." Other readers identifying the striking verse included Mrs. JOhn H. Brenneman, Greenville, Pa.: Mrs. Gerald W. Bunyan, Avon; R. G. Geiger Jr., North Canton, and Dawson Kelly and Robert Barnett.</p>
<p>Office address of Neihardt, who was born in 1881 is: English Department, University of Missouri, Columbia, Mo.</p>