<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 29
May 19, 1969
Dear John, 
<p>The manuscript is in the mail, except for "Laurel Decade" which I still have to do some work on. I will send or bring it later. The rest is all there, and I recommend that you read it straight through just as if you never heard of John G. Neihardt (as if <underline>anyone</underline> hasn't!) and it's all new. Then go over it again to make comments. When you see it all at once you get a different effect from reading isolated chapters. Quite a bit of it is new, more about your work.</p>
<p>I should caution you that the footnotes are not accurate. I didn't want to delay getting it to you till I could get all</p>
2
<p>all the corrections in and I can't send my one revised copy. I included them so you could get an idea of what kind of details I've put in footnotes to keep them from interruping the flow.</p>
<p>I will arrive on Saturday the 7th of June, and as soon as I get in I'll call you. We should have some time on Saturday unless the plane is awfully late - it gets in fairly early in the afternoon. I will have to have on the 10th, but not till afternoon, and will have three good days.</p>
<p>One of my English department colleagues has been reading the chapters- she knows criticism, and she teaches modern poetry. You'll be interested in her reaction. SHe wants to read the whole <underline>Cycle</underline> straight through, and she says</p>
Aly__    5-21-69
Page 30
3
<p>your work is impressive and you <unclear/> sound like a great win if you have never written anything. I think myself the <underline>Song of the Poet</underline> is the best of all - and that doesn't run down the epics either.</p>
<p>It will be very good to see you - it <unclear>sure</unclear> like a long time. I have been with you so much in my mind that I can hardly believe it is <underline>two years</underline> since we've talked face to face. We have a lot to catch up on.</p>
<p>I'm trying to write this in <underline>big</underline> handwriting. It's wonderful that your eyes can be better - won't they go on improving as you recover form the surgery?</p>
<p>Bower sends love. He is very busy all the time, and we don't play often- we almost have to make appointments to see each other. He is reading the</p>
4
<p>manuscript, too - he says it's about his favorite poet. I will store up all his comments for you, and I may quote Stewart too. He sends love, by the way. Stewart still considers that he has a special position with you as honorary grandson. I'm enclosing a copy of his announcement- he's getting married in September.</p>
<p>I hope you like the book!</p>
<p>More later- I have an appointment with a lot of footnotes.</p>
Love to you and to the Youngs,
Lucile