<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
228 - <strike>229</strike> Fink Collection 12
Neihardt 
Branson Mo.
BRANSON. 
SEP 8
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs O. F. Fink 
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis County
13
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Saturday 
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>You'll know by the Knife Daddy has been making ever since be returned Home, how much he has been thinking of you - The blade goes clear through the handle and the brass band he made to fit! You'll have no more trouble cutting - but <underline>be careful</underline> of your thumbs and fingers as I cut mine up miserably on Daddy's brand of knives!!</p>
<p>You'll wonder what I</p>
14
2
<p>have been doing, so here you are:
Cutting grass, washing clothes, transplanting Geraniums etc. house cleaning, changing furniture to suit the new needs. Cleaning out the shed, <underline>Daddy and</underline> I together - Burning trash and making room for our wood supply. Putting the children's thing away in closets etc - besides getting meals for <underline>two</underline>, which is a pleasant game! Today Daddy has been pulling weeds and grass, also cutting with the sickle where I could not mow with the mower. Next week he'll use the scythe where necessary, on the West and South where the grass is very tall. - Yesterday</p>
15
3
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>we got Mrs Miser to go with us for a little ride in our car, stopped for some ice cream on the way home which we enjoyed in our cool dining room.</p>
<p>Your Kitchen Linoleum gave me the idea to fix up mine - So now it is white with blue stippling. Tomorrow I am going over the whole thing with the clear varnish Sigurd gave me. Daddy and I are both pleasantly surprised at the pretty result. Next I'm going to stipple the bathroom</p>
16
4
<p>with pink on white foundation. Swell not? This is thanks to <underline>you</underline>, although I have done mine a little differently - so you'll have to come Home to see it!</p>
<p>Next comes the ironing then a crate of tomatoes to can, then a bushel of lovely apples - wish you had some just like 'em! After that I have to go after our dining room ceiling and front room walls before I can get down to what I want to do: sculp Daddy for the last and best time.- No I'll have no</p>
17
5
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>time to be lonesome, really! Besides all these things I have to make Alice a coat of <underline>hard, black</underline> material, and then get around to my own clothes!</p>
<p>Please tell Mrs Harrison I think of her as a ver dear friend of yours and am so grateful and glad she is so close - The next time I come up I'll certainly stop and see her. Enid Darling I do</p>
18
6
<p>want you to take these Ozark babies over to Mr Vollruer when you have the leisure and ask him to fire them and then give them a pale pink glaze - They should be on sale at the Art center on Enclid. When he has them finished ask him to deliver them there - He Knows the outfit, and tell him to do them at his convenience when he has the right space in the proper Kiln - Love to Ollie the best of men, and love to you, dearest of women from your grateful and devoted</p>
Mom - MotherJ




