<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<unclear/>27 Fink Collection 1
1940
Wednesday
Afternoon.
Dearest Enid of mine:
<p>Your good letter made me feel your eagerness for a little Stranger - and surely you will be blessed with his or her arrival. I would be too thrilled to have a May-baby - and yet any mouth is O.K. when such dear good Parents are behind it!</p>
<p>So do not be over excited, my darling, and Know that I am feeling all you are experiencing <underline>with</underline> you. It is hard to feel <underline>quiet</underline> that I Know - but it is good for one!</p>
<p>I went out yesterday morning and layed down a red rose shoot, a snowball, a mock-orange. So now there are those for you to plant next Spring besides the Wistaria, the flowering almond, the Forsythia and the pale pink, doubl<unclear/> Althea. You may have some of these but I'll bet you can use one from each of these varities here at home.</p>
<p>Our morning glories are now all blooming in masses - the back</p>
2
<p>fence is truly lovely. The ones behind the baby in the pool that refused to bloom, are now also beinning - so I hope they may continue<strike>s</strike> clear into late Fall. Our geraniums are again starting to bloom, we have <underline>3</underline> in bloom now.</p>
<p>Enid darling, the girls always tell me of the good times you prepare for them. Maxie was sorry too she could not go but you realize how terribly full her days are, don't you? I mean really <underline>too</underline> full.</p>
<p>Daddy and I are having a real rest. We miss all of you dreadfully but we are surely getting things done that we need quiet for. So we are very contented. Enid, my head of Daddy is progressing almost too quickly, since I'll have to leave it till we return from our Denver trip. But it surely is a powerful thing. I am glad I can say this myself. Daddy says it is corking.</p>
3
<p>I am going to be so glad to meet Allen True when in Denver, that will be nice, won't it?</p>
<p>I am very busy with my clothes now and feel I am getting along nicely. My hat is done and <strike/> surely good looking - Frankie is going to take a look at my coat tonight - It looks swell to me - and she will help me fit the velvet skirt part of my dress. The top is of all over lace - it is <underline>very</underline> becomming I think!!</p>
<p>Your wee lemon tree has two new leaves, and the ice plant looks adorable hanging in the center of our front window by a wickerhandle I found here abouts <unclear>au'fastened</unclear> to the little can you gave it to me in, making a sort of hanging basket of it.</p>
<p>We are in for golden Fall weather again, and the place is begging for a visit from some of you folks!?</p>
4
<p>I have <underline>almost</underline> washed all of our windows now, but there always seem to be yet a few more!</p>
<p>I have 47 quarts of canned goods now. I just finished 6 pints of Chili Sauce and 3 of little yellow tomato preserves. Do you remember how you loved them in Nebraska?</p>
<p>Mr. A.E. Long's son and his little wife dropped in here a few days ago - Strange how empty such young people are, not at all like you folks or the rest of our children.</p>
<p>A Springfield lady bought Dr John Mitchels' place next to Cautwells and she is making it a for rent Place with <underline>three</underline> new houses on it, and her own. Madge Bennet's is beign stuccoed cream, she still wants to sell it - so there's your chance!! <underline>Are</underline> you <underline>now</underline> buying from Harrisons?</p>
<p>Loads of love always to my Enid and her Ollie.</p>
from 
Mama Mother.
