<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
48
Saturday afternoon
October 5, 1940
Dearest Mama and Daddy!
<p>We were all so happy to get your letters with all the good things they told us. Now you are happily on your way, and we are eager to learn how you are and all other things.</p>
<p>Many thanks for the check for twelve, Daddy. I keep an account for Alice, so we can see when adn for what the money was spent.</p>
<p>I am very happy to say that in my voice I have suddenly made a real improvement that seems to be the way of it - for some space of time seemingly no progress, and then all of a sudden quite some <unclear/> is made. I now know the whole Jewel Scene (17 pp.) by herat. Sig and I will work on it tomorrow. All I learned </p>
49
<p>from Jeannette as for as the Jewel Song is concerned is that she is very out of place in opera. <unclear/> act time I hear her sing it, it seems worse. Max and I agree that she "butchers" it especially teh "Roix de Thule". A <strike/> metallic voice can be nice and even beautiful in an ordinary song, but it is no good for the "Jewel Song", in which every tone must be a jewel in itself. So much for that. I have a new song, "La Violetera", a Spanish number. I have a record of Luerezia Bari singing it - very fascinating! I am very happy over my voice as it has been of late. I feel I'll never again let it go for as long a time as I did this summer. Sig and I shall be able to practice now only on Sundays. But I am doing a great deal by myself now. I practiced about an hour on the Jewel Scene last evening and</p>
50
2.
<p>have done exercise today. Tomorrow is Sunday, and Monday I have another lesson. So it is not so bad. I should make real progress now. I really feel so excited about it, for one reason or another.</p>
<p>Yes, Mama, I hear from Max several times a week. He writes me such nice letters. Max plans to return as soon as he gets the needed papers from Switzerland. He must be back by the end of October to make and send out a new catalog.</p>
<p>My loan at the bank is now all paid off! That is a "great" feeling, to say the least. Now I am going to be on the up-grade soon.</p>
<p>I am so pleased the radio is going again (just in time for your departure!)</p>
51
<p>I do not mind working at the office now any more. It is very nice, really, and I was just in a fussy mood for a while there. I'll be so glad when I can start saving money once mroe, so I'll not feel I'm getting nowhere. I am just waiting for the<underline> moment</underline> when I feel I am ready to sing.</p>
<p>You saying all those lovely things about my voice makes me very happy and helps a lot. I will say that I never hear a soprano who has more than <underline>I</underline> shall have in time. Sig is going to give me piano lessons, and I am going to go at that very hard. Monday morning he is going to <unclear>Hunleth's</unclear> pick out a really good book for me to use. He says the one I have will not do. With piano to my credit, even just a <unclear/> sort of "singer's piano",</p>
52
3.
<p>I'll gain <underline>years</underline> in my singing.</p>
<p>Alice has just come home, <underline>very</underline> happy over the way she danced at her lesson today!! She is such a cute girlie! She looks lovely now, especially with her new hairsytle!! She is really very pretty and very well-looking. We are all very well looking!</p>
<p>I shall clsoe for now.</p>
<p>Wishing to hear from you very soon---</p>
Endlessly loving you both, 
Hilda
<p>P.S. Daddy, Alice just remarked about what you said about your thinking of her dancing effortlessly, adn she thinks it is working. She has improved these last days so much. Perhaps you have been thinking of my singing too? If not, please do. And think of me</p>
53
<p>singing with perfect tones, absolutely clear and flowing. Also you might envision me trilling perfectly! this sounds a bit silly - but there is no doubt that things come that way. Mr. Serak believes so much in the power to accomplish of thought and concentration. I am thinking practically all the time of singing and all such lovely thoughts!</p>
<p>glad that I am impressive as Madam <unclear/> yesterday, - and see no reason why thought keep right on going up, <unclear/> you?</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I'm so glad you're going together on your <unclear/> trip. That is certainly as it should be. I say three cheers for your lovely trip too!</p>
<p>We are all well and very happy that is, as much as possible in this period of transition. Won't it be marvelous when our plan is working?</p>
<p>Daddy, I know that you have been and are helping me in much more than a <unclear/> way. The last two days I had good lessons and today I had a very good one. Madame said I put feeling in my dancing and complimented me <unclear/> <unclear/>. Several of the girls said my work looked beautiful today <unclear>and</unclear> real dancing. One, <unclear>Joanie</unclear>, <unclear/> said "What happened all of a sudden?" I said I didn't know, but I do, for I'm sure you have been communication wtih something for me! I am <underline>so</underline></p>
(<unclear/>)