<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
122 Finn Collection 74
PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
SIGURD NEIHARDT, MANAGER
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON
APR 21
3 -PM
1939
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs Oliver F. Fink
9716 Hawthorne St.
Overland, 
Mo.
St Louis 
County.
75
Friday
A.M.
Dearest Enid and Ollie
<p>You may feel with us down here for after using over 12 <unclear>ricks</unclear> of wood and over 8 tons of coal we are still shivering around as the fuel is all gone, cleaned up to the last scrap, and it is April just the same as it is up there! and yet it is miserably uncomfortable - The place however is very lovely, every thing a glorious, clear green and there is some blooms on the cherry tree - also the lilacs are budded and the red red rose behind the pool is thick with tiny buds. I am placing the darling bird house on the right hand side of the arch formed by this rose and above the Van Fleet rose on top of a cedar post. My Sweet Peas are up - but I only just planted my Naturtiums, so you are ahead of me with them, and with the Zinnias also - which I planted yesterday. Also some big, beautiful</p>
76
2
<p>pansies, like yours.</p>
<p>I had a wonderful trip, sat right in front and rested all the way - I can return to you <underline>any</underline> time you need me - so count on that.</p>
<p>I enjoyed you both and my little visits, and I shall always cherish the memory of them. I have your pictures on the small Walnut table besides the big Oriental Lamp there and everyone admirers it and likes it of both of you. I found the double bed that was yours in the guestroom - So when you come you will sleep in it - and I know you won't mind!</p>
<p>Sig put his desk up there too since Dad has his work table in my studio - and I don't know where I will be when I <underline>do</underline></p>
77
3
<p><unclear>ulp</unclear> - but I believe it will be out of doors, which is the <underline>best</underline> studio after all, requiring only God's Light and Aloneness - no electrical assistance and no bulky instrument! such as Daddy and Sigurd need for their hand work._</p>
<p>A strong boy will be here after school to help be arms and legs for Daddy who is going to have some cedar posts set in, and the drain-pipe cleaned. It is so wonderful to be doing things on this dear place.</p>
<p>We sent the girls some snaps yesterday to be <unclear>devided</unclear> with you. There was only one of Maxie in the bunch, and you'll have to fight over that one!</p>
<p>I have your curtains up in the front room - instead of my old ones, There was just enough - and we all love their warmth and material beauty, fitting perfectly into</p>
78
<p>our color scheme.</p>
<p>The blue and white table cloth is on the dining table - an you may picture it there most of the time for it is <underline>exactly right</underline>!</p>
<p>So very many thank for all your gifts, both of you dear children!</p>
<p>Everyone here loves to hear all about you and I'm having a lot to tell them.</p>
<p>We are eager for your next visist and hope you make it snappy!</p>
<p>Daddy, who <underline>loves</underline> your onyx is so weet and dear, and I hope he will get over the cold he seems to kepp - due to this chilly weather.</p>
<p>They leave Sunday for Lincoln -</p>
Loads of Love to my Enid and Ollie
from Mom, Mother.