<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
242 Fink Collection 36
BRANSON
DEC20
3 -PM
1940 
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
MO
St. Louis Co.
37
Enid Darling:
<p>Your good letters have been very much appreciated. It is too bad that Elaine has taken on those monkey tricks of Dicky-boys. If I were you I would help Maxie by stopping anything of the sort by simply saying that you cannot allow any such going on in your home - or elsewhere. You don't allow any little girl to tug and pull at you nor to make silly faces etc. I had to do thsi with Joanie and it was <underline>very</underline> easy to get her to feeling ashamed and sorry. I cannot believe Elaine would be any more difficult to handle. Joanie heard us talking about your letter - and she said "Nanny write and tell Aunt Enid that I am <underline>not spoiled</underline> and that I don't do those "sings" any more! - so I told her I certainly would! She is the dearest and the brightest little girl! She spells on her blackboard - truly it is remarkable! and now she is starting to make a comforter top of squares sewed together to form blocks. She has two all done and starts on the third tomorrow. I crease the line so that she can <strike>stitch</strike> sew strainght across! Bless her heart!</p>
<p>We just came back from a walk on Dewey Bald - We love that mountain and pretend we are buying it and building a house on top and running cattle and sheep on its hill sides etc - it is fun!</p>
<p>Joanie wants to</p>
<note>text underneath is upside down to flow of letter</note>
Featuring the Scenic Wonders of One of the Nation's Outstanding Regions-by Screen Projection of Natural Color Photography
THE ILLUSTRATED LECTURES
OF 
FRANK LAUDER
SIGURD NEIHARDT
Booking Agent
BRANSON
MISSOURI
38
<p>stay there always, she says!-- I made her two shirts out of old ones of Daddy's and she wears them in her overalls, reminding me of you children long ago.- The days are so short now that they are passing very quickly. I am about to finish Daddy's bust and hope to send you a picture soon.</p>
<p>Your dear Xmas card came, and I thank you so very much for it. The long package is in our ice box where it will stay till Xmas. Thanks again to Ollie and your dear self.</p>
<p>"We" expect to finish Jed in February. I am wondering if we will then be able to come to you for our visit! I hope so - but one can only live a tick at a time.</p>
<p>It is a wonderful comfort to Know you and Ollie are doing so well and are</p>
39
<p>being so happy. Too bad about Mrs Facke - Please give my kindest regards to Mrs Harrison.</p>
Love to you both
from your devoted
Mama
Mother.
Dear Ones:
<p>You bet you can depend on those walnut legs. I'll cut the board today &amp; have it sawed Monday. They will be about 1 3/4 in square at top &amp; tapered. Getting on finely with the work,</p>
Love
Dad
<note> text underneath is from margins of letter</note>
<p>Enid, I've just finished Max's ring to replace the one I made that didn't hold up. Do <underline>you</underline> too want a crystal - jade ring? I have the material, if you do.</p>
<note>text underneath is upside down to flow of letter</note>
SIGURD NEIHARDT
Booking Agent
BRANSON
MISSOURI