<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
137 Fink Collection 27
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
SIGURD NEIHARDT, BOOKING AGENT
BRANSON, MISSOURI

BRANSON
AUG 5
3 --PM
1939
M.O.

Mrs Oliver Fink.
9716 Hawthorne Ave.
Overland,
Saint Louis County
Mo.
28
Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie
<p>Your good letter, as well as the wonderful news everyone gives of you makes me very happy. You surely have helped a lot at a time when help w<unclear/> most acceptable - and my thanks go out to you in great waves of love. </p>
<p>Now you can rest a bit, Enid darling, form the exertion of caring and cooking for a big family!!</p>
<p>The preserves look <underline>so</underline> perfect I would hate to break into them if the taste of the lovely jelly did not make me eager for more such delicious <unclear/>. So you can bet both jars will soon be empty - Thanks for them too.</p>
<p>Sig is just getting started on Hilda's accompaniments and Oh, how beautiful they sound! I can scarcely wait for them to perform together! Alice practiced with Max yesterday afternoon, while Daddy and Sig and I went to Springfield with the model of Old Matt's Cabin - which we left with the Aluminum founder, who is to make two copies today, and on Monday A.M. we are to take them to the Bronze man, or better <underline>iron</underline> foundry to reproduce in grey iron - then by the end of the week we may hope for some finished pieces to take to the gift shop in Branson and to Mrs McDa<unclear/>, the owner of Matt's Cabin, both</p>
29
<p>eager to have them for sale. Please hold your thumbs for use and pray that I sell at least $1000 sets this year, which would mean $500.00 cash returns. I'll feel as though I were worth my living then - because I simply cannot believe that it is my destiny to be a burden in <underline>any</underline> way. I feel capable, and not old or ailing and I cannot give up trying to make good with my gifts however great or sell it may be I Know <underline>it is real</underline> and the proof of the pudding is in the eating! I am <underline>so</underline> grateful Daddy is so sweet and willing to help me. He says he believes in this thing being a moeny maker - so I am in luck.. I hope I hope....!</p>
<p>We are having marvelous weather and practically no mosquitoes - and they flowers are gorgeous in the pool - Oh do try to come down soon, and of course be sure to come in October to stay as long as possible. Everyone joins me in sending you much much love and more Kisses than you may want.</p>
Devotedly Mom.Mother