<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
86
107
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON DEC16 3-PM 1938 M.O. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS
Mr. & Mrs. O. F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne Ave 
Overland, 
St. Louis Count 
Mo. 

Thursday or Friday! 
87
Enid darling: 
We all enjoyed Ollies letter about the convict so very much. Be sure to send his articles everyone - 
About Xmas - that will be simply grand for you to arrive in the night - and go straight up to the little room at the head of the stairs. There are 2 beds but you'll probably curl up in one of them. Yes, bring plenty of bedding for you. We are delighted about your bringing the ducks - that will be swell. i have been writing Hilda about Joanies doll 

88
and Elaine's "Panda". I asked her to attend to the shopping very soon for we, adding whatever she wanted to, to the sum of $5.00 which I will send her next week. I was afraid something might keep you from coming - and that the children's Xmas would be spoiled if we did not have the doll and the Panda here in ample time - So I asked her to attend to them and send them. Please Enid talk to her at once and find out if she has attended to this for me or not. Thanks to you for all your planning and helping - It will be a wonderful Xmas for us, having you here and sharing our Xmas tree and Home on that day, and I do so hope you will not be too tired ot be happy while here - It is so good of you and Ollie to be planning for us all - 

89
we will enjoy your ducks and dressing - and every thing - and please do not spend too much money - as we are not spending any extra. It will be simp-ly grand to have you! You will have a surprise at once when you arrive, and what you will see is our Xmas present from Sig!-
I am so glad you have started to sew a lot - you can do wonders with the needle Enid - you know you have the gift - and the sewing machine is the finest thing you could have re-arived to make your days useful and happy. It is so lovely that you are 

90
<unclear/> Alice. She will appreciate that as much as I do. It will be a real job to make that elaborate costume - I hope it will not be too hard to do - I wish I might be able to help on it too. 
Thanks again and again, darling. 
I am so happy that you girls are together a lot - that made it bet-ter for me - 
I am quite busy on Mr Good now - Hope you can see a good job when you come - besides the "baby" in the Ozark - bed. 
Loving you as always
Mom-Mother. 
