<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
25
49 Piper Collection 
GRINNELL DEC28 5 PM 1930 IOWA 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 2CENTS2
Miss Mildred Piper 
Wayne State Normal 
Wayne Nebr. 
a.m. Neihardt 
1234 West St
Grinnell 
Iowa 

26
Dec 28-1930 
Grinnell Iow.
My Dear little girl-
As Ever your presence was very dear and near when I opened the package containing the box of lovely handkerchief making quite an addition the lovely ones of other Christmas so dainty - so dainty! so sweet, so thotful just like your own dear little self.-Santa Clause was very kind this year my 72nd birthday & christmas - I came here the 16 of Nov. just to get away from pointer housekeeping and Expect to stay until the first of march or until the weather is nice down in the Ozarks. John and Mona have moved back to their home in Branson and they will <unclear/> after my home, - Sister and I am making rugs and piecing quilts I expect to go to Lulu's sometime before I return to Branson. 

27
girl I wish you could come to us again, It has been a long time since you were there. John has two cars now Enid and HIlda both drive and of course Sigurd when he is home He came home from St Louis to spend xmas - He is going to the Rankin mechan-ical School - will finish this year, can you realize that Enid and Sigurd are grown - Enid 19 and a very, Efficient Stenographer - Is at home doing the <unclear/> rotary work for her father John says she is fine, and she is so pretty not one bed of the flupper about her - Sigurd is a fine looking boy and doing fine in School, Hilda you remember her as a dear little girl. She is not large for her agents in the Second year of High school and leading all her classe 14 in Dec Alice the apple of Grandma's eye in the foruth grade and a star pupil, loved by Every one - Hilda has the kind of brother father has, is her father's <unclear/> to. 

28
2
Mona is not sculpting now is too busy with her family - is well - still plays the violin and sings, and John you know all about his work. He was given a year's leave of Absence from the P.D. on the same salary. We were worried about his helath was threatened with a nervous break down - He is so much better is out in the woods as soon as the children return from School - such sports. Hilda is quite a sports man is a good shot - both the little girls ride horse back swim and dive. Come down and see what a good cook John is he cooks almsot Everything in holes in the ground, when it is Summer and we all have such a good time gathering persimmons, wild grapes wal nuts butter nuts and hickory nuts, please write and tell me all about 

29
self-as for me I am not strong but am very content and happy, Lulu and her boys drove down from Minneapolis last Summer, I correspond with Mr. Bailey and Bardwell - He has been so nice to write, I Enjoy his letters and I feel as tho I had heard from <unclear/> the weather is turning much colder this morning. - They are still pulling turnups out of my garden down home I suppose this that will soon End Dearest girl this letter carries loads of love to you and all of yours, Had cards from Miss "Fish" & Miss "Knapp" 
very lovingly
Alice M. Neihardt
1234 West St
Grinnell 
Iowa 