<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
22 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 54
[1940]
[40]
<strike>Possibly '39</strike>
Denver, Monday, Oct. 7
Dear Sig:
<p>We hit Denver about 2 o'clock yesterday, having stopped on the way to cook dinner in the cottonwoods along Kiowa creek. Spent several hours around Grandpa Culler's homestead, and had a good talk with one of his old neighbors. We found pieces of dishes, crocks, window glass in front of the wound that was Grandpa's sod house. The huge cottonwoods got a disease two or three years ago and died, but the box alders are still flourishing. All that country is definitely oil land, and Mama &amp; I have flirted with the notion of geeting hold of Grandpa's 160 acres, of things turn out fairly well, A Negro owns it now, and $500 ought to buy it. The stone Grandpacut could be used for a small house, where we might spend a month or two in the best season. There is an oil well about 1- miles away, &amp; south about 30 or 40 miles as one of the biggest oil fields I've seen. Nobody knows when the S <unclear/> field may be developed. But how fine if we could just hold it in the family, you kids or your children might profit, and</p>
<margin>These were great Grandma's dishes. No one <unclear/> ever lived there.</margin>
55
-2-
<p>taxes would be very little. If things turn out fairly well, I may do this. I'd love to build Great Grandma's stone house at last! And with Grandpa's stove. I <underline>remember</underline> the chisel marks on the stove and the look of his chisel 53 years ago. The chisel point was like this: point!</p>
<figure = "handdrawn"/>
<p>the car runs like a sled on smooth ice, and I've kept it greased &amp; cared for very carefully. On those vast plains, 65 m.p.h. seems like <unclear/>, and with no ditches to speak of and nothing in sight but the rim of the earth, it's as safe as 40 m.p.h. other places.</p>
<p>We can see snow on the higher mountains from here.</p>
<p>Say, Sig, Mama &amp; I have talked about your registration. Mama suggested this, &amp; it may be worth doing: Register, not as a mechanic, but as a concert pianist. Momentarily forced to take a job that gives you time to get up a larger repertoire. We can't guess what this version of your</p>
56
-3-
<p><unclear>staties</unclear> might accomplish; but it might be favorable, and could not be unfavorable to your interests. Then, at worst, you could insist upon your mechanical training. You will, of course, given Rankin as your school.</p>
<p>It should do no harm to try this. What do you think?</p>
<p>We'll stay in Lafayette (10 miles from Boulder) tonight, &amp; go on in tomorrow forenoon.</p>
<p>We're feeling bully - in fine shape. We do love this air!</p>
<p>Did you try Peru for a <strike/> $25 fee on the way home?</p>
<p>I can make it to Wayne in <underline>two</underline> days from here - very easily.</p>
Endless love to all of you &amp; each of you there
Dad.
<p>I find a "pasture" wherever I am! At Stockton we</p>
(over)
57
<p>had a little rain <underline>and</underline> a <underline>rainbow</underline>! There was also rain &amp; lightning the night before we reached Denver. It's practically desert.</p>
Dad Gaki
<p>Mama says this is for her too.</p>