<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
56a
May 1, 1942.
1400 N. State
Dear Daddy, Mama, Enid, Ollie, and Nei, Sigurd, Maxie, Joan, Elaine, Albert, and Hilda,
<p>How grateful I am to have such a list of dear people to call "my family"! You have no idea how I think of you, and <underline>how</underline> thrilled I am that you are all together.</p>
<p>It has been very warm here for Chicago - but still not sultry as St. Louis. Last night we had a delightful rain and today it is cooler though still threatening, Great and sudden pulls of wind almost blow one over here near the lake. Oh! I love it. Any day nwo in our leisure</p>
(2)
<p>we shall don or slack and trapesey down to the beach (only 2 blks. from our home) for a sun bath. Soon it will be warm enough to take a dip.</p>
<p>Last Sunday the three of us went to Mc Mullins for a chop suey dinner, and a very lovely evening. Bill's father and Mother and some other friends were there, and all of us enjoyed ourselves greatly. Sylvia and Doris were so thrilled to be included that they still speak of it and it is evident that we will be asked to the older McMullins too. Bill talks and talks about you Daddy, and you, Sig.</p>
<p>Monday we went to rehearse with Ruth Pryor and her partner. We worked on the waltz (overture to the "Fledermaus:) and <unclear/> a Russian character no.</p>
56b
(3)
<p>to "Volga Boatman" and "Two Guitars." Oh! We loved the work. Monday evening we ate out again and came back to our hotel to sleep.</p>
<p>Tuesday we moved to our new home here at 1400 N. State. It is cheaper here than at the hotel, but we think an apt. with cooking possiblities would be still <strike>be</strike> more reasonable. We have also placed an ad. in the Tribune for room and board in exchange for companionship and help to an elderly lady evenings and mornings. If this doesn't pan out we shall move anyway and perhaps get evening work of <underline>some</underline> sort to help out till we begin performing.</p>
(4)
<p>The Countess has sent us (<underline>dear</underline> person that she is) an introduction to a kindergarten principal, as a means of getting a job airing and exercising some professor's children in afternoons. Now, however, it seems that rehearsals will be mostly in the afternoons, when that would take place. Perhpas we can work into this in the evenings - care of children while parents are out, etc. We'll see what works out. Certain recent developments have changed some of our ideas considerably. Yes, we do have problems, but we'll work them out, and be better off for it.</p>
56c
(5)
<p>We have several objections to our place here not enough privacy, certain hours, too heavy food, etc. Hope to get out this week if it's at all possible.</p>
<p>Wednesday we had rehearsal again at 2:00. Worked on waltz with Ruth Pryor, and Russian, with frequent suggestionsby George Leon her partner. Thursday we did a barre here in our room and had rehearsal again at the Jo Keith Studio. Yesterday, Friday, we again rehearsed with Leon alone. Today, which is Saturday, we did a barre here, then left for the Keith studio and rehearsed for about 2 hrs, Besides, we learned several things which may change our plans for the present. Ruth Pryor, first</p>
(6)
<p>of all, will not be <unclear/> to get our act with her into shape in less than three or four weeks. George Leon, on the other hand, is able to get us going in his act after not more than two weeks, for his bookings are already established. You see, some weeks ago he and three girls were all ready to tour when he broke down under the strain of trying to be manager, dancer, director all at one time. Upon becoming ill, he had to cancel engagements for the time being, and let his girls go. Two of them are now working in a line in Canada, so he wants us three to replace those</p>
56d
(7)
<p>three (the 3rd girl is away and perhpas wouldn't care to rehearse 2 more wks. for this) in the act. Since recovering from his illness, George Leon was told by his doctor to give up active dancing. Therefore, a new dancer is comign Monday to replace him, while George himself will be manager and director alone. Now, today, after rehearsing with Ruth Pryor the following plan was proposed. Since George cannot be Ruth's partner as was first planned, and since Ruth cannot promise us work for 3 or 4 wks., George wants us to come into <underline>his</underline> act for the presnt</p>
(8)
<p>Ruth Pryor feels she cannot claim us when George Leon can offer us work sooner. As for our personal desires, we <underline>do</underline> prefer Ruth Pryor's setup, for we love her and her work. Leon's work is mostly character - very good, but not as much in our line as would be work with Ruth Pryor. However, <underline>either</underline> would be grand experiences and good pay - so we'll see. Now, we plan to go to rehearsal Monday with George Leon, work like dogs and ask more about the complete act. Then, later in the week well see Ruth Pryor, for she plans for us to keep</p>
56e
(9)
<p>up rehearsals with her, in order tat we may work together in the future. We shall tell her the <underline>whole</underline> story how we love working with her, how we wished we could do than in preference to Leon's act, and then we'll see if she has anything more to say for the present. She <underline>is</underline> a sincere sweet person and truly wants good for us. That is why she felt she couldn't hold us when Leon could use us sooner than she. It <underline>might</underline> be possible that we could hold out here with evening work, practice and rehearsals during</p>
(10)
<p>day till she could <unclear/> act ready, if she is sure she can do it in a month. <underline>Please</underline> read this carefully (Daddy, please take note!) and tell me at once what you think we should do. <underline>Either</underline> would be good expereince I feel - but the Pryor affair would be nearer to her hearts and our classical work. It would be grand if Leon would book Pryor and our act, but his doctor's verdict cut him out of that, and further more, his <underline>original</underline> act is already booked in many places. I do hope you can understand all of this.</p>
<p>Wednesday evening</p>
56f
(11)
<p>we went to Seymours for dinner and evening. They were simply <underline>lovely</underline> to us - made us write in the Guest Book (after a <underline>sumptuous repast</underline> like we haven't had since we've been here), showed us their marvelous rare books, brought out <underline>all</underline> your books, Daddy, and later on had several good Bookfellows over for delightful conversation as well as ice cream and cookies. We really enjoyed ourselves, and received an invitiation to the Book fellow tea on Mother's Day, May 10<underline>th</underline> besides. I certainly do love teh Seymours - and so do Sylvia and Doris. They are fine, aren't they?</p>
<p>Countess Korzbaka is</p>
(12)
<p>a person I wish you could all meet. Hilda and Albert, she is far dearer and more human than we could find out in our meeting. We love her - and she is being a realy friend and consultant to us. She has invited us to come and see her anytime we wish.</p>
<p>Hilda, our place here is reminiscent of Hotel Clubs, except that the food is even heavier (if possible) and that we have double decker bunks as in the hold of a ship. Howeveer, the people are nice, and try to be nice to us. The <underline>main</underline> objection we have is cost.</p>56g
(13)
<p>Our negro waiter in the dining room here dislikes his job to the point of threatening to quit each day. He likes us and tries to make us eat more than the management desires its guests to do. "Oh wish yo'd eat ten helpings o' these" he siad to me as he brought my second dish of prunes (3 or 4 per dish) day before yesterday morning!</p>
<p>I just thought of something I forgot to mention concerning our work. Ruth Pryor intends to use us <underline>between</underline> bookings with Leon, if possible. This will work out, some way. I feel we will be with Ruth Pryor alone in time. If <underline>both</underline> things work out</p>
(14)
<p><sic>oboy</sic>!</p>
<p>I do appreciate what all of you do and have done for me more than you know. I will <underline>show</underline> you soon in action rather than words. Yes, madame and Dr. Klopper <underline>are</underline> my responsibilities. We haven't written Madame yet because we've wanted to have something definite to tell her first. Also, we dont' want everyone there to know about this fo rthe present. We'll write Madame confidentially, tonight. Please don't tell too much of this yet.</p>
<p>Pray for us. I do hope you are all happy. Daddy's idea sounds interesting,<strike/> would not be too much of a bore for him, as it <unclear/></p>
Loads of Love, 
Alice
<p>For safety's sake, coudl you send 2 or 3 dollars? I keep track of this.</p>