<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
186 Fink Collection 83
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON.
JUN2
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. &amp; Mrs O.F. Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, 
Mo.
St. Louis County
84
Sat. noon.
Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie:
<p>Your good letters have made us feel closer to how things are going for Sigurd, so we thank you very much - Ollie you have "learned Sigurd" in a very short time and you have entirely the same view that we have. Before Sigurd was born</p>
85
<p>I yearned for a son who might be like John adn like my father - and Sigurd certainly is that. He is so much like my father who combined business genius with Music, in which he had been given no training, to that he played entirely by ear. He would come home from a new Operetta with my mother, and would sit down at the Grand and</p>
86
2
<p>play the parts he liked from it - and when worried about some big finanical deal <strike/> he would pace the floor up and down, back and forth, then sit down at the Piano and play rapid, intricate things I did not Know - resolving into some thing simple which I Knew - that always meant Papa was through with what ever it was bothering him -</p>
87
<p>and then come the sweet smile on his dear face - and he would be <underline>my Papa</underline> ready to play with me once more! - So <underline>Dreams do</underline> come true - and some day you and Enid will have a boy who is like you adn like Enid's daddy too!</p>
<p>Sigurd will be happiest in a steady, quiet job with the Piano to glorify his existence night and morning. the car has always been the Devil in his Life</p>
88
3
<p>the Piano has always been his good Angel. Believe his Father and Mother for that! -- Mechanics - if he can save himself from War by using his very sound gift in that direction inherited from John - will benefit him when we go into this hellish war (as John has always Known we would do) So <underline>teaching</underline> Mechanics when they call for such teachers to train</p>
89
<p>the Million Men "they" are now <strike>hiring</strike> calling according to a recent Radio report may be a splendid thing to look in to soon. Maybe you can help in this too Ollie dear.</p>
<p>Maxine is planning to remain here till things are ready and right elewhere - This is the ideal place for the Wubs.-- Alice's recital is</p>
4
90
<p>June 10th and it all but broke my heart to have to stay away. But <underline>you</underline> must go, and then write me about it in detail, <underline>Please</underline>!</p>
<p>"Die Puppen fee" is the very first Operetta I was taken to see by my father in Germany when I was 6 - now Alice is dancing in it!-</p>
<p>John and I are going to be to</p>
91
<p>gether after this - We always are so happy that way. Jed Smith is growing into the grand thing it has to be. John will not stop writing on this next lecture trip as we are going to travel in the afternoons and write in the mornings. We would not go if we did not need the moeny from the lectures - but of course <underline>we do</underline>. When John and I are alone together he does not feel anyone is around!</p>
92
5
<p>and I take joy in being nobody! So the great work progresses.</p>
<p>I am finishing two of the best things I ever did - The Pottery bowl which beats the old sea nymph all to pieces, and a head of our Joanie "Children's faces looking up, holding "Wonder" like a cup!" This last is the mood of it-</p>
<p>I <underline>really see</underline> with my new glas</p>
93
<p>ses - what a difference! And how strange I went so long without them - never guessing my eyes were wrong!-</p>
<p>I'll bring every thing I can Enid for your home - Will lay down a piece of the Paul Scarlet as I dont think it has a runner now. It is a shock now when one suddenly comes upon it, so beautiful!</p>
94
6
<p>a veritable "shout of red" like John's poppy bed!-</p>
<p>Excuse this vague ramble - and Know that I love you so very much always,</p>
Your devoted
Mama-
Mother.

