<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
697 Fink Collection 144
pm June 5, 1941
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Wednesday p.m.
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>Just rec'd the pictures of the bust! And I for half the family, want to say, or <underline>try</underline> to say, how excellent I think it is, &amp; how life-like &amp; true it is! Mom, you should truly feel <underline>deeply</underline> satisfied with &amp; <underline>very</underline> proud of this excellent work of art! It surely <underline>is</underline> Daddy! I know how you feel about it - or <underline>can</underline> I? You've tried for this for so long, &amp; certainly the time has been very well spent. I don't see how anyone can do such a beautiful job of work! The expression in the thing is almost too well done - I had no idea it could be accomplished to such a great degree in sculpture! I've seen a lot of those "busts" at the Art Museum, but they don't do what this does to me! Incidentally, the large picture <strike>one</strike> in which you're standing up next to the bust is an <underline>excellent</underline> picture of you, too! I'd like to frame these two large pictures. The more one looks at those pictures, the finer and more beautiful the bust becomes!! I can't wait for hubby to see them tonight.</p>
<p>Dad, I didn't get to write, as yet, much about the good news from Maxmillans. Ol &amp; I are both so <underline>very happy</underline> about what Latham wrote regarding <underline>Jed</underline>. Of course, we all know the truth about <underline>The Cycle</underline>, but it's good to hear that the publisher, a business</p>
145
2
<p>man gets it too! Ol is going to write very soon. He thinks &amp; talks about you often, Dad, but you know how hard 'tis to write letters! And, too, he's been having it pretty tough at the office. They're tearing down the bldgs. net to the PD &amp; are making terrific "balmings" all day long! It just wears Ol out - all the noise - &amp; he just doesn't feel a lot like doing much when he gets home. He's all excited about the possiblity of the jade stickpin, too!</p>
<p>Sig got us all interested in this Mrs. Denton, the landlady, who is materializing medium. Said that when you &amp; Mom come up, maybe we could get her to come out &amp; give us a seanee. Ol was most interested in the idea. We'd like to have a sort of buffet supper some evening - paotatoe salad, etc. Then afterwards we could have a seanee! She told Sig that Ol &amp; I were going to have a boy! Ha! We'll see! How'd you &amp; Dad like to do this, Mom? Hil &amp; Alice would be here too; maybe Albert, if he'd care to. Might be nice for him! Are you coming up this week - end for Al's recital? It won't get to go, but I went last year! Hope we'll be seeing you!</p>
<p>Maybe you'll be here after all, when the "bunny" arrives!?! I'd like it that way, of course, 'cause I've never had a baby yet!! It's somethin' kinda new &amp; wonderful! Boy, I'm going to <underline>love</underline> it! It's so sweet to feel its</p>
146
3
<p>little body moving around in my tummy! I'm certainly "two" instead of "one" now.</p>
<p>Not a lot <sic>o'</sic> news. But we hope we see you soon.</p>
<p>Sig reports gorgeous things about the home place &amp; the folks in it!</p>
Loads <sic>o'</sic> love, always,
Enid
Enot
<underline>P.S.</underline>
<p>Isn't it a grand coincidence that you finished the bust just as Dad finished <underline>The Cycle</underline>, Mom?</p>    