<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
28 Neihardt Collection 
[J.G. Neihardt 5544 Pershing St. Louis]
147 
July 8th, '36, 
1465 Fourth, 
Louiseville, Ky; 
Dear Dad, 
I rec'd your letter, & am doing the best I can to keep the right state of mind. There is nothing to do. It is so beastly hot outdoors that a fellow would be-a fool if he did much running around I had a fine lesson with Karl Schmidt this morning. It is valuable to me - the many things he teaches. He stressed simplicity of harmonies always. I'll be glad when the book on Indian Song arrives. This will be fine! I'll study it carefully, & will of course get valuable information. 
I had an appointment with Earl Keller for 11:30 today, but while I was sitting at the Studio waiting - he phoned there (from his home in the county) & told me he had been sick with the terrible heat, so could not get to see me 'til Fri. He does seem to be the kind of a 
(over) 

148
-2-
fellow one could depend on. You see he phoned me 'on the dot' when he saw that he couldn't get to town for our appointment. 
I hope you have written to Mrs. Sealock Keller is interested, & I only mentioned to him that you were doing some contacting for no. 
How fine it woudl be to get an audition I feel that the whole trick would be easier after we were once heard. The Baldwin store is all torn up, & on the way to being beautifully decorated. The floor (main one) will be <unclear/> the size before & covered with $1800. Worth of plush rug Tuell has never said anything, even tho! I was informed by the other (Settles that Wyman had been in our store all morning mond. God only knows what they talked about. Anyway I'm not to let it bother me at all. 
The only good in being here is Schmidt, & Keller. I'm at least learning some important things while being as long as possible on this job. 

149
-2-
If Wyman could only talk with me in private instead of referrring all to Tuell - he'd for once find out what's what down here. When I have this opportunity - I'll tell him facts, & without knocking a single name' in the store. He's be surprised at my returning good for evil. There has been much talk & gobble about me while I was away. I can feel this, but they'll never know my tho'ts even tho' I do know theirs! Please take care of yourself in this terrible heat. Many people are beginning to show suffering. I'm getting thinner each day, but so far I feel fine. 
I hope Max will get better soon. I believe it is heat indigestion. 
Always love from myself, also - 
Max & John, 
Sig. 