<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
35a
August 24, 1942
Monday
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad;
<p>We are bacK after a very worthwhile and enjoyable trip. We plan to go bacK to stay just as soon as possible. Sig made some good contacts. We swam in the laKe every day and enjoyed the lovely beaches that strtch for miles along the laKe. It was wonderful weather too.</p>
<p>Alice is fine - signed contracts for a 5 weeks tom while we were there. The girls let us cooK our breaKfasts &amp; dinners at their place. We all ate together most of the time.</p>
<p>Chicago is so different from St. Louis. The tempo of the town is much more leisurely to begin with. The beaches are full all the time - and people live much slower than they do in St. Louis.</p>
<p>We went to Field Museum &amp; there saw the beautiful gem exhibit and the jade exhibit. In all my life I've never seen such marvelously beautiful things. I would have given my eye teeth for you to see them Dad. I must say you have a good mexican fire opal. Those I saw were only a little larger and exactly the same color. Beautiful amthyists (? sp?) The one you gave Hil is <strike>only a</strike> abou t3/4 the size of their largest one there and is the same color.</p>
2
<p>Neaps of things cut from rock crystal and what they call smoKy <strike>crystal</strike> quartz. A beautiful rose quartz bowl about the size of an ordinary serving bowl. A large group of regular opals - very stunning. Pearls' galore. Copies of the largest diamons in the world. My goodness the sizes of them. A large hen egg is the largest and oen uncut was <strike>enough to</strike> the size of my fists put together. They were magnificiant. I cna't remember half of them now. The jade was lovely but they show very few pieces of the emerald colored jade. The finest piece they had was one medium sized table incense burner - beautifully carved with dragons and chinese motifs. A truly amazing piece for I've no doubt its the only one of its Kind and its astonishing that such a large thing could be cut out of one piece. The largest crystal ball was there too. Lots of white jade.</p>
<p>Went to see Seymours - Mr. seymour was not there but we got to see her and she was so nice to us. It seems Mr. Seymours eye operation was as much a success as is possible. I enclose a little thing he wrote fro the occasion of the Indian <strike>Legation</strike> Bureau coming to town. Mrs. Seymours brother Carl is much better - walKs without a cane now and worKs around the house there.</p>
35b
3
<p>Bill McMillin was nice as was Katie - their children have grown so much. Katie is still the same little brow beaten mouse and Bill the same blowhard. I'd Kill him if he were my husband. I really dont' believe the man is normal.</p>
<p>Sorry Amama is leaving. I hope her visit has helped her.</p>
<p>I've been thinKing of you so often lately and wondering what move is is order. What about Boonville? Did you do up there Dad? Or what it necessary?</p>
<p>Mom while in marshell Field - the big dept. store in Chicago I saw a display bowl for water lilies that wasn't a patch on the Dream the way you have it worKed out now. Isn't it maddening.</p>
<p>I will send the bunch of babies you sent to Alice as she gave them to me while I was there. She hadn't pacKing facilities.</p>
<p>I must close - let us hear from you soon.</p>
Endless love from all -
Max, Sig &amp; Wubs.