<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
146 Fink Collection 58
Sept. 15, 1939

SIGURD NEIHARDT
BRANSON, MISSOURI

BRANSON
SEP 15
3 -PM
1939
MO

Mrs. O.F Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Saint Louis County
Mo.
59
Sep. 13th 39

Darling Enid:
<p>Your dear letter came to make us so happy about you there. It will be wonderful to be with you sometime this Fall or Winter, and I am hoping I can visit you during the three weeks that Daddy is lecturing at Knox College some time in <crossed>October or</crossed> November. Sigurd will then be here with his family, and it would be so nice if I could than be with you. The men are leaving the last of this month for the South, and they have <unclear/> all of Oct, November and some of December booked. I don't want to leave here while Max <unclear/> the Wubs are alone. Not that I <underline>could</underline> not do so, but I feel better if I can look after things and we really have a cery restful time of it when the men are gone. You Know how simple every thing is when there are just women to consider! Besides I feel this <underline>is my</underline> Home and I want to be here. You will understand that dear!</p>
<p>I have been very busy with canning lately. Today I made 12 or more pints of apple <unclear/> - the Kind that jells the</p>
60
<p>the way Daddy likes it. Yesterday I canned 6 quarts of tomato juice and 6 quarts of applesauce. Daddy helps a lot <sic>pealing</sic> and you Know how good he is at it.</p>
<p>We still have S.of O canned goods left from last Winter. Now we have just 24 more quart jars to fill - we would like to have peaches - but the Elberta crop has been <underline>dried up</underline> with the heat lately instead of maturing - so we may not have any. We have been eating suppers in our grove, where Daddy made us a couple of bench-seats, and we use the old Kitchen table. Daddy and I eat breakfast every morning out by our seat, and we have been sleeping on our <unclear/> close by. We love that! The air has been hot and dry like desert weather - it seems to be able to rain.</p>
<p>I am going to be sewing quite a bit soon. We all need things for every day. I have been doing a little for Alice but she could have make up her mind to even begin to express herself as to anything she might need while she was home - so all I <underline>could</underline> do for her was at the last minute and very little of that.</p>
<p>Maybe now that Alice has only her dancing to do you and she could get together and do some sewing. I'm sure she could learn a lot from you. I remember</p>
61
<p>fixing a number of things last Winter that should be O.K. for her now._</p>
<p>I'd love snaps of your place if you can send me one or two. The cowboy picture I got up in the Northwest for you is waiting for a proper packing - I had left it in our leather satchel, which Daddy left at our last stop in Monet, so we had to write for it, and it did not get here still after Alice left, so I could not send it to you by her as I had intended doing._ but it will get to you <underline>some</underline>time! I want you to buy a frame that fits it at the dime store and consider it a gift from <underline>me</underline>, will you? This is cheap, but is not meant that way.__ Also Enid, can</p>
<p>you still get that white enamel <unclear/> 65 cents a half gallon? I want to have you send me one if possible, and let me know what it costs, will you? I did that way for Sigurd when I was up there, adn it was cheaper than buying paint down here. Please let me Know about it.</p>
<p>I think like you about War - if only Congress beats Roosevelt and keeps us Neutral! I have very little affection for any Nation that is as hypocritial as England - and it makes me sick to think of our young men having to fight on <underline>either</underline> side._ Let us not talk about it <underline>at all</underline>.</p>
62
<p>and think about it all as <underline></underline>little as possible! The people who <underline>do</underline> the fighting are <underline>all</underline> too good to be used that way. My heart aches for all of them no matter on what side they are. It is a pitiful <unclear/>, and would surely be funny if it were not so tragic.</p>
<p>We Americans <underline>should not</underline> get into the Old World's quarrels. But <underline>will</underline> we??</p>
<p>Tell Ollie to write more about himself.</p>
<p>Kisses for you both and a heart full of love</p>
from 
Mama Mother.