<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
118a
(1)
Tuesday, October 24, 1939
Dear Mama, 
<p>I really can't imagine why you haven't been hearing from me, because I <underline>have</underline> Alice writing you. Only a few days ago I wrote, and less than a week before that I wrote too. Maybe you haven't been getting the mail so often since Daddy &amp; Sig have been away. Anyway, I'll write as often as possible from now on.</p>
<p>Last Saturday we saw "La Boehine" with Nino Martini, a <sic>Cshechoslavakian</sic> soprano, Morelli, and many others. It was really marvelous - especially Martini. The music is <underline>so</underline> beautiful isn't it? Mildred, Hilda, &amp; I went together. Later we found out that Eny &amp; Ollie we there too - in the $5.00 orchestra section! They got the tickets from the Post.</p>
<p>Sunday we went out to Eny's &amp; Ollie's for Eny's birthday</p>
(2)
<p>dinner. We had a lovely time &amp; a fine dinner. <unclear/>. Hil &amp; I bought a gorgeous cake, a lovely <unclear>shirtuiosr</unclear> blouse, and some good looking black pigskin gloves for Eny. We gave them to her from "All the Neihardts". You telegram arrived in plenty of time.</p>
<p>Our life here is going along swell now, as usual. The other play Madame told my in class that I have been improving very much just lately, and Snippy said she had noticed it a lot too. I've been practicing every day, in addition to having one or two lessons. Tonight Hil may come to see our class. I hope it is good.</p>
<p>Last night, I came home from the studio at 7:00, after a full day of dancing. I had a lesstion from 11:00-12:30, a practice at 2:30-3:30, and finally, a lesson from 5:15-6:30. Then I dressed, rode part way</p>
118b
THE HOTEL Mayfair IN ST. LOUIS
250 AIR CONITIONED ROOMS AND SUITES WITH
PRIVATE BATH, RADIO, AND OTHER REFINEMENTS
(3)
<p>home with a girl friend - fellow dancer - and walked the rest of the way. Then I ate dinner with Hil and the other girls. After dinner, Margaret Deane, Mildred Daniels, and Janet Young came to our room to talk, hear records, &amp; dance a little. We had a wonderful time talking. Then we bathed, etc., did our bending exercises, &amp; went to bed.</p>
<p>Thursday we're going to see "The Taming of the Shrew" at the American with Alfred L<unclear/> and Lymn Fontaine practicing a very gay, rouwdy version of Shakespeare's play. It should be very interesting</p>
"Live in the atmosphere of an exclusive club with Downtown at your doorstep"
The Hotel Lennox, 9th and Washington Avenue, St. Louis,
under the same management.
(4)
<p>Eny &amp; Ollie are coming to dinner a week from this Thursday - guest night. Very soon they are going to bring some of there records in to play on our phonograph - radio combination.</p>
<p>I'm so glad you're having your bad lower teeth removed. Of course we won't be ashamed of you. Are you going to have the work done in Branson or here? We'll all be so thrilled to have you here to visit us. (Eny &amp; Ollie included)</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<p>Give my love to Maxie, Joanie, &amp; Elaine - also George!</p>
<p>Daddy's letters were very enjoyable. We'll give them to Eny &amp; Ollie to read.</p>