<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
15 
109 Fink Collection 
pm August 10, 1938
BRANSON AUG 10 PM 1938 MO. 
Mr & Mrs O. F. Fink
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, 
Mo. 

16
Dearest Children:
It would be perfect if you were here with us - Heaven is a state in which we all can live together! And I feel it can be in this world! 
I am thinking of you a lot Enid dear - your first experience of married life really - for while you spent your days at the office you had not yet become adjusted to a woman's lot. 
I know it must be hard but it will not be so when you look forward to the little Stranger who may or may not be like your Daddy - but who will be wonderful and so worth the sacrifice 

17 
or she will necessitate on your and Ollies part - Marriage is: "dying" <del>a death</del> into a seed, liv ing is that, when all is said and done and after all there is nothing without the next generation. 
I believe Ollie will get a higher salary if he stays on the P.D. and if he leaves it and gets a start somewhere else, that will ammount to the same thing. 
Our cave is beautifully clean and all trash is burned up. Daddy has coal ordered for Winter - our cook stove is nearly in shape for use - and I bake a big baking twice a week - I found some plums I canned when Mrs Glanville sent us plums seven 

18
rs ago - and made plum jelly and plum-apple butter out of it, all of which the family heartily devours! It is good to see! I have all the children's clothes mended and Maxie says "Mom I have no more need for pins"!! 
I have been operating on my fountainbaby's head - It had water on the brain and enlargement of the neck and head - and the operation was most successful - I <del>t</del> looks too good to be true - All was made possibly my good eye lenses, and a sharp chisel! Tomorrow I iron - and that reminds me that you are very welcome to the ironing board and any thing else you want Enid dear. Do you want our dining table? I thought 

19
you had gotten all you wanted - but if you'd like ours you are welcome to it. If you do not want it tell Hudson's I'll take what they will give for it - but may be they would trade me a kitchen cabinet for it? I want one very much, a small one, with out^cabinet top - Just a good table top that I can roll bread on, with a bin below for flour - I have nothing of the sort and need it - Must be very compact 
Wish you'd write me oftener, as I get lonesome for you, and no one can take your place in the heart of your devoted 
Mama 