<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
68a
5540 Cates Ave. 
St. Louis, Mo. 
Nov. 7, 1938
Monday Afternoon 
Dear Daddy, 
I'm finally answering your very encouraging and greatly appreciate letter, now, although I should have done so long ago, even though I have been quite busy, as usual. 
Hil & I have been having a great many good times with Eny & Ollie lately, on week-ends. We went on a picnic in the Meramac woods on Eny's birthday, had a party here on the Sat. before Halloween, and, last Sat., had a marvelous party for Francis at Eny's & Olli's. We ate a delicious chicken & pineapple cake birthday dinner in <unclear/> beautifully decorated dining room & afterwards played <unclear/> roasted marshmallows on the fireplace, popped corn, & drank Sherry wine! Sunday morning we had Eny's & Ollie's usual Sunday morn-ing treat of waffles! Then we came home, cleared our apt. & went to the show. So, all in all, we had quite a pleasant week end! 
I'm very tickled over my new clothes, which I made a detailed description to Mom. Hil & I decided that a new coat & a new shirt would be a much better buy for all practical purposes than a suit, so Sat we thought then the coast is truly a fine, high class 

JOHN G. NEIHARDT 
(2) well-made & beautiful dark rust one of 100% all wool fabric. The shirt is soft very nifty indeed - the newest swing variety with a zipper in teh back! I certainly appreciate these new clothes! They're really very good, and were very <unclear/> priced. The coat ordinarily a $97.00 one, was only $8.00 Isn't that pretty reasonably? We all think it is a very lovely coat, including Eny & Ollie. You see now I have an ordinary everyday coat. (the one I bought 2 yrs. ago) and a fine dress & rare-occasions coat! 
That is much more a desirable well separately - bought shirts, than a suit which would not be <unclear/> arm enough in itself outside & would he too warm all - together inside! 
My dancing is coming along pretty well - as well as could he expected with school more to he contended with, etc! We have been getting several new <unclear/>s and a couple new set of exercises lately. I do love dancing, and I do want to dance, so badly. I've always wanted to dance, to do something different from the ordinary drab existence of so many humans. hate is something marvelous a <unclear/> doing something marvelous about doing something in which you <unclear/> as express yourself and to create sauce thing beautiful! Of course, no one can know that. better than you! I am going to my dancing lesson in about half an hour. I go every Monday and Thursday, now. 

68b
(3) 
The weather is quite had today - or at least, if it generally considered so, for the temperature has droppped below 40o (probably freezing now) the wind is blowing a mist of cold rain. Last night it rained practically all night. 
We have been hanging ten wk. tests in school lately. Two of mine are already over; chemistry and Ger-man remain to be written. 
Last Wednesday school was dis missed at noon, so that the school children could go to see the parade of the U. S. mechanized cavalry. I was not patriotic however, as hard-ly anyone seemed to be, and instead rode out to Eny's on the street car? The day was golden and crisp, and the leaves were turned to beautiful golds, reds and browns! The ride was lovely, and the afternoon spent with Eny, after a delicious lunch, was even lovelier. I had as much shelter time than I would have had if I had seen that parade of <unclear/> and uniforms! had it been a horse cavalry, I should have liked to have gone. About 5:30 I came home practiced my dancing for about two hrs., & then got dinner (or started to get dinner). for Hil & me This Friday school will be closed all day for <unclear/> day. I certainly shall be tickled!
I msut go to my dancing lesson very soon now, so I'll conclude my more or less boring account of some of the happenings in our daily life here. 

(4)
PLease do write us soon, Daddy. We love to here <unclear/>, <unclear/> you write such encouraging letters - in fact, we hardly think we deserve ^all the praise you give us. Never the less, we are deeply grateful to have such ^wonderful parents as you and Mama, who believe in us so deeply, and want you to know that we return that <del>belief</del> love as far as we are capable. Hardly a day goes by that we do not say their to each other, and that we do not wish we could be with you. Please do try to bring everyone to see us on Thanksgiving, when you come its lecture at the Jefferson. We could have a marvelous time out at Eny's & Ollies on Thanksgiving. Eny & Ollie both want everyone at their place on Thanksgiving & would be very very disappointed if that didn't work out. I think. We should all be together if possible, for that, after all, means more than any-thing else to us all. 
PLease write us soon, Daddy. 
Loads of Love, 
Alice 
JOHN G. NEIIHARDT CENTER 