<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
SIGURD NEIHARDT COLLECTION m. Feb 20, 1933 
0b
Dear Sigurd,
Your letter reached me jsut as I was leaving for the fast Lansing to visit Arthur Farwell, Press, the Crists, all my friends there. The wife of my best friend here was going with me and while waiting for her( ever so when it concerns the so-called fairones!) I had a chance to read it. For some reason (hard to guess????) a joy always comes with your letters. It is ever a pleasure to hear of your activities aknd the occasisional words about your father or any of your's. I read the programme with great interest. The remarks of John at his friend's funeral are very beautiful. I read them aloud to Arthur who said "There are but few who can have such words spoken over them." Then Mr Crist read them aloud to me and Mrs Crist. All who read or heard them were much moved by the poignant beauty of John's words. Tahnks for sending them. The Crists have written to Springfield for a copy of the paper. But why did you tear our Joyn's picture; was it as bad as that? Newspaper cuts are as a rule worse than 

0c
that. As usual I had a glorious time with my friend's in East Lansing; music, poetry, philosophy, all the things men who are alive live for. The first time I played it seemed awful to me. I was tired, had eaten a big dinner, Had drunk a cocktail and several glasses of vemouth all which made me heavy headed. I played wretchedly. Of course those who did not know my playing thought it beautiful. But it was so below my average I feltvlike never touching the piano again. Sunday evening I was my self and have no regrets. I forgot to say it was near midnight when I played first. It would be just like me to play wretchedly for you the first time. I have no control over my feelings. There is a curse being temperamental. I wish I coudl drop in(not too hard!) to hear you and Monda play. The ms of the Chopin C sharp minor Waltz beings on the chord, not preceeded by a G sharp, on the first beat. I will show you how the god's work has been handled by some vandals. 
It was beautiful that you played at the funeral. I hoep when i go thtey will give me bakc to Mother Earth without any remarks, unless they coudl come from one who knew me and was acpable of saying 

0d
things that would not offend me. 
When I left for East Lansing it was in a storm of dry, driving snow. It was glorious. The paterns on the raod made by the driven snow; the hills in the mist of the snow; then the bursts of sun; it was too much. Such days make up for the hatred I feel for winter. How soon now the wildflowers will be blooming with you! 
The Study has not come. I will try at Summy's in Chicago. It is nearly time for the mill to start and I have another letter to write before that, so with best for all of you, with Love,
affectionately, 
<unclear/> 
Hoem, Tuesday P.M. 
I may have a surprise for you in my next. It only concerns me. 
