<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Thompson Collection 50
May 1942
Darling Alice: 
<p>We are so thrilled over all you are doing - It seems so perfectly marvelous that you should be in an honest to goodness dancing group and that you should have succeeded in getting started in so short s time! Now you are having real experiences - and the fact has a very electrifying effect on us here, especially on your old mother who still remembers your <unclear/> uplifted arms and your appeals: "Mama-<underline>tate</underline>" Bless you dear heart my own Darling! Indeed I pray hourly for you - a deep undercurrent of good wishing exists all the time, whether I actively Know it or</p>
51
<p>not. You are so good to write as often as you do - and that Keeps us near to each other. I am Keeping your letters and they will some day make most interesting reading.</p>
<p>Daddy and I were invited to a steak roast with Dr Plank, Viriginia and some of the Unitarian friends - We all had such a nice time and it will be so very nice to become better acquainted with such folks. I have had so few friends! We think Mrs Stoker will buy our place, and we will try to buy a good farm within 25 miles of St Louis. She certainly loved it when we took her down last Thursday. She planned to put in a lot of lovely improvements, includ</p>
52
<p>ing a second bathroom, maple floors, a fire place redecorating and repainting inside and out. The Garden was simply heavenly, the hedge was in full bloom and very fragrant as well as the iris, making a beautiful showing. She has not the cash bit has a very big income - so she is trying to juggle things around so she can buy it. However "there is many a slp twixt cup and lip" and we do not Know just how all will turn out. However we hope to see a Missouri River Farm very soon that we may be able to get - Would it not be wonderful for Daddy to live in a place overlooking his River? I could then make his monument</p>
53
<p>right there! And some day you children can scatter our ashes into the big River! - Nei is adorabler each day - and Nannie has made his bust - it is almost finished!</p>
<p>A dear pitiful letter from my Mother makes Daddy and me glad to be able to really be of use to her - as she is terribly nervous and heartsick after the War etc etc - She truly <underline>needs</underline> us now, and we expect to have her come to us very soon now, to remain till she feels better - <underline>if</underline> she still <underline>can</underline>. I wrote her all about you and the other children and she was very glad for me. She will pay us enough to make it possible for Daddy and me to live</p>
54
<p>in Branson or in our new place - So this will be a Godsend to us, aswell as to her. Nice, not? the Unitarian <strike>Church</strike> minister may go to Larson's to see you and do something helpful for you - any way befriend you there - so be on the look out!</p>
<p>Ollie is so engrossed in his Garden here now - it is truly fine to witness his genuine interest, and he surely has a beautiful looking garden, with tall potatoes and chard big enough to eat already!</p>
<p>We had a really nice birthday celebration for my 58 years here at Enids' - with all the dear children and grandchildren - and only you</p>
55
<p>absent - but the thought of you was so encouraging and happy! Hilda and Albert gave me a beautiful new white blouse and Enid made me a lovely sheer old rose dress - My brother Ottocar sent me $5.00 and so I bought me a lovely pale rose felt hat with gloves to match - and now I may still get a pair of nice sandals. Mammie sent me a great big box of chocolates - So I was wonderfully well treated!</p>
<p>Hold your thumbs for us and the Missouri River farm, will you? And in</p>
56
<p>the meanwhile know that we are going to be alright one way or another - I mentioned to Mrs Stoker that some day in the distant future, you might buy back our Home from her - adn she said,. "Yes, maybe she will!"</p>
<p>Loads of love to you, my darling, and give you friends the Kindest thoughts from me.</p>
Your devoted
Mama
