<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
50a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
March 8, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I received your card this morning, Mama, and was very glad to hear from you, never so little. Now I'm eager to hear what you say about my last cards. For the present, I shall be forced to accept a job of some kind here - I shall write you of it if I succeed. We all hope to hear something soon regarding the act either concerning another job, or our long - overdue papers. Recently, I've heard that some people who waited here for their papers were held in this hotel several months, <hi rend="underline">but</hi> at the end of that time they were finally rewarded. That gives us some hope. Now that you have again written Truman,</p>
(2)
<p>Daddy, perhaps will <unclear/> a definite statement from Washington soon. Surely that is not too much to expect - it is cruel to keep us in total ignorance. Somehow I believe we'll be helped to see the Light soon. Doris and I went to chapel at Mercy Hospital (just across the street) last evening, and how we prayed! We just happened to arrive at Chapel time, so we heard the prayers of the head sister and the answering chants of the other nuns while we were concentrating on our own problems - and , as always those of our dear ones. How truly dedicated they are to Good - and how unbelievably much they have sacrificed - yet, do not we who live in the midst of the <unclear/> they condemn perhaps suffer more? Not that I know much of Life yet - I realize my inexperience, now as never</p>
50b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>before - but I believe we are all learning, and also, that we will be allowed to see clearly soon. The only thing to do, it seems to me, is keep on our own feet in <hi rend="underline">any</hi> way possible till we see what happens for our act. I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> not feel it is right to help break it up now <hi rend="underline">just</hi> when we've begun to get along in the higher fields of entertainment. Jobs are not easy to find in dancing now - except plain ordinary, <unclear/> chorus jobs with <hi rend="underline">no</hi> chance for development. See? God! I realize all the burdens I should be assuming, and can't and I've suffered over it, but what good does it going wild do? None, as I've found <hi rend="underline">except</hi> bring about a true realization of the problems</p>
(4)
<p>we face. i have no money now to go anywhere, and "going" seems silly anyway unless it's to bide time with a job till <hi rend="underline">our</hi> act's ship comes in. George will assume (or per contract) charge of transportation back to starting point, but going <hi rend="underline">back</hi> would be useless if we're keeping act intact. In fact, as I've already explained, Mexico City is much closer than St. Louis or Chicago (Fare is <hi rend="underline">half</hi> that to St. Louis) and, in the event of our papers were coming soon, we girls <hi rend="underline">could</hi> go on to Mexico City to get a job for they seem to be gettable there according, to Max. As I told you, we've received several communications which contained a warm invitation to stay at his and his brothers' ranch. Yes - it <hi rend="underline">may</hi> sound like</p>
50c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>a rash step to take, but <hi rend="underline">really</hi> it would entail 1/2 the expense in travelling <hi rend="underline">and</hi> living that would going to Chicago. Then, <hi rend="underline">if</hi> M.C.A. or our Chicago agency offered us a job, we could come back here from Mexico City. If we could receive definite news that we may safely <hi rend="underline">expect</hi> to receive the papers <hi rend="underline">sometime</hi>, this would be a wise step to take I sincerely believe. Staying here I can make <hi rend="underline">no</hi> more than my expenses $<hi rend="underline">18</hi> is <hi rend="underline">big</hi> money here, Mama - almost unheard of!! You see, most of the "help" here are Mexicans and live across the border where the rate of money exchange is 5 to 1.) So you can see why salaries are so low. How</p>
(6)




