<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
95 Neihardt Collection 3
11/3/40.
Sun. noon.
6235 Southwood,
St. Louis, Mo.
Dear Dad &amp; Mama:
<p>today is 'rest day', following a week of very hard hustling. I am now to the place in my prospecting where I'm "sitting on the fence" with a good many deals pending. Dad, ol' pal - please pray for my <underline>real</underline> success during thsi November; for if things even do moderately well - we <underline>will</underline> make enough bonus moeny to put us on our feet financially. I have never worked so hard before, nor with such a hell-fired desire to "really go to town". I <underline>must</underline>! Money is the only thing that can give the Neihardts their necessary footing. Judging from the business that my predecessor did, I should be able (at the rate I'm hustling) to get into the $300 month class.</p>
<p>I am pracitising quite O.K. &amp; am happy to say I'm not sliding back, but in many ways forging along</p>
over
4
-2-
<p>I have a prospect now who is another Neihardt fan. Rev. Oelschlaeger. He is pastor of a new church soon to be completed in St. Louis Hills, the district directly S.W. of the Arena. This fine chap fell in love with your work before that K.C. Kansas affair. (Remember? You'll probably recall that a man named Miller got you up there (close to Univ. of K.C. visit) &amp; only paid you a small honorium. Anyway Rev. Oelschlaeger says you left that group with great thoughts for them to medidate upon.</p>
<p>Gee! I'm glad Jed goes along so well. Fine &amp; dandy this is.</p>
<p>We are working on a number of lecture pssibilities. Thanks for referring H. Clark Brown's proposition. We'll get on that shortly. Dad, Denton Texas says unable to take us up on that original plan. Sorry this cannot be had.</p>
<p>By the way, looks as <sic>tho'</sic> next mon. Nov. 11 is a holiday. If so with my Co., We'll all come home next Sat. eve. &amp; stay over Sunday. We all miss <underline>you</underline> &amp; <underline>Mom</underline> terribly. We have a Chrysler, 1936 Deluxe Sedan, from original owner, <underline>perfect</underline> car, with overdrive. Payments are only $14.16 per month. Car is like new almost. It was a real 'break'. Got it for <underline>$120</underline> below its present loan value. S.M. Stewart took the old Plyon no part payment &amp; let me have the Chrysler at wholesale, because I <sic>bro't</sic> Hilda's "Max" to them for a cash car sale a while ago. Nice?</p>
<p>Must close.</p>
Endless love,
Sig.