<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
52a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, MO.
Jan. 26, 1941
Dearest Dad &amp; Mom:-
<p>Just rec'd your Special this a.m. Ol has <underline>just</underline> gone to work. No, we didn't worry Friday, as we got our card, Mom.</p>
<p>Gee, that's <underline>just awful</underline> that Dad has to have that painful leg &amp; hip!! Couldn't you call that <unclear/> who's in Branson there, or Forsythe? A working over of the affected part's would surely help to heal the cold in his leg. Anyway, don't you think some doctor should see it? Never has Dad had to "crawl" anyplace that I can remember! Gee, that's such a dirty shame that Dad had to lift all that heavy, cumbersome stuff! I do wish you could go someplace once without a load of stuff, don't you? As I said in a previous letter, that lifting isn't much for men with sense, but, rather, for brush apes!!</p>
<p>Just called the kids &amp; they are <underline>so very sorry</underline> to hear about it all, Dad &amp; Mom. They'll write too right away, they say. They are looking forward to seeing you too, you see!! We'll all write often, even <sic>tho'</sic> we don't have a lot of news.</p>
<p>The pain &amp; all will probably leave all at once when it does leave &amp; so you can't tell when you'll be here!! I guess ironing is just about the best thing, <sic>altho'</sic> I <underline>hope</underline> you'll use trick's Vaporub as they suggest for muscular aches &amp; pains, too! It did wonders for Ol!</p>
<p>Dad, Ol is just as sorry as he can be that you have to have that, &amp; surely knows what it's like! I wish you were here now</p>
2
<p><strike>now,</strike><sic>tho'</sic>, instead of there!!</p>
<p>Sig is going to play anonymously over <underline>WTMV</underline> in East St. Louis this P.M. at around 4:30 or nearly 5:00. He &amp; Max are going together. Nice?</p>
<p>There's snow on ground here still, <sic>altho'</sic> the highways are all clear, etc.</p>
<p>If we can do anything, let us hear it!</p>
<p>Mrs. H. has been all excited &amp; would lately, as her sister has had an operation to remove a blood clot on her neck, which may make her more normal &amp; bring down her blood pressure. Mrs. Tacke is doing very nicely.</p>
<p>Hope you'll be rid of that pain very soon, Dad, &amp; that we'll be seeing you, at least Friday. That'd be nice, as Ol's home Fri. &amp; Sat. you know! Of course, come sooner if you can.</p>
<p>Well, here's loads <underline>o'</underline> love from us both to you both</p>
as always -
Oddie &amp; Enot
<underline>Late Afternoon</underline>
<p>Just heard Sig play as I've never heard him play before. Three gorgeous pieces! They announced him as a "Big Surprise". Said they had as guest one of America's greatest pianists &amp; for people to guess who he is- they get a prize it they guess rightly.</p>
<p>I <sic>tho't</sic> of writing in having a different name! but it wouldn't be fair! I <underline>could</underline> write &amp; say it sounded like Sturki, tho!!</p>
