<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 58
Wed. Octover 1
OCt 1, 1941
St. Louis Mo.
Dearest Daddy:
<p>I have been so pressed that I have not yet written you about <underline>Jed</underline> Since I finished it, a strange feeling has clung to me, and I keep remembering certain passages. It is seemingly very simple, and yet every page, every line even, is filled with so much meaning that reading and absorbing at least a part of what it tells gives one a much greater vision of things. Really, I do not see how anyone,<underline> anyone ever</underline> <strike>could</strike> <underline>could</underline> write the things you have. The more I read over your works, the more and more completely <underline>amazed</underline> I am. I have always felt and known how great your work is, but perhaps I am becoming more and more able to appreciate it. I only wish now that I might spend mroe time reading. As soon as I can, I am gonig to read every one of your works several times over again. Alice and I read to each other quite often from</p>
59
<p>your lyrics. The other evening we were reading "the Death of Crazy Horse", and I find that I still am unable to read it all aloud without sobbing outright.</p>
<p>Unless you need this copy of <underline>Jed Smith</underline> I'd like to keep it here a little longer; for I want to read it once more now. I have been reading here at the office, and there are unfortunately quite a lot of interferences - these annoy me terribly, for one does not want to break away from <underline>Jed</underline>. In addition to every thing else, <underline>Jed Smith</underline> is terribly interesting as a story alone.</p>
--
<p>I received yesterday $100 part paymetn of my previous seed business commisiions! I am a rich girl!</p>
<p>Sig and I practised Sunday, yesterday morning from seven to eight, and again this morning. It is really fun, and Sig is just wonderful for me. We are going to practice again tomorrow morning! I find that what I need is much practise. I think you'll be proud when you hear us next time.</p>
60
3.
<p>Albert is studying advanced math now. He is going to have to work very hard - he says the teacher goes very fast. I told him he'll have to get you to help him!</p>
--
<p>Mrs. Stocker called yesterday. She just returned from Wisconsin, where she went last spring. She was so thrilled about all the wonderful comment on <underline>Jed</underline>.</p>
--
<p>I feel that I must once more become consular! Please let me hear from you soon!</p>
Much, much love to you and to Mama,
Hilda