<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
241 Fink Collection 26
BRANSON
DEC7
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. adn Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
27
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Sat. A.M.
Dear Oddie &amp; Enot
<p>It must often seem to you that I don't carefully read your letters and that I don't realize the genuine, deep-rooted goodness they express. But that would be wrong. I just don't get my <sic>feelin</sic>'s into letters. Your assurance, Ollie, that you want us there is deeply appreciated, and Enot's too.</p>
<p>Since coming home, I've done 73 lines, and I'm all breathless with the culminating lines just ahead. It's that breathless feeling which has to be conquered at every sitting. The feeling of tiem and of hurry are deadly. One goes slowly in a hurry and hurries actually only with a loose sense of infinite leisure.</p>
(over)
28
-2-
<p>And here I want ot correct a possible misconception, <sic>altho</sic> I may only fancy to existence. It may seem from your position that <underline>Jed Smith</underline> just drags on and on, and that I've been at it a very long time. Please consider this, if it seems so to you:</p>
<p>I wrote 30 lines of the beginning while still on the P.D. job, and could get no further. I began work on teh narrative very late in the fall of 1938. It is now two years since then, and during that elapsed time, I have made numerous long and wearying lecture trips, which took time, before and after, away from <underline>Jed.</underline> (The trips cleared nearly or quite $5000) It is doubtful if I have had <strike>one</strike> more than one clear year of work on Jed, adn here I am with 2281 lines, <strike>with</strike> and 320 to go! So my progress has been <underline>nearly</underline></p>
29
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>three times as rapid as in the case of <underline>Hugh Glass</underline> or <underline>Three Friends</underline>.</p>
<p>When you consider the above, it's the opposite of what it might easily seem. So much is like that in this world.</p>
<p>Enot, please give me the last <underline>two</underline> lines of what you have copied, as I may want to sand more MS for coping before we come up. I don't know when that will be.</p>
<p>Anyway, you're <unclear>dollinks</unclear>, and we love you.</p>
Dad
<p>(But you're a coupld of <sic>goddam</sic> plutocrats, just the same! Huh! Country home, and all that!)</p>