<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
38 Petri Collection 60
1940
[October 12, 1940]
Norfolk. Neb., Sat. Morning
Dear Ones:
<p>We left Denver Thursday at 3:30 P.M. and arrived here Friday at 5:15 P.M. Lovely drive. We are in the cabin where I completed <underline>The Messiah</underline>, and have just had breakfast. Will go to Wayne (30 miles) tomorrow after lunch.</p>
<p>No mail at Grand Island, but there'll be some at Wayne.</p>
<p>Bully about Blair, which is on the way home, that is where I was talking the hour Mama died.</p>
<p>I can't remember any success that surpassed Boulder and Denver. It was all 100% &amp; then come tho' Authors League luncheon was on Thursday, and that seems to have hit exceptionally hard. Talked 1 1/2 hrs there, not, at first, intending to say anything much.</p>
<p>The whole tings out there was a thoroughly happy experience. Sig will receive a letter from Boulder &amp; also from Denver - testimonials for the next folder.</p>
<p>I found lots of <underline>real</underline> fans at both places. The men who introduced me knew all my stuff &amp; have known for 25 or 30 years. At Denver the big book store sold</p>
61
-2-
<p>a stack of books.</p>
<p>We're in love with the country and the climate. Irrigated places right <underline>near</underline> the mountains sell reasonably. We should live near Denver. The place is <underline>alive</underline> to the arts. The attitude is the same as Albuquerque, but things <underline>grow</underline> rankly there.</p>
<p>Sig, several spoke with regret of your inability to be along, &amp; we advertised you. They believe us too.</p>
<p>Business will have a pickup - <underline>very</underline> much so - after the first of the years, Sig. Until then, worry, I suppose. <underline>But we'll go through</underline>.</p>
<p>Alice &amp; Hiddy, it's striking what you said about a <underline>sudden pickup</underline> in your progress. Surely this world is mroe wonderful than we realize.</p>
<p>Letters don't get much said; but this carries what is already with you all - love for each one, beginning with 'Laine &amp; Joan &amp; going on upstairs to Ollie.</p>
<underline>Dad</underline>