<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
80
Fink Collection 
65
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
ROCK SPRINGS SEP 9 630 PM 1935
Miss Enid U. Neihardt 
<del>For Laramie</del>
% Chas W Kelly 
473 - 1st Ave 
Lake City Utah 
<del>Laramie Wyoming Rock Springs</del>
p
SEP 18 1935
SEP 16 192 
8

81
Sept 3rd 35
Dearest Enid girlie:
Your two cards were so gratefully received - I am glad everything was O.K. now I am getting used to your being away but at first I was jumpy and nervous I could accomplish nothing. 
We all sewed yester-day and got a good deal done towards Hilda's things. = two skirts changed, the white suit finished the formal dress changed again and materials

82
ready for a pink crepe slip to go with it. - Betty is tucking the left fa the flesh colored dress - and doing a lovely job. - 
I had a Mr Barker bring a load of cow manure and it is spread on my garden - now when it rains things should take a new start, 
I have piled a lot of dirt up behind our canvas making a good sized flower - bed for next year, and where I dug the dirt away from the solid rock I am going to dump all of our ashes this win- 

83
ter, then in the Sprin gI'll rake the surface earth back over the ashes, and that will form a high background be-hind our ordinary annuals to plant the tallest flwoers upon - such as Cannas and Hollyhocks. Won't that be fine? I am thrilled with Daddy's but - and am half expec-ting Mr Good over this after-noon. Mrs Good said he might be over - Oh how I do hope he will come! 
Sigurd is in Harrison. Maxie is here and Alice has 

84
just gone back to school. There are only 53 pupils in the fresh man clan this season!! 
Alice has a perfect permanent in back, and her hair is combed back straight and tight in front. She never looked so pretty or so neat before. The new beauty parlor lady has the very latest equipment and is certainly good. Mrs Parmel has been at the Hos-pital for Eczema for weeks - and has just returned - can you beat that? 
Hilda and Betty are out riding and picknicking today, I am going to get the mail 

85
now, send this off to you, and find out if Mr Good is going to be here - if not I am go-ing out to Miss Beenett's and to see Mr Denton too, before supper time. 
I do hope you will both have a wonderful time and that you will not be disap-pointed in your man, if that is what you most want - Loads of love to my dear, dear good girlie, 
from 
Mama 