<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Mrs. Mahnskey was a well-known and much loved old - timer of the Branson Country. Suite a poet too. Note the refers to the burning of the Messiah MS, J.W. 
Refers To 
My MOther 
J.N. 

8 Neihardt Collection 88
Oasis Mo. March 1, 1935.
Mrs.Neihardt, dear friend. 
When I read in Branson paegr of Mr.Sigurd's marriage, and then of Miss Enid going to New York, I thought, O how lonely they will be, and now, with the little mother gone away, it will be real lonliness. 
How beautifully she lived, in her little flowery house, and how happy are we for knowing her, and how happy you can be who did so much, I think of her so often, with her pretty blue coat, and her dainty little gloves, and her inspiring little ways. She was a real companion. and has left an influence that shall be everlasting. 
I gireved over the loss of the manuscript,and thought how gallantly he bore his loss. Maybe in going into it again. he will be inspired to some thing else, for in my humble little work, I see that very frequently if I go back and re-read some thing I wrote maybe a long time ago, it opnes a little door out into a fresh and lovely garden. 
It was such a pleasure to hear you play,and another ish granted,one number was the most beautiful thing I ever heard, I am speaking of the last club meeting I attend.When Miss Palmer lectured, and you played. This selection had a sort of running trill,simply heart breakingly sweet,wish I had known the name. 
Some day you will be coming out,wish you could come and camp in the little shack that was made form teh old,old black smith shop,there is a little out door rock oven,very crude,where happy people have cooked happy meals,and Mr.Neihardt will feel the strange presence of the hills and the water, and walking along the haunted lane,may hear the ghost!That would be a new and impressive series of Ozark stories, to make a study of the h'anted lanes,and hollers. the ghost in this lane is phantom horse hoofs,galloping,galloping,my little daughter heard it, and old timers say it has been heard before. 
I'm sorry that I cant stop this,without my bad habit of sticking in a home made poem, but my friends are kind,and display much fortitude,an forgive me.This one is about your playing. Sincerely,Mrs.Nahnkey. 
Magic.
O Miss Mona,go get your fiddle 
I'm curious to hear you play 
Fer never sich singin' come from a fiddle
Is what the neighbors all say. 
O Miss Mona,play on your fiddle 
Like the wind plays out on the hill
Where wild little stars come and dance in the water 
And the she wolf is mouthing her kill. 
O Miss Mona,is that a fiddle- 
It speaks witha  silver tongue 
An' here they come laughin' to take me a-dancin'
The lads that I danced with when young.
(over) 

89
April's Restrictions.
I can milk a cow
I can knit a sock
I can thread bright daisies 
On a child's small yellow frock. 
I can sing while walking 
Along a thorny way 
I can work with patience 
While others are at play.
But I can not keep form weeping 
When I hear the whip-poor-will and April rains are reaching down 
To kiss the daffodil.
I love this one! 
Jno. N. 
1-3-1958 
