<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
46 Thompson Collection 113
Neihardt
1917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
SAINT LOUIS, MO.3
JUL27
1230PM
1943

BUY U.S. SAVINGS
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER

Miss Alice Neihardt
4920 Blackstone Ave,
15 Chicago, <hi rend="underline">Ill</hi>

114
July 26th 43
Darling Alice:
<p>You were dear to write me that good letter, and the card too which you might send me again, would be appreciated! I Know that there can never be any serious differences between you and me - adn that we will always love and admire each other. My attitude has been too maternal - and I will understand that it might be annoying - Let us consider each other friends, <hi rend="underline">very close</hi> friends form now on - that is, I believe more correct - and not at all objectionable, not?</p>
<p>you are quite able to make your own decisions - and you will always find illumination when you go to your Daddy and talk things over with him - that I Know so I am glad you did just that, and as a result feel better.</p>
115
<p>As for helping me to get around to my sculpture Darling, with almost no heart ache I can honestly say that it is <hi rend="underline">too late</hi> - I no longer even wish to express myself in any such way. It might have been, years ago - but not now any more - and I say this with almost <hi rend="underline">no</hi> regret My entire interest now is with Daddy together to get into an independent state financially - and to see you children happy for life in something suitable for you after I am gone. I understand your wanting to have some measure of success with your Act - and I want that too for you. You already <hi rend="underline">have</hi> succeeded, for you are a <hi rend="underline">very good</hi> dancer.</p>
<p>I would hate to see you do anything to cut off your chances to marry Max and live the glorious, good, free life be <unclear>betoidently</unclear> want to offer you. I would hate</p>
116
<p>to see you renounce anything so splendid and soul filling for even a great dancer's later years. Marrying is a young business, but dancing is <hi rend="underline">still</hi> younger - so I do not see any need for you to miss out on either.</p>
<p>If I had been able to live in Italian air everything that I now wish for you might have come true. As it is, I am not sorry for me - but I don't want you to have to give up <hi rend="underline">real living</hi>, for anything as tawdry as our American way of life. My satisfaction has been <hi rend="strike_through">the</hi> helping Daddy to become himself, and the writer of <hi rend="strike_through">a</hi> really great American Poetry. But the common American does not interest me, and never no loyalty to the U.S.A - and on the contrary, I feel Daddy has given the U.S.A. - something to be forever proud of. - I feel</p>
117
<p>that you too have a perfect right to leave the U.S.A - and become a Swiss or a Mexican or whatever it might be.</p>
<p>More and more Mexico is becoming one with the U.S. in all ways that matter - and you are of the Future, not of the Past, as <hi rend="underline">I</hi> am.</p>
<p>Alice - I do appreciate your wanting to help us - but we are not yet truly <hi rend="underline">old</hi>. As long as we can, we want to be independent - and later if you have made a Life for youself - you may then have the chance you now wish for, to go on with your dancing must be <hi rend="underline">only because</hi> it <hi rend="underline">gives you real</hi> satisfaction - That is the only good reason for an artistic career.</p>
Endless love to my Alice
from her <hi rend="underline">friend, 
Mom</hi>