<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
68 Neihardt Collection 84
[Edward's Hotel]
Jackson, Miss., Monday P.M.
Dear Mona:
<p>I wrote you a long and very interesting(!) letter this morning. Since then I've been as lazy as possible (which is a sight!) while Sig went to town and practiced. He's back now &amp; supper is preparing. (Incidentally, it will be fit to eat!) I've griped about most of the country we've seen, but Mississippi up here is really rather charming and "<underline>homey</underline>" looking. I'm amazed at the appearance of prosperity in Jackson. Wealth - my gosh! And a beautifuly &amp; extremely built city. Three skyscraper hotels! The capital bldg is conventional Roman - dome etc, but it's impressive. near here they've recently struck <unclear>ore</unclear>, and the place is agog with visions of prosperity. The weather is soft and pleasant - no <unclear/> of frost. The nights are dampish, like our nights of fog.</p>
85
<p>We are in a new cabin camp. A nice young chap &amp; his wife have just built it &amp; are full of hopes. He told me of his plans with the enthusiasm of a kid.</p>
<p>From here we go through Birmingham, Alabama, and Chattanooga again. thats 406 miles for the first day. Then it will be just 260 miles to Richmond, Kentucky, for the second day. Easy! Then we'll have a night's rest and do our stuff at 9:30 A.M. Fromt there it's a short day to Cincinnati, and there's a firm that handles rough semi-precious gem stones there. I'll see if I cam get something pretty to cut, so that I can take and make me a beautiful ring for to wear on my finger.</p>
86
-2-
<p>In N'Ambis I cam a medium. Sig assisted, saying he wouldn't get anything &amp; maybe I would. She is said to be <underline>the</underline> medium there; and she seemed pretty wise. <underline>But</underline> (no harm intended, and you shouldn't have thought of such a thing anyway) <underline>but</underline>, she did say I'm going to be very wealthy and all the rest. She say a statue, but didn't know of what. It seemed to be related to me somehow, maybe it was the one you're to do for the Junior Commercial Club. Going went too - all the same as usual. "You sometimes fear you'll never finish that big work of yours, and sometimes you half wish you'd never started - not quite. But you'll finish it in 1940.." And all the rest after this. She said jealousy had held my stuff back, but that I have many may <unclear/> anyway; and all the jealousy will pass. Of course, we know this much for sure.</p>
87
<p>Funny! And educated fellow at Gainesville came up to me and said "Much as I've always liked your Mike Fink, I think I like the "Messiah" better." The Dean who introduced me was mellow with Greek &amp; Latin culture, &amp; made a fine, pat statement by way of explaining epic &amp; making clear what I've done in the Cycle.</p>
<p>A Priest came to me at Gainesville &amp; said he was one of Father. Somebody's boys who had written me a joint letter about Hugh Glass years ago. I sent my love to the Father.</p>
88
-3-
<p>Sig saw Prof. White of Millsaps College today. His daughter recently died, &amp; in her private papers was a copy of "Let Me Live Out My Years" with comment by her. Prof. White wants me to recite the poem on the program.</p>
<p> Sig is playing at his bestest. I'm glad he practiced today.</p>
<p>When you talk to people about us, don't tell them we're <underline>working</underline>. Tell them it's a tour for our health, and then they'll think we're rich. Say "Florida" kind of off-hand as often as possible. Also, mention Biloxi frequently! And N'Ambis, too. Wear the crystal ring when you say these things, and have Max wear all the jewelry you don't wear.</p>
<p>Incidentally, Biloxi, Miss., on the Gulf Coast is surely a gem! Miles &amp; miles <underline>&amp;</underline> miles of luxurious homes.</p>
<note>drawings in letter</note>
<p>Me in Florida</p>
<p>Sig in Florida</p>
Lovingly and wealthily,
Jno. (Dr. Neihardt to poor people)
<p>P.S. After my rest, I feel almost like a humane bean.
Jennevein at Bison sold 20 copies of Glass and Wars in two days and wants more. He sent Macmillans the money at once. Good old <unclear>Jennevein</unclear>!</p>
(over)
89
<p>at <unclear>Gamesville</unclear> Sig had a 10 ft <unclear>stairway</unclear> grand and he made it sing like an angelic host. People loved it, naturally.</p>
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
EDWARDS HOTEL

<stamp>JACKSON OCT 10 1030 AM 1939 MISS.</stamp>
Jackson, Miss.

Mrs. John Neihardt
Branson, Missouri
Box-167.