<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
6 Piper Collection March 26, 1922 <del>7,8,9</del> 7 
box 145 Branson Mrs. - 
BRANSON MAR 127 1 PM 19<unclear/> 
UNITED STATES POSTAGE <figure/> 2CENTS2 
Miss Mildred Piper 
Lyons-Nebr. 

8
Branson Mo-
March 26 - 1922 
My Dear little girl;"
If I don't hurry up it will be vacation again and I want to remind you of your trip to the Ozarks, For weeks this letter has been pending. Hardly a day goes by without some mention of your coming, now I hope htere will be nothing to hinder the coast is clear here. No new babies but we have the dearest thing here. You will just love her to death. She not only has my name but my hair as well and they say a red headed temper <unclear/>, But she is the best baby. Just no trouble except for the washing. 
Well we were pleased to hear of the pain being read in your church I know you had a little thrill all your won, because you know him ^("John") so well and he surely has always been an admirer of you. When Miss Knapp was studying "Hugh Glass" in school, he used to say it should be you who were teaching "Hugh Glass" 

9
We have a real live Paren Teacher's Association here in Branson. You will wonder how they happened to Elect me President, well I was reelected for the second turn, now we are getting up a "home talent" missed. Mona both sings and plays. I'll send you a program when they are printed. The proceeds go to a Teacher's fund. We are to have a new school-house. Oh how I wish you could afford to teach for what we can afford to pay wouldn't it be glorious to have you <unclear/> here all year, when you come we will look things over and will know by that time what we can pay. 
Don't try to do any of your swing before you come. You don't need any new clothes just <unclear/> things heavy shoes and a big sun hat. Oh of course you may need a little besides, but you can use your own judgement that. Mona is so well and strong Evry one Else is well. I have been making garden my yard is getting green and I only sowed the seed in Feb. have eight hens "sitting" will have plenty of fries and lots of milk when you come. give my love to your father and mother and know that i love 
Jno 
Alice Neihardt 