<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
39a
<header>A New Modern Hotel 
Dining Room Service

Inner Spring Mattresses
Some Rooms with Bath
Hotel - Kasson
MR. AND MRS. L.A. SMALLEY
Proprietors</header>
Kassson, Minn.,<underline> August 26 </underline> 194<underline>2</underline>
Dear Daddy, Mama, Amama,
<p>Here we are in Minnesota - believe it or not, and have just completed our third night's show here. We do our closing show here tomorrow night (8:30 show time - over at 10:30) and leave Friday morning for Preston Minn. 50 miles distant. Write me there at once and I'll receive your letter there.</p>
<p>We had a lovely trip here by train through <underline>lovely</underline> country - hills topped with white birch, castle-liek rocks, and Alp-like pastures covered with grazing herds. There were many glorious, cold, clear lakes, which shone like silver in the sun, and with the softness of lighting at twilight, were like something from fairyland. We came into Kasson at 9:30, after twelve hrs. on the train, and</p>
(2)
<p>the three of us inseperables sat on the baggage at the station, watching the cold silver moon, which shone down across the tracks after the train had left. George, you see, left in a hurry to secure rooms for us at the hotel. He was successful, for we now have lovely <underline>soft</underline> beds to sleep in (for a welcome change) and we breakfast here in this delightful little hotel's dining room each morning. People here are very friendly if a trifle awe-struck.</p>
<p>I'll try to tell you about our days with the Ernie Young Fair Shows as clearly as possible, so (I hope) you can visualize our life. The show, first of all, consists of a line of sixteen chorus girls (all very nice, young girls) who do the chorus dancing for four large "production" numbers, an octet (consisting of good, experienced operatic singers, and our act, which completes those production numbers. Between each of the "big four," various types of acts are inter<unclear/></p>
39b
(3)
<header>A New Modern Hotel 
Dining Room Service

Inner Spring Mattresses
Some Rooms with Bath
Hotel - Kasson
MR. AND MRS. L.A. SMALLEY
Proprietors</header>
Kassson, Minn.,____194_
<p>a muscial act, a comedy dance act, a perch act, a balanceing act, etc. The production numbers are, in order of presentation, the Navy, the Spanish, the Russian, and the Patriotic. We do our Russian flash act (3 numbers) in the Russian production with the line girls as background, and singers too. It is really quite thrilling. The stage is portable (huge) and has beutiful stage scenery.</p>
<p>Now - for a typical day. We arise around 8:30 or 9:00, bat, adn practice and rehearse for several hrs. on the stage. Then we have our dinner-guess where? In the park! And it has been for the past two days a dinner that is really primitive, besides super-delivious. George is a <underline>real</underline> steak griller, by the way! He loves everything about</p>
(4)
<p>the outdoors - and knows it too. Yesterday, we had steak, roasted ears of corn, and roasted potatoes, and toasted buns - roasted apples, and oranges. today, however, was an even greater triumph. Our gypsy blood <underline>really</underline> asserted itself for this is what we did. (It must be the influence of "capriccio Espagnol") After rehearsing in a little room at the hotel (It was raining <unclear>draupen</unclear>), George and I went to forage wood while Sylvia and Doris bought groceries. Then we built a roaring fire in the W.P.A. 4 part fireplace (a wonderful oven-built fire-hole) and prepared dinner therein, over and under red-hot coals. George and I, finding that the girls had been unable to buy ears of corn at the store, saw a <underline>beautiful</underline> cornfield not for off, so decided to do a bit of borrowing therein. We had not trouble at all in selecting and picking!</p>
39c
<header>A New Modern Hotel 
Dining Room Service

Inner Spring Mattresses
Some Rooms with Bath
Hotel - Kasson
MR. AND MRS. L.A. SMALLEY
Proprietors</header>
Kassson, Minn.,____194_
<p>huge, tender ears of corn (We were quiet however - speaking only in whispers) Then we concealed these in my coat and walked back bearing our burden between us. We <underline>never</underline> enjoyed any dinner more if half as much - such steak, <underline>such</underline> corn, and besides, buns, baked beans, roasted apples, and oranges. We played and laughed a bit and then walked home across green fields and down wooded streets. Upon returning to the hotel, we found <unclear/> Ernie Young wished to see George. It worked out that he wished to ask a "favor" of one of us girls - to work 3 numbers (all but <underline>our</underline> Russian) in his line-up, for it was one girl short - for $25 extra per wks.</p>
(6)
<p>Doris didn't wish to, and I did for various reasons - so I am! You see, no one will se me in the line on these Fair Shows, so it will be no degradation to our act in any way for me to work in the line too. I have nothing to do except the Russian otherwise, adn I'd <underline>muc</underline>h rather dance <underline>lots</underline> and earn more money too while I'm in the show. George said he would do it himself were he I, and so does everyoen else. They all consider it, in the musical conductor's words "A.I. Showmanship" to "help out the show this way. It not only saves amount of time and worry. I am thrilled to do it - think - $25 extra per wk. I thank <underline>God</underline> for great favors.</p>
<p>So, in accordance with the above, I rehearsed only today with the girls</p>
39d
(7)
<header>A New Modern Hotel 
Dining Room Service

Inner Spring Mattresses
Some Rooms with Bath
Hotel - Kasson
MR. AND MRS. L.A. SMALLEY
Proprietors</header>
Kassson, Minn.,____194_
<p>and jumped smack-dab into two numbers, the Sailor, and the Military. The Directors said I did very well - and I enjoyed it. A couple more times and I'll feeling at home. The girls and conductor too said I sparkled it out - "smalzed" it at me say - that's what <undelrine>our</undelrine> dancing does for us. My first work in a "line." the nubmers are really quite clever - some nice steps - and lots of formations - good experience too.</p>
<p>We leave in the morning for Preston on bus at 9:00. Will perform tomorrow night there.</p>
<p>How are all of you? <underline>Please</underline> write <unclear/> all about yourselves!</p>