<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
115a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT

9917 Emerson
Overland
Mo.

October 23
1939

Dearest Mom &amp; Max:-
<p>This is my birthday today. The folks gave a grand birthday yesterday and of course you were in on it in a big way! I want to thank you for your share in making my birthday a happy one! Those black pigskin gloves are something I've always wanted but never felt like spending the money for! And they go so beautifully with my black coat-suit! And that beautifuul pink shirtwaist blouse thrills me equally! It's so nive to have things you don't make yourself once in awhile; I like "boughten" things if they only weren't so expensive by comparison to the homemade! When Ol &amp; I came down, I'll be wearing both things! I didn't tell you yet what Ol's gift to me was, did I? Well, something I just wanted badly__A set of silverware for the table! And it's such a beautiful pattern - has the beauty of simple lines &amp; matches well with the silver carving set Aunt Grace gave us for our wedding present! Ol always has</p>
2
<p>such unbeatable taste in things, I think!</p>
<p>Now I must tell you of the dinner. Ol had baked chicken &amp; dressing, mashed potatoes, stewed carrots, Boston head lettuce with his own delicious dressing on it, cranberry sauce, and, of course the 3-layer chocolate-pecan iced white cake that Hilda &amp; Alice brought me. Hilda had orange &amp; green candles on it &amp; it was put on a yellow plate! Then, I had the centerpiece of red barberry which has green &amp; orange tints in it! It was a lovely dinner &amp; setting, with the green &amp; yellow dishes &amp; the lovely silverware &amp;, oh yes, yellow wine! They gave me a lovely toast for my happiness in the next year. Really, Mom &amp; Max, it was <underline>perfect</underline>! I do wish you could have been here. But we though of you deeply while at the table &amp; elsewhere all day yesterday.</p>
<p>In the afternoon yesterday Ol &amp; I fixed up our back next to the porch. I planted iris &amp; he made some steps which were needed there. It looks truly nice now. Oh, we have <underline>plans</underline> for this place. We want to make a sunken garden in the back yard. We'll show you what we have in mind. You'll no doubt have some suggestions of value, Mom. Ol &amp; I are so anxious for you to come up, Mom, &amp; go back when we go ---</p>
115b
3
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>sometime after Nov. 13<underline>th</underline>, when we've rested a bit or, rather when Ol has rested a bit from his daily routine. So, we think it would be great if you could come up the last of this month - perhaps when Sig comes? Then you'd have no transportation by the dull old bus! It'd be a joy for Ol &amp; me to have you with us, Mom, you should know that. Ol likes you so very, very much &amp; I'm so happy because it's due to your kindness and sympathy for us that makes you so dear to us both! We always enjoy deeply having any of my <underline>dear</underline> family with us, for Ol feels just as much a Neihardt as do I! I feel bery close to Ol's Mom, too; she's a dear! We certainly are lucky insofar as family relatiosn are concerned. Ol's Mom says she just loves to be with us! I suppose she feels that we have more of a "home" than Art &amp; Maude. You know, care shown to make "home" something besides a "house"! She was always that way &amp; she likes it. When you're here, I want to drive you out to Art's to see Ol's Mom &amp; the others. They'd appreciate it &amp; I know you'd consider them dear people in their way.</p>
<p>But, as I say, one can't expect</p>
4
<p>everything to be perfect in this world. There is something always. Speaking honestly I'd have had a better time on my birthday, if we hadn't had Frits out here, but we never have anything without hime, for we feel a bit sorry for the kid. And, of course, I admire Ol for being the way he is about Fritz, because, it's obvious that Ol is the only <underline>real</underline> friend Fritz has. But, as I told Ol, &amp; he mentioned himself several times, that the kid is as near like his mother as possible! And, he is, &amp; is getting those mannerisms of his Uncle, which Ol &amp; I just don't like - that's all. But of course that can't be changed, under the circumstances. However, if we had him, we might help him out of it, but perhaps it's best the way it is. I feel like Amama - a child belongs to the right Mother. There are nice things about the kid too, of course. But, I feel he rrather resents me, and I suppose it's natural enough. I have been good to him in many ways. I always have his birthday dinner, etc. We see him often. His birthday is Nov. 4<underline>th</underline>. But, Mom, it's <underline>awfully</underline> hard - to kind of "half-way" have a child!! Because, when one corrects him, which must be done occasionally here, he goes home &amp; gets right back to his own old ways; then when he gets out here again, it was all for nought. that's Ol's &amp; my <underline>one</underline> trouble. Everything else is a perfect heaven,</p>
115c
5
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>We just get along beautifully &amp; are planning for the future now more than ever. Perhaps when we have our ouw children, it will be easier with Fritz; for then, he'll have a brother or sister to look out for when he comes out- and there won't just be "little Francis" to be considered &amp; spoiled! I think it'll be a <underline>very good</underline> thing if we are able to have a family. Ol wants to have two or three children. He's a perfect family man and <underline>I</underline> think, of course, the <underline>dearest</underline> of <underline>men</underline> as my husband. Dad has his place right on top as the dearest of men in Dads. We want to show you what we plan for the upstairs too, when you're here. It'll be such fun, talking about it. I can harly wait, Mom!</p>
<p>Ol took me to the opera Sat. nite to hear Nino Martini. His voice is <underline>lovely</underline>!! We found out yesterday that Hil &amp; Al were there too. We had downstairs seats that a friend, the opera publicity mgr. gave Ol- $5.00 seats too! Hilda said they were upstairs. That was also part of my birthday to, you see, I feel that I've been entirely to lucky to have so <underline>very</underline> much done for me. I'm a most lucky &amp; happy person, I assure you!!</p>
<p>Just rec'd a telegram from Dad from Ada, Okla. It reads:
"The best of everything to you on this, your birthday, &amp; in all coming years.
Love,
Dad &amp; Sig"</p>
6
<p>Isn't that dear? I <underline>am</underline> happy &amp; lucky.</p>
<p>Mom, I just wanted to blow out a <unclear/> to you &amp; Max. But, please don't mention it in a letter. It would only complicate matters. I'm sure you two, as women, &amp; my friends, understand why I want to say it to you &amp; won't mind! Naturally, I can't talk to Ol much because naturally he can't see it my way, it being <underline>his</underline> son &amp; not mine. I'm sure you both understand. He understands, the; of course.</p>
<p>Max, I'm so happy the hat fit. I had to sort of guess. Kiss Joanie for me. And hug Leine. I want to make Laine something cute for her birthday--Feb. waht?!</p>
<p>It's beautiful out back here now - very much like fall!</p>
<p>Must go to town &amp; shop a bit. Am washing today. Are you? -!?! Probably, you're doing a <underline>real</underline> one!</p>
Loads o' love, Mom.
Loads o' love, Max.
Always, 
Enid
Eny
<p>Did you hear of Donald MdD's marriage is to <unclear/>! Hil, Al, &amp; I are going together one a gift!</p>
Enid
<p>Tell Joanie to please do send me a snap of her in the little "modern" hat! -Eny</p>
115d
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO  <underline>Fink</underline>
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS M.O.
OCT 24
7 -PM
1939
<stamp>300<underline>th</underline> ANNIVERSARY 
OF PRINTING IN COLONIAL AMERICA
1639
1939
UNITED STATES 
POSTAGE
3 THREE CENTS</stamp>
Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
<underline>Taney Co.</underline>