<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20
114 Finn Collection
Jan 17th 39.

Dearest Enid,
<p>Your package came on Max's birthday as well as your telegram while Mr and Mrs Melton were here after dinner. I had made Max a date cake with 7 min. <underline>brown</underline> sugar icing so I had been thinking a lot about you as it was, there came your package and we are all so glad for everything. Max will wear the gloves and the net - and I'll get to work a little later on these things for Joanie as I am now busy for Max.</p>
<p>It was a fairy laud <underline>here</underline> today with soft beautiful snow - Daddy sewed grass seed in the "pasture" or better "park" on top</p>
21
<p>of the snow - ideal!</p>
<p>Our place is so clean, and Mrs Causwell has put new fences all around <unclear>Graud</unclear> was - and has cut and burned till it begins to live again. Such fun! No more backwoods neighbors!</p>
<p>Sig has lauded hope Girardeau now He is surely going after <unclear/>, and doing as well in every way - I am so very happy about it. As soon as I can finish Mr Good I'll feel so relieved - The F. of O. people were detained, but should be over tomorrow rulers this snow will make travelling too hard. Then I can cast. It is so much better finished than anything I ever did of that sort. Mr Leonard said he would send the balance immediately after I tell him I have completed the work. Nice, not?</p>
<p>I'll be so glad to see you</p>
22
<p>all again.</p>
<p>If I don't write now for a while you'll know it is because of casting. That is such a big nervous job for me. Also I am making Maxie a dress, it is very beautiful and she is thrilled. She will not have to wait as long as I did to go on a trip with her husband. I'll love to have Joan and Elaine all to myself!</p>
<p>They go in about 2 weeks. _After that I'll be thinking of going to see you and the girls. If I can have my lower teeth attended to then I will, but it the <unclear>ex peuse</unclear> seems ill advised, I'll just have a good time with you all. Dad was ticked to get good pencils again. Many thanks again dearest girlie!</p>
love to your dear Man and to you the same old love from Mom.