<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
134 Fink Collection 5
<gap reason="torn off"/>
SIGURD NEIHARDT, BOOK AGENT
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON
JUL 5
3 --PM
1939
MO
Misses Hilda &amp; ALice Neihardt.
9716 Hawthorne Ave.
Overland, Mo

St. Louis
County
6
Tuesday
Darling Alice:
<p>Your dear note made me happy. Daddy and Sigurd left for Cap Girardean and Carbondale this morning, and they will be back Friday, so I could not share your letter with him but I am sure your plans will meet with his approval. However Daddy and I are planning to go up into S. Dakota in August the latter half of that month we think, to "exist" there while Daddy writes on Jed Smith. So you will be here with Sig and Mx and the Wubs a part of your vacation without Dad and me. But that will have to be that way, and should be pleasant all round - only I shall hate to be away from you._</p>
<p>I am so glad and grateful for your fortunate liking of Mrue Cassan - do write me more about it all. Daddy will send you money as soon as he returns if he does not do so on this trip.</p>
<p>Indeed it is wonderful for you to be out at Ollies' and Enids'. They are dear.</p>
<p>Also I know how much they helped at moving time.</p>
7
<p>We are having the two roofs properly recovered so that they will no longer look the way they have been doing. It has been awful._ but our place is <underline>so</underline> very beautiful - and talk about <underline>cool</underline>, it is wonderfully so. Please tell me if you would like to practice in the school gym while here, so that I may know whether to ask Mrs <unclear>Jawes</unclear> about it, or not.</p>
<p>I will make you two new outfits while you are home - for dancing I mean. Please tell me about Sylviee 0 is she also studing with Mrue Cassan or not?</p>
<p>I am happy to know you are at Enids'. Give every one my best love and keep your very own full share. -</p>
from your own , devoted
Mama.
8
Tuesday
Hilda darling
<p>Thanks for your good letter - which <underline>never</underline> is enough. I think you can be sure that I always write you the truth and all the facts that are in my mind when I write. I think letters are useless if they do not help to make the correspondents able to <underline>live with</underline> each other, sharing all they go through individually <underline>with</underline> each <underline>other</underline>. This is not good rhetoric but I think it says what I mean. Daddy says I am too subjective too personal so you can judge for yourself what that fact must do to my letters; but one thing is certain you may rest assured that I am telling you what I believe to be true. I am not withholing anything from you. Things look fine for us, excepting Sigurd's state of mind which has been awful - just when he had every reason to feel happy. - but I believe most of that was due to his health and the worry over his arm, and his natural impatience. Anyway I trust he'll come out of it on this trip. He still has one bad</p>
9
<p>tooth to pull _ and his arm still goes to sleep. but since his legs also have done that there seems <underline>no</underline> reason for him to be worried about Pian &amp; paralysis. I guess it is just one of those  d- things that have to wear off.</p>
<p>We are so eager for your Home coming and the thought of the Radio makes us glad. <underline>I</underline> miss it more than I ever thought I would.</p>
<p>It is too bad Alice will not come home when you do but I suppose that will have to be as she says, and it is O.K with me.</p>
<p>I don't know why you thought my letter different, darling unless it was that my worry about Sig showed through <underline>too much</underline>. - Yes I too think Dr Jennings would be a good man to see unless he is clear over this trouble by then.</p>
<p>Mrs Good wanted the bust bronze color, so I am changing it. I expect to see her tomorrow again, Mr Leonard says I am to please <underline>her</underline>, and he will be satisfied. I like Mrs Good so expect no trouble -</p>
Loads of love to my HIlda
from her Mutti.