<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
2a
Home 7:20, Tuesday
evening, 1941.
Dear Daddy,
<p>I know it is really rather silly for me to tell you how much we all love and admire you, but I'm trying to do just that! Just speaking for myself, I can see you growing finer and finer everyday as you have been doing all your life (Please dont' think me silly in saying this), and your influence on me is something wonderful to feel. All of us feel this and speak often of it to one another. I know that you have tapped Something Divine or you could not be as you are. So often when I am troubled about something or angered or upset I think of what you have said or would say, and I welcome my</p>
(2)
<p>wrong feeling. In your lyrics there are meanings too which come into my consciousness like a light when I read them now. I am going to read all the Epic Cycle over again, for I know it will now be again as much <underline>more</underline> to me now than it was when I first read it.</p>
<p>Another thing I appreciate tremendously in you is your understanding and your completely sympathetic <underline>backing</underline>. I shall not let you down - nor of course, myself.</p>
<p>Daddy, one of the girls at the studio is a real radical - in everything. She thinks as we do about the social condition (as far as she is capable of course) and about religion too. Yesterday several of us got into a converstion</p>
(3)
<p>about religion. I had just finished "Science and the Unseen World," so I ventured a bit of its contents, meekly of course. One of the girls is a <underline>very</underline> religious Bible Presbyterian who believes the Bible is absolutely <underline>infallible</underline>. Doris, the radical girl and I really agree in not believing in a certain limited man-planned creed or in a man - like God. I tried to show where we all are basically alike in our beliefs, and the discussion ended peaceably. However, I would really like to know why the Bible is infallible - it is man-made, isn't it? Why, it those who wrote it were human, even though divinely inspired, can it be considered infallible? I didn't ask this of the girl</p>
(4)
<p>who believes in this, but I wished at the time that I had been capable of drawing her out by questions as you would have done. Today Doris and I had a great time talking and completely agreeing, and I told her about Black Elk and your connection with him. Now she wants to read "Black Elk Speaks."</p>
<p>Dancing is really coming along quite well. I shall keep you informed about my progress, and I do appreciate your helping me.</p>
<p>I am deeply enjoying Sir Oliver Lodge and also "Red Snow" - the latter is rather depressing, but the idea is one to ponder over.</p>
<p>I do hope you have a lovely Birthday, Daddy, although I know you don't make over it.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
