<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
22a
5042 Waterman.
St. Louis, 
July 25, '41.
Dearest Dad:
<p>Your fine letter came just in time to give me some badly needed reinforcement. So <underline>fine</underline> of you, by gosh, to take the lovely attitude that you do, and I want you to know that I would be permanently wounded if I did not have your affection.</p>
<p>I received a letter today from Clarence Sandage, whom you know is really a friend, regardless of some points which neither you nor I approve of. Quote Sandage: "I am thrilled that you have considered coming to California, and I want you to come right away, just as soon as is possible, &amp; SOONER if possible. I know you can get a job here, &amp; a better one that you now have. Yuu must <underline>be</underline> here to get a job. I've found this out since doing considerable investigating. I have good friends in every Piano Firm in Frisco &amp; San Jose. I have a marvelous room in a fine home, best district in Valley's, with turn beds etc. You</p>
22b
-2-
<p>may live with me until you land a job, and IT WONT COST YOU A DAMNED CENT EITHER!" "Now how does this sound to you? Please say 'yes', my friend, and get yourself out here. This is God's country. I wouldn't live back in the middle West again if it were given to me &amp; I be forced to live there -- and I <underline>mean</underline> that."</p>
<p>You know that I've tried and tried throughout the middle West &amp; it has for me been the same disgusting experience as Sandage had, in this selling game. Sandage is &amp; has been continually earning an excellent income for the past year out there in California. I too could do so Dad. It is not the salesman's "Super-ability" that counts. It's the "<underline>opportunity</underline>" that one has.</p>
<p>Sandage wants an early reply from me, but I'll hold him off 'til I hear what your reaction is. I could pay all my debts several months ahaead, &amp; get out there &amp; land a job inside of <underline>30</underline> days.</p>
Endless love,
Sig.
over
-3-
<p>I'm not contented to try much longer in this job I now have, for it is a case of having a ball &amp; chain around both ankles &amp; being expected to perform miracles nevertheless.</p>
<p>Everything happens for a reason, &amp; somehow I feel that it is intended that we (Max &amp; kids) migrate Westward just as you &amp; Mom are about to do. Wouldn't it be great? I positively <underline>have</underline> to take a jump if I make more money. Maxie &amp; the kids <underline>must</underline> see me doing a better job of making ends meet!</p>
Sig
<p>Fine how Dewey Short is plugging away. I do hope he gets you in where you can get a kick out of the word.</p>