<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
154 Neihardt Collection 121
[July 16, 1942]
Thursday evening
Dearest Daddy and Mama!
<p>Thanks for your cards!</p>
<p>Albert and I are here alone. Sig asked Max and the wubs to be at the store with him, since he is on the floor <underline>alone</underline> tonight. Albert is practising the piano now.</p>
<p>We had Mr. and Mrs. Pedri here for a birthday dinner last evening - candles and all! I believe they were pleased. Afterwards Albert took us out to "Znn weissen Rosse". For refreshments and music. It was fun in the garden.</p>
<p>I had my last lesson with Mr. Gerak today until the fall. He and his sister are driving to Denver. While he is gone, I'm going to practise myself and with Sigurd. I must make progress with piano also! Mr. Gerak seems quite pleased with what progress I have made. He says I am singing absolutely <underline>true</underline>.</p>
122
<p>By the way, Mama, you some time ago sent Alice's shoes, shorts, etc., to her at Chiacgo. Now she is there and wonders if the package has been returned to you. No doubt she wrote you in this respect.</p>
<p>Daddy, I left the ring at Jaccard's. They will (as once before) try to find a buyer for it, acting as our agent. If they affer a reasonable price, we'll probably sell; if they do not, we plan to keep the ring and try no more to sell it. The buyer at Jaccard's said they'd not want to break up the ring, since its value is as a piece, and the mounting alone is worth $50-$60." At Jaccard's they are at least friendly and polite, which I found not the case at the other places. These business men are too unkind to suit me. - As Albert says, how can they know I'll not one day be a <underline>purchaser</underline>?</p>
<p>We really like the ring. Albert would not want to sell it - I am the one who has wanted to do so, in order to keep Albert from having to pay so much for <underline>me</underline>. <underline>You</underline> should not feel</p>
123
3
<p>bad about this matter. It was all my idea, and I'd still not want to go for $100.</p>
<p>The slappable saleswoman at Jaccard's still thinks the ring "<underline>so</underline> odd" and said she'd like it "so much better" without those two rubies." I said "Oh would you?" People here don't know that originality <underline>adds</underline> to the values of nearly <underline>every</underline>thing. Oh, well-</p>
<p>It is <underline>really</underline> hot here now - for the first time everyone is sleeping downstairs. We are lucking to have such a (relatively) cool, <underline>airy</underline> place.</p>
<p>Give our love to Amama. I think of her so often - If it were at all possible, we'd have driven down a time or two. Albert has mentioned my paying you a visit. We'll see.</p>
Loving you endlessly ever,
Hilda
<p>Albert says to tell you lots of lovely things!</p>