<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
61j
June 4, 1942.
The Palmetto
Apt. 210
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
Dear Daddy, Mama, Hilda, and, Everyone else,
<p>We finished a week's work at Larson's Sunday evening. It was a grand week of experience - each night brough us new poise and self-confidence, besides showing us our weak spots. And besides all this, we love our work, for it really does give us opportunity for self-expression and development in that respect. The club itself was very nice as to floor space and cooperation of orchestra, but it was beneficial to us mainly as a breakin date. We now knwo better just how we stand, if you understand what I mean. We got</p>
(2)
<p>"good hands" on our numbers, and real attention, but the numbers as a whole are really too high class for a place of this type. They suit hotels and more exclusive clubs much better. As George says, we should (and <underline>are</underline>) very gald for this, for we want to be better than (quote Leon) "happily mediocre." We really are missing our performances these two days! Queer how quickly one gets used to a reversed day and night schedule - when one likes the work one is doing. Oh! yes, and one more thing. After our closing performance Sunday or rather, Monday morning at 1:30, we gathered up and packed all our costumes and then received our pay - what a thrill! We receieved $35 which will be our mint</p>
61k
(3)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>imum at any time - and is a break - in date salary for us. This, even, is more than almost any "line" girls receieve. Forty dollars should be our average salary <unclear>hences</unclear>. We are joining A.G.V.A. (as principals) whose iniation fee and dues combined amount to $14, $7 of which we are paying now. Our rent here is $6.15 apiece, (rents are sky-high in defense-plant Detroit) and food about $2 apiece per wk. Part of - that is, nearly all of last wk's rent we have paid - don't have to pay rent till end of week. I mus tsend the dentist $10, and have to spend some amount on hair and clothes. Therefore, I cannot very well send any to Madame Cassan yet.</p>
(4)
<p>Next week, when we are at the Northwood Inn, as we hope to be, I shall set aside money each week for her. I shall write her concerning this, too.</p>
<p>The weather is finally getting summery. I can really use summer clothes from now on. It is <underline>beautiful</underline> around Detroit. This was driven home to us after the splendid time we had Monday on our picinic to Belle Isle. At 11:00 A.M. (on the dot as George and his mother always are) we left by car, driving through Detroit to the Detroit River, which we crossed at a distance fo less than half a mile from Candada. Thence we proceeded to Belle Isle, driving through the gorgeous park of natural woods.</p>
61l
(5)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>and man-made landscaping, for several miles. The trees there are extremely tall elms, oaks, willows, and maples, and below these all <unclear/> of vines and grass grow luxuriantly. Every type squirrel seems to belong there too, along with countless birds, (pheasants even) and deer, too. The park also has a large zoo which we thoroughly explored - George's mother, Mrs. Carson, followed closely by Nanette, tho adorable although <underline>so</underline>spoke French ppodle (which George simply ignores), Doris, Sylvia and I (all in many colored outfits of slacks and shirts and jackets and baboushkan, and lastly George, who was patiently accompanying</p>
(6)
<p>us enthusicastic looker on <unclear/>. After our walk, we felt hungry so went to a lovely spot in the park where a large table afforded convenience and comfort. There we had a most delicious <sic>picnic</sic> lunch - everything one culd wish for, and topped off with ginger ale, little gateaux, and strawberries. The day was just right for a picinic - and likewise for a boatride or a drive. Therefore, after funding that no boats were available without waiting in line, we hopped in George's well-preserved, nice-running  car and drove for miles along Lake St. Clair - a baby of the Great Lakes. Oh! Goodness how <underline>beautiful</underline> it is along that drive. Water, sparkling and placid in the crystal air and brilliant</p>
61m
(7)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>golden sunshine - shellboats in the distnace, and along its shore only the white highway. Then, set far back from the latter, surrounded (except for a bird's eye view) by tall <unclear/>, every description of evergreen, red-colored bushes and trees with scarlet leaves (at <underline>this</underline> season) were mansions of such beauty as one could only vaguely imagine before seeing. The landscaping, the green carpets of lawn, and the beauty of the lake in front of all this - it was truly breathtaking. As to living there though - they are not what makes one truly happy - not me</p>
(8)
<p>anyway. For to me, happiness is in the work I so love nad in knowing that those dear to me are happy and prosperous. It will not be long till the debt I owe you can be begun to be repaid - and that with progress in my work in all I ask for myself - and that is a great deal. Anyway, we saw all this beauty (what a comfort it is) and then returned home after being treated to a hot fudge ice cream puff at a favorite ice cream shop, Sander's What a day! And what truly lovely people I do feel you would (will) all like them.</p>
<p>Yesterday we shopped and went to the library for books (Courtesy of George - his library card) and practiced.</p>
61n
(9)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>Today George and his Mother came at 10:30. A.M. to perform hair-remodeling on us. Mrs. Carson, George's Mother was adorable as usual - and George now chalant, friendly, and generally swell. The hair fixing got under way very quickly, for that is the way this sprightly French lady works. I was permanented first (all machineless - as Mrs. C. prounces it) We had a delicious lunch prepared mostly by Doris and Sylvia while I was being worked on, at 12:30, and then work was quickly resumed. All three of us were permanent waved, and with the interruptiion of several hours (when Mrs. Carson and</p>
(10)
<p>George went home to Mrs. Carson's for dinner she was constantly "travaillant" form 10:30 A.M. to midnight. By that hour, all of us had been "permanently waved and retouched." The "retouching" in my case was done with the highest grade geniune Eqyptian henna - and has given my hair a reddish cast which gleams liek a sunset (or something) under lights. In a few weeks the permanent will be looser and easier to manage - but you would probably liek it now that it is very tight. Mrs. Carson does no beauty work now except for friends - and for our <underline>complete</underline> job she only charged $3.00 apiece. Isn't that lovely?</p>
61o
(11)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>She siad she knows we can't afford much now and she wants to help us. Furthermore, "You <underline>must</underline> has beautiful hair. It is part of a dancer's charm." she said! Of course, it is <underline>very</underline> necessary to have hair which catches the lights and is well kempt. I don't know ( as you Hilda say in your letter) just how gorgeous I shall be - but it <underline>is</underline> a great help - and who knows how much better I will look, yes?)</p>
<p>We have been rehearsing several hrs. every day lately, working up two new numbers, the French sailor number and</p>
(12)
<p>"Dancing in the Dark." The <unclear/>former is relaly adorable a pantomimic ballet on the points - which  I've already explained to you, and the latter is a nice ballroom type dance with lefts and balletic steps too in it, and will be done in new rose gowns, 3/4 length. We are to work up a dance to "Malaquena" by Lecuona and a musical comedy number soon. These we'll need for our engagement at Colossimo's in Chicago. Then, later (I hope quite soon) we are to work up a "toy dance" to "Golliwog's Cake Walk by Debussy. Mrs. Carson told me George wanted to make me the <underline>doll</underline> in this. Oh!</p>
61p
(12 1/3)
<p>Oh! Yes we are going to have new pictures of our act taken as soon as George uses up some of the old ones in which he has much money invested. Won't that be nice?</p>
<p>Tomorrow we are going on a picnic to Belle Isle as guests of George and his mother, Isn't that sweet of them? We'll tell you all about it</p>
(14)
<p>in next letter.</p>
<p>Mama, could you please send me my <underline>nice</underline> summer clothes? Don't send anything that I couldn't wear and look nice in however, I'd like the white dress/white shorts, purse and hat just a little later - I'll tell you when to send (those) and anything esle that looks good. On 2<underline>nd</underline> thought - send all the whtie things except shoes now, please. This is a big order - but I do appreciate it too.</p>
61q
(13) (12 3/4!)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>I do <underline>so</underline> hope this comes true - for I'd druther be a doll than anythign else - if'n I had in' druthers. Doesn't it sounds clever? All these new dancers must be costumed and rehearsed after being worked out so it will really take some time to get them going. Our repertoire must constantly be added outo, as you see. If I only had my Scotch worked up, I could do it sometime soon, for George asked for solos but perhaps it's best to preserve that for future uses we'll see. Pray for me in the doll part though.</p>
(14)
<p>As I told Sylvia, you say don't look human - so I must be mroe on the doll side - n'est ce pas?</p>
<p>We have been goign early to rehearsal and doing a barre before it. Yesterday we worked from 12:00 till 4:30. then we went downtown to shop and tend to Social Security, mail letters, etc. I put in the applicaiton you sent me, and they are to have the card sent here to me. Now, this morning, I receive the duplicate card from Baltimore Md. where I'd already  written before you sent the letter to me! So I'll have several cards soon. Thanks ever so much, everyone.</p>
<p>No theatres here (or even</p>
61r
(15)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>in St. Louis are featuring acts now, so we are taking a bouquet engagement instead. This Monday we'll open somewhere here or more likely, out of town. Will tell you when we know more about it.</p>
<p>I sent the lawyer $6, for I must go slowly now. We'll may $9 more by 23<underline>rd</underline> and then I am in better favor, right? I shall begin paying Madame when we get mroe settled. This beginning - with to be expected. Things shoudl get into smoother working order soon. Our agent is working on lights and</p>
(16)
<p>properties and new costumes for us. Indeed, he and George (partners in the act financially) are investing a considerable sum of money in this, our act. It all costs a lot to get started.</p>
<p>I'll so appreciate the clothes Hilda - how I do need them!</p>
<p>You must be terribly busy, Hilda. You know I can sympathize with you, but I also know you are enjoying being at home and practicing besides. I'm <underline>so</underline> glad for you (I'd liek the bathing suit and two prs. of nice shorts - one white - one blue)</p>
<p>Yes, let us hope you can see us work in St. Louis.</p>
<p>Millie is a dear. Please</p>
61s
(17)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>give her all my lvoe nad tell her I'll write soon, really. Also, say how I love my little make-up case - I use it always.</p>
<p>George introduced me as Alicia Nye today! My, it sounds different not so very though- on second thought.</p>
<p>I'm so glad about the gifts. Nice of Max too.</p>
<p>Doris' knee is much better - and we are so grateful. She says to thank you for your interest, Hilda.</p>
<p>Thanks so for the letters, Mama, Daddy, Eny, everyone. I should have know you weren't coming in each day now, Mama, but just didn't know</p>
(18)
<p>The garden must be lovely, Ollie! How is yours, Hil and Albert? Wish we could tasts some of those garden vegetables. We ahve to buy ours - but we do enjoy cooking and eating them.</p>
<p>Keep praying for us. Yes I do pray for you - all of you. So glad about Amama, adn your piano and everything else good there - dear dear fine people of mine.</p>
<p>Mrs. Stoker wrote a woman here (Mrs. Plul Baker) me. The called me at Larson's - and was lovely. Wanted to see us dance. When she can, I'm not sure - but we'll see. Thanks Mrs. Stoker for me, won't you?</p>
<p>Please answer soon Everyone!</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alicia