<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
90
Fink Collection March 1
24
BRANSON MAR 2 3-PM 1935 MO. 
UNITEDSTATES <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS
Miss Enid Neihardt
Suite 118 
Hotel Somerset
150 West 47th St
New York City N 

91
March 1st 35.
Oh Enid Darling-
Today I was so thrilled when Mrs Mac Querter called me on the phone and said she wanted her husband to write a real good recommendation for Enid, as "they" had written to ask for one! So that must mean they are thinking of promoting you: they asked for information about you as secre-tary, and Oh Enid, I know they are getting ready to take you out of that room with those common girls, where you do not belong!! I knew they would soon realize what you were and they like you all the more for being willing to do any thing at the start. Mr. 

92
Thompson also has written a recommendation just recently! I am all excited now to know what it means! 
I have not heard from you for ages it seems- but I know that I am just un-reasonable - and that you really have done your part - So I'll just reread your last letter and amy be a couple of others - and feel satisfied! Mrs Spurlock also was so happy to get a letter form you - so was Maxine. 
Branson has been all excitement over its Basketball team - it has been win-ning every game lately against South Western Mo towns, and jsut this after-noon it lost in Springfield against Wheat-

93
land.-Daddy,Alice and I are going-to Springfield tomorrow - I am going to your medium! Do you remember her telling you that "they" had called for references in your home town? Well they have! As usual she missedin time. How I wonder if you will work for that oldish man she spoke of!--
Daddy has been judging the literary efforts of High School pupils here it was a contest that the Study Club organized - It has been most interesting for it has brought some 

94
very remarkable talent to the pond. Daddy is so interested in them, especially two young men and two girls. One of the boys is from Rockaway - one from the S. of U. one girl from Hollister and one from Branson High!-
I'll let Max tell about her prospective "move"-
I hope you received my last 2 letters. This is teh third one I have written you since receiving you last - Loads of love to Amama and to my own sweet dear good girlie 
from Mama. 