<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
18b
21 W. 14th St.
New York
January 21, 1943.
Dearest Daddy and Mama,
<p>It's been a week now since we arrived in this "Titan City" - and we've been enjoying ourselves immensely as well as doing things of usable value. The week spent with Sig and Max, JOan and Elaine, and Armin Mueller in their adorable 4th fl. FLushign apt. was one I'll long remember. What a <hi rend="underline">truly</hi> congenuial time we <hi rend="underline">did</hi> have - and how tremendously happy it makes me inside to see Siggie accomplishing wonders at his piano! Maxie and I are <hi rend="underline">very</hi> close you know - and our ideas, our ideals are practically identical especially regarding the works of "the clan". We spent most of <hi rend="underline">every</hi> day</p>
(2)
<p>talkihng endlessly - and more of the <hi rend="underline">nights</hi> too. Often we'd not fall asleep till 3:30 A.M! That was <hi rend="underline">necessary</hi> and after all - such things <hi rend="underline">are</hi> of real importance in the ever-shaded, changing plan of Life. Nothing, as Gaki says, is like <hi rend="underline">real</hi> communication. But like us all, I'm the restless kind - and it was good to "get <hi rend="underline">active</hi>" again.</p>
<p>The weather - next topic! - has been mildly nippy. It snowed several days after our arrival, covering the nively spaced, high-roofed Flushing apt. houses and homes with a deep layer of fluffy whiteness. Then the roads "commenced to become" rather messy - all slushy and dirty. We</p>
(3)
<p>were forced to don our galoshes (those lucky ones who own such things!) in order to slip-slop our way through the slush to Flushing! That town is quite fetching-wide streets, fine stores, lovely homes - a grand place for children and general Peace of Mind Sig's place of practice in only a couple blks from 41-69 Parsons. By the way, that apt. - community is among the prettiest I've yet seen "Our" court has a pool and statuary -andor clsoed in by greenery and lawn.</p>
<p>We've been rehearsing nearly every day, since last Sunday - in a studio very near <hi rend="underline">our present home</hi>.</p>
(4)
<p>A negro-friend-dancing mster of George is resetting "Frankie and Johnnnie for us - in "<hi rend="underline">solid</hi>" fashion Comprendez? Don't be alarmed it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> clever - and a real novelty. There is a doogon lot ot learn, by the way, about the "negroid <unclear/>"! Last Wednesday we had an audition for an influential agent here. He like the act, offered us a date at the "Samova" in Montreal, Canada! Some time, maybe, we'll go - but <hi rend="underline">now</hi> it's New York for us. <hi rend="underline">Many</hi> chances here. There <hi rend="underline">is</hi> something stirring Thursday evening we opened here at the Jamaica Theatre in Jamaica</p>
18c
(5)
<p>a suburb not terribly far from Flushing. We'll be here for a four-day run, ending tomorrow Sig and Max and the girlies are coming tomorrow to see us.</p>
<p>Tuesday noon I had lunch with Uncle Dick. He was truly "swell" to me. We, accompanied by his boss, went to lunch at a snazzy restaurant near Uncle Dick's place of work the huge center of the world's Y.N.C. A's - at 347 Madison, only a small distance from <hi rend="makeup_stain">Grand</hi> Central Station, where I had lately disembarked from the J.R.T. subway train. We talked of many times. Foremost among</p>
(6)
<p>those "things" was Uncle Dick's desire for you Daddy, to write "them" the lyrics - need lyric. I told him I believed you <hi rend="underline">would do</hi> it. It seems he must know very soon for it must make publication of the Annual - or something Daddy, you don't do things on order," - I realize that only <hi rend="underline">too</hi> well - nor <hi rend="underline">can</hi> you do it without the <unclear/> urge. <hi rend="underline">But</hi>, you did do Easter on request, didn't you - and it came when you needed it through dream. Why then, will not <hi rend="underline">this</hi>
 too, for which there is true and immediate need, <hi rend="underline">come to you</hi>? Daddy, you</p>
(7)
<p>cannot fully realize just what an overwhelming effect yoru lyrics have on people - <hi rend="underline">any people not</hi> just "dilettantes"! On Maxine's birthday, for instance, Betty Beillings, a former member of St. Louis Grand Opera Singing Chorus when I was at the Ballet came to spend the evening. (She is a pupil of Armin's) After the festurtion, toast to various <hi rend="underline">Goods</hi>, etc., (1/5 gal. of wine!) Max, Betty, and I retired for one of those soul-restoring sessions of Neihardt lyric-reading <hi rend="underline">on Betty's request</hi>. Betty is a sweet talented, unblase, unaffected girl my age with a remarkably similar - to our own outlook</p>
(8)
<p>on Life. <hi rend="underline">But</hi> she'd never heard your lyrics! Max and I love <hi rend="underline">nothing</hi> better than reading your lyris to others - nor does anything else give <hi rend="underline">us</hi> such inspiration. <hi rend="underline">So</hi> - Betty was overcome. That is plain <unclear>unwarnished</unclear> fact. She said she'd never heard of such a poet - that your lyrics give her what she's always searched for in poetry and never found. She said she didn't see how it was possible. <hi rend="underline">That</hi> is typical - <hi rend="underline">not</hi> unsual. <hi rend="underline">Don't</hi> you see, Daddy of ours - your lyrics mean ture inspiration to people who <hi rend="underline">need</hi> it? God knows everyone needs it - but if we here in civilian life do, <hi rend="underline">what</hi> of those who are facing Heaven - knows what horrors</p>
18d
(9)
<p>in <hi rend="underline">foreign</hi> lands,<hi rend="underline"> away form their source of power</hi>. You could help them maybe for more than you realize and you can do it <hi rend="underline">now</hi> if you only will. You'll laugh and say "Yes, child - but <hi rend="underline">do</hi> you realize what a lyric takes out of one -especially when I come home exhausted from controlling dozens of earthly little urchins?" Mayve I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> realize, Daddy - for the lyrics have, in the finishe thing <hi rend="underline">too</hi> much of strength and eternity - besides passing emotion - for the <hi rend="underline">mere words</hi> of which they are built. It is the miracle of time <hi rend="underline">creation</hi> - and it is obviously "out of this world" - yet how <hi rend="underline">painfully within it</hi>!</p>
(10)
<p>Well - no need for further rambling on my part; excuse <hi rend="underline">this</hi> much! But, Daddy, belive me, you <hi rend="underline">must do this now</hi>. It world be a crime not to - and furthermore, you will be allowed to do it, provided it's meant. I for one belive it is. Where was I? Oh! Yes - Afer lunch with Uncle Dick I took leave to hurry to rehearsal at 66th and Columbus, via Uptown Local I.R.T.! Was few minutes late - but what can one do when in company of so handsome wan Uncle? No teasing, we had a <hi rend="underline">most</hi> congenial time - and I'm invited to his and Aunt Jane's apt. in Greenwich Village <hi rend="underline">any</hi> time I care to clunh for flights of stairs - <hi rend="underline">and I do</hi>! Eager to meet Jane. Uncle Dick promises to come see us somewhere soon - with his clique!</p>
(11)
<p>After rehearsal we three went "home" ensemble - to my present home at 21 W. 14th though I'd not yet moved in. You see, I was to spend the night there, Sig's ngiht off. As I'd received your letter concerning Olga, Mama Mia, I decided to call her up. That I did, - and dear Florence, her daughter invited me to dinner. Therefore, at 7:15 I had hopped out of hte subway and found myself eagerly searching the house no's on 12th St., year the Greenwich Theatre. Then there it was - 133W made their home in the cozy basement apt. of that address. It was</p>
(12)
<p>most Bohemian - and adorable. We spent a perfectly relaxed, natural, evening together the threee of us. We talked during and after a delish dinner. of Mona "in <hi rend="underline">glowing</hi> terms, of open past together, of Olga's family (all of them artists, of our family, of Daddy's works, of future plans, of their meeting Sig and Max, of Hilda's possible attendance of Juillards with Florence, of our dancing, of Mexico, of New York, of Paris! Whew!!! Oue Chirrier son, summer theatre at Kennebunkport Me. - the home of famous "Garrick players"; another daughter is an accomplished dancer now marred and happily settled  in Fla.; Florence is the singer, who has done pro. work in Clubs, etc., but is now attending Juillard to perfect her voice</p>
18e
(13)
<p>She wants our Hilda to <unclear/> study with her! It is the <hi rend="underline">school for our Hilda</hi>. We'll see what comes but of course Chicago is <hi rend="underline">also</hi> a good place to learn and Bolmar is fine - and Albert will be in Chicago. So for now - Chicago is best. Olga is <hi rend="underline">dear, dear</hi>; she thinks more of you than. I can express. She told me, for instance, of your <hi rend="underline">great</hi> help to her. in overcoming her self-consciousness told Story of the Greek statue you gave her a picture of and how you said <hi rend="underline">she</hi> reminded you of it - head bowed, and personality closed within! <strike/> Flo and I <hi rend="underline">like</hi> each other - and have a <hi rend="underline">great</hi> deal in common. We talked forever. I read</p>
(14)
<p><hi rend="underline">several, no many</hi> of Daddy's lyrics to them. They loved them - and knew many already "<hi rend="underline">So</hi> like German poets" said Olga - "<hi rend="underline">So strong</hi>!" Ah! Yes! - Is there not Strength in all Beauty? <hi rend="underline">Some</hi> kind of Strength? She copied several "unuusual lyrics" - and intends to try putting them to music. She has also written a marvelous "Impromptu" for <unclear/> which I greatly want Sig to hear. Many of her songs are truly beautiful. At 2:00 A.M. &amp; finally forced myself to leave; But not without the mutual promise of our becoming real friends! I felt as if I'd</p>
(15)
<p>always known them!</p>
<p>Had several grand letters from "Dit" He is a <hi rend="underline">stimulating</hi> person - writes me much of great interest to me, concerning books he's reading, ideas, etc.! He's quite some lad - and he'll go places and see things. Yes and I believe he'll <hi rend="underline">be</hi> someone too - don't you?</p>
<p>There is not much more to say! Tomorrow is Sunday - our last day here - and we're to see Sig, Max, Joan, and Elaine here! Monday, guien salie? We'll rehearse like everything</p>
(16)
<p>next week - and when we dance again publicly we'll keep on rehearsing. Are planning several new "exotic numbers/ Harold, our costumer "has ideas," too</p>
<p>How <hi rend="underline">are</hi> all of you?</p>
<p>Please write me soon and often - as you do, dearest ones! Maxie says I have a letter these for me! Swell. What ideas are you entertaining? Maxie and I've been indulging in a bit of astrology - amazing how much fits! Olga, by the way, knows much of same. I'll send you your horoscope soon. Tues. max and I have a "date" for something special!</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alice
<p>Maxie, dear girl, helped me move! It was easy for the two of us. Siggie wanted to help, but there was no need of breaking up his few hrs sleep! He's a dear too!!!</p>