<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
51a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
march 17, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I am really ashamed of myself for not having written in so long, but perhaps when I've conversed with you for a few pages you'll understand and forgive me. Busy? that is hardly a strong enough word to suit the care, but I am thrilled it is so, for idleness I cannot like.</p>
<p>Oh! How glorious it is here! Never have I seen more radiantly sunshiny, paradise-like days or such nights of moon-flood. Really, <hi rend="underline">there</hi> is a</p>
(2)
<p>spell cast over this country, and to some extent at least, I have fallen under it. Romantic - yes, truly so - and the people reflect something, at least, of that peculiar something which blows in the very air of this beautiful land. One can know what I mean only by experiencing same - si?</p>
<p>now, I must give you an idea of our life now and for the past few weeks. I have been working two weeks now at the Hamilton. The pay is very good, for I receive</p>
51b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>$12.00 per week salary plus all meals (anything I want), <hi rend="underline">and</hi> tips which <hi rend="underline">never</hi> drop below 1:00, and have lately been <hi rend="underline">averaging</hi> $1.50, some times being as high as $1.75 or <hi rend="underline">2.75</hi> per day. So you see I am among quite a collection of small change. This I <unclear/> ($9.46 worth) at the bank the other day for dollar bills. The clerk probably thought I'd won on a slot machine (as I mentioned to him!)</p>
(4)
<p>The work was very tiring at first (I work 8 hrs. on my feet, running most of time), but I am used to it now and do not tire badly at all, even though I scarcely get enough sleep with all my other activities I started out as a counter girl, with rush orders mostly <hi rend="underline">plus</hi> big dinners and all. Everyone seemed surprised at my speed and soon customers began to inquire where I hailed from, and what I was doing here. I told them about our problem, and thusly have made</p>
51c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>many influential acquaintances here in Laredo, for all the best people come to the Hamilton. My "boss" Christine, said I was her hardest working counter girl, and even the Hotel Manager said I was a very good waitress, so I was pleased. The cooks and bus-boys and waiters. Are all Mexican, but the waitresses are practically all Americans, soldiers wives. The cooks are helping me learn how</p>
(6)
<p>to call orders <hi rend="underline">correctly</hi> "Ham on plain" or "One egg over easy with ham or "strip bacon," or is orange juice on", etc. They are extremely friendly to me, call me many lovely names in Mexican "Chula", "Bonita", "Linda", accomodating, if a bit lazy (on the part of bus-boys!) Many timers a day mainly when I come into the kitchen one smiles at me and ask for "cafe chula, por</p>
51d
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>favor", so I dash and and get same for them. The compliment me lavishly as do these Latins; ask me if all Chicago women are as pretty as I, etc. One is sure he is in love with me, and several time's he has said "Chula, Why do I love you too much?" Of course I gaily pass if off with "Really?" or "Oh! No you don't!" I serve many many soldier boys far from home and starved for some contact with</p>
(8)
<p>real Americans. How many times a day do they ask me if I'm here with my soldier - husband, and when they find I am unmarried, <hi rend="underline">my</hi>, what undisguised interest they do show! I turn down many many chances for dates. Some are light and <sic>flitatious</sic>, others are a bit dangerously intent, and still others are sincere - and fine, and - lonesome. The other day one fine clean - cut looking lad said "When am I going to see you again? I'd like to very much." I said</p>
51
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>we'd be sure to meet over many cups of coffee, in my gayest manner, but he was still serious. Our immigration official here comes in every day for coffee, and talks to me like an old friend as do <hi rend="underline">many</hi> of Laredo's most influential business men, American and Mexican. I met the American in charge of Immigration in Nuevo Laredo, Mexico (he is at American Consulate there), and went to a movie and various</p>
(10)
<p>Mexican Club with him. He has been all over S. America, knows it and loves it. Another gentleman form Chicago (<hi rend="underline">many</hi> here are from Chicago or St. Louis) comes in every day to chat with me about Mexico, our chances for getting through, etc. He has introduced me to one of the most respected men here, Senor Benivedes, a member of the oldest family in Laredo. he too I serve and chat with daily. One gentleman left me a grand complaint</p>
51f
11
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>at the desk. "You certainly have a fine little waitress there. She really gets a job done, and she smiles <hi rend="underline">all the time</hi>." Of course I'm new at this, but I do <hi rend="underline">like</hi> to please people, and to appear before them, respectably of course, which true in the Hamilton. We have adorably beige and red uniforms, little head pieces of same, and time aprons of same. I get complimented very often on my appearance,</p>
(12)
<p>mostly from gentlemen, naturally. These Texans are very out and out, <hi rend="underline">not</hi> subtle like the Mexicans or Spaniards. They are <hi rend="underline">never</hi> insulting, but tease a great deal. "Would you like something else?" I asked a big handsome Texas cowboy the other day as I gave him "a half cup o' coffee." "Sure, he said "I want <hi rend="underline">you</hi>. Call me up sometime when you're not busy." Whew! Some places</p>
51g
(13)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>that could be misunderstood, but he meant no harm. Another man, a patrolman, had been asking me to go out for days, so I graduate, writes wild, youthful lyrics, dances wonderfully, and is generally simply too terribly romantic for me to keep track of now! We ate enchiladas and <sic>huacamole</sic> together, danced rhumba and tangos, and walked home in a flood of silver - which listened</p>
(14)
<p>like something from heaven. Don't worry - I know what I want and what I am and I <hi rend="underline">cannot</hi> deviate far from it. However, I do not believe in being afraid of <hi rend="underline">people</hi> and <hi rend="underline">life</hi> - I believe in exercising enough precaution, but I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> like meeting new people and doing new things - Believe me, I am learning much from my contacts with different types. The Mexicans love clowning and fun - and yet are terribly serious and passionate</p>
51h
(15)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>in certain moods. I have met one Spanish young man here who is really charming, but he is too serious, or thinks or says he is so i do not see him. Several, no, <hi rend="underline">many</hi> people know of us now and have seen us dance. This leads to new engagements here for us and new possibilities for our going on to Mexico soon. Today Reynolds <unclear/> Washington for up and he should he should hear tonight some</p>
(16)
<p>thing. This gives you a jumbled up glimpse of my contacts at work during the day. Several gentlemen gives me Mexican money for tips - I got a 2 pesos tip from another man the other day - and often I get quarter tips from single people. Beginning today I am working tables instead of the counter - tips are more as a rule, excepting cases where my newly-made friends are concerned. The personnel at the Hamilton are very high-class</p>
51i
(17)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>Americans, and truly nice to work for - so I am glad I have a job as nice as this as long as I must work thusly. You can see that I get <hi rend="underline">easily</hi> $22 a week <hi rend="underline">plus meals</hi> which is really quite good I work from 8:00 to 4:00; have all afternoon and evening left when I return from work.</p>
<p>Now I shall tell you what we do in the evenings. I return, real sho, or write (?), or practice. I do not</p>
(18)
<p>eat an evening meal so I usually do my bare al that time, if I have something to do in the evening. If not, we often have classes - with George as teacher. Now - we come to performances. I told you of our engagement at camp McIntosh, n' est ce-pas? We had a fine time there; were treated royally by all the soldiers, and highly complimented. This led to our engagements at the Victory Club this last Saturday and Sunday, and possibly this coming Tuesday (tomorrow). The Victory Club is an</p>
51j
(19)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>adorable place, with two large swimming pools, a large dance floor, a patio, orange trees, and all! The one pool is beautiful - blue and round, with a concealed path all around it and beyond that a wall of concrete with murals of ships, and above this, oriental looking turrets of blue. It has a grand diving board, and there are fine locker rooms near nearby for dressing. Mr. Cole, owner, is grand to us, says he is really <hi rend="underline">glad</hi> to pay out to us, and has given us the run of his club.</p>
(20)
<p>We have a grand M. C. there - a young soldier who used to be a jockey and is really funny - and very very intelligent and gentil. We have mostly an officer audience - and others in Laredo too who are really appreciate. We got grand compliments; one of the Lieutenants used to be in show business, and he was especially appreciative, making it a point to express his and his friends enjoyment. Tuesday is an officers banquet which we are probably going to dance for other things are coming up which I'll tell you about then - as a result of Hamilton contacts.</p>
51k
(21)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>Now I have not much more to tell you. I am so very thrilled and relieved and <hi rend="underline">joyous</hi> that you two are happy together and that all is as well as it is. That is something that is <hi rend="underline">so</hi> good to know - for it is all important to me. I am enclosing a few pictures - and tomorrow I am sending $5 which perhaps will help a bit for the Dr. I do hope so</p>
<p>How is your job, Mama? I do hope you are happy in it - and it certainly sounds <hi rend="underline">gentille</hi> - certainly a perfect job</p>
(22)
<p>for you to do with a flourish! Daddy, <hi rend="underline">do</hi> take care of yourself whatever you do - I know you will soon be very well again if you do.</p>
<p>I am readying "Three Friends" oh! how I love it. So are the girls! You have no idea how like a Bible "Collected Poems" is to us.</p>
<p>Mama, I need my ration book for shoes. Will you be kind enough to send it to me? Then I will get my 2<hi rend="underline">nd</hi> book and return 1<hi rend="underline">st</hi> to you or Enid whoever has it. Also, <hi rend="underline">could</hi> you send the lovely viole flowered dress? How I could use it now!</p>
<p>Please know how I love and admire and think of you always, dear ones, dear dear dear ones, your Alice</p>




