<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
53a
Important letter notice Alice & Hilda 
Alice M. Neihardt 
to 
Blancho Barber-
About the momment unvaled at Wayne-City park 

53b
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
July 4th 1926
My Dear Blanche-
This letter has been pending for days and days the times that I have scolded my self and that I have been scolded would fill this page-So after eating a good dinner of new potatoes and peas with steak &^ cucumber salad and green grape pie ^at John's supplemented with the impunction to write this letter immediately I am happy 

53c
2
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
to begin - and where? Since I am so full of a number of things - the booklet of Black Hill's since brot back to us many things of years ago and I assure you we did not stop at that, the memories of Bancroft days in which the Barbers figured <del>were</del> are not the least treasured indeed I think the club, & the social affairs missed much when you people decided to change your 

53d
3
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
stamping ground-and as I remember you made just about as little fuss over the event as the Neihardts did when they "took up their beds"-I have been back just once in six years surely the town is dead as it ever will be - I passed thru last summer on my way to Wayne when the monument to John was dedicated-Mrs Ross Cates was the only 
1

53e
4
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
person on the platform except a possible half doz. who boarded the train, several from Bancroft motored to Waynore that day - Delegations from Lincoln, Omaha Tekamah Lyons <unclear/> Emerson, Soo City, Shakefield, West Point, Randolph Carrol and a number of other towns that I can't just name the Gove. The chancellor of the univeristy Dr. House of the English, Dept of Wayne three 
1

53f
5
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
Newspaper Editors or I think it was five made speeches Oh Blanch it was a great day - It was my day and I unveiled the monument, my cup was full - my fondest hopes were realized and I was a very happy woman - 
MOna has been doing some sculping - a most wonderful bust of John It was photographed in the 
1

53g
6
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
clay which was very fortunate as the <del>paster</del> plaster <del>with</del> she used in casting was old and the result was a failure-the photograph is to be used as a frontispiece for John's collected poems for which he is now reading proof His Indian Tales will be repub-lished in the Early winter I was so happy in looking over the Sturgis woman's club year book to note that you 
1

53h
7
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
had the Riview of "The Indian Wars,"- I knew just what sympathetic thotful work you would put on the review John and Mona too were pleased that you were doing it-we are having blistering hot weather and my garden is drying up. - I have a beautiful little stone Bungale and a pretty yard in which I spend my days and my nights in a hammock you no doubt my hammock days in 
1

53i
8
MRS. ALICE M. NEIHARDT
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
in Brancroft, Please write me and where you do please tell me all about your mother your self Leila and her family and then I have reams I should like to continue this with - we are all well I go swimming with the crowd 2 or three times a week, ful just about as young as I used to unless I have forgotten every one from both houses send love and thanks for your thotful-ness-Most sincerely Alice M. Neihardt 
1

