<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Sigurd Neihardt Collection 109
[65
July, 1943]
Dearest Children:
<p>We here think of you so much and so lovingly and I wonder if you know quite how it hurts us to be so far apart. Alice is very hopeful of good things in her word. She is one of 2 girls now since Doris has been "canned" and the George Leon Dancers continue as a Trio now which is a much better and more harmonious ensemble. They have had beautiful pictures taken by "Seymour" and have been having auditions - of which several look most favorable. - No fooling - these are the dark ages once more - and all of Daddy's values are in "absenlia" from the present scheme of things. So for the time being you, Sigurd are in the same boat with Daddy, as far as your Music and his Poetry are concerned - and you are <hi rend="underline">so</hi> lucky to be a fine mechanic in spite of anything else that is a pity.</p>
<p>I Keep hoping that we may see you one of these days - but if you do come to Chicago be sure to do so when <hi rend="underline">I</hi> am here. I leave for Enids' the 20th of this month, and will be gone about 3 weeks.</p>
<p>Daddy will remain here and take care of himself by his lonesome in a cheaper room</p>
110
<p>than we have now - Amama has gone with Uncle Dick who recently motored to San Francisco, and I don't Know where she will go next. I will take a job when I return from Enid's too - then our combined salaries will get us out of the hole we are in.</p>
<p>Please tell us how things are going for you all. Nanny thinks so much of you all four - and how she wishes she could <hi rend="underline">serve</hi> you in <hi rend="underline">some</hi> way!</p>
<p>We may Keep on with our present work here for a year, and then go elsewhere. We have been able to save the home in Branson, and it may yet mean something for <hi rend="underline">all</hi> of us - especially if we could sell it.</p>
<p>Endless love to you dear, dear children and Kiss my Joan and my Elaine again and again for their Gaki and Nanny -</p>
Endlessly loving you -
Mom.


