<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
71 
130 
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON JUL 5 7-AM 1936 MO. 
<unclear/> 
Miss Enid Neihardt 
5544 Pershing Ave 
Ilene Apts. 
301 
St. Louis, 
Mo. 

July 4th 
131
My own darling Enid: 
You don't know how eager I am for you to be happy in your way not mine - But just because of this I seem to be trying to exert my influence upon you - but when you are a mother you will look back and forgive my mis-takes in this way. Or may be you already do so?! <unclear/> the fact that I did not want your heart broken was the reason years ago that I cut off any com 

2
132 
munication whatever with Mrs Stoker. This no one knew but I myself. She then was dif-ferent about Nelson. Then she spoke strongly for Nelson's mary-rying into a rich and old aristocratic family - and I knew she would not ap-prove of our girlie. I did not know that you were in love with Nelson then but I feared you might be-come so. Aside from this I did not like Mrs Stoker's putting Daddy's picture in her bedroom nor her taking him out to lunch. In other words I was jea-lous of her. This was all I 

3
133
ever told any one but the con-versation in which Mrs Stoker showed her self to be a schemer for her son in a direction anta gonistic to our girlie was ^the deeper reason never expressed to any one before this, for my cutting her off so sud-denly. I just tell you all this that you may better under-stand your very often mista-ken old mother. Now that you have expressed a definite point of view i am all through trying to direct you, darling only know that whatever makes your happiness also makes minee, I am so glad to know that Maxine and Joan and Sigurd are to be with you today and Oh! how I wish we 

4
134
three might gain you four 
However that is a thing to be looked forward to in the future and I fear not so very near either.-I am much better - slept more normally than usual and last night so I'll not need the whisky but thanks for the sugges-tion.-but my "sausage-fest" is so slow to become normal - and so the danger of another relapse keeps me helpless as far as even trying to walk is concerned. I can not see the end of it! 
Enid if you knew how regularly I say to Virgi-nia, when she washes my face and hands anew 3 or 

5
135
four times daily (to say nothing of the daily bath), "Oh isn't that the loveliest soap - and how good it smells! How I wish Enid coudl know how I love it"! You would feel you had indeed made me happy. But whenever I have written to you I'd get tired before getting this said! So now you know how welcome a present that was. My skin is clearer than it has ben in years! The other morning I had Marie cut my hair jand thin it and it is sweet to see how thrilled the children are over "how nice Mamma looks". Bless their hearts. Wasn't 

6 
136
it nice of Marie to walk out here and do that for me! And she woudl not take more than 25 cents! 
Hilda got up early this morning and baked a huge cake for the Birthday of our wise and glorious motion! She is now busy with it. Alice is a staunch little helper. The two kids certainly have been wonderful all the time and it is thanks to them that I do eat like a pig and that I can enjoy this lovely home, fo rthey keep it so well; it always is a new treat to be carried into the front room to look around at the pretty place. I have your pictures constantly before me Daddys yours and Sig's. 
Loads of Love Mamma. 