<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
308 Fink Collection 65
Branson, Oct 7th 1941
Darling Enid:
<p>Thanks for the lovely pictures of Neihardt the 1st. Surely he is a perfect baby and I Know how much you and Ollie are joining in loving him. I wonder if Ollie has done any thing about the relief? I think he has been too busy doing other and helpful things to have even a moment to devote to the relief but nice as photographs are they cannot do what sculpture does in the way of making permanent a passing stage in the growth of a dear one. I realize this more than ever now, and I do so wnat to have the chance to</p>
66
2
<p>model you with Neihardt next Summer when you come home and he will be perfect.</p>
<p>Daddy thinks a statuette is the finest way to make a real portrait. He things the one I made of Frankie so charming and so true, and he wants me to do others.</p>
<p>We have <underline>40 perfect</underline> Ozark babies now; they are still met all but ! which are finished and delicately tinted. When Hilda and Alice came next week-end I want them to bring Dad's Tux etc down here as he will need it for a reading on the 22nd. They then will take</p>
67
3
<p>a number of Ozark babies back up with them to place in St Louis for me.</p>
<p>We want you to get the Book Page of the Globe Democrat of Saturday September 27th and read the very wonderful review Mr Burke wrote about Jed Smith. Enid it makes me want to weep with joy, that anyone could write that way about our Poet - and every word so true. <underline>Of course</underline> Dad <underline>deserves</underline> the Pultizer Prize, but deserving is one thing, getting another. We Know that, but we cannot help hoping that he <underline>does</underline> receive it <underline>this</underline> time. This is a strange world.--</p>
68
4
<p>You ask about my foot. It is almost well, but I cannot as yet wear any shoes so I have been mighty glad I had the pair of sandals to cut so that I could walk as comfortably as I have been doing.</p>
<p>Now that Max is with Sigie Gaki and I are so glad to have the Wubs for without them it would seem foolish to be here. We have a big suppy of coal for the Winter in our garage - and wood in the cowbarn - so we are well fixed. Also we have two bushels of Irish potatoes, 2 bushels of apples and 1 of sweet potatoes</p>
69
5
<p>shead! I want very much to have 100 chickens and two pigs next Spring plus a Jersey cow - the Nanny will make money and a wonderful Home for all of you children to come to aswell as all the grand children! Besides this I Know I can sell my "dodads" in various places and this should mean happiness for me during the rest of my lifetime in this strange but beautiful World. -To do this I must have the place fenced for chickens, and some building done about the "guarage" which would make a perfect chicken house with small expense. Daddy</p>
70
6
<p>does not like the idea of being so tied down, but he would not have to be here when he wanted to lecture or travel - I feel this is far more sensible for me than running around so much; I have to have a home where I cam "stay put" when I want to do so - and that close to the Earth, not in a city.</p>
<p>Mr and Mrs Oesch and their adorable little boy have been here and we like them <underline>very</underline> much. They are so <underline>real</underline>. Mrs Oesch likes the Anchor Village and Branson <strike>and</strike> so very much - I am so glad!</p>
<p>I understand your not letting your baby cry - I never let you either! Pretty soon he will be wearing the little outing flannel gowns his Nanny</p>
71
7
<p>made for him - and them he'll just be a regular "Wub" and a "big fat" too! Kiss him in the back of his sweet, soft neck for me.</p>
<p>Let me help you by sewing for you if you need or want any thing made for your Man for yourself or for our Baby grandson - and I'll be delighted.</p>
Loads of love as always
from your devoted
Mama
Mother
Nannie.