<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
July 6, 1936
27 
140
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON JUL 7 7-AM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Dr. John G. Neihardt. 
5544 Pershing Ave 
Ilene Aptmts
301
St. Louis
Mo. 

July 6th 36
141
My own Darling
I have so many things to say since I did not write yester day! Darling will you find out from Sigurd right away where our boat engine is? You must not have to lose that, and the children coudl have such a good tiem with it this summer. Our boat is well painted and taken care of and stands at Camp Ponca, where a man feels responsible for it. This is thansk to Mr. Wilson. 
Next Darling coudl you pick up a book on Mo. birds for me? I watch our Mullberry tree hours at a time and it is a bird - heaven or haven. I have watched many birds I would so like to identify. I know we have a book on birds, but being in 

142
the library it is as you know lost as far as I am concerned. I thought you might be able to trade for one at teh second hand book store, or buy one cheaply. 
I wrote Mr Leonard to pleease be patient with me for another year, as the Dr in Spring field told Hilda I <del>n</del> could not think of going to work for 6 mo. Please tell Enid that she must not think of making the ex-pensive trip down her ein or-der to see me. Hilda has set her heart on taking me up to you before going back to Lincoln, and then getting her clothes for the winter in your big city. She will need a number of things. 
Virginia has been accompa-

143
nying Hilda on the Piano and Hilda is getting the "hang" of it we get so much pleas we out of Sig's Piano! Virginia's Mother and Sister were down here yes-terday and they were so nice and Virginia was the happiest kid you ever saw! the sister is a pupil of Mrs Kinsey in Springfield; plays in a masterly but unfeeling lmannr. It was a pleasure to hear her even though the Piano is not in good condition. 
Lache drove a sick friend up to North Minnesota to a Hospital for <del>soldiers</del> 

144
how much you mean to Hilda! When she read your letter about Lache she suddenly burst into fears more violent than I have ever seen her! Then she laughed with pure joy and gave me your letter to read! The chil-dren as well as their mother are so dominated by you and what you really do think. That is all as it should be! God bless you dear, over and over Nothing is too good for you and you will receive unli-mitedly. 
Loads of Love 
from your pudgy
old girl 
Mona. 