<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
129h
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
May 25, 1941.
Dearest Mom:-
<p>Alice &amp; I are sitting out here in the backyard, knee-deep, almost, in blue grass, getting sun-tanned! Hilda &amp; Albert were out last <sic>nite</sic> &amp; we all had a nice time chatting. Hil went back with Albert &amp; Alice stayed all <sic>nite</sic> with us. She needs a bit of sun-tan, &amp; I fear I have a bit ahead of Alice! The "bunny" loves the sun, as it kicks my tummy off when it gets out in the sun!</p>
<p>Tomorrow is your dear birthday, Mom, &amp; don't think hubby &amp; I aren't thinking of you with the <underline>greatest</underline> admiration &amp; <underline>deepest</underline> love!! Somehow as yet, we haven't gotten around to picking out a suitable birthday gift, but hope to in a day or two! May there be <underline>many, many, many</underline> happy returns of May 26<underline>th</underline>, Mom!! And we are sure there will be! We send <underline>all our</underline> love!!</p>
<p>Hil was mentioning about the shortage of beds at home! Now, why can't we put this extra bed &amp; mattress of yours on the Campbell truck soon? Why should it be here? Ol &amp; I will do that very soon, after we inquire into the matter. You should have the dresser, too, but I fear that might be mroe expense than it's worth to get it there. It's different with a metal bed!! We'll see about this very soon, because you surely need the bed, what with all the visitors you have!</p>
129i
2
<p>We're going to transform the sunroom very soon now - perhaps it'll be next week - end &amp; that'd be a good time to look into sending the bed down - prepaid incidentally! The sunroom will be a nursery, from now on, &amp; we'll have the studio couch to let people sleep on in the dining room!! Ha! Ol is going to paint the wicker divan &amp; the sunroom linoleum &amp; then he'll be thru painting! I painted a number of things too!! The high chair, a toy &amp; book rack, the basket, &amp; the chest of drawers!</p>
<p>By the way, thanks so much for the <underline>adorable</underline> birdie! With your permission, Ol would like to paint that on the chest of drawers! Wouldn't that be darling? I want to paint animals around in various places in the nursery anyhow! Ha!</p>
<p>Please tell Max that we enjoyed her dear letter &amp; I'll write her tomorrow sure.</p>
<p>Too bad you can't be here with us today! When are you coming up again?</p>
<p>Write us soon!</p>
Loads of love to the <underline>dearest</underline> of Mothers form a <underline>most</underline> loving
-Ollie &amp; Enid
