<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
107a
4920 Blackson Ave.
Chicago, Illinois
June 18, 1943.
Dear Madame Cassan,
<p>Needless to say, I was very sorry last Friday when, passing through St. Louis, my schedule did not allow enough time to see you. I did telephone you at the studio however, but found no - one in. Therefore, a letter shall have to suffice Sylvia has told me all about you, however - and for that I am very grateful. How wonderful it would be to <hi rend="underline">see</hi> you though, and have one of our old heart-to-heart talks! Sincerely, Madame, what I have absorbed form, had all I remember of, you kids been and shall always remain perhaps the strongest influence in my life - and I want you to know that I am ever grateful, as are so <hi rend="underline">many</hi> of your pupils. Your "happiness" rings are constantly with us, all three, and I actually believe they have some sort of power! Sometimes surface impressions are deceiving, aren't they? Perhaps, in our case, all will be happier in the long run for the bit of sadness now. Of course,</p>
(2)
<p>Sylvia has told you all about Doris "leaving" our little troupe and the scenes which led up to such a drastic change - so I need say no more. Of course, we are as good friends as ever, and all is well understood by each of us. Now we three can get down to real work as a trio, which our agent has advised for some time.</p>
<p>We are having lovely weather here in Chicago now. The lake is glorious, and, all in all, our U.S.A. is still a fine place to live!</p>
<p>Mexico was, for me at least, <hi rend="underline">extremely</hi> fascinating, and I can truthfully say that I felt terribly sad in having to leave it so soon. The ways of doing business are impossible - for any unexperienced (in Latin business - doings!) person, but otherwise the country is almost a paradise. Exciting too - just far enough from Heaven to <hi rend="underline">be</hi> exciting! Sylvia had no time, she said, to tell you about all our doings there, and of course, it would require a book to do so on paper. Right now, all I can say is that we had an experience never-to-be forgotten and, speaking personally, <hi rend="underline">very</hi></p>
107b
(3)
<p>personally, Mexico means more now than merely another beautiful foreign land. Had I <hi rend="underline">seen</hi> you Madame, I should have wanted to tell you something very confidentially, and, since I didn't I want to tell you something very confidentially, and, since I didn't I want to tell you now. I laugh so when I remember what you used to say concerning such possibilities - and I can see Snippy's twinkling eyes as she would say "Didn't I always say so?" It seems, getting down to brass tacks, that all of us have done a bit of "tumbling" - but it is <hi rend="underline">my</hi> business to tell you of one case alone - my own. While in Mexico, I re-met a former friend of ours who had spent a year in St. Louis several years ago, a Swiss. He was dashing, charming, "gentille," and inately gentle manly as ever - and seemed as glad to see me as I he. To make a long (?) story shorter, we "saw the sights" in Mexico City together, and he insisted on entertaining the whole troupe on other occasions, making our arrival in such a strange land the more pleasant. We, of course, entertained him in such a strange land the more pleasant. We, of course, entertained him in our apartment, and sat spellbound after dinner listening</p>
(4)
<p>to his tales of "Mexico in the <unclear/>." You see, he downs and lives, with his brother, on a ranch in the "birds" of the State of Mexico. "Bandith" still exist there to a certain degree, they have even had horses stolen, and have had mild shooting scrapes. The ranch now produces raw materials for the war effort, equal to <hi rend="underline">fifty men on the front</hi>, yet, two years ago it was nothing but a historic name and an adobe ranch - house. The two brothers, high-born Swiss, bought the ranch for security in case Europe "goes up in smoke" - and they have practically built the whole establishment themselves. At present, of course, a large crew of "peones" does all menial labor, and only the overseeing is left to the brothers. To get back to my subject, Max (<hi rend="underline">the</hi> certain brother!) came just three different times (every time he could escape form the duties of ranch-life to drive 90 miles over a dirt, mountainous road!) to see us. He watched our performances, then took me out afterwards, and during the daytime we went shopping or to a movie together.</p>
107c
(5)
<p>Suddenly one night as we were dancing to (Oh! <hi rend="underline">How</hi> he dances rhumbas and tangoes - and <hi rend="underline">how</hi> many times I've blessed the days I struggled away in Jr. League, <hi rend="underline">learning</hi> same, Madame!) one of those beautiful, haunting, <hi rend="underline">sad</hi> Mexican tunes, we both simply <hi rend="underline">knew</hi> and felt - and that was all. I've never, never, know such ecstasy, yet such sadness as I felt then, and have felt many times since that certain night. And, stranger yet, I didn't even question the whole affair! Till now, I've been absolutely disinterested in attentions from <hi rend="underline">men</hi> (Just an old <hi rend="underline">ballerina</hi> at heart! Poor Ballerina") but <hi rend="underline">this</hi> time I really tumbled." Fortunately, this is extremely two-sided. In fact, I think he loves me even more than I him - if <hi rend="underline">that</hi> is <hi rend="underline">possible</hi>! But perhaps you are chuckling at me by now - and I don't blame you - for a year ago I would never have believed this. Max wants me to return whenever I can and <hi rend="underline">will</hi>. You see, I left because I felt that the only <hi rend="underline">right</hi> thing to do at present for various</p>
(6)
<p>reasons. I have never seen him as upset as he was the day I left the ranch, where I visited several days after the close a four engagement at the Folies Bergere. After three glorious days of riding horseback over the most beautiful country one could hope to see, swimming in cold mountain water, watching incomperable sunsets with snow capped mountains as background, and counting (?) innumerable jewel - bright stars set in the velvet sky of that God-graced Land - together - we were suddenly and almost cruelly brought back to earth. That occurred when George came tramping up one glorious night just after I'd retired in the little guest house which I shared with the family of the Head Peone (I don't really know his <hi rend="underline">title</hi>!) Hearing the familiar voice, yet so unexpected on <hi rend="underline">this</hi> far-distant rancho, I dressed hurriedly and, managing to unlock my door, though all was pitch - dark, ran to the main ranch-house. George had already been rescued from the Great Danes which guard the rancho, and I set about getting him a bite to eat. Both Max and his brother were up, looking sleepy</p>
107d
(7)
<p>and - should I admit, quite lacking in joy! George soon told us that he had been forced to come, for the Immigration officials intended to escort us to the border "<hi rend="underline">en masse</hi>" - that meant only <hi rend="underline">one</hi> thing - I must be brought back to Mexico City, instead of remaining a few days longer on the ranch then being driven half-way to Laredo by Max. Since no telephones exist in that land for miles (the nearest village is like something from a fairy-tale!), George had to come via bus and on foot - with a guide. The next morning I arose at 6:00, made the early morning rounds with Max, walking across several miles of beautiful fields, breathing the crisp cool mountain air, seeing the dew on the grass, and looking in amazement at the majestic mountains, the Volcano of Toluca Nevada - <hi rend="underline">for the last time.</hi> Having been brave and calm "till now, I could not be so any longer, but was forced to borrow. Max's handkerchief and disgrace myself most thoroughly. We discussed matters very frankly. I insisted that I <hi rend="underline">must</hi> leave then, but that whatever is real <hi rend="underline">will</hi> last - and I promised</p>
(8)
<p>to return one day. Max simply intended, as he had one night previous when I explained to him what dancing meant to me, and how I <hi rend="underline">could</hi> not give it up on the spur of the moment - no matter how much he meant to me. Do you understand, Madame? When I was through he said, "I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> understand you, though I do not <hi rend="underline">want</hi> to, and I will respect your wishes. If it were not so necessary for you to go I would go, I would do everything possible to keep you here." Knowing Max, I firmly believe that no-one could have <hi rend="underline">made</hi> me leave had I not been agreeable. <hi rend="underline">Does</hi> this all sound like a piece of romantic fiction? Hearing it told thusly I can almost think so myself - were it not so terribly, beautifully <hi rend="underline">real</hi> to me as it is. After a peaceful breakfast, the four of us chatting together as gaily as possible, we prepared to leave. Max was again his reserved, dignified self, but all the gaiety, the spark, that I had helped bring out in him was now gone - and it made me want to weep. He was so dear - told me then how his plans to go "shopping with me" in Mexico City were completely frustrated. And so</p>
107e
(9)
<p>we left - the brother Heinz driving us back to Mexico City - and so away from something that had become somehow a part of me. Heinz was dear - even came to see us off, and took care of my baggage for me. I could hardly believe we were actually leaving - but we did. And life has been going on ever since. My people noticed a change in me at once - and they <hi rend="underline">liked</hi> it! Strange! Now I have told them and they are most understanding and sweet about the whole affair. Asked what I plan to do, I can only say that I <hi rend="underline">do not know now</hi> - all I can do is accomplish what I must now - then hope for the Best - which I <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> will come. But I have been boring you with my private affairs, Madame, and I suppose I am silly. However, I <hi rend="underline">wanted</hi> to tell you, and so I have done. Will you forgive me?</p>
<p>How are all things at the studio? Recital must be over by now, and, undoubtedly, you are greatly relieved. Any news you care to write, I shall be extremely happy to hear, Madame. How are Mr. Burridge and Lal? Give them my best regards. Tell Snippy "Hello" for me, and convey my best wishes</p>
(10)
<p>to Miss Williams and Miss Crist - as well as all the little ballerinas.</p>
<p>We have had pictures of our act as a trio taken by Maurice Seymour, and picked poses just yesterday evening from the proofs. They are really very nice - Seymour is pleased as well as we! Now we shall continue rehearsing, and may leave town this next week on another engagement. This life is never without its thrills and <hi rend="underline">adventure</hi> is certainly a requirement of mine. - I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> that now. <hi rend="underline">Life</hi> is <hi rend="underline">so</hi> intensely interesting to me in all its phases. So often, Something you said concerning that occurs to me, and I know <hi rend="underline">how</hi> true it is.</p>
<p>I hope you will overlook the enthusiasm of my over-lengthy discourse concerning "mi amor en Mexico." I wrote all that yesterday while in such a mood and now almost wish I hadn't. Perhaps it will amuse you, however, and if so, I am glad! Strange how un-funny it is to me however; I never before realized. All I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> is that the thought of never returning to Mexico is <hi rend="underline">unbearable</hi> to me, however much I love dancing. He feels just as I, as letters prove - and such <hi rend="underline">beautiful</hi> letters! So much for that!</p>
<p>Please write me when and if you find time, Madame  - it means more than you know.</p>
Love as ever,
Alice