<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- letter is incomplete -->
43a
Hotel Berkshire
15 EAST OHIO STREET
CHICAGO
April 23, 1942
Dear Daddy, Mama, Hilda, and Albert,
<p>I want ot write you something of a resume of our doings so far. Everything has happened so quickly I'm quited in a doze - and thus far I love it.</p>
<p>We had a nice train ride, arriving here in Chicago at 6:10 Tues. - coming straight to this hotel where we have a special rate for one week. We got a good rest after going out to eat dinner and admiring the glorious open skyline of Chicago. That is we rested as well as possible on a new bed, and with the slight annoyance of the nearly elevator, which keeps up its worried sound most of the time day and night.</p>
<p>Wednesday was a <underline>most</underline> unusual day - different from any I have ever spent before. About 10:00 we emerged into the sungliht, decked out in our best Spring outfits, and walked down Michigan Blvd. to the "agent section" of Chicago,</p>
(2)
<p>for indeed, it seems to be so that they are all within a few blocks of each other. That walk was a new and wholly unimagined thrill for me - and the glorious sunshine sparkling on those high white buildings added a great deal to the beauty of it all. We asked a certain man directions, and he took great pleasure in telling us all about Chicago. He also wrote a note to a certain man in the Nat. Broadcasting Bldg. whcih will get us passes to a radio show some night. He ws some "big shot" in that business, it seems. After leaving this gentleman at our first calling place, we really made the rounds, and got valuable information. All agreed there is a terrific shortage of "line girls" in Chicago, but not till we came to one certain a gent did we receive word of real ballet work.. We were here instructed to see Ruth Pryor, who was at the Civic</p>
43b
(3)
Hotel Berkshire
15 EAST OHIO STREET
CHICAGO
<p>Theatre here for several years and is a Soloist. Therefore, we did go to see her at the Jo Keith Dancing Studio where she teaches now. This place looked like something out of the "Arabian Nights" - it is turly fascinating with its unusual decoration and statuary. Ruth Pryor came out to see us and arranged fo ran audition this morning at 11:00 (Thursday). After leaving the studio we went to Edna McRae's where we inquired as to possiblity of placements before studying, and were informed that no placements are made till one has studied some time with McRae, quite naturally. We met two people, a girl and a boy</p>
(4)
<p>whome we knew at Fortuna there, and they asked if we would like to watch class. This we did do. McRae teaches very much like Madame and yet, Madame Cassan still has something over her, we all believe. However, she is a <underline>grand</underline> teacher and lovely person. We left McRae's Studio at 5/4:00 and went to eat at a very quaint little place called the "Green Shutters" - delicious food with a home touch. After this we walked home (Everyone walks a lot here) and rested awhile. At 7:30 Bill McMullin came for us and took us all on a <underline>real</underline> tour of Chicago - outside and in - and I do mean we saw Chicago from a lovely point of view. The skyline along the Lake Shore Drive was something I shall never forget - the cool lake aire and the beautiful, glorious architecture were</p>
43c
(5)
Hotel Berkshire
15 EAST OHIO STREET
CHICAGO
(5)
<p>there. We visited Ruth Sexton (of Madame Cassan's) and talked over some prospects with her. She is working at the Bismarck and wants us to come see a show Tuesday night. When we returned to the hotel, and before we called the Countess, Mrs. McMullin invited us to dinner Sunday evening - all three os us. What a day!</p>
<p>Now, to continue thsi morning we arose, had breakfast and set out after more contacts. Everyone was lovely to us again. We left our names everywhere of course, and one in special was very encouraging. A Mrs. Ame was working out of town at $30 adn $35 per wk. will, according to her Asisstant whome we contacted, "undoubtedly be interested in you for a new line</p>
(6)
<p>She was tickled when we said we specialized in ballet. We are to hear Tuesday from her concerning this. We called the Dance Directress at Edgewater Beach Hotel (Swankiest hotel here) and got an appointment with her for 5:30 this evening. This was through an agent whom we had contacted already. To be in good shape for this audition, we went home and slept several hours. At 3:15 we got up, did a barre, and dressed. The ride was marvelous - along Lake Shore Drive on a double decker bus! The hotel was gorgeous outside and in - all bedecked inside with cherry blossoms. The audition with Dorothy Dorhen proved quite easy and very satisfactory. She said she'd liek very much to use us in a new line ("With you and a few others like you we'd really hve something," she said.) This will take some time to come into being she thinks.</p>