<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
141a
(1)
Home -10:00 Tues
morning
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Please do forgive my not writing lately. I simply must write more often and I shall.</p>
<p>The bread did arrive, Mama, and is delicious, but due to the way it was sent it come a little crushed so next time you'd better put it in a box. I do like it so very</p>
(2)
<p>much - it seems like a part of home and makes my lunches much much better.</p>
<p>We've been rehearsing almost every day including Sundays from 2:00 till around 6:00. Yesterday Madame told us our czards (Jessie, Sylvia, and I) was very nice, and told me I am going to be lovely in the</p>
(3)
<p>Moskovsky (?) waltz (my solo). Today I have rehearsal alone on that. I do so hope recital will go over very well. WE're all doing and are going to do our <sic>doggondest</sic> to make that happen. I do hope that you can come to see recital. Couldn't you</p>
(4)
<p>come back with Sig? Oh! that would be grand.</p>
<p>How long a zipper do you need? The one on my blue tutu is only about 6 in. Should it be longer?</p>
<p>It's swell that Sig could go home. Too bad he's so blue though. I do so hope things get better for him - Daddy can help him</p>
141b
(5)
<p>Hilda looks marvelous and is really quite happy again. Everyone loves her hair; I think I'll get mine cut too. I'll ask Madame what she thinks.</p>
<p>Mama, the bust looks simply marvelous. Everyone here thinks it is wonderful - and it certainly is Daddy</p>
(6)
<p>You should be greatly greatly happy over it, because it certainly is a master piece. We can hardly wait to see the large pictures of it. You look so happy in the picture too - just as you should be.</p>
<p>It's been glorious weather here - quite, that is, very hot,</p>
(7)
<p>at times, but beautiful anyway. It must be gorgeous at home now. How often I've wished I could jump in our crystal Roark pool.</p>
<p>That is marvelous about Jed Smith. I can hardly wait to read it all, Daddy. I've played over your record so often that I know both "April Theology" and</p>
(6)
<p>"And the Little Wind" by heart. Oh! they are so perfectily beautiful and absolutely meaningful - if you can understand my expressions. I've quoted these and others to several people a certain fitting times and they are simply struck by the combined beauty and directions of meaning. They are a great help</p>
141c
(7)
<p>to me, and reciting them is such a thrill.</p>
<p>Recital is next Tuesday, June 10<underline>th</underline>, dress rehearsal is Saturday. We've been busy getting fittings at the costumers as well as rehearsing.</p>
<p>I got a letter from Nakanawa explaining the council ring ceremonies and ask-</p>
(8)
<p>ing me to write them "my" plan for what might be interesting. I'm going to write a complete account to them very soon.</p>
<p>So you're not going West tell Fall? Maybe things will be better that way anyway. Do you think you might get to drive</p>
(9)
<p>to Nakanawa?</p>
<p>Eny called yesterday. I must call her very soon again. We've had loads of fun out there, and Eny is very well so is Ollie.</p>
<p>I must go to rehearsal soon now. Loads of things are yet to be done in getting</p>
(10)
<p>ready for our big event.</p>
<p>Please do be happy - <underline>don't</underline> be "heartsick" as you say, Mama when I don't write. I simply must not put it off anymore.</p>
Loads of love to all of you dear good ones,
Alice
<p>West riding with Hil and Ol in car, Fri. afternoon. Saw folder - it's very good.</p>
141d
Alice Neihardt
3532 Holliday Ave.
St. Louis
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 4
JUN3
530PM
1941
BUY U.S. SAVINGS
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMAN
<stamp>UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Mo.