<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
89 Neihardt Collection 44
[August 31, 1942]
<header>HOTEL STATLER ST. LOUIS</header>
Tuesday, 10 1/2 A.M.
<p>Before starting to find my way to sweet wife mother - Enid, let me say to my two loved ones, that, had I followed this old Heart of mine, I would like a contordly, sick beast, have taken tail between my legs in Springfield, have cast all considerate plaus aside, &amp; returned to you. I did though the feave thing - i continued my journey, holding back the ever-too-ready to gushing tears - it <unclear/> voice - this A.M. ni such a cold-air-cooled comfortable room, after a hot bath last night, &amp; at 7 o'clock sharp, after dream after dream of you, my ownly Danglitre modeling baby-boy figneres on &amp; around a stump. And in spirit I had one usualy companionable, dear breakfast with my so only appreciated beloved children. Enough - or else liek the war-another subject make</p>
45
<p>dollar-promise, &amp;, ni a bus so full there seemed no seat anywhere be had my black bag on my seat, and I was at comfortable in it at crowds, &amp; great beat, &amp; heartache for you , &amp; memories of such sweetness &amp; love, our garden &amp; hammock -ease would permit. We had two extra, full busses following ours - many stops for would-be travelers, a number of dear American boys, gaily enroute to be slaughtered believing however the war would end very soon - very soon, poor innocents! And to my happy regretful surprise, when, over an hour late our bus landed me in St Louis, there stood with shining face &amp; eyes our beautiful little Hilda &amp; handsome Albert to meet, dirty, sticky old Amama M their <unclear>cer</unclear> we went to Statler, with look at my wisely reserved room on 12th-floor, without washing hands even, we went to the club-bar-room they so love, had a drink - I a ham sandwich &amp; iced tea - &amp; just talked -talked. They exude happy courageous - sensible Youth - several wonder</p>
46
<p>ful possiblities - Brooklyn, N.Y. - A place in New Jersey Ec &amp; intend to act as if no war-draft may interfere. Such bubbling joie de vivre - you must be happy with, about, for them too - but I cant talk any longer if I am to be - as arranged &amp; with Enid &amp; Baby Nei, Hilda said, seemed to sense the packages on his birthday belonged to himself only, cried when Enid took one away to give him another, &amp; was simply adorable. Sigurd can get off, whereas Albert</p>
<header>HOTEL STATLER ST. LOUIS</header>
<p><unclear>my nice ha is able tear</unclear> spring pour forth its hot, burning, salty water. The bus-driver from Branson was one of those born mean surly beasts. M Spingfield a new negro parter, as well, alert, nice ugly man took me &amp; my baggage in charge &amp; saying, if humanly possible, &amp; my preferred seat not occupied, he would get it for me. I was to just sit in station room &amp; wait for him to fetch me. I somehow <unclear/> him - &amp; the one</p>
47
<p>can not - &amp; thinks of fetching you in his car. And my advice is expect &amp; have him do this - for his, as well as your saks Ec. Ec.</p>
<p>Miss Boehmer is, as I expected, in this hotel. Hilda seems to sense &amp; feel -- our convictions - I cited a case where her pride (haha!) should have had her solicit in person, not write, &amp; expect the employer, who is as our Hilda says: after all is the big her-up &amp; in command - And so - will if lucky she will land a job, worthy of her all-greatness - &amp; my humble self will not encumber her here.</p>
<p>A dear, dear note here from Olli, anticipating his &amp; <unclear>Gwynne's</unclear> happiness if I am well enough to return - Ec.</p>
<p>And as Hilda &amp; Albert cant say enough of how well Amama looks - you, dear, loved Daughter &amp; son John will feel repaid for the priceless love given </p>
Your love-hungering, greedy, old
Mammie
<p>John please send the prayer &amp; the forgotten Hemmingway review. I had fried chicken at Davids on, almost choked our bones for King George because you were not with me.</p>

