<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
24 Thompson Collection 31
[Fri, Feb 12
1943]
Darling Alice:
<p>Your good letter describing the Auto accident has been read with real admiration for the writer and also with profound gratitude for your "rescue" and now I have placed the letter along with all the other ones for you to use some day later on! You have not sent me the <sic>promissed</sic> clippings you were to get for me from George, remember?</p>
<p>Your dear good letter telling only the <hi rend="underline">pleasant</hi> side of your forced stay in Laredo still leaves us to worry over your wellfare - Are you per chance having too little to eat? I have been so afraid of some such state of affairs.</p>
<p>Daddy is doing every thing possible to get himself a job - Oh why is it being so terribly hard for him to get any thing when he is so outstandingly <hi rend="underline">able</hi>?!</p>
<p>Any way, that is that! I</p>
32
<p>am finishing your costume tomorrow when Daddy and I are going in to Hilda's to spend the night sleeping in Amama's room. She left today at noon for Cartland N.Y. where she expects to stay till something comes to make it feasable for her to come to us. If we had had <hi rend="underline"> some</hi> money from <hi rend="underline"> some</hi>thing such as reviewing or from you children, she would have gone to Branson with us, but she did not want to meet out entire expenses, and any way she is now in very good health and was not really in <hi rend="underline"> need</hi> of my caring for her as she was the other time when we went down to Branson together. Also she <hi rend="underline"> wanted</hi> to see her little granddaughter Sally. So that is that.</p>
<p>Now Daddy has one book to review and we have a good outlook in Chicago - If that should work</p>
33
<p>out then Hilda could be with us in that city, and if <hi rend="underline"> you should</hi> have to go on your own again, and want to try for some other opportunity in Chicago, you could come to us there, and you and Hilda might then have a chance <hi rend="underline"> together</hi> as you two girls used to dream of doing. I should <hi rend="underline"> love</hi> that so! In that case Amama too might be with us and would we not be a happy family? Please don't feel downed, darling - You are brave adn so much that</p>
34
<p>is hard at the time is truly for better things in the future.</p>\
<p>I don't like your having to be in such "low" things as Frankin and Johnny. It makes me sick - and I also know that Mexico City people hunger and thirst for <hi rend="underline"> beauty</hi> like all the Latin peoples do, and I doubt if it is even good to appear there with anything so crude. Daddy is sending you $2.00 because we have the fear you are needing money terribly. I'll send your costume tomorrow.</p>
Endless love
from your Mama