<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
3
Honolulu
Feb. 9th. 99. 2.30.p.m.
<ucnlear/>. I am well. The Frankfort Ohio laid anchor here at 12 O clock today with about 9.co.s of soldiers. I had an hour and half off up town. Honolulu, is a city of 30.000 pop., 6.000 are Americans. I have been in 32 of the U.S. passed through Post Huran wonder the St. Clair river at that point. On to Lake Huron Ontario, East to the Englandish styled city of Toronto. 
but have never seen 

2 once page 4
a more beautiful City than this. Washington City with its 3,000 acres of <unclear/>, and boulevards, in my opinion, is not equal.
I passed 20 acres Lil's residence, The American flag floating in the gentle breezes over the magnificent structure, and the large enclosure filled with Tropical vegetation, - Cocoanut - trees bananas, vines, and clusters of flours. All peoples look clean, intelligent, and healthy. It is 2/// from Frisco, to here I do not know how soon we sail for Manila over 5,000 mi. 

page 3 sheet 2 5
All the soldiers but a few they having been on the Ocean recently, became very Seasick vomiting badly, but the greater number, began to get better after 24, hours, however, many felt badly for five and six days and poor little nick caught Hades too. 
I was offolly bad and thank fortune that magnificent that Glorious, that Herioc Craft, that great traveller The Oregon, 

page 2 6
is anchored here, and with about four hundred sailors welcomed us with a salute, and a thousand voices echoed from the Ohio. O how I love that, one of the Greatest of Ships, The Oregon you know much of her too. The Ohio, is considered a good transport she is 360. ft long. 40 broad and carries, or cuts about 19 to 23 ft. under water. Fri Feb. 10. 10 oclock, a.m. Kind children. I wish to write some more, and this morning is lovely though pretty warm. about an April or May day at home. 

3rd page 7
There are enjoyable moments - eating a delicious Cocoanut of the new crop. Which Charley my comrade gave me, and thinking of you too. I hope to get to go up town this P.m, There is a street-car line here - <unclear/> by roles There is also a R. R. on this Island, I know not how long it is. I see many of the Cocoa-trees laden with nuts get green but about full size apparantly. the nuts hang in great clusters, clinging to the main trunk of the tree, the Cocoa tree is, I now think, the prettiest tree that I have ever seen. 

2ond sheet three 8
The Cocoa tree grows tall and slender having few limbs if any, but the leaf is from a foot or so, to 6,8,10,12, even 14 ft or more feet in length. about a foot broad or so Their are about 30 sail-ships here in the dock, only fur or five <unclear/> ships. At present The Trans-port-Sen-a-tor. 
started from Frisco when we did but we come here two hours ahead She last one soldier on the way he fell over-board when drugs or sea sick but no one saw him disappear. it was soon after they left The Golden Gate. wish to call notice to the above name and place in another letter. 