<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
231 Fink Collection 30
BRANSON.
SEP25
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo.
(St. Louis Co.)
31
Sta-Sold Baking &amp; Cutlery
Std.
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
<strike>THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS</strike>
This Evening, 1940
Dear Ollie:
<p>I spoke to our Mr. Katt about your shipment of doughnut holes. It seems that Mr. Katt misunderstood the order, owing to our conversation regarding your self-propelled patriot. He was under the impression that the orifices were to be used in the connection, and therefor sent you a trial order of 1 gross of our new adjustable anuses devised for piles sufferes. He deeply regrets the error and hopes that you did not use any with your doughnuts. However, if properly fumigated, they are quite harmless, he assures me. You need not return the order, but may keep them for Xmas presents with the - compliments of Pastry &amp; Cutlery Inc. Furnished with small twigs of mistletoe, they make lovely &amp; suggestive gifts. Every gentlemen is sure to have numerous acquantances to</p>
(over)
32
-2-
<p>whom he would enjoy sending such a remembrance.</p>
<p>The factory is working at full blast, employing less than 100 men in afternoon shifts. And you should see the jewelled carving knife that is developing! Iron-wood handle, set with rubies in brass mountings! Iron-wood sheath, brass bound! And the <underline>swank</underline> of the whole thing. She's a lulu! It is the Family Ceremonial Knife, to belong <underline>to the Tribe</underline> &amp; be used whenever &amp; wherever the family or any section <strike/> thereof wishes to use it for special occasions - birthdays, holidays, weddings, anniversaries, Xmases, Thanksgivingses etc! O Boy, is she a darb! Today I mounted the rubies in their brass settings whcih will next be inserted into the handle. They look as tho' they grew in the brass!</p>
<p><underline>And</underline> I'm making thrilling progress with <underline>Jed</underline>! It proves richer than I'd foreseen. I'm happy with it. The hand work always flourishes as the other flourishes - or vice versa. They go together, and always did. If you see the knife <underline>now</underline>, you know how the other really is.</p>
33
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
<stirke>THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS</stirke>
