<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
89a
Hotel Clubs
5406 Delmar
St. Louis, Mo.
Oct. 10, 1939.

Dear Mama,
<p>Thanks loads for your swell letter. Glad you enjoyed my letter. I expect it seemed rather over-enthusiastic, but I was rather thrilled about what Mrs. Boyles said</p>
<p>We got a couple of cards from Sig yesterday. I'm so glad they're getting along so well.</p>
<p>Glad Joan had such a lovely birthday. I bet she's having a swell time having tea parties with her neighbors! I got the leaf from John Baker who is attending the University of Michigan at Anne Arbor. I just thought Joanie might like to see it. She'll soon see many more like it I bet!</p>
<p>It'll be swell for <unclear>Eng</unclear> &amp; Ollie to go to Branson for their vacation, won't it? Hil &amp; I would love to come down sometime too, Mom. Wish we could come home Christmas. Wouldn't that be keen?</p>
(2)
<p>The place must be looking <gap reason="cut off"/>, all painted, etc. Please don't work too hard though Mama, will you?</p>
<p>Mama, somehow or other I have misplaced or lost your letter, and with it the check. I simply cannot find it anywhere, and both Hil and I have been looking for it. Could you please send us another check? Then, if we find the original one, we'll destroy it. I can't imagine what happened to it - maybe. False Alarm! I just found the check, so don't worry about the matter. It was in the letter which was underneather the Swiss calender on the desk.</p>
<p>Yes, I can wait for the costume, Mama. Don't make it until you are free from all the housework you're doing, etc. I love your description of the changes being made! The place will be lovely I'm sure. I don't think Hil would care it you sold the phonograph &amp; I wouldn't either.</p>
89b
(3)
<p>That's wonderful about your making a statue for Branson. I do so hope you do "get the job." It would be lovely - something really worth your while and worth while.</p>
<p>Give all my love to Maxie, Joanie, and Elaine.</p>
Loads of Love to you,
dearest Mama,
Alice