<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
25 Neihardt Collection July 4, 1934 123
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON JUL 5 3-PM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Dr. J. G. Neihardt 
5544 Pershing Ave. 
Ilene Apts. 
St. Louis Mo. 

July 4th 
[1936] 124
Dearest One:
I am wondering if you all are together today Sigs' family and you - and I win so much hoping that Sig will not have to be on the High ways when a lot of drunken drivers are <unclear/> them; the fes-tive spirit of the 4th causes so many accidents! -
Hilda and Alice surely did give me a treat! They had a stake dinner, and had Virginia fix me up in your chiar at the dining room table and they had some <unclear/> Miss Bennet had given us and drank a toast to me! 

2
125
Hilda got up before six this morning in order to bake a cake before it got oo not and is not a cake to remember! It stirely beats any thing I ever made. We are ex pecting to has ice cream with a piece of the cake for supper. It is now afternoon. Hilda is looking over a may <unclear/> by the Ra-dio waiting for something bet-ter than baseball reports-and I am sitting in GRand-ma's chair. Darling, my stu dio and beyond it the garden look so pitiful - Don't men tion this, but I just wanted to tell you about it; in- 

3
126
stead of being a thing of beauty it is worse than nothing - sad, burned up weedy garden, nobody seeming to know what is a flower or a weed - and the studio is a clutter of ugly things put there to be out of the way - instead of the lovely vista I was so proud of there is Chaos. It just goes to show what I did when well, and <unclear/> inside of a few weeks ever thing is gone - was it worth while for me to have it <unclear/> at all? It shows me that it was all very foolish 

4
127
because if no one in my fa-mily cares - why should I? You evidently have felt all this for some time - and I am so sorry I could not see how foolish I was long ago- but maybe that is what my sick ness was for or better one of the things it was for.-Now I think we should put the place up for sale. Then I should box all your library, I can get boxes in town - and we can have a man Lake all the bookcases down so that they can be shipped. Then we should let Swimmeys 

128 5
know that we are planning to sell and therefore will not used any care takers. Then we can rent this place I feel sure and if our be longings such as guns, look and a few hours should things are packed away we do not have to care so much about renters coming in - Now I'm all muddled and I'm just talking to you. It will be long till I can do anything but think about things and that not clearly. 
Please tell me what you really want because it is 

129 6
so hard for me alone. 
I think we should plan to move your library up to some place near Saint Louis that is a good buy some small place. But in the mean while till we do sell what should we do? 
I hope I'm not bother ing you but it all goes round and round in my head and comes out no where. 
Loads of Love to the best More and the dearest one from Mona. 
