<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
909 Fink Collection 86
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Thursday A.M.
Oct 24, 1940
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>yes, we're "g-d- plutocrats" all right, Dad &amp; I am what you'd term an old "richbitch"! I feel so very, very fortunate &amp; am as I mentioned to Ol, I wonder at times how such perfect existence can last! He says he feels the same &amp; worries quite a bit about the same thing. We feel so fortunate and <sic>altho'</sic> we don't have much money, we feel richer by far than those we know who have more. We do, I think, do a lot with our money and, by not wanting much when we get anything we feel so very filthy rich! And, Dad &amp; Mom, we speak from experience___that's the key to happiness, not wanting much! Isn't this right? Why, we could be happy together with nothing! And this is <underline>truth</underline>!</p>
<p>Another, and most deeply important way in which we feel so rich is in having our dear ones <underline>all</underline> friends &amp; not just relations. That is something unusual too. Never any fighting, always happiness there too! Why, I wonder if <underline>we could</underline> fight about anything now! We haven't for so long!</p>
<p>Max called me last week and asked if we'd come in to dinner there on my birthday. I would have loved it, but Ol had asked me before that to go out to dinner with hime. So, of course, Max understood. But, then, she asked</p>
87
2
<p>us to drop by afterwards; so we did. Well, first of all, I met Ol at 6:30 at the Golden Fried Chicken place on Delmar &amp; we had a glass of beer, a pot of coffee a 2 1/2 lb. fried chicken between us &amp; some Italian breed, a stuffed celery stick &amp; potatoe salad. That was so much fun, not just the thing, but the spirit back of it - that he wanted to take me out to dinner! We don't do that often, as we always eat at home. But this was such a treat. Then, after dinner we dropped out at the kids', little dreaming that Max would have a big cake, 10 candles, and a wonderful fruit jello ready. It all looked so very lovely, &amp; they were all so dear! I blew out the 10 candles <underline>all at once</underline> before there was a chance to make any wishes, &amp; Alice said, with such a blowout as that, any wish you'd want should come true! Then Sig said the cutest thing, he hoped that the "29" would someday be "92"! It was a cocnut iced white cake with pink candles. Then Alice, Hilda &amp; Max had made up the following verse &amp; had it on a card at my place over three lovely pkgs.! As follows:-
"The Birthday Fairy so light &amp; airy
Flew down from skies of blue
To bring good health &amp; luck &amp; wealth
And all our love to you.</p>
(Next page)
88
3
<p>"From Branson she gathered green &amp; gold
From St. Louis a warm red hue;
And of course she had to bring a cake
And fruited jello too!
For Enid, just 10."</p>
<p>Wasn't that cute? Then they told me to figure out the meaning of the substance the verse by opening the pkgs. I did!! And, Dad &amp; Mom, first of all I want to tell you how very dear it was of you to present me with those dishes! It makes my set <underline>so</underline> useful &amp; makes me feel <underline>so</underline> rich! I found two cups &amp; saucers, two salad plates adn a vegetable bowl!! So much! I believe I told you not to get so many - I said just <underline>one</underline> of what I listed as needing!! Well, I surely appreciate it, I tell you!! Thanks loads &amp; loads! And, I also thank you for the adorable telegram. It came during the day while I was alone &amp; I <underline>did</underline> get a lovely happy feeling when I rec'd it! You're wondering by now what the "warm red hue" was. Well, it was a lovely burgundy wool jersey turban to roll on the head, to wear with my burgundy suit. And, I surely got a kick out of that too. That was from Hilda &amp; Alice. Max &amp; Sig &amp; the sweet little nieces provided the party! Max said Joan</p>
89
4
<p>&amp; Elaine helped in it by going to bed for a nap!! I know what she means! That <underline>is</underline> a help, for they do love to get into things while one's working. Oh, the kiddies were so sweet to me! They led me into the dining room &amp;, one on either side, put me in the seat of honor at the head of the table! Then, afterwards, Joanie insisted on decorating me with pink crepe paper!</p>
<p>And my hubby, not content with buying the mattress &amp; starting on the house, got me two pairs of silk hose, a box of chocolates &amp; a pair of lovely pajamas, as well as taking me out to dinner! Of course I mentioned to him that was <underline>too much</underline>, but he said, "Let's enjoy it, - your birthday only comes once a year"! Sweet? Then, of course, I consoled myself to the fatalistic viewpoint &amp; did thoroughly enjoy myself! Mother Fink remembered too &amp; sent me an adorable card! There was only one thing wrong with the whole thing - you two <underline>should have been here</underline> and gove to dinner <underline>with us</underline>! But - things can't be too perfect can they? We all tho't of you both with endearment, &amp; Ol &amp; I made a toast to you at dinner!</p>
<p>And, on the morning of my birthday three gorgeous big "Sunburst" (yellow with orange tinge) roses &amp; one Los Angeles (pink, with orange <unclear>cast</unclear>) roses bloomed for me! Sweet?</p>
90
5
<p>Of course, I figured fate was telling me that we'd have two boys! Ol represented by one yellow rose, me by the pink, &amp; the two boys by the two yellows! But, at that, I <underline>do</underline> hope it's boy &amp; girl!! Mom, you made me feel so much better about the whole thing, when you said what you did about my forgetting about it &amp; I'd become in the family way &amp; okay. I think you're right - I fear I've been too anxious as Dad often says. I'm glad you said it, for I feel easier now! And, Dad, that's so dear of you to be working for the speedy arrival of "it" in the pasture! I'm sure it'll help no end! Well, I've been too hasty!- We've already picked out the names for both - John N. (and or) Mona L. So, we must have girl &amp; boy! Ha! And, too, I've made so many thing! But it's a profitable &amp; lovely thing to do! I enjoy it.</p>
<p>I believe I've told all!!</p>
<p>Hallowe'en, nest Thurs. <sic>nite</sic>, we're all getting together out here for a wiener roast. Wish you coud be here! Up here you have to have candies or fruits around, for the kids expect to get it when they come to the door in their funny costumes!! They don't do that in Branson, do they? I don't remember it. Joan &amp; 'Laine are going to have a coupld of lighted pumpkins. Ol</p>
91
6
<p>and I are going to fix them up into scarey faces for them &amp; have them ready when they come out! We'll be thinking of you then too! Wish you could be here!</p>
<p>Oh, Mom, thanks so much for the beautiful pictures of the home! I'll have fun showing them to the neighbors!! I had no idea the place had bloomed out so gorgeously since we were there last! Ol hadn't either. gee, it is a heavenly place. We hope this place will be just half as lovely someday. We're doing lots of things around now. Are continuing the hedge in front across the drive to the end of curb line under the oak tree. Then, when you want to, sometime, we'd love to have more hedge to put along the side (east) of the place, near the vacant lot. We want high hedge all around us. Then, we're going to put in a white birch in the back yard. Think we need one tree back there. We continued the iris (in a <underline>straight</underline> line) along the ditch clear up to the street, near the driveway you know. Looks lovely. Have put in iris on either side of front walk. Put dwarf iris as a border around our front hed. Ol made a large oval hed in middle of front yard &amp; we're putting</p>
92
7
<p>peony in center, roses all around &amp; tulips to border. Irvin gave us lots of tulips! He's been lovely to us, Mom! We planted three hopes of flowers he gave us. The mums you gave us are blooming once more &amp; have lots of buds. We also have a few others that Ol's sister-in-law gave us. We're having <underline>more</underline> fun! As Dad said, it's great to feel you own the plot of ground you inhabit!</p>
<p>I hope this long missive doesn't choke you! I did want you to hear about the grand brithday I had!</p>
<p>More later.</p>
<p>Perhaps we'll see you Thanksgiving?! Hope, hope!!</p>
<p>Mr. Greer's daughter (eldest) got married last Sat. We sent her a small gift - a bun warmer. We rec'd an announcement.</p>
<p>Give George the Katt our best caressing strokes &amp; tell him there's a gorgeous big tiger cat here running the neighborhood &amp; they really should correspond a bit. Poor Mrs. H. <unclear>Llames</unclear> this poor male for all the kittens she gets! Maybe we'll keep one of Mrs. H's next batch if there's a decent male among them! Ol has to help Jack kill the rest of the batch coming up! Isn't it a</p>
93
8
<p>shame kittens can't all be wanted? They're so adorable! The mama cats should all be like our Mitzie was &amp; have nothing but hay-cats! She was odd that way!</p>
<p>So long for now.</p>
<p>Loads o' love, always, 
&amp; thanks again for the lovely
birthday!</p>
-Enid
Enot
<underline>J</underline>