<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
163 Fink Collection 158
[December 1939]

Mr. &amp; Mrs. Olive Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
159
Amarillo,
Texas.
Dearest Children:
<p>I trust the Xmas wire reached you; Daddy had it telephoned out to you from St Louis.</p>
<p>We have been having a very happy time, but a beautiful snow-storm stopped us, and we had to spend a coupld of nights here, waiting for the roads to be cleared.</p>
<p>Daddy went to a Medium, who proved to be very remarkable. She read his character perfectly and then told him abou his whole family. She said he had in his wife a good friend who would back him in every way. He had 3 daughters of who the eldest was married. Her husband was</p>
160
<p>a fine man and about to receive <underline>two</underline> raises within the next year. (So, what did Mother tell you Ollie?!) She said you had just made a change of houses. She also saw a slight accident to one of Dad's girls which was not serious, but could have been a hospital case.</p>
<p>Then she saw two younger daughters. She said both were "majoring" in something they would both be very successful in. the one who had had her tonsils taken out was to be very successful over the Radio, she assumed it was singing, and the other one would also be most successful in her specialty being as bright as a whip and a winner. She said the only son was workign with him, and would make money and be all <unclear/> a great success. She saw Daddy be-</p>
161
<p>ing kept from a trip to Europe by the War, but she saw him going 5 years from now. She saw him moving West before August, and knew that he had absolutely nothing to do with this town or State, but assumed he was passing through. She saw him travelling a great deal, and making lots of money <unclear>beginning</unclear> with May.</p>
<p>I have tried to share this good outlook with you dear Ones, and hope you are feeling happy and successful as indeed you should.</p>
<p>Alice darling, please write to me - and tell me about your vacation and work. Don't forget to see that <unclear>Mme Cazan</unclear> recieves the <unclear>Ozark baby</unclear>.</p>
Endless love to you all 3,
from Mom - Mother.