<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
50a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
March 8, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I received your card this morning, Mama, and was very glad to hear from you, never so little. Now I'm eager to hear what you say about my last cards. For the present, I shall be forced to accept a job of some kind here - I shall write you of it if I succeed. We all hope to hear something soon regarding the act either concerning another job, or our long - overdue papers. Recently, I've heard that some people who waited here for their papers were held in this hotel several months, <hi rend="underline">but</hi> at the end of that time they were finally rewarded. That gives us some hope. Now that you have again written Truman,</p>
(2)
<p>Daddy, perhaps will <unclear/> a definite statement from Washington soon. Surely that is not too much to expect - it is cruel to keep us in total ignorance. Somehow I believe we'll be helped to see the Light soon. Doris and I went to chapel at Mercy Hospital (just across the street) last evening, and how we prayed! We just happened to arrive at Chapel time, so we heard the prayers of the head sister and the answering chants of the other nuns while we were concentrating on our own problems - and , as always those of our dear ones. How truly dedicated they are to Good - and how unbelievably much they have sacrificed - yet, do not we who live in the midst of the <unclear/> they condemn perhaps suffer more? Not that I know much of Life yet - I realize my inexperience, now as never</p>
50b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>before - but I believe we are all learning, and also, that we will be allowed to see clearly soon. The only thing to do, it seems to me, is keep on our own feet in <hi rend="underline">any</hi> way possible till we see what happens for our act. I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> not feel it is right to help break it up now <hi rend="underline">just</hi> when we've begun to get along in the higher fields of entertainment. Jobs are not easy to find in dancing now - except plain ordinary, <unclear/> chorus jobs with <hi rend="underline">no</hi> chance for development. See? God! I realize all the burdens I should be assuming, and can't and I've suffered over it, but what good does it going wild do? None, as I've found <hi rend="underline">except</hi> bring about a true realization of the problems</p>
(4)
<p>we face. i have no money now to go anywhere, and "going" seems silly anyway unless it's to bide time with a job till <hi rend="underline">our</hi> act's ship comes in. George will assume (or per contract) charge of transportation back to starting point, but going <hi rend="underline">back</hi> would be useless if we're keeping act intact. In fact, as I've already explained, Mexico City is much closer than St. Louis or Chicago (Fare is <hi rend="underline">half</hi> that to St. Louis) and, in the event of our papers were coming soon, we girls <hi rend="underline">could</hi> go on to Mexico City to get a job for they seem to be gettable there according, to Max. As I told you, we've received several communications which contained a warm invitation to stay at his and his brothers' ranch. Yes - it <hi rend="underline">may</hi> sound like</p>
50c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>a rash step to take, but <hi rend="underline">really</hi> it would entail 1/2 the expense in travelling <hi rend="underline">and</hi> living that would going to Chicago. Then, <hi rend="underline">if</hi> M.C.A. or our Chicago agency offered us a job, we could come back here from Mexico City. If we could receive definite news that we may safely <hi rend="underline">expect</hi> to receive the papers <hi rend="underline">sometime</hi>, this would be a wise step to take I sincerely believe. Staying here I can make <hi rend="underline">no</hi> more than my expenses $<hi rend="underline">18</hi> is <hi rend="underline">big</hi> money here, Mama - almost unheard of!! You see, most of the "help" here are Mexicans and live across the border where the rate of money exchange is 5 to 1.) So you can see why salaries are so low. How</p>
(6)
<p>ever, I need money now. I <hi rend="underline">must</hi> work at something. It seems stupid to have to think of other things when one <hi rend="underline">should</hi> be dancing, but such are our problems that we must. Don’t' worry it won't kill us. We shall try to keep up our practice as we've been doing so far - and hold on. If you hear from the Senator we'll certainly appreciate your telling us by <hi rend="underline">airmail</hi> oh!! Something must happen soon.</p>
<p>We've been living along as usual, with several pleasant interruptions - and others of "less - pleasant through educational description." One night last week we went to Neuvo Laredo (the three of us) with a Mr. Manuel Carillo, a nice Mexican-American (Tex-Mex) to whom we were introduced through a sister</p>
30d
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>at Mercy Hospital - a former resident of St. Louis and friend of Doris' Mother. He took us riding in a little Mexican "coche" - a horse and buggy affair with little gas lights on the fenders and a low flat roof on top - s<hi rend="underline">ans</hi> sides of course. The stars were brilliant as they always are here when there is no moon, and a deep velvet backdrop of a sky set them off admirably. We sat face to face and chatted, sang, laughed gaily as we bumped along the unlighted, rough cobblestone streets of this Mexican sister city of Laredo Texas. After making a tour of the town, Carillo gave detailed directions to the driver in his staccato, yet musical, and somehow indefinably - strange native tongue, and our little "Cavallo"</p>
(8)
<p>set out at a brisk trot on <unclear/> highway which leads eventually to Mexico City. We passed several night clubs, situated on the barren prairie, but did not stop at any of them. We rode on, as far as Las Vegas Club, then turned around and returned to a slight different route - by way of the "Plaza del torros". We stopped at a night club in town for some santerne, then re-crossed  the International Bridge, with scarcely any questioning, for our host is well known here. Night before last Carcillo and a friend of his took us to dinner in Nuevo Laredo, followed by an evening of real gayety. I had "cabrito" (baby <hi rend="underline">goat</hi>) and chuacamole salads, torillas toastades (<hi rend="underline">very</hi> good and crisp like potatoes chips) Some little</p>
50e
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
March 6, 1943.
<hi rend="strike_through">Dear Madame Cassan,</hi>
<p>street urchins crowded about us flourishing camelias, and our hosts bought us each a lovely one. Thence we proceeded by car to "Villa Espanola," where we were led to a ringside table. After a delicious glass of clering wine (sweet), we danced a bit. I was quite thrilled when the orchestra leader came over and serenaded me at our table, with a trombone solo! We left there in about an hour, proceeding to "Las Vegas Club" which we'd passed the previous week in our "coche" ride (<hi rend="underline">caw</hi>-chay). We hurried inside for we were a bit cold (Tengo frijo). "I am cold" Speaking of atmosphere, this place <hi rend="underline">really</hi> had it. The interior was furnished with</p>
(10)
<p>many small tables, and <unclear/> around the dance floor <unclear/> covered with pictures of bullfights, Mexican Acts, and strange Mexican paintings. We drank the same cherry wine (were not at all affected) all evening laughed, and danced much. Some of the gentlemen we danced with friends of our hosts could speak no English - and I little Spanish. One of them had lovely, <hi rend="underline">gentille</hi> eyes, and he sang Schubert's Serenade to me while we danced to it - how beautiful, and <hi rend="underline">good</hi> is such an experience. Yes, Mexicans are interesting and so is their music, but as a rule there is something strange and not altogether <hi rend="underline">good</hi> about them. That makes me appreciate more than ever even the hint of a soul - a heart that feels <hi rend="underline">Goodness</hi> as I wish always to feel it our hosts were most entertaining and we had a grand time. There was a floor show consisting of a comedian a rumba singer</p>
50f
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>and dancer, a tango singer (<hi rend="underline">How</hi> she suffered - but sang well), and a couple of Mexican folk dancers. The orchestra consisted of eight or ten pieces, was entirely Mexican in personnel, and had a leader who play the piano remarkably. They played one of his our compositions "A Mexican Pasodie", as well as endless rhumbas, tangos, <hi rend="underline">and</hi> American tunes. Then, besides, there were several groups of troubadours who sang and played guitars and other Mexican instruments, very artistically. One singer was especially heart stirring, and truly artistic. Never have I heard more feeling.</p>
<p>Hil wrote me she was to leave Saturday evening</p>
(12)
<p>Has she gone? I am <hi rend="underline">so</hi> thrilled she can go at last.</p>
<p>I <hi rend="underline">just</hi> received your letters. <hi rend="underline">Thanks</hi> so for your help <hi rend="underline">and</hi> advice, and for writing Truman again, Daddy. We <hi rend="underline">should</hi> get an answer now; <hi rend="underline">I certainly hope so.</hi> Yes, Mama, you're right about God helping he who helps himself, but <hi rend="underline">what</hi>, could we have done? I've been wild to know, but something indecision is worse than anything - desire <hi rend="underline">not</hi> to act too rashly. I don't want to tear down all we sweated and suffered to build. See?</p>
<p>I'm <hi rend="underline">so</hi> thrilled you are better Daddy, that you Mama are happy in your new work and that all is generally well with you.</p>
<p>No, Geo. has no money now, but he is trying hard</p>
50g
(13)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>to raise it now, and should hear any day. I hope we hear something for act first. I have no money now, but I am trying for something as I told you already. I pounded streets all day looking - and have chances several places. Will see about something tonight which require no Spanish - care of child in home. It seems so silly really, but I need money at any cost - that is I must live. I'm telling you because I know you want to know. Please don't think I want you to worry for me. All will be O.K. soon - I'll write you.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">So</hi> glad about your sale of gun, Daddy. Very good deal there!</p>
(14)
<p>What you tell me of your chances is simply grand, Daddy. Hurrah! is all I can say.</p>
<p>I must quit now and attend to things.</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alice
<p>Give my love to Eny and Ollie and Nei in abundance. Tell Albert I send my love and congratulate him <hi rend="underline">joyously</hi> on his promotion. May there be many more such for him!</p>


