<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
58
May 27th 41.
Darling Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your dear birthday letter was so very welcome and added a great deal to my happiness. Letters from Hilda and Alice arrived with yours and Max had an extra dinner for Nannie too. Besides I did not have to wash the dishes but could feel like a lady! Joanie asked that I dress up in my pretty green and pink dress - which she remembered from <underline>last Summer</underline>! So I got it out of my dresser drawer and ironed it for the occasion. I like it even better than I did last year, which is saying a lot, Enid dear!</p>
<p>No girlie please do not buy me a birthday gift so we all must save money now.</p>
<p>Daddy had pictures taken of the bust today and it should be successful as they certainly took pains with it. I'll send you one as soon as possible.</p>
<p>I am looking forward to the time when I can make a little "Madonna" of you and your baby for your mantlepiece. So when you come Home here next Summer you can Know what to expect!</p>
<p>Marie si right now in the Springfield Hospital for her new baby, Maxie just heard.</p>
<p>We had a little much needed rain last night - our poppies are about 3 inches to 4 inches high, Hollyhocks are as tall as I am, and cannas over one foot. Roses are marvelous -</p>
59
<p>the Mulberries are so big and juicy that the birds have not bothered with our cherries which we have enjoyed to the fullest this year. They are all gone now.</p>
<p>Daddy works around th eplace pulling weeds, trimming trees and thigns it is a joy to me.</p>
<p>But I'm hungry for my children once more and the place is dead without them. It is fine to have Max and the Wubs but I want more of you!</p>
<p>The nursery is a great event - and worthy of all your labor and artistic endeavors. So wonderful too about your wagon - I am so glad you are lucky - and trust your baby is making you so! Bless it and you my darling!</p>
<p>Do you read your Stranger at the Gate? You should!</p>
Love in endlessness
from your devoted
Mama.
Mother.
60
<p>I wanted you and Ollie to read this!</p>
(Not printed at Government expense)
Congressional Record
United Staes 
of America
PROCEEDINGS AND DEBATES OF THE 77th CONGRESS, FIRST SESSION
The American People Have Not Been Told the Truth
SPEECH 
OF 
HON. DEWEY SHORT
OF MISSOURI
IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
May 6, 1941
<p>Mr. SHORT. Mr. Chairman, we are not yet in this war. We are never in war until the shooting starts. The greatest menace to our peace at this tragic hour is that many of the lovers of peace have been persuaded through insidious propaganda that we are in war; that we have been led down the road so far that is is impossible to turn back. I never turn back or walk back, and I will never go back until I am thrown back; this blantant babbling that we are alreday in war is exactly what the warmongers, the international financiers, and the interventionists want us to believe, feel, and talk. They have cultivated it. THis is their weapon. "As a man thinketh, so is he"; and if we think we are in war, then we are in it. The greatest service we could perform at this moment is to turn our thought and attention from war to the defense of our own Nation and the promotion of peace. [Applause.] If any nation wants to fight us, let is come over here; we are not going over there. [Applause.] If we are dragged into this war, it will be against the overwhelming desire of a vast majority of the American people to stay out, and it will be our own fault. No nation on earth has yet insulted us; no American ship has been sunk; no American life has been lost; not one shot has been fired at us or by us. We are going to war only when we choose to go, because the belligerents have exercised meticulous care and the greatest caution not to drag us in. This is not out of their high idealism or love for us, but it is to their own selfish interests because they fear America, and because their masses of the people back home know what happened when we entered the war in 1917.</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, while we are not yet in the war I will confess that, step by step, word by word, day by day, act by act, we have been led dangerously closer to the brink of actual involvement. We have called other people dirty names, denounced their philosophy, threatened to force our four freedoms upon them in the name of freedom, hurled epithets at them, pictured their black character, even gone as far as to say that we will give all aid that is necessary to insure their defeat - yet they have been careful not to commit any overt act which would justify our declaring war upon them. This administration yearns for them to declare war upon us. If we enter this war, it will be of our own choosing and nobody else. Remember wars are not won by words. Many high officials have repeatedly said that we will be in this war whenever Hitler chooses to have us in it. I deliberately declare in answer to this silly charge that these men are either stupid or dishonest. They cannot point to one step taken by the belligerents in the present conflict which threatens our sovereignty, security, or independence.</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, what steps have been taken, and by whome have these steps been taken, that will lead us to actual involvement? The arms embargo has been lifted; destroyers and war materials have been illegally transferred by a supposedly neutral country to one of the belligerents; peacetime conscription has been enacted into law by a country that never had it before; lease-lend give-away bill has been passed by a Congress; $7,000,000,000 have been voted to one of the contestants and now it is proposed by a country hypocritically called neutral by itself to seize the ships of one belligerent and to transfer those ships to its enemy in the conduct of the war. By whome were all these steps taken? By the United States of America. In the name of neutrality! Oh, such hypocrisy! Such sophistry and subterfuge! Suppose the United States of America were at war with Great Britian as it has been in the past and that Germany, a so-called neutral country, would turn over many of our ships in its ports to Great Britian to use against us. How would the American Government interpret such an act? How would the American people consider such a dastardly deed? Does it not violate every rule of international law and principle of decency? Where is the Golden Rule? It does not appear in this bill! Would we treat others in a manner different from that with which they shoudl treat us? Why bother so very much with the toothpick in our brother's eye when there is a saw log in our own?</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, this bill regardless of what intentions may be behind it, irrespective of what motives might have dictated it, is just another slap in the face and kick in the pants to the Axis Powers. I am not pleading their cause, but I do want to see my own Government honest. On page 5, line 3, of this bill subsection 3 reads: Nothing in this act shall be construed to modify or affect any provision of the Neutrality Act of 1939, as amended.</p>
<p>This language is nothing short of fraud and deception. Let us stop playing the role of the hypocrite; let us stop walking on egg shells. If any country is our enemy and threatens our security then the honorable and manly thing to do is to declare war and fight it out. Be honest and logical like my admirable firend the gentleman from Georgia [Mr. Cox]. Let us stop hiding behind high-sounding phrases of Christianity, democracy, and liberty. Let us declare war and fight as men should. What could we gain if we entered this conflict? What did we get out of the lst war except thousands of killed and wounded; billions of dollars added to our debt; years of depression and unemployment; hatred sown throughout the world and the present debacle. As Will Rogers, that great American and lover of humanity, once said, "The United States never lost a war and never won a treaty." In the last scrap we asked for nothing and got exactly what we asked for. If we enter this one all we shall get will be thousands of the young flowerhood of American killed, perhaps hundreds of thousands sacrificed, and their parents and loved ones will later learn that they receive citations or perhaps a few post-humanous medals. What comfort will that be to them? And what gain will it be to this Nation?</p>
<p>We are told that Hitler is our enemy. Grant it! We are told that Great Britian is our friend. Well, yes. Who would not be undre the circumstances? Is it wrong to ask when are we loved and when are we hated? Shall we play the fool or shall we just be smart?</p>
<p>Mr. Chairman, if we are realistic, if we face unpleasant facts, if we follow reason instead of emotion we shall do what we are able to do. The United States of America is no more prepared at thsi hour to enter this conflict against the Axis Powers than I am to enter the ring against Joe Louis and I imagine we would last about as long as I would against the Brown Bomber. Certainly if we continue to give away all we produce or manufacture; spend our strength in fighting a foreign war instead of staying home, gearing up produciton to its maximum quantity and making ourselves invincible to attack from any nation or combination of nations from abroad,</p>