<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 53
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
ASSISTED BY
SIGURD NEIHARDT, PIANIST
BRANSON, MISSOURI
<p>Just read your letter. Everything fine. Love always Jno Dad</p>
March 20, 1939
Monday Morning
Precious Girls:
<p>I got back at 2:20 yesterday, and found Max, Mrs. Brown, Miss Goldylocks, and Mr. George Katt in fine shape. Had a heck of a sound sleep last night, and can use another tonight. But I'm well. I wrote you a short note after the Younkers Tea Room affair, &amp; gave it to a red-cap to mail. Did you get it? The whole week was successful, &amp; the last affair glowed with a land of witch fire! Balduf, the forum creator and manager, was powerful happy. He's a great fellow - full of the wine of life - a German , finely educated, gemiithlich, and yet I could imagine him clicking his heels &amp; giving Prussian orders! It's a great breed!</p>
<p>I didn't make much of the week's work - only $75 clear. But we'll get a fine testmionial. The pay fo rthere forum lectures comes our of regular school funds, set aside for adult education. Baldulf is about to get a special approoriation - so he hopes.</p>
(over)
54
-2-
<p>Very earnest people attend the forums in groups of about 75. My last forum group was considerably largely than usual, I was told.</p>
<p>I found 21 nice lettle gems - some sweet things, not expensive, but worth while. You, Mona (naughty-girl to rum away from we shame on you!!) will have a set of coral cameo earrings and a matched coral cameo ivory ring. All in ivory. (Then you'll be sorry you ran away!) Found three pink sapphries which might work into the rose-quartz ring - how do I know? And there's a lovely little Wedgewood medallion for and ivory-mounted pendant. (Exquisite) When I get fairly rich, my lovely gals (and what a gang of them!) will go around looking like Christmas trees!!</p>
<p>Mrs. Brown reports, in a matter - of - fact Mrs. Mulivy, as well, but she has so many little girls and boys! I infer they're quite a care to the poor woman! Funny! Nobody ever heard of Mrs. Mulivy before. And the other day, Max says, Joan saw "blue" little people on the couch. Max said: "Fairies?" and she said: "Yes, blue fairies!"</p>
<note>next few sentences were written in the margins of letter</note>
<p>Alice, I saw a ruby ring, like yours almost, for $175. Yours was nicer. </p>
<p>I'll be getting to work on Jed very soon - probably in the morning. I heard a lyric in bed last night. Very beautiful. Endless love</p>