<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
87b
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
May 28, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We arrived in Laredo (Nueva Laredo, Mexico) on your birthday, Mama dear, and stayed overnight there. The next morning we arose early, passed customs inspection and installed ourselves; here in the Bender hotel as per several months ago. it hardly seems possible that so much has happened and so much time has passed since we were last here in pretty little Laredo, awaiting the opening of the Golden Gates of Mexico. We've learned a good deal, had experiences and joys beyond one's wildest imaginings, and now are happy to be on our way to me to our dear ones once more. I have so very much to tell you, that I cannot begin now, in a mere letter,</p>
(2)
<p>to express myself as <unclear/> to. It will take a week of solid talking to tell you all I have to say. Can I really honestly <hi rend="underline">talk</hi> with you <hi rend="underline">this</hi> time? Probably for the first time in a long time this will be really possible. I am happy, <hi rend="underline">so</hi> happy about Esquire Daddy - and I do hope (as I am sure) that you enjoy your work. Chicago <hi rend="underline">is</hi> a nice city, isn't it? Mama, how is the apartment? And Amama, I want you to know how happy I am that you are with my dearest Daddy and Mama once more - for that is both right and good for all concerned. It will not be long till I shall <hi rend="underline">see</hi> all of you and say what my pen cannot allow me to say - nor my tongue, for that matter.</p>
87c
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>I haven't written for some time because of various changes in plans which kept me from giving you a clear picture of our plans Comprenez? now that we have taken a definite course, we are so near home that I shall wait to tell you our whole complete story. Mexico, outside of business dealings, is almost a paradise - but where business dealings are concerned (and here <hi rend="underline">all</hi> outsiders are absolutely agreed), Mexico is almost impossible for outsiders. We were warned over and over of this beforehand, but one cannot <hi rend="underline">know</hi> without personal experience. If we went again on business, we would be wise in ways we were not</p>
(4)
<p>this time, but learned only through sheer experince. Naturally, I could tell <hi rend="underline">nadda</hi> of our business dealings while in Mexico, for letters pass censors, but now I can mention what we have been up against. First of all, our agent proved to be not only unintelligent and un-dynamic (as any agent, first of all, <hi rend="underline">must</hi> be) but also a bit crooked. he took money under false pretenses, for taxes which do not exist, and he worked against rather than with us - whether through utter stupidity, crookedness or a combination of both, we are not yet sure. Then, the manger of the Folies Bergere Theatre where we worked <unclear/> all American acts. He preceded to do all possible to present not only</p>
87d
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>us, oh, now, but three other outside acts in the worst way possible, for the sole purpose of presenting in a bad light all talent other than Mexican - and thus ruining their chances for a pleasant, successful job. As far as audience reaction goes, we have been <hi rend="underline">very</hi> successful. Have gotten "success music" quite regularly, (This is an old Mexican custom - playing a certain set strain as a "chaser" for any act which receives a certain large amount of applause!), and have <hi rend="underline">never</hi> had any cause from <hi rend="underline">that</hi> standpoint, to feel bad. Where our trouble lay was with the Mexican agents and managers - and there <hi rend="underline">only</hi>. Our agent was to place us in</p>
(6)
<p>the Patio - it was in a pair, so the Waikiki was next in line. This he "loused up" for us because he wanted us to accept a ridiculously low salary, that he might pocket the remainder as per pre-arranged contract with Club. Near the end of our stay we accepted a contract with another cabaret, the Bremen, with a human manager and <unclear/> a <hi rend="underline">capable</hi>, intelligent manager <hi rend="underline">other</hi> than Valencia. This agent, also an actor at Folies Bergere paved the way for us so that our stay there at the Bremen was both successful and pleasant, although the club itself is not as high class as the Patio. Had we been handled <hi rend="underline">at</hi> first by such an agent we would have had no trouble - and all would</p>
87e
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>have been as successful as was our stay at the Branso. Drapping all thought of unpleasantness connected with business, we are grateful to Mexico for many things, at least I am - for business can never be <hi rend="underline">all</hi> of life for me. And I have found Beauty unforgettable, indestructible in Mexico. You must see it with me some day. At that, <hi rend="underline">we</hi> did not see 1/10 of Mexico - <hi rend="underline">no</hi> not 1/10 - and if I did not know that one day I'd return, thsi would greatly sadden me. As it is, I know I shall return - and so I shall return - and so I shall <hi rend="underline">not</hi> be sad to leave Mexico now.</p>
<p>When I get home I shall explain much in detail</p>
(8)
<p>which I shall not mention now. And I have much to talk over with you, for, I must admit I am a bit perplexec at the moment.</p>
<p>We are going to dance here Friday and Saturday or rather Sat. and Sun. and <hi rend="underline">plan</hi> to leave Monday for chicago. That means we'll arrive chez vous Thursday, I believe. I cannot be <hi rend="underline">sure</hi> of this, so just "stand-by" for further instructions, will you? I am <hi rend="underline">so</hi> eager to see you, and to <hi rend="underline">talk</hi> to you - really talk with you. You cannot know how long I have yearned for this. Yes, before I left too, for somehow I could not talk to you while you were with Eny and Ollie. You know what I mean dear ones don't you? And I <hi rend="underline">so</hi></p>
87f
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p><hi rend="underline">long</hi> for a real <hi rend="underline">communication</hi> between us again. We have <hi rend="underline">much</hi> to accomplish in Chicago - a new girl to train, for Doris is leaving us after Laredo. If not a new girl, we must re-arrange numbers for a trio. we have several new numbers to arrange and learn too - before me begin our ascent to New York.</p>
<p>You may write me <hi rend="underline">if</hi> you hurry, so please do dear ones. Give all my love to Hilda, Amama, and to those in St. Louis, our Albert Engy, Ollie, Nei, and I shall write our Sig and Max, Joan and Elaine.</p>
<p>Had lovely trip here, but</p>
(10)
<p>it is almost too warm humid. After the mountain air, and 8,000 ft. elevation we've been used to for the past six weeks, Daddy, <hi rend="underline">you</hi> of all people can understand my discomfort here. I guess I'm just a chip off the old block, Daddy - I'm a savage at heart - and I love that Something out There like I could never have anything else - and God Great Spirit keep us thusly. Cities are good for much - yes, I love the culture they present, the beauty they hold, but I love <hi rend="underline">more</hi> the wildness of the mountains, the llanxos, the Aaroncas of God's country - and these I'm sure you would lobe as I do in old Mexico.</p>
<p>I thought of you so on</p>
87g
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>your birthday, Mama, and decided it would be almost as quick, in all the excitement to send you a telegram upon our arrival in U.S.A. Could not send a real greeting - but you read between the lines, didn't you?</p>
<p>Please write me adn know that I am always, as ever,</p>
Your adoring
Alice
<p>P.S. Some of my letters which are being censored for me now may be sent to me c/o Seymours. If they arrive before me, please keep intact, and unopened</p>
(12)
<p>for me till I return, for they are not interesting to anyone but me - and do not contain letters form em to you! I don't mean this the way it sounds, I'll explain later!</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice