<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
80 Neihardt Collection 132
Neihardt #610
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
GALESBURG, ILL.
NOV
3 -PM
1939
Mrs. Mona Neihardt
9917 Emerson
Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(Taney Co.)
133
[No 1, 1939]
HOTEL CUSTER 
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMERL DIRECTION
Wednesday Morning
Precious Girl:
<p>I was very glad to find your second letter in my box this morning at breakfast. You've received my first letter in which I wrote about your teeth. That <underline>is</underline> important as for the suit, I wish almost that I hadn't encouraged Sig to get it, as I could have gotten along with what I have, but of course I'll need it later.</p>
<p>As for your coming, I certainly want you for selfish reasons; but I'm afraid the experience might be dull for you. I've had only perfunctory social contacts thus far, and have not yet arrived at the point where I can get results with the students. My first lecture on Poetic Values was given to an audience of about 200,</p>
(over)
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
134
-2-
<p><underline>mostly townspeople</underline> with little background. There were students too, but not a large percentage, and some were as young as 15. I'm going to have to give up the idea of a systematic presentation of the whole thesis, and try to present some of it in an off-hand talk. It's too bad, but I did greatly overestimate the audience. Strange that when I gave the thing as I letures, systematically presented, at St. Mary's, the result was perfect. Also, when I gave it as three lectures at even Omaha University, the crowd increased greatly with each lecture. It's a trifle puzzling; but I suppose, in some ways, I <underline>have</underline> run too far ahead of the majority. When I get at them with my poetry, it will, no doubt, be different. I hope so, at least.</p>
<p>But everyone is kind to me. It's just been, very dull for me so far. I've had no chance at students, and they're</p>
135
HOTEL CUSTER 
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMERL DIRECTION
-3-
<p>all wild about football just now. If, later, I can see how you could get pleasure out of the experience, I'll want you to come at once. But, first of all, the teeth are important, and you'll have pain &amp; shock to live down. How glad I'll be that you are really fixed up!</p>
<p>I fear I should not give my view of Literature Since 1912, as I've suspected that the going fashion is respected here. I feel a certain smug adjustment to the world as it is - socially, economically and otherwise. But they're fine people, and many of the faculty are brilliant in their specialties. <underline>I like them.</underline></p>
<p>Everything will work out, and I love you and all the others. I'll write good old Enat &amp; Oddie soon.</p>
Jno.
(over)
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
136
<p>P.S. We can pay Ford $50 without any hardship, I think.</p>