<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
66 Neihardt Collection 50
DAYTON HOTEL CO. H.L. DAYTON, Pres. &amp; Gene. Mgr.
"OPERATING FRIENDLY SOUTHERN HOTELS"
[September - October? 1939]
VALDES Hotel
VALDOSTA GEORGIA

Monday Morning
Precious Mona:
<p>Just got here. Stayed at a nice camp 17 miles worth last night. I wrote you 3 post cards yesterday, numbered 1, 2, 3. There's nothing new since then. Valdosta is just a fairly nice town, like thousands of others. It was almost cold last night, but it's warming up today. Very pleasant - probably much like the weather at Branson now. Glad you had a rain. This is a pleasant hotel with palm trees in front; but palms aren't very numerous yet. Five oaks, China-berry trees, quite some magnolias, and lots of yellow pines. We looked over a turpeutine camp yesterday - must have been</p>
OTHER FRIENDLY DAYTON HOTELS
NEW ALBANY HOTEL, ALBANY, GA.   HOTEL SUWANNE, CORDELE, GA.
HOTEL WINDSOR, AMERICUS, GA.    HOTEL DOUCOFF, DOUGLAS, GA.
HOTEL POWELL, LAKE CITY, FLA.
51
DAYTON HOTEL CO. H.L. DAYTON, Pres. &amp; Gene. Mgr.
"OPERATING FRIENDLY SOUTHERN HOTELS"
-2-
VALDES Hotel
VALDOSTA GEORGIA
<p>thousands of acres of pines tapped for turpentine. The niggers, who do the work, tipped their hats to us! White folks are "quality" down here - except the poor whites ("Georgia crackers") who are said to be of human origin a long way back. Many of the niggers, we have been told, are hardly civilized at all - those living back in the bush &amp; a crub pines. The poverty of this state is terrifying - and yet there are beautiful homes, and the big towns are finely built.</p>
<p>This morning early I got what seems to be a picture of Thessia's</p>
OTHER FRIENDLY DAYTON HOTELS
NEW ALBANY HOTEL, ALBANY, GA.  HOTEL SUWANNE, CORDELE, GA.
HOTEL WINDSOR, AMERICUS, GA.   HOTEL DOUCOFF, DOUGLAS, GA.
HOTEL POWELL, LAKE CITY, FLA.
52
DAYTON HOTEL CO. H.L. DAYTON, Pres. &amp; Gene. Mgr.
"OPERATING FRIENDLY SOUTHERN HOTELS"
[September - October? 1939]
VALDES Hotel
VALDOSTA GEORGIA
-3-
<p>probable purpose &amp; procedure in this mess just beginning. Thus: Russia's purpose is to bring about world revolution. She uses fascist Germany for a spearhead against capitalistic West Europe. Fascism has only a short way to go to be radical socialist. Under the stress of war, Hitler could easily confiscate the highly concentrated industrial groups left in Germany. These could be taken over by decree in a war crisis - and <underline>there'd</underline> be socialism! Now isn't it probable that Stalin &amp; Hitler considered this? How else could Russia stand with Germany? And Hitler <underline>was</underline> a radical</p>
OTHER FRIENDLY DAYTON HOTELS
NEW ALBANY HOTEL, ALBANY, GA.  HOTEL SUWANNE, CORDELE, GA.
HOTEL WINDSOR, AMERICUS, GA.   HOTEL DOUCOFF, DOUGLAS, GA.
HOTEL POWELL, LAKE CITY, FLA.
53
DAYTON HOTEL CO. H.L. DAYTON, Pres. &amp; Gene. Mgr.
"OPERATING FRIENDLY SOUTHERN HOTELS"
[September - October? 1939]
VALDES Hotel
VALDOSTA GEORGIA
-4-
<p>Socialist to begin with.</p>
<p>So we may well see a Russo-German attack on capitalism in Europe, with Hitler's government turning radical socialist &amp; confiscating private capital &amp; industry in the Reich as a part of the process. I have seen nothing of this anywhere, but it seems a vital pattern in keeping with Russia's purpose. Of Germany &amp; Russia continue together, I feel that it is inevitable.</p>
<p>Yes, Mama, you'd better get the linoleum - a <underline>good</underline> quality - on the Sears account.</p>
(over)
OTHER FRIENDLY DAYTON HOTELS
NEW ALBANY HOTEL, ALBANY, GA.  HOTEL SUWANNE, CORDELE, GA.
HOTEL WINDSOR, AMERICUS, GA.   HOTEL DOUCOFF, DOUGLAS, GA.
HOTEL POWELL, LAKE CITY, FLA.
54
<p>Endless love to you. I'll bet you're all scard of Jaine with Gaki away! But just wait till I get back. I'll be very firm &amp; stern with her. I'm sure Joanie is a lovely little lady, with hardly a single pout left.</p>
<p>Tell old lady Max I don't like her and always will. Give my regards to Mr. George Kott</p>
Jno.
Dad
Gaki
<unclear>Grandan</unclear>