<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
2e
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
<p>Thanks so much for costumes to make me a new one too! Oh. I'll love having it so!</p>
January 4, 1942.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We've been living along each day about as usual or rather, a little differently because of the holidays. Now we'll go back to regular life again.</p>
<p>It is <underline>very</underline> cold here now - your ears even get red - but at least it is stimulating, high, blue weather.</p>
<p>Madame will be able to listen to our suggestions this week I feel sure - and we'll get busy soon. Has Sig told you of "Hark, Hark the Lark" (his special version of Liszto arrangement) for "April the Madien"? Nothing could fit it better or be lovelier - that we all feel! Can't wait</p>
(2)
<p>to see what Madame will say about it. We also have been discussing other ideas. I'll tell you as soon as I talk with Madame what she thinks.</p>
<p>Friday, Saturday afternoon and evening adn this afternoon I was at the Ballet Russo! Hil got two tickets for me, and we "crashed" the other two performances after the first ballet. Several of the ballets were lovely, several I didn't hink so good. As a whole it was very enjoyable though.</p>
<p>Thanks so very much for fixing the costumes so beautifully, Mama. I now have three lovely costumes.</p>
<p>Albert was here for dinner and hsa spent the evening with us here. Last night after the ballet</p>
2f
(3)
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
<p>April the Maiden" will be nicely complemented (although it is of course also "very" complete!) See?</p>
<p>Now it seems that we can get up a Variety Show to be presented in smaller towns using American idea in part, as a means toward the goal of our Neihardt program. Mr. Mueller wants in on it too, and Sig, Hil, perhaps someone else (although I think we're enough) will all contribute. Madame Cassan suggested various numbers for this, which she'll work up with me at once. One is a Scotch in adorable ballet tu tu of satin bodice, with plaid towering over skirt, and plaid hat! This</p>
(4)
<p>would be done on the point to cute Scotch melodies, <underline>and</underline> Hilda would introduce it with a Scotch Song. This I can also keep up a a novelty number on <underline>our</underline> program later. This immediate plan would be marvelous experience besides money. Madame thinks it an excellent idea - said my work has improved so that I should start as soon as possible. Sig is getting my Scotch arrangement tomorrow and will play it for Madame Cassan at studio. This program in full would be first - various songs dances, piano pieces of foreign (friendly) countries then <strike>the finale</strike> would</p>
2g
<p>a section of American songs and music, finishing with an all American finale - I could do a march on the point, singing, etc. What do you think of the idea? The thing now is getting my dances worked up. The Scotch is good because it is <underline>novelty</underline> - not depending merely on an audience appreciative of ballet - <underline>and</underline> <unclear/> also be used later on our Neiahrdt program where your're putation Daddy will of course make any amount of spirituality in my other dances most desirable. For the first program I can also</p>
<p>do a picikato polka (?), a rumba, a Spanish dance, anything which will be a little different and catching to a general audience. Hil will sing things like "La Nioletera" "Maids of Cadiz." etc. Sig has various suit able numbers. Mueller wants to sing all American songs. Please say what you think of this as a starter for our goal. It sounds reasonable, doesn't it?</p>
<p>We will all work like the ___ and we'll get where we're going!</p>
Loads of Love to you dearest, most marvelous
Daddy and Mama
<p>May we be able to make you happy one of these days!</p>
<p>I got a request to return to Nakanawa next summer. I don't wat to tread water again this summer. Once was good, but this summer I must be dancing.</p>
5833 Bartmer Avenue
St. Louis, Missouri
January 5, 1942
Dr. L. L. Rice
Lebanon, Tennessee
Dear Colonel Rice:
<p>I received your letter dated November 26 a few days ago, and I am indeed pleased that you want me back next year.</p>
<p>Unfortunately I cannot say definitely now whether I shall be able to return to Nakanawa next season, but I will let you know within a month, if this is satisfactory to you.</p>
<p>I take this opportunity to wish you and Annie Hays all good things for this new year.</p>
Sincerely yours,
alice neihardt