<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
18a
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
July 16, 1941.
Dear Daddy and Mama, Max, Joan, and Elaine,
<p>Thanks again for the drum and for the words to the Ogalalla Spring Song. We've been waiting for the costumes etc. and so plan to have the last five Council Rings be used as I've told you, one for each tribe, and the last one for the big ceremony you planned. We want to get the girls really ready before they put on there ceremonies. Daddy we thought we should have a name or title for each of the six in the tribal group who are costumed and take part in the ceremony, like chief, two fire builders and what else? I'd like to save the prayer to the Great Spirit and to Mother Earth which is in Black Elk Speaks for the last ceremony. What do you think?</p>
<note>text below is in margin of letter</note>
<p>Thanks for shorts Mom - this should arrive today - also for sending wigs, etc.! Yes, we should have completed regalia for final ceremony - also great shirts</p>
(2) 
<p>For each of the separate tribal ceremonies, one member (the medicine man?) will pray to his tribe's special quarter and to the Great Spirit and Mother Earth very briefly? Could you suggest something very brief for this? I have written a prayer to the West, using phrases from Black Elk Speaks, as I couldn't find a specific prayer to use the Spring Song for each tribe, making the center verse go with the special quarter of each tribe. That is, I made three other verses like the middle one, changing words to suit each of the other three quarters. Then each tribe will sing three verses of the same song, the first and third alike, and the middle varying according to the quarter it represents. How is this?</p>
<p>I don't like to be bothering you continually, but would you, Mama, look through my children's books upstairs and send some of my best books, such as "White Indian Boy," one of Hinkle's dog or</p>
18b
(3)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>horse stories, and anything else that looks as if my young charges here might enjoy having it read to them in the evenings before lights out and taps. I'd also be very grateful if you would send me a copy of "Indian tales and Others" and the "Quest" I want the latter for myself, and the counselors here who've asked about you, Daddy. I want to pay the postage on them (out of what you've <underline>already</underline> given me I mean!) so please tell me what it is - also on the drum, I hope you don't mind all this bothering I doing to you.</p>
<p>Yesterday was new counselors initiation day. We had to say "Ya Ma'am" to everything the old counselors said, and had to serve and set table at breakfast, taking the places of regular camp "aids". Then yesterday evening at 5:30 we all went on a truck trip about fifteen miles to Bee Rock, and stayed till about 8:30. Bee Rock is a lot like Chula Vista on one side</p>
(4)
<p>only I think the valleys are deeper, and the drop is more abrupt. It is simply breathtakingly beautiful there in broad daylight, and when the sunset colors spread across the sky it is really heavenly. "Ray," Mrs. Irvin is our dietician here, and she of course got our picnic dinner together. We had t bone steaks (gosh! what food) homemade Parker House buns, deviled eggs and lettuce, jars of the best fruit salad I've ever eaten, made with homemade mayonaise, stuffed olives, coffee, golden cake with white pecan icing and <underline>delicious</underline> chocolate marshmallow ice cream - homemade or rather, camp made. We ate too our hearts content and then rode home in the truck under the stars, and sang all the way back! Willie and I felt so good that we really sand quite well (for a change). Ray even asked us who was sitting in our corner singing! We sand every song ever written, as someone said. It was a grand day and I went to bed quite exhausted, having practiced quite a while in addition to all this!</p>
<p>Yesterday Willie and I went for a nice long walk out in the woods after supper. She's a swell girl - enjoys everything I do and feels the same way abou things</p>
18c
(5)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>Mrs. Long has some adorable ideas for our dances. The small children will do the fairytale of the Princess and the Pea and the older ones will do a modern version of this about camp. The girl who does sleep with a canteen under her mattresses is the perfect camper. Cute, N'osb ce pas? We plan to have a dance about each activity. I have a tennis dance which Sylvia did in recital and I'm teaching it to four girls two on each side of the "net".</p>
<p>My girls are so eager for stories in the evening, so I'd be very <underline>very</underline> tickled if you'd send me a book or so.</p>
<p>How are all of you doing? Please tell me about everything.</p>
<p>How are Cantwell's, Misers, etc.? Tell them I'll write them, and I'd love to hear from them too.</p>
<p>Maxie, wish you were here to help with our bunk stunt. We're planning to have a sports "newsreel" and make it funny save you any suggestions?</p>
(6)
<p>You're always so good at such things! Gosh! It seems as if all of you are doing my job for me!</p>
<p>I received three letters from you yesterday, music from Hilda too! I feel so lucky! Daddy, thanks ever so much for everything! We're getting things in order now. The Omaha air is lovely but I can't quite remember it on pitch for some reason. It goes down the scale, doesn't it? Rudie, my coworker, thinks the one song with substitution of the middle verse sounds very good. However, for an extra song, the other would be grand. If I remember the tune (could Mama not write the notes as you sing them?) I'd be simply thrilled to have you put the words of Black Elk to it! Have you any good plays of Indians - or rather Indian plays. We think this would be good for part of our Council Ring. Wouldn't some of your Indian tales be adaptable?</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<note>text below is in margin of letter</note>
<p>I'm going to talk to Col. Rice as soon as possible and say what you said.</p>
18d
MAYLAND
JUL
17
2 PM
1941
TENN.
<stamp>UNITED 
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt and Mrs. S. Neihardt
                                  (and daughters)
                                  Branson, Mo.
junior camp nakanawa Alice Neihardt
                    mayland, tennessee
<p>Max - Have you a better idea for our cabin's stunt - a play of some kind that will be funny. Tell me if you have!</p>