<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
56m
1425 North Dearhorn
May 10, 1942
Dear Daddy, Mama, and all the rest of you dear ones,
<p>today is Mother's Day, and I am thinking of you with all the love and gratitude that I feel all the days of the year - only in a more concentrated form, Mama. Some of these days I hope to be able to <underline>show</underline> you something of this feeling - in act as well as words. As far as I personally am concerned, just the thought of you - fine, dear, strong, and good - is an inspiration and a great happiness. Now it is up to me to prove my</p>
(2)
<p>self half worthy of you.</p>
<p>We're having a spell of cold, rainy weather here in Chicago. It's been lovely and sunny up till now and we've had little taste of the intense changes which characterize Chicago weather.</p>
<p>We rehearse all afternoon every week day now. today, being Sunday, we are at home in our cozy apt. sitting around our dining room table, each busied with her own correspondence. Our midday meal is beginning to be prepared, and we needn't rush away so I shall have a nice long one - way traffic chat with you! First and foremost, we are supposed to open one week from this Monday</p>
56n
(3)
<p>in Detroit, doing three long numbers, the Russian which I've already described to you, the Jungle or native voodoo, and a waltz which we must learn this next week. We have worked like <strike/> (dogs) this past week and shall do so again this coming week. Do pray for us - for our time is rather short. George Leon our manager and partner, will drive us to Detroit where we will be for at least a week. For the present, until he can secure and break in another dancer, he will dance himself. Being a French alien, Leon is not subject to the draft, at least</p>
(4)
<p>at present. Friday night, Leon and his sweet chubby French Grandmother came over to our apt. with the costumes. There we tried on and found surprisingly well fitting, as well as good-looking. The Russian costumes have full white satin skirts with handpainted flowers, white or <unclear/> blousese with huge sleeves and brightly colored beads, and adorable red and black velet bodices and matching headpieces. Red leather open work shoes with ribbon ties go with this costume. The Jungle costumes are very scanty but also very decent - and cute. They are made of imitation leopard</p>
56o
(5)
<p>skin - a two-piece set of top and trunks. We wear huge headdresses of pheasant feathers dyed <unclear/> ritoous colors, and green nature sandals with this outfit. The itself is very wild and primitive, the music being based on primitive Haiti rythms. It is really exciting to do. Getting back to strict business, alterations will be made on these costumes and we'll have them for dress rehearsal probably Wednesdady. Incidentally, the Countess wants to watch this rehearsal - and Leon says she may</p>
(6)
<p>We are to see and sign our contracts some day this next week, probably Monday. This is, you will say, very short notice, when we are to open in a week, but we are determined to be very careful about our commitments.</p>
<p>leon has high hopes fo rour act. Of course experience is what will improve it and us, so we shall gradually work in better and better places. As it is, we <underline>shall</underline> work in good clubs, hotels, and theatres all over, for Leon has a grand reputation</p>
56p
(7)
<p>at least, that is the impression everyone we talk to had of him - as well as he! I wish now that I had been able to work up the Scotch, for it is possible I could have used it in the act - he asked if any of us knew solos! I do have the music at home and one recording - but Sig never had time to do it over in the required dance tempo, adn this thing of Chicago came about in <underline>such</underline> a hurry! Perhaps it is better to wait for other experience first anyway. I would greatly appreciate it if thsi mu</p>
(8)
<p>sic and record <unclear/> carefully put away.</p>
<p>We like our little apartment very much and even have room for another person. If we are back in town sometime, we'll try to get this again, and then one of you can visit us! We pay $4 per wk. each for rent, and our total grocery list will certainly not exceed 47 (with the care we take) So you can see how reasonable is this set-up, and besides, we can see how very much more comfortable and satisfying</p>
56q
(9)
<p>it is than a room and board set - up. We plan our meals and shop cooperatively - and each succeeding meal is better than the one before. Today we had liver and onions, baked potatoes, rolls and butter, apple sauce, orange, lettuce carrot and cottage cheese salad, celery; and peas. We shall have cookies and milk later on. We count our pennies and divide each grain of cottage cheese with absolute accuracy - so as a result, everyone is happy. One thing we have neglected to do is register for sugar, and if it is</p>
(10)
<p>too late now, we shall have to ask you (our parents) to send some. I believe the time has been extended, so I'll tell you if we <underline>do</underline> need some sent. Incidentally, we don't eat meat every day, but more often have spaghetti, egg, cheese, bacon dishes for our main course. The girls just now say I should see tomorrow about the sugar - then we'll ask you for some if we need it.</p>
<p>We haven't had time to see any Art Museums yet - and I do so want to see the Hall of Man. This we <underline>shall</underline> do <underline>some</underline></p>
56r
(11)
<p><underline>time</underline> if we don't get time before leaving for Detroit.</p>
<p>We had <underline>so</underline> much to do today that we couldn't go to Seymours Bookfellow tea. I'll call them later to say why I couldn't come, for nothing was definitely arranged. Today we're spending in writing, reading, resting, dyeing tights black, and ironing. We shall go for a little outing to collect any behind time mail at our former home just around the corner very soon now.</p>
<p>You should see us in rehearsal. In the first place, we board an old red rickety street</p>
(12)
<p>car (not as all nice) <unclear/> our new St. Louis cars, and rumble away across the Chicago River (on the bridge which divides in two and pulls up like drawbridges when a barge wishes passageway) through downtown Chicago, into and through Chinatown, thorugh niggertown, and finally arrive at the Grand Terrace Cafe, on the boarder between white and negro sections. There we enter by the back enterance and climb stairs which lead to a large airy rehearsal room. This is available to Leon</p>
56s
(13)
<p>free of charge. This explains his choice of place, which is however, <underline>very</underline> decent and also very suitable for rehearsing. Upon our arrival upstairs, we find an unoccupied dressing room and emerge there from a few minutes later dressed in black tighs, consumte or red sweather, and character shoes, with our hair in a net adorned with a white head band and flower. We try to look similar in our dress, and besides, this is a comfortable attire as well as, to most people, a strange one. Please <underline>do</underline> pray for us for much is yet to be accom</p>
(14)
<p>plished and perfected. <unclear/> mood is coming now which helps immensely in characterization. I do so <underline>want</underline> to do this well, and furthermore, it <underline>must</underline> be done well.</p>
<p>George Leon gave us tickets to the Carnation contented Hour program this Monday night so we are planning to go. It would be nice if all of you were listening. I might well something into the "mike."</p>
<p>Sig, I met a concert pianist at rehearsal. He has four scholarships offered him, which he refused. I tried to get</p>
56t
(15)
<p>soem information form him concerning them, but rehearsal prevented this. Next time I see him I shall try to find out more about them. He played very well for us but <underline>I</underline> could even tell a difference - yes, a great difference in both attack and expression. How about your Baldwin affairs, and has anything come of the Small Arms or Emerson Electric? I do hope so.</p>
<p>Daddy and Mama I hear you're (in letter from Hilda) looking very well, and seem to like being there. I'm so glad. Eny, Ollie and Nei, <underline>please</underline> do write</p>
(16)
<p>me a line if you <unclear/> time. I'd so love to hear from you! Every day I think of little Nei, his bursting smile and his triumphant exclamation of "S-." Tell me all about him, and if you have an extra picture, please sen it.</p>
<p>Hilda, I do hope you'll get time to write me a bit and also <underline>force</underline> the sturdy old pioneer (eh! Alberto?) to pen a word or so. Maxie, over the flu <underline>completely</underline> by now and that you are, as I'm sure you are, much happier since you have your big adorbale girlies</p>
56u
(17)
<p>with you. By the way, Joan and Elaine, you promised to write me and so far I haven't heard a word from you! <underline>Please</underline> find time from your all too busy days to pen a little note to your big-city aunt you rehearses all afternoon in black tights, wont' you? How do you like your Daddy and Mama, and your new backyard, and your new cousin? Also, did Dr. George Henry Katt come along with you? How is he? Joan, what about school? Do</p>
(18)
<p>you help Nanny during the day?</p>
<p>How are the Victory Gardens coming along? Do you all work hard in them" I can imagine the lovely vegetables you'll have.</p>
<p>Mom if you find my dancing pants, please send them, I'd greatly appreciate your trouble. Also, the white cotton bathing suit with lastex top would be a lovely costume if it were hemmed. I can do that here if you send it.</p>
<p>I have 46 soem change left. As I expet, I'll end only a few more dollars before we leave. I don't know yet how <underline>soon</underline> we get paid. Wish it were in advance, but I'm afriad not.</p>
Loads of love to each and every one of you,
Your Alice