<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
129g
Eny's and Ollie's 
May 25, 1941.
Dear Mama,
<p>Eny and I are sitting outside in the lovely sunny backyard letting the sun get at us as we write to you. It is really lovely here with the birds twittering and a soft breeze making the grass wave. I came out yesterday after class and Hil came out before that. When I arrived Harrison's asked me if I'd like to ride. I told Hil to come with me, but she said she'd come over after she'd called Al. So I got on the lovely black and rode out to meet Jack and teh Jack across the road who were out riding their sorrels. They turned around and went riding again with me</p>
(2)
<p>I happened to mention that Hil had never ridden. Stepper and that I'd like her to try him out when we got back, and Jack said "I didn't know Hilda was out here or she could have gone on Stepper. I'll go back and give him "to her." With that he galloped off, and soon Hil reappeared on Stepper. We three had a grand ride all over lovely hills and valleys near here on mere paths, not roads, and were gone over an hour. Needless to say, we had a marvelous time. The black is a very fine horse - very willing, gorgeously gaited, and has become very lovely to look at since she has lost her</p>
(3)
<p>winter coat and gotten rid of her mange. Stepper is still loads of fun to ride.</p>
<p>Radishes are beginning here and cherries are nearly ripe. I bet they're ripe already at home, aren't they.</p>
<p>I'm going in to rehearsal about 12:30. It's really thrilling to have a solo part and gosh I'm gonna do my best!</p>
<p>Mama, this is really supposed to be a birthday letter, but so far all I've done is jabber about things here. You must know how greatly all of us love you every single day of the year and how much we'd love to be with you tomorrow on your special day. We will "be with you in spirit rejoicing with you" as all of you said to me in the</p>
(4)
<p>telegram you sent. No one ever had a more marvelous Mother, that is certain, and you are so much in addition to that, Mama. Some day I'll do something to show you how much I mean all this. Of course you'll have a lovely birthday with everyone there, even without us!</p>
<p>Eny informs me were going to have potatoe salad for lunch. I still like to eat, you seen. By the way, Mama, could you or would you send me some of your bread again sometime when it's convenient to do so?</p>
<p>it's a huge treadt for us - you see Mrs Uthoff loves it too.</p>
<p>Again, Mama, have a good birthday!</p>
<p>Love to all there from here</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice