<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
39 Petri Collection 62
1940 [October 12, 1940]
Norfolk, Neb.
Saturday A.M.
Dearest Children:
<p>We are here in  the very same cabin where Daddy finished the Messiah - and it seems nice to be here and realize how much farther along we are than we then were towards an inner Peace adn a solution of our problems. Personally I am happier and "weller" than I then was, and chaotic as things are I feel you dear children are closer to the doing of things you truly want to do! Our Joanie is quite a lady, and our 'Laine is already being a good dry little girl!</p>
<p>We are so hungry for mail, and since there wwas none at Grand Island, we feel confident there will be some at Wayne.</p>
<p>Daddy's success in Denver at the regular affair was great as always but at the Luncheon where it was informal it was even greater.</p>
<p>The women as well as the men seem to grab hungrily for what he has to give them. I wonder if a tours of all the <underline>Women's Clubs</underline> might not be a good thing to try, Sigurd? -The Davisons</p>
63
<p>are such dear <sic>peopl</sic>! Denver would give me as a sculptress all I could desire. They have nobody there and it is surprisingly eager for the Arts The Lady who took us around, Lenore Taylor, is certainly a live wire and was thrilled with Dady and so delighted to hear about my fountains. She wants me to send her everything possible on the subject! Would it not be grand if she would want one, and through her I could get some other orders? She has a magnificent Home and is so proud of her back yard, which really has nothing in it!</p>
<p>Daddy and I both <underline>love</underline> Denver. It's air is swell and its people are wonderful. They would go more than halfway to get no there.</p>
<p>I have already written you about the <unclear>Lhevins</unclear> being there every Summer at the La Monte School of Music.</p>
<p>Alice Knows about the fine Ballet Teacher there too. From my con-</p>
64
<p>versations I Know they think highly of the finest Singers only, and one man said to me that there really were <underline>very few great</underline> Saprano singers, because of them had <underline>no</underline> interpretation.</p>
<p>Our what problem is this; hang on the way we are now doing making no change that we might regret - and then, when Dad has some money through his Cycle, break away from SO. MO. to where Life is vigorous and healthy and free. I think Denver would be a marvelous center for all of us. In irrigated farm for <sic>Olie</sic> to run would surely make his and Enid's dream come true. <underline>My what</underline> chances to <underline>really</underline> make money on cream and eggs! We'll talk about his when we get together again.</p>
<p>Dear Children, would you please share this letter with Enid and Ollie as well as the others - There are nore of you at Southwood, and Mial get to you</p>
65
<p>faster there than at Overland - but I'm thinking of you all together always when I write.</p>
<p>We left Denver at about 3 o'clock day before yesterday and last night at the proper time to stop we arrived in Norfolk just a pleasant little drive away from Wayne! So we'll remain here to get <underline>entirely</underline> fresh again, and be ready for the dinner Sunday evening and the affairs Monday.</p>
<p>Blair is quite close, and right in the heart of John's old stamping ground so that will be esay to take in on our way So. We wish for a few more engagements since we are here - but even so We will be able to put $200 down on the $900 mortgage, making it only $700 - These will melt into zero long before we really need worry - So goodbye for today -</p>
Endlessly loveing your <underline>fine splendid</underline> children
Nannie Mother Mutti - Mama.