<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
94
Neihardt
6235 southwood Ave.
St. Louis, Mo.
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 5
OCT27
10<underline>30</underline> PM
1940
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Mo
95
(1)
Home - 2:45
Sunday 27th
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We have been so glad for you wonderful letters, and for all the good they contain. Letters home both of you are always on inspiration to us - it is marvelous to have such parents, and we do know it. <strike>and</strike> In addition we love you more than you can know.</p>
<p>We are all quite well. Hilda is not feeling too well, but I don't believe she will get a cold as she is afraid she will. We are going out for a bus ride soon and the fresh air and gorgeous sunshine will do us good. Joan and Elaine are going to Dickie's birthday party in a few minutes.</p>
<p>Hilda yesterday. We had a very nice lesson, and I certainly enjoyed having Hil there as much as she enjoyed coming. Madame told Hilda that I have done 4 yrs. work in 2 yrs. and that if I keep on unproving as I have been that in a little while I'll be the best technician at the</p>
96
(2)
<p>studio. I'm so thrileed that she thinks that of me. I see <unclear/> reason why I should keep on improving, dont' you? And I'm going to be more than a "technician" too. The other day I talked with Madame and she said I had gained a lot of strength in my dancing just in the last 2 wks. in spite of my cold, and that I must work on plita now on opening on too, and in getting more resilience and softness through my chest and back. She said I should work on playing with facial expressions as I dance, too, so that I will be more able to show certain emotions, etc. Madame also said I was ready for all this now and that I should work on a very well-rounded course of practice. That I shall do.</p>
<p>Maxie wants me to inform you, Nanny, that Baby 'Laine dearly loves her lovely silk panties - says she'll never wet them at all. She's a good girl mostly - and so is Joanikens.</p>
97
(3)
<p>Sig is playing his Mozart Concerto now - it is so very beautiful. By the way, we are learning a Chopin Mazurka now which is really a fem - one that Barbara Dix'on did a Detroit <unclear/> Madame took some girls there for a convert several years ago. Hilda loved it too.</p>
<p>Mama, I do need a costume very much. I am sending you an old dress, the skirt and zipper of which I'm sure you can make a costume from, using the pattern of my white flowered costume. Please, white rif this inter<unclear/> and then dye it a lovely Kelly green or dark blue, will you? Eileen has a green costume which looks lovely on me. Would this all be too much trouble for you? I'd appreciate it very much. Mama. For some reason the little flowered <unclear/> always <unclear/> <unclear/> or than the silk one perhaps the silk is</p>
98
(4)
<p>too <unclear/> So, if you can do <unclear/> pe you did in the case of the first one the white flowered <unclear/>, for that one fits just right.</p>
<p>Joan and Elaine just came back from their party and we have just had some popcorn and popcorn balls. Hil and I went out for a little walk around the block awhile ago too. The children had a marvelous time - they ate cake, chocolate milk, sandwiches, and each one recevied a gift, as well as bringing one. Elaine got scared of the paper <sic>blowers</sic> so Maxie went back with ehr for awhile.</p>
<p>I must quit now as Sig and Max want to mail this letter.</p>
Loads fo Love,
Alice
<p>P.S. The dishes cost 41.10. Eny loved them! We had a lovely time with her and Ollie.</p>