<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
19
Neihardt Collection 
56
1012 Ambassador Building 
St. Louis, Missouri 
October 13, 1938
Dearest Mama: 
I was so happy to find your letter here for me when I came into the office this morning, and now that I have some time to spare, I am going to answer it right away. 
Mr. Jost is gone for a few days, and I am here all alone. Nevertheless, I have been busy today, for there were some things that needed to be done, and for which I did not have the time when he was here and I was busy with more pressing matters. It is rather lonesome here in the of-fice since he is gone - I had forgotten how it feels to be in the office alone: 
What you say about my thoughts concerning spending some time in Europe is absolutely right, and it is what I know, but still Id o like the idea of it all. And in the end it might turn out that I should go, but you can be sure that I shall not do so unless I do have something really def-inite in mind - something which undoubtedly would be a real bettement to me. 
That is too bad about Amama. Have you heard from her since you wrote me? It seems to me that one has to consider her not at all as one considers other people - Amama is indeed a law unto herself. Don't you think so? Therefore it is as you say, impossible that you disagree with her, for she can-not to use a slang expression, "take it". You say that you wrote 

20
-2-
her about a week before I told you that I wrote, yet she has not answered you. Mama, when I told you that she had answered me, it was not with a letter, but with a few postcards; she said that she did not feel like writing. Yesterday I got a very nice letter from her; in the belief that you will enjoy reading it, and with the request that you send it back afterwards so that I can answer it, I am sending her letter to you. Please do not feel bad as you ahve, for I do hope what you say is true of how she feels in con-nection with you will not be so long, or prove to be not so at all. She is jsut a little "funny", and really thinks all the world of you, in spite of what might be considered jealousy of you as one woman to another. You can see that from her letter. Of course, she still considers you "idolatrous" - but take that lightly. I know you think almost too much of us, but we realize what a great gift it is to have one's Mother think so highly of her children, and as Alice and I have said when talking about teh matter, we are going to try to justify your faith in us. In fact, I think that you should take lightly any side of Amama which goes against the grain, for surely her sides which do not go against the grain, for surely her sides which do not go against the grain, for surely her sides which do not go against the grain, for surely her sides which do not go against the grain, for surely her sides which do not go against the grain are many. I do love her dearly, rather sadly, for she is lonely, and though one might justly say that she has brought on this loneli-ness, to some extent at least, through her own actions, still this fact does in no way do away with the unhappy state of mind she is in. All I wish is that I might be able to make her feel a little better, by making her know that I do love her - for no reason at all except that I do. Indeed you are right when you say she is an egotist - and how little she realizes it! 
And yet I know that all I may say can mean little to you - how I wish that I could write you something about Amama that would make you feel better. She cannot realize that, although 

-3-
21
her own life has not lead to peaceful happiness, she could, if only she would, experience the satisfaction of achieve-ment through you. That is what she should do, and it is also what you yourself would do if you were in her place, but she just cannot. 
But you are not in the place she is, and of course never could be. You have set an example for your children whichh they can follow and which they hope to follow. 
So much for that now. I wrote to Daddy and to Sigurd at Wayne. We had such a nice letter from Sig after he left here, telling us that he enjoyed being with us. I am so glad; you know how thrilled we were to have him here: And now we can look forward to having you here at Thanksgiving time. I do think that at least y o u should stay with us (with Al and me) then. What do you say? 
Indeed I do not consider your letter "a strange sort"; on the contrary, I am deeply happy that you wrote it to me. And I do hope that you will write to me more such letters, and I shall of course write to you anythign that I feel. It is fine that way; it makes me very happy. 
That is fine about your writing down important facts concerning Daddy's life; perhaps some time I shall be the one, or one of the ones, to wrote his life. That would be something real. 
Give my love to Max, and kiss Joanie and Elaine for me - tell them their RICH OLD MAID AUNT HILDA does love them, even though OLDMAIDENHOOD is turning her heart to, to - well what? 
So much love to you - more than I will express. 
Enid 
Hilda 
<figure/> 
Mr Aizler took me to lunch!! We had a delicious <unclear/>. Not bad, eh? 