<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 94
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
Oct 17 39

Precious Mona:
<p>I had my first affair at the Sacred Heart College for Women ( a college of Notre Dame, which is for men) at 11 A.M. today. It was lovely. Four hundred young women of university age &amp; a dozen sisters - all of them truly gentle &amp; <unclear/>. It went off <underline>right</underline>. I gave the Messiah. Sister Madeleva said "It was not a lecture; it was an experience." Sig heard them talking in the hall, I'm hoppy about it, for I got something over that was worth while.</p>
(over)
<italics>Air Conditioned Banquet Facilities</italics>
95
-2-
<p>Queer! I slept only an hour or two last night. Fluey for a couple of days - all right now, tho' weary. But that made no difference somehow; and until I'm actually talking on the platform, I dislike the idea - would far rather be in <unclear>Slim</unclear> Buttes.</p>
<p>This evening <unclear>denmir</unclear> with faculty &amp; the Poetry Society - and something afterward on impromptu talk. I'll be all right when the time comes, tho' I don't know what I'll do.</p>
96
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
-3-
<p>Tomorrow A.M. at 8 and 11 I'll do 2 lectures on Poetic Values. Have it worked out nicely. I'm a little weary now, but I'll come alive. Wish I could talk, instead of write to you.</p>
<p>I think Sig will play tonight. I'll see, that he does, Altho' it's not on the program here.</p>
<italics>Air Conditioned Banquet Facilities</italics>
97
-4-
<p>Noble was dear to us. However the house depresses me greatly. He certainly accepted Sig's technique without any comment except to me: "Damned nice finger work". Poor Noble. Dear fellow, and so unlucky in so many ways. I wished for Joan &amp; Jaine to stage a good rousing fight in that dead house. Kisses for them.</p>
<p>Endless love to you &amp; to the Old Lady who is a hangin' around there! How is her rheumatiz? And her poor nose?</p>
98
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
-5-
<p>I'm crazy to see the house all fixed up!! Bully! Fine about heating now!</p>
Jno
Dad
Grandan
Gaki
<p>Does Jaine still love Gaki?</p> ?
<italics>Air Conditioned Banquet Facilities</italics>