<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
177 Fink Collection 1
MRS. John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON
APR 5
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
mrs. O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, 
Mo.
2
<picture>lady in a dress, arrow pointing to the crown of her head</picture>
<p>8601--A princesse dress, demure as the flower-strewn snood, yet sophisticated withal. A moulded bodice, a bouffant skirt, a tiny jacket long or short-sleeved, all "Easy-to-Make". 12 to 20; 30 to 38. Price, 75 cents</p>
3
April 5th 40
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>"Somany" thanks for your good letters. It has turned cold enough once more Ollie, to make me wish for that Kerosene stove in your illustration of me! When will Winter cease!? Yesterday I planted my hollyhocks out and today it feels like freezing! However I did protect them with fruit jars so I hoope they will survive the cold. Nasturttiums I planted out of doors are all up - think of it! Pears are in full bloom - also Forsythias, small Spireas, red buds, japonicas, Jonquils are so beautiful, it hurts to look at them! Our yard is tru</p>
4
<p>ly lovely, adn the first time I have seen it flowering since before I was sick, ages ago it seems!</p>
<p>We are all so eager for Hildas coming - and do so hope a cold spell will not ruin her all too short vacation with us.</p>
<p>P.S. No.1.* Enid, you did not mention the $10.00 Sig sent you for April the 6 adn for Alice the remaining 4. Is that O.K.? You did not understand my asking whether you could accomodate all the folks. What I meant was, in case Hilda should return with them, could you look after the whole outfit including Hilda - but it looks now as though Hilda will be leaving here sooner than our folks will leave. I Knew you would <underline>welcome</underline> all of us, dear children that you are!</p>
5
3
<p>I have been so very busy - there seems always a great deal to do, and at best I can accomplish only <underline>one</underline> of a number of possible things! You feel the same I know. You have beaten me at house cleaning! I have done that only in spots.</p>
<p>I'd love to see the arm chair you mention. I am sure it is gorgeous in a refined way, and I will understand how much more it means to you than any <underline>bought</underline> thing could possibly mean. What color predominates in it?</p>
<p>I wish more every day for a fireplace - to live in the midst of wood going to waste and have non in all these thousands of years is <underline>so foolish</underline>! I trust we will have one</p>
6
4
<p>before 1941. Luckily we still have more than a ton of coal - and are using plenty in the furnance today!</p>
<p>I am going to make clothes for Hilda and want to get a lot done while she is home - so you can make up your minds about what I am doing it I do not write much during her stay. I am so very happy to be of service.--</p>
<p>We had a big men of greens the other night which Daddy picked out they did not agree with him like we had hoped they might. I worry over Daddys health, it is not so good. The same old trouble with indigestion! He is surely doing the finest writing he ever did on Jed - every thing he has learned through out his living and growing goes into this last and in</p>
7
5
<p><unclear/> estimation greatest of his poems. I am so glad and grateful fo rthis. The other day Daddy and Sigurd swung the cellar vines on wires from our maple to the Walnut trees. They did away with all the posts! <strike>of which</strike> (there are 13 which I can use for my future chicken fences!) Swell idea not? I believe I already told you this but you won't mind the repetition! Our peas are up and also our lettuce - Now Max put in green beans which cannot stand the cold - and here it is almost freezing once more!</p>
<p>I'd give a lot for 50 pullets and a Jersey cow right now! Our pasture is <underline>so fine</underline>!</p>
<p>I guess I have very little news</p>
8
<p>but that which is always strong and new - my love for you and my prayer for your happiness - <underline>always</underline> your devoted</p>
Mama Mother.
<p>P.S.No 1.
Please give enclosed picture to Alice with my love and tell her I think she should wear the <underline>front</underline> of her hair like the girl in the picture. Alice should not wear her hair brushed up form her forehead. The hair should fall <underline>down upon</underline> it, more or less carelessly. Tell Alice too I want another (another) good lettter from her.</p>
M.
9
<p>*P.S.No 2.
Your letter to Sig just came and <strike>answered</strike> relieved my worry over the checque. You are talking <underline>no</underline> renumeration from us as it is, Enid and I fear the $6 may not even cover the extra expense. We are going to make the grade, and Daddy will have the cutire cycle completed before he is 60 - so why ask for mroe from this crazy world?! If I can just Know that you children will achieve your <underline>biggest desire</underline> in this Life, I shall feel satisfied - Loving you so much, so terribly much</p>
Always your grateful
Mama
10
<p>What a work! I don't know <underline>how</underline> I managed to do this!</p>