<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
77a
6235 Southwood, 
St. Louis.
2/8/41
Sat. <sic>Nite</sic>
Dear Dad:
<p>I thought it might be well to start, right away, trying to figure a way to prevent things from growing even more difficult than they already are. It is time for Max &amp; me to make another change, prompted at this time by the fact that Hilda is <underline>also</underline> in rather a difficult financial position &amp; cannot afford to continue with paying her part of the apartment expense. She plans not to be here in March (vacation). Her not being here in March of course means that another huge demand would take ahold of me on top of what I allready am paying out.</p>
<p>Maxie &amp; I &amp; Hilda have discussed our financial standing &amp; feel that, effective the 1st of this next month, we'll have to split up for a period, &amp; relieve ourselves of some debts that would otherwise grow bigger &amp; bigger.</p>
<p>Maxie &amp; I have figured as follows: If she &amp; the kids could come to Branson for about <underline>two</underline> months, we could during that period get rid of considerable debt as well as be a help to yours &amp; their cost of living in Branson.</p>
<p>You know, this darned business of each pay day, going more &amp; more in the red, will not lead to anything</p>
over
-2-
<p>but disaster in the course of a short while. I am at a place where I must consider borrowing money. And against what security? None! it just isn't feasible.</p>
<p>Luckily, &amp; of course as the result of hard work to a great extent, I've done quite a lot of business in the last couple of weeks. This didn't mean extra income for us. It merely meant 'getting otu of the red' with the Co. somewhat.</p>
<p>Unless business grows <underline>worse</underline>, then this job could be a Godsend for a while, knowing that Max &amp; the kids were supplying some money down there, &amp; me paying these dreadful debts off up here.</p>
<p>So hard to explain things in a letter. You have a clear picutre of our set up anyway.</p>
<p>to have a job <underline>at all</underline>, these days, is to be fortunate, and that means make what money one earns - go as <underline>far</underline> as it will.</p>
<p>Maxie feels that she could be a help down there as well as keep money coming into the Branson home instead of all of it going out.</p>
<p>I want you to say (<underline>Mama</underline> too of course) what you <underline>really</underline> think about the plan.</p>
<p>I hope that your condition is better. I feel sure it will turn out allright.</p>
Endless love,
Sig.