<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
349 Fink Collection 29
Box 167
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
AUG21
3 -PM
1942
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STAES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland 
MO.
(St. Louis Co.)
30
Branson, Aug. 21, 42
Dear Ollie &amp; Enot (Not to mention old Nei!),
<p>That was another good letter. I note all you say, and have said, about the garden, and I've been genuinely intersted. There's nothing to say in return because the news is all on one side! But I think it's bully the way you've made the garden pay in spite of various cranky conditions of weather. I told Amama yesterday, that if you set your heart and mind on a task, you'd <strike/> accomplish it.</p>
<p>Yesterday's note was mailed just as your letter arrived.</p>
<p>Many thanks, Ollie, for the offer to help me on the house payt. I have $100 yet, &amp; should have a bit more. I owe $135 on Sept. 13. Kemper would solve all our problems nicely, but I'm still waiting for the final word. No doubt Hitch &amp; the faculty as a whole want me; but there's some quandary as to arrangements. I have a final suggestion</p>
(over)
31
-2-
<p>to make, if the opportunity arises. At worst, I could run up to Boonville for two days each week, &amp; Mama &amp; I could stay with you'ns &amp; do our rightful share. I'd consider such an arrnagement bully for we <underline>do</underline> want to be with you, and we'd be completely happy if we could keep a bit. With that scheme, we could actually reduce your present budget, while living for much less than a home in Boonville would cost.</p>
<p>Well, we'll see. Anyway, theree'll be something, and the assurance that we can be with you will make planning &amp; scheming easier.</p>
<p>What you say of G. &amp; co-ops is amusing, and true, I'm sure. His mental processes are emotional, characteristically feminie; and he's dear as well as able in his live.</p>
<p>How woudl you regard this suggestion? Is it not likely that when the co-operative movement is viewed historically, it may be seen to have been <underline>symptomatic</underline> rather than <underline>curative</underline>?</p>
32
-3-
<p>During the hey day of peace movements it seemed to me that they were symptomatic of the disease and not indicative of a world - will to peace. The parallel is not perfect, but does suggest the idea.</p>
<p>Incidentally, isn't the co-operative movemnt a phase of the deomcratic dream? And would you suspect that catastrophe will lead to democracy?</p>
<p>You know I don't care in the least one way or the other. Deep down in me I'm happy.</p>
<p>Just to think what a miracle it is that old Nei actually <underline>did</underline> come and is <underline>here</underline>? That's the way I feel &amp; think about him.</p>
<p>Enot, I often see you around the kitchen and the house generally.</p>
Love always
Dad.