<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
51p
March 30, 1943.
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I sent you a card this morning saying we were leaving for Mexico in a few hours. A few things have arisen at last moment which are detaining us awhile. There has been a lot of bungling in this whole affair, which none of us could help. Now our hand must be reposted and the Mexican consul must personally receive instructions to let us through (from Mexico City) before we can go</p>
(2)
<p>Are expecting call soon from man in Nuevo Laredo who handles such matters. We hope to leave tomorrow. Pray that we are gone when this reaches you. Oh! this war business.</p>
<p>it is a strange, lovely night, with a soft, cool, almost - threatening breeze, a lightly clouded sky, few stars, many bug - noises. Wish you could feel it with us. I've been lying here on the bed dreaming a bit of the Golden Days at Home: how we used to lie out on the porch at night under the glorious star-strewn heavens - you in your hammock, Mama, you on the cot, Daddy, and Hil and I on the floor. I even hear</p>
51q
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>a church bell as we used to there - and I can feel again that old thrill - the Godly Beauty of it all.</p>
<p>Doris sits on the foot of my bed now and says "Tell them the breeze is whispering that we're going to Mexico tomorrow." She also says "Hello.</p>
<p>Awhile ago Sylvia threw cards on the floor, I turned around thrice within the circle of same, then selected a card at random. It was 8 of Diamonds, which Madame Perdu described as signifying "un voyage." Let us pray.</p>
(4)
<p>I left my work at the Hamilton yesterday at 2:00 (early by permission of my very congenial "boss," Christine <unclear>Worshaur</unclear>) Everyone including waitresses, waiters, busboys, and hostesses was <hi rend="underline">lovely</hi> to me, wishing me Bon Voyage and all. Christine said she'd received more compliments on me than any other waitress she'd ever hired - not because I was a good waitress, but because they lived me and I was <hi rend="underline">nice</hi> - my personality it seems. That makes me really happy for I do want to please people - to <hi rend="underline">accomodate</hi> them - and I see no special virtue in desiring such - why <hi rend="underline">not</hi>?</p>
51r
(8)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>"Send me a card from Mexico City, Alicia, and if you ever want a job again, Ill give you one" said Christine. I helped serve at a Graduation Dinner Dance for some 600 Gunnery School Students. Soldiers here last Friday on the Hamilton Roof got extra days pay - and really enjoyed myself too. So many fine young men - and out for as good a time as <unclear/>. They all begged me to stay for the dance even in my uniform - poor kids!</p>
<p>We have had some nice engagements at the Victory Club here. Mr. Cole and</p>
(7)
<p>his wife were lovely to us - gave us full usage of pool, etc., and was otherwise very kind. Complimented us highly on our act - and asked us to break our jump there whenever we came back from Mexico. Nice to meet gentil people.</p>
<p>My many customer friends at the Hamilton have been grand in wishing us a happy trip. One gentleman, who is likewise waiting here for his papers knows French (also Spanish, Portuguese, and Arabic) and has come in several times lately for me to serve him dinner. He is a very distinguished person age - really so - middled aged, handsome,</p>
51s
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>highly cultivated. He has many friend in Mexico City who are of real influence there, and wants us to meet some when he arrives. He wanted to take me out last night, but I felt we were too busy. My Chicago friend has said he may see us there too. So many fine and interesting people. I've learned a lot too through knowing several of different ideas and goals from those of mine. "Live and Learn" I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> believe in - Something protects and tells me just how far to proceed, however. But above all I <hi rend="underline">want</hi> to live, to venture, to <hi rend="underline">learn</hi> - to <hi rend="underline">grow</hi>.</p>
(6)
<p>Such "characters" everywhere here - such distinctive personalities. The code for instance, at the Hamilton: Fredrico,  the patient, singing, eternally-sweating, eternally-gay and sparkling-eyed disher-outer of leg o' lamb, spinach and cottage-fried potatoes; Gonzales, the temperamental creator of salads, waffles, super-deluxe sandwiches, and coctails; the head chef, a really intelligent man, etc. When I said goodbye to same, they were very sorry to see me go - even Gonzales, who, laughed like a little boy, saying "I'm really</p>
51t
(9) (over)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>sorry you're leaving because I thought you might get to like me". Fredrico beamed awhile, then thrust his greasy paw over the serving counter where he daily placed so many hundreds of orders of food and shook my hand <unclear>approush</unclear> -</p>
<p>How are you all? I hope you are much better, Daddy, and I hope you are feeling grand, Mama dear</p>
Loads of Love, <hi rend="underline">dearest</hi> ones
Your Alice
(10)
Next Day - Wed.:
<p>We are leaving! Are at customs now. Will cross to Mexico, eat there and await but at 1:00 A.M. tomorrow morning. Oh! How grateful we are. Write me
c/o American Express
Mexico City D. 7</p>
<p>Rec'd your letters. So glad you are better Daddy and you so happy Mama dear. Yes, I shall see about you and gems, Daddy. How grand for you to come there above.</p>
Loads of Love
Alice
<unclear>Slim Trabulse</unclear>
Plaza Hotel
Laredo