<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
53
Fink Collection 
pm Sept. 10, 1938
92
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON SEP 1938 M.O. 
Mrs. O.F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne
Overland Mo. 

54
Darling Enid: 
So wonderful to hear from you! I don't under stand your saying I had not written for so long, because you owed me a letter when Daddy went up to St Louis, and I never received from you there was the one in which you asked for <unclear/> table, and I immediately answered you yes, but did not hear from you again. How this is fact and truth, both! 
But I am not trying
to prove my point, I only do want a weekly letter from you and a weekly answer will fol-low from me! I do so wish you would put all your Mo-ther love into a baby instead of a cat, no matter how sweet when a man has a steady job - no matter how little he is earning, his wife can af-ford to be a mother. The fi-nest men have not come out of easy street; Babies are not expensive unless they are 

55
poiled. You would not spoil one, neither would Ollie, but you <del>y</del> would find that you have plently to share with one baby. On the other hand if you wait and wait, you may wait too long and then you won't be able to have that which alone makes life truly worth the suffering. However this is only your Mama's view, and you may not think it right - so in any case I do love you my own girlie - and hope you will come soon. 
We have been very busy. Daddy and I had a wonderful day in Spring field Wednesday. We went to the dime store, got a sack of plaster, and two bushels of apples to can. We have one of them put up. It made 19 quarts. 
We have 22 quarts  

56
of grape juice and 62 of tomatoes, and I'm going to make some green tomato chow-chow soon. We will have all our jars full about the middle of next week. I am so thrilled! Also I am happy over our wood and coal - we never had so mu9ch good dry wood and good coal. We believe we can live well on $25.00 per week, including $12 so we send Alice our Groceries are $7oo a week, our milk $1.30 per week. Max washes and I iron. We bake all our bread at home - so we are very lucky and very happy - 
Loads of Love to my Enid 
from Mama 
