<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
61a
<note>Thrilled about news of Eny, Ollie and Nei - and his new sister - to-be. What of Sig and Max - and Joanie and Elaine?</note>
Donato Guerra 14
Departamento
Meuco D. 7
May 15, 1943

Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I am still marvelously happy and thrilled over the news you dear letter brought me. I want to go to some beautiful place to pray and give thanks to God and the Great Spirit for all the Good he has blessed us with. Just what do you do Daddy, and does it please you to do it? Esquire! Hurrah! It certainly sounds like a position which will be both interesting and remunerative. You will probably be better appreciated there than be better appreciated there than you were even on the Post. I want to hear all about your new life and how you like living in Chicago. Have you driven around Lakeshore Drive lately? How is old Lake Michigan these days? By this time Mama, you and Amama must be in Chicago too, so I am writing you there, as well as Daddy. So you are <hi>all</hi> there together - you Daddy and Mama, Amama and my Hilda. How grateful I am to know <unclear/> How <hi>right</hi> and <hi>Good</hi> it all is. Everyone here is extremely thrilled for with you - and me. God Great Spirit keep you happy and strong, and time to bless you, my dearest ones</p>
(2)
<p>You cannot know, and I cannot tell how trilled and grateful and happy I am. Are you all going to get an apartment together? Tell me all about it, oh! please - for I do so want to know what each of you does each minute of the day. More than ever - the same constant love and appreciation for all you are - and are to me, fills my heart and soul, and inspires me in <hi>my</hi> life. Always know that.</p>
<p>You must have been very busy, Mama and I do understand. Now however if you have more time <hi>will</hi> you write me more often? Thanks so for waning through my tangle of Francais. yes, I shall. I am learning Spanish to some extent and shall continue I am learning several Mexican songs too. There are many <hi>very</hi> beautiful ones - some gay songs sad - but all with a Soul. Yes, this country itself has a Soul. Business methods are different - life in general strange to us. No strangers - but I love many more aspects of Mexico than I dislike. Someday <hi>you</hi> shall visit here too wait and see. And I shall show you all around. You cannot know how I've wished for you dear ones to appreciate with me the Beauty I've been seeing - the quaintness, the adventure - the newness, the <hi>Romance</hi></p>
61b
(3)
<p>of this land. As yet we have not seen Mexico ourselves - not <unclear>Aryonlco</unclear> on the seacost nor Guadelajora nor Cuernauaro, nor Taxco, nor the wildness of the Interior. All that I have <hi>great</hi> desire to see - oh we must.</p>
<p>As things look now, we may have Mexico soon unless we decide it is better for the act to decide it is better for the act to stay here longer. There is certainly no lack of work for us for we have many offers, but George thinks it might be better to return, after termination of our "Folies Bergere" contract, to Chicago, via dates in Texas, etc. Our agent there wants to send us to New York soon, and also the money here is not very good for Geroge since agents fees, etc. are doubled (Chicagoan plus Meucan. We shall see what turns up. Now we are doing two shows at the <unclear/> and one at the Club Bremen each night. That brings us extra money and is really quite an easy routine. Tomorrow we are to dance a matinee at each a two mover tres, the Alameda and the Bucared then a matinee and two evening two performano at the Folies Bergere, adn finally, two shows at the Bremen</p>
(4)



