<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
129d
(1)
Wednesday May 21,
1941
9:00 A.M.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I am writing you at last. Have been quite busy you know. (I think that's what one usually says after neglecting to write.) Seriously though we <underline>have</underline> been busy.</p>
<p>Last Thursday after rythmic Jessie, Sylvia and I were asked if we could attend rehearsal at 3:30 the next day, and if we could dance on Sunday night. Of course we were thrilled, so on Friday afternoon we three came for rehearsal with about your</p>
<note>text below is in margin of letter</note>
<p>Mahi - Which is nicer for a two-piece dress (onya owkna onya orfa) rayon silk or a dull rayon crepe or spun rayon?</p>
(2)
<p>others who were to do numbers for the same program, the opening programs of the White Shriners convention at the Jefferson in the Gold Room. Jessie, Sylvia and I did a czarda which we "learned" in rythmic, but which took hard rehearsing to get into shape in three days. It really was nice at the end of that time however. Snippy did two solos, both rythmic type, oen modern, one Spanish, Another girl did antoher Spanish, Barhara did "Tennis" a tow solo she's done often</p>
129e
(3)
<p>in recital, and Sylvia, Betty McCormick and I did "Traviata". The stage was very nice, and our audience quite friendly, so we did quite well! It was loads of fun, and I wasn't excited after I got my make up on. Character work is getting to be real fun, after catching the knack of whatever type of dance it is. The entertainment was over by 8:30 and we all got out picutres taken in costume before leaving with many of the White Shriners. By the way, we gave</p>
(4)
<p>our services but Finagan's costumers furnished our costumes gratis. I think we're going to do all these dances for recital, which is June 9<underline>th</underline>. Do you think you might possibly get to come? Don't worry if you can't - I'd just like to know, that's all.</p>
<p>I spent a night with Millie last wk. - had a very good time. Millie's really swell.</p>
<p>Hil and I must go both out to Eny's soon to see her and to get our summer clothes.</p>
<p>I think I'm staying home from Troy today so I can attend rehearsal</p>
129f
(5)
<p>for "Mignon" tonight. Four of us have an adorable dance on toe in the Wilhelm Tell Ballet all of which we are going to do.</p>
<p>I must get dressed now.</p>
<p>Hil tells me all about the bust of Daddy, Mama. She's really thrilled about it, just as I was when I saw it several wks. ago. It must be truly marvelous now. Be sure to send a picture as soon as you have one taken, won't you.</p>
<p>That was lovely of you to take pictures of Helen, Daddy. I know how she'll</p>
(6)
<p>appreciate that.</p>
<p>Hil told me all about Mme. Follata (sp. ?) It sounds remarkable - all of it!</p>
<p>Sunday night after performance all of us girls went ot Parlmor for ice cream, etc. Then I had Jessie come home with me. Hil was here when we arrived, and we sat up till nearly 12:00 talking about everything. Hil told all about everything at home - how there has never before been a Spring so beautiful, and about all your good time together. The roses brought back marvelous memories too. Isn't it <underline>marvelous</underline> to have such a home? Joan and Elaine sound too dear for words. Also heard about picnic at Dewey Bald and banquet.</p>
Loads of Love to all -
you two, 
Max, Joan, and Elaine






