<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
31
13 
Petri Collection 
After 5 days, return to
...................................
John G. Neihardt 
BRANSON, MO. 
NEWPORT&CAR TH T222 JAN27 1934 R 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE SPECIAL DELIVERY RMS <FIGURE/> AT ANY UNITED STATES POST OFFICE <FIGURE/> 10TENCENTS10
UNITEDSTATESP <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3 
Miss Hilda Neihardt 
767 East Elm Street 
Springfield, Missouri 
SPECIAL DELIVERY 
4
Free claimed at Springfield, Mo. 

32
<unclear/> 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
"Of Making Many Books" 
<figure/> JOHN G. NEIHARDT <figure/> 
BRANSON, MISSOURI 
Today, Present Year. 
Dear Hiddy: 
You see I'm back again. Arrived yesterday P.M. Had a fine time all the way, including 24 hrs in Grinnell. 
Here is something that will interest you especially: I have Tacke's 45 S.A. Colt (nickle plated, <del/> pearl handled) and a Mexican holster and belt with silver buckle & silver medallions and studs all over it - the most gorgeous outfit I ever saw! You'll look fine in it: It's just the thing for you to wear to church! It's too beautiful to offend even a man of God. 
Will enclose the needful mayuna herewith. 
Endless love
Dad 
(over) 

33
Mrs. Markel was right about the disappointment which had just come to me - a very trivial one, but enough to make her statements remarkable. Sunday afternoon (just before you went to church) a man called on me at Aunt Lulu's. I had hoped that he would be worth knowing, & he was a well-meaning flop: I had forgotten this, but it happened. Mediums are an hysterical breed. Their "power" not know when they are rihgt and when wrong. As prophets they are, in general, for less dependable than many who have no such gift. Their phenomena, when proved by the event, merely serve to indicate that consciousness can somehow expand in what we call true and space. But one can lose nothing upon their statements, which too often are only a muttering in a phase of troubled sleep. 
Dad 
Dr. Schmitt came to me through a Minneapolis medium & said he ^only would me to know that he is living. He seemed clearly identified. 