<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
58aa
Donato Guerro 12
Devartmento 16
Abril 9, 1943.
Mexico City.
Dear Daddy and mama,
<p>It has been several days now since I wrote you, so naturally I have much to say. This is so like another world, this Mexico - and a very, very wonderful one too. In fact, the beauty and scope of interest hire are <hi>so</hi> great that one is actually <hi>dazed</hi> at first - it is too much to comprehend all at once. Oh! I do so want you to know this Land of Enchantment.</p>
<p>The weather, first of all, is as near ideal as one can imagine. It is neither hot nor cold at any time - but bracing deliciously cool and invigorating. Although the elevation causes quite a bit of difficulty in breathing when one exercises strenuously, still, it is in the main part very beneficial to one's entire circulatory system (I am told). If feeling is any indication of wellbeing, we are certainly healthy people.</p>
<p>Where did I leave you? (It must have been with news of our first day in Mexico D. 7, so I shall continue from there. As you know, we arrived here on Monday, and spent a most exciting day at Bellas Artes, and in visiting our new apt., as well as Sansborn's Restaurant where all types of people swanky Americans, distinguished looking. Germans, French, and Spanish, and what have you come</p>
(2)
<p>to dine. This is a very charming restaurant founded by a Texan Pharmacist who came with the intention of establishing only a drug store, and, finding that food was often the cause of various disorders of his patients, decided to start a restaurant too. Besides this, Sanborn's now includes a large silvery and curio shop, expensive but really fine. The interior of the cast itself is quite the most beautiful. I've yet seen. made all in Spanish style architecture (balconies, etc.) it has a skylight of colored glass (high - very high up) which sheds a glow over the entire, large floor. The waitresses are all dressed in one type Mexican costume, and the food itself is both Mexican and American. Even Madame Perdu approves of its coffee. You see, here in Mexico we have cafe con leche (with milk), much more frequently than con cremo, and the coffee itself is so highly concentrated that a ratio of 1 cafe to 3 leche is generally required! I personally like it as such. Me gusto mucho!</p>
<p>Tuesday morning, the 6th we arose at 10:00, ate breakfast in the restaurant adjoining our hotel lobby, wrote letters, and went out walking. We went to Sanborn's for lunch (or dinner), then hurried black to the hotel to pack. moved into our lovely new apartment around 4:00, and unpacked, raving a bit about the general aspect of our little mansion as we worked. We have never had anything as nice anywhere - and we have this for 70 pesos apiece per month with gas, electricity, and telephone. That is, roughly, $14 per month. Our food we</p>
58bb
(3)
<p></p>

