<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
69 Neihardt Collection 90
[1939]
Cincinnati, Friday Evening
Oct 13.

Precious Mona:
<p>We are in a camp 13 miles up the Ohio from the city. Reached here about 5 P.M.</p>
<p>The run up from Jackson, Miss, to Richmond, KY. (667 miles) was slick as grease, and we had a good sleep before the <unclear/>. The affair at Jackson was nice - lovely people. Members of the local Poetry Society were there, and it seems they (or someone else) sent flowers for the stage which I didn't notice. It was beastly hot there that night, but before morning a cool wave came, and when we reached Chattanooga, the night seemed near frost. The Richmond school (Eastern Ky State T's Coll.) is very lovely &amp; <unclear/> - wonderful campus. Big auditoruim, practically full. Fine results. Altho the engagement woo for convocation only (10 to 11 A.M.) I was asked to an English class (11 to 12) and went. Fine time, and the usual affectionate feeling at the end. We like the folks a lot. They had us out for dinner at</p>
91
<p>the hotel, &amp; we all had a bully confab. The steak was leather - sole leather! But the talk was good.</p>
<p>Sig played as usual both places, with the usual results. Everybody seemed happy, including us.</p>
<p>Gosh! We <underline>did</underline> miss letters at Richmond. Had looked forward to hearing from home; but we can wait until Tuesday at South Bend. Sig did get a card. But we aren't sore at all!! We think you are all nice girls.</p>
<p>Tell Jaime that when Gaki gets back, we'll go around and gather up all the dishes from under the beds &amp; sofas and in the ashpile &amp; in the sink, and we'll have a good dish washing. She can do the wiping.</p>
<p>Looks as tho' we'd repeat in some or most of there places. Richmond might have we for several days, it seemed from their talk. We'll, I do like you people - like to tell them things. They seem so eager &amp; so willing to grasp at new ideas. I never talk to a bunch of them but I grow to love them very quickly.</p>
<p>Last of my paper.</p>
Endless love to you &amp; the others
Jno. Dad.
<note>sentence below are in margin of letter</note>
<p>Have Max tell you how beautiful eastern Kentucky is. Golly! And <underline>horses</underline>! O my!!</p>