<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
296 Fink Collection 26
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
JUL31
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis
County
27
Wednesday
Darling Enid and Ollie:
<p>You cannot know how often I think of you dear ones - and always with a grateful, happy feeling - because you are fulfilling each other and experiencing the blessing of a <underline>real</underline> marriage. May you continue to be so really truly happy and contented, only <underline>more</underline> so! I Know you will have a marvelous time with your sweet baby when it finally gets here! You have waited a long time Enid as you say - but that is so of all of us Mothers - We wait for our baby and then we wait some more</p>
28
2
<p>for one thing or another connected with it - and then all of a sudden our hair is snow white and we <unclear/> the same sweet story taking its course with our children and childrens' children - and after all it is a very wonderful and good experience! -</p>
<p>So you want us with you when you go to the Hospital - and we hope to be there - We ought to hear from Mitchel - He has gotten Daddy to sign a contract from September on - so if we hear - we must go, of course but we have not heard anything for so long that is does not at all look good. Certainly we cannot go to California with no assurance of any</p>
27
3
<p>sort. We want you to tell us when <underline>you want</underline> us to come to your home. We do not want to "visit" but we do want to come when we can be of use. I Know that our being there while you are still "expecting" will only make things harder for you Enid, so just call us when you want us and we will arrive very shortly after.</p>
<p>Ollie dear, your birthday making you 41 is near at hand, and I want to wish you many happy returns of the day.</p>
<p>Alice has a birthday soon now too. I want</p>
28
4
<p>to get a big cake to her.</p>
<p>I have been painting the floor in the front room a "faun" color and it makes it so lovely. Then I painted the guestroom floor <underline>white</underline> and it is very clean and nice <sic>loooking</sic> with the white and green walls.</p>
<p>Maxie wants to paint the floor in the big back room upstairs a pale blue shade and also the linoleum. I hope she does so! --</p>
<p>I just finished the ironing. Max washed yesterday.</p>
<p>Enid I certainly would love that set you spoke of giving me that you had on your big chair - I did not say anything as I un</p>
29
<p>derstood you were sendign it. I want to fix up some new curtains for our upstairs so badly - you Know the way I mean without buying any thing! I don't Know just how I'll accomplish it this time!</p>
<p>The coffee table piece and Dad's bust both are cast, (not yet out of the molds) in white cement and fine sand - they should be lovely. I now am finishing Frankie's <unclear/>.</p>
<p>We all are well and have had some splendid rains lately!</p>
Loads of Love to you all three from 
Mama - Mother.