<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
150 Fink Collection October 22, 1939
111
Neihardt
Branson,
Mo.

<stamp>BRANSON OCT 23 3 -PM 1939 M.O.</stamp>
Mrs. O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson,
Overlan,
Mo.
St Louis
County.
112
Branson
Sunday Oct. 22nd
My dear, dear Enid:
<p>So this, your birthday is also the beginning of another precious life behind the scenes of this stage we know so little about! My arms already enfold that priceless <unclear>infaut</unclear> in immaginary hugs and I am showering Kisses all over it's dear little face and body! It had better be, because few babies can have been so lovingly expected as this one, by all concerned!</p>
<p>Today you are having Hilda and Alice and I wonder how it will seem for you not to be doing the cooking! Great, I'm <unclear/> I would like to be with you in fact on this occasion, and my heartiest good wishes are travelling you words for this birthday and for a great many more of them, surrounded by dear ones that truly appreciate and</p>
113
<p><unclear/> you.</p>
<p>Ollie certainly got character into his P.S. No.2! Tell him the reconciled sage look his face, adn the little down-turn to the corners of <underline>your</underline> mouth while the master of the house bawled bravely, is simply a scream! Max and I laughed and laughed over it - and even Joanie enjoyed and asked for the picture over and over again. She recognized the diapers!!!</p>
<p>I know:"how "your" buzy finers weave with fate" - Enid dear- for you are a mother like your own mother, who wants to make all possible lovely things for her baby. There were few mothers now adays who are not glad to <underline>buy</underline> every thing, few who <underline>want</underline> to work for the litte stranger! The crocheted quilt you made for Joanie is such a master piece that Max wants you</p>
114
<p>to use for <underline>your</underline> baby rather than go to so much work once more. The little hat outfit is the cutest thing I ever saw on a child of Joanie's age, and fits and suits her to perfection. They have gone to town this afternoon while I am home with Baby Laine who is asleep, and I've done all the dishes and cleaned up the Kitchen, then modeled a bit and now am enjoying this chat with you. Please tell Ollie that I promise to say no word of gratitude for his lovely plan to take me down here after my visit up there - Indeed I <underline>would love</underline> that - and here with say so for the last and only time!! I want to come to you as soon as Sig returns. May be he will take me to Springfield, maybe I'll leave here before he arrives but <underline>I'd</underline> rather see him first. Then I'll be so happy to stay with you and get some necesary sewing done for myself and Alice and Hilda. But I</p>
115
<p>am a bit worried about Daddy. He has been having Fluey spells, and <underline>if</underline> things are so that I <underline>could</underline> be with him most of the 3 weeks he is at Knox College, I want to do that, and maybe I could make him a bit mroe comfortable than he would otherwise be. I have written to ask him.</p>
<p>Early in November I should arrive at your Home, if things continue to appear as they now do. Then I will either remain with you, or go on to Knox College. In any case however, we want you to plan to take the round about trip you mention down to Branson, staying here at Home as long as you wish, the longer the better, and I will be back as soon as Daddy leaves Knox for the Western trip.</p>
<p>I hear my baby, and must-hasten to pick her up before she "pe pes!"</p>
Love and always more love to my darling Enid and to her Man
from Mom
