<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
152 Finn Collection 94
May 26, 1939
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
MAY 26
3 --PM
1939
MO
UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3
Mrs O.F.Fink
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, Mo.
St Louis County
95
May 26th 39.
Dearest Enid and Ollie
<p>You surely did a great deal for Mom on her birthday - for I felt the exquisite bag you had made for me was a marvelous gift, and here comes a beautiful house coat with your names added to Hilda's and Alice's.</p>
<p>I have had a marvelous birthday _ Everything but the weather was perfect. Sig and Max made a marvelous birthday cake with coffee butter icing and pink lettering also in butter icing with Mom, Mona. Nannie on top and 5 and 5 candles = 10!</p>
<p>It was all in shades of rosey cream</p>
96
2
<p>Inside was a delicious white cake with Banana filling - really a masterpiece!</p>
<p>It has been raining so hard that our babies could not play out, which make things rather strennous for the grown ups, especially when there are so many letters that have to be written.</p>
<p>Daddy is very busy with a beautiful graduation present for Alice. Enid dear, it is just like you to have saved a copy of Hildas' graduation speech - and I am hoping Alice will repeat it word for word.</p>
<p>Amama is now at 39 Prospect Terrace Cortland, NY. </p>
97
3
<p>she remembered my birthday with chocolate mints.</p>
<p>Aunt Lu also remembered me._ We have your baby dresses all safe Enid, for you someday - Max would not send them to Marie - but what she did send would not be the thing for a gift outside the family. I will write the young folks from when we received an announcement - Thanks for the address.</p>
<p>I understand your feeling Fritz should got to a camp - and it will be fine for him - and also for his mother to get some Christian science - but that will of couse take him far away from you inwardly, maybe it is best.</p>
98
4
<p>so but we would be glad to have him here this Summer.</p>
<p>Your place must be <underline>so</underline> lovely now! I hope I can send you the money soon for a 1/2 gallon of white enamel, for we need it and it costs 3 times as much here. Please let me know before you come so that I can do that in time. Please also bring all those things I left at Hildas' for I do not see us coming to St. Louis very soon. I hope I am not imposing on you too much and I do not want you to be overloaded, but aside from the violin. I believe you can get everything in your rumble seat - and the violin you could just keep at your Home for me. Hilda said something</p>
99
5
<p>about leaving her present apartment and I think she is wise not to keep is during the summer, as it is a big expense for only one. I told her I though you would allow her to store her things at your Home if she rented a room maybe or boarded somewhere.</p>
<p>I'd give a lot to see Alice graduate. I did not see Hilda in Nebr. and I did so enjoy your graduation form Kirkwood High Enid. You were the pretiest girl of them all!</p>
<p>Daddy reads at Aberdeen S. Dak. on the 15th.</p>
<p>I am daily expecting Mrs. Leonard, and my $50,00 from Mr Leonard in Kansas City.</p>
100
6
<p>I had intended sending it to Hilda but she wants me to spend it here, and so I'll be <underline>very</underline> happy to give it to Daddy.</p>
<p>A letter from Idwald Jones asking Daddy for a 1500 word story of Jed Smith came yesterday - sounds very interesting! I believe it could be the beginning of a change. But in any case it is good for us to keep our Home here and I don't feel it would be amiss for you to try getting info Springfield, because I don't see us selling here.</p>
<p>Daddy and I have been noticing that the lack of order in</p>
101
<p>that Springfield paper is outlandish. I have never "spilled the beans" about your plan to try the Springfield Paper - and I hope with all my heart that you <underline>do</underline>. I cannot see Daddy ever satisfied <underline>any</underline> where- and I think he will be very happy moving about, and there returning here from time to time.</p>
<p>You will think Mom is surely showing her 55 years by this rambling letter - but I have had difficulty in getting quiet.</p>
<p>I am still helping Mrs Shahan, but not so long every day. She is much better.</p>
102
Loving you endlessly
Always Your ownly
Mom_Mother
<p>The Wisteria hangs thick - the Red Rose is gorgeous - and my baby Zinnias are getting big - also the nasturtiums.</p>
<p>Wish you could come soon!</p>