<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
179 Fink Collection 13
Neihardt 
Branson,
Mo.
BRANSON
APR 15
3 --PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F. Fink
Miss Alice Neihardt
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
St. Louis County Mo.
14
April 15th 40.
Dearest Girls:
<p>Your good letter, Enid, was so very welcome dear. I Know just what you mean about the flower-children - and you certainly have a very big family of them. You will have to be fair to each one of them, and sometimes that is hard!!</p>
<p>I have not so many babies. I am going to try to work out the Indians Garden idea from teh stand point of color and maybe Hilda's friend Max will be interested enough in this unique scheme to come down over the weekend and visit it and thereby us! It seems he writes about American Gardens abroad and I do believe ours is the <underline>real American</underline> one!</p>
<p>Alice darling, I do so hope you are not unduly worried or disguisted with</p>
15
<p>my suggestion that you try to find work for Saturdays. I know of very good and capable girls who have done this sort of thing, making them happier for the feeling it has given them - to say nothing of the real help.</p>
<p>Hilda is so much better now - she has not been able to sing yet, but she has rested a great deal - eats well now, and feels much better too. I have finished three of her dresses completely as well as one under-dress. I have still the white chiffon <underline>over</underline> dress and one business dress to finsih. Although they too are well along to accomplish, as well as Max's help for she has done all the meal getting etc to make me free to "sit" and sew. Hilda has been riding too since C.P. brought his horsey and lets him graze in our wonderful pasture all the time. He said nice things about your caring so well for him last year. - Now Alice</p>
16
<p>will you please answer this question: Can you use a Spring coat made of that bug blue suit coat of Hildas? And if so will you please send me the skirt at once? I will need it to use in making an up to date coat. If however you like the <strike>co</strike> skirt and are wearing it, then Keep it and I'll make you soemthing else. Enid is so good to help you with your Spring clothes. but I want to do something too for you, as I believe the same patterns will do for you that I am using for Hilda. I have on especially that requires no changes. So send me the information.</p>
<p>I ask you for as well as your <underline>waist</underline> measurement - that is all I'll need. Please tell me what Enid and you are making, so that I will not duplicate</p>
17
<p>them.</p>
<p>I am so eager for a letter from you Alice. I am looking forward to your vacation here in August and believe C.P. will have his horse here all Summer as he hsa no pasture for him.</p>
<p>We had a terrible freeze, that Killed <underline>all</underline> my lovely Morning Glories and my "special" red nasturtiums - but not my Hollyhocks, thank Goodness, which I had planted out the day before, and covered with glass jars.</p>
<p>Our roses were <underline>not</underline> Killed either nor most of the pears and shrubs.</p>
<p>So now <sic>Im</sic> going to get new seeds to make up for the losses!</p>
Loads of Love to you both and also to Ollie
from you devoted
Mama-Mother