<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
113
e. April 23, 1941
Wed. 4-what
Dear Folks--
<p>The difficulty about writing letters is that there never seems much to sayandit usually takes about six pages to say it. There is an advantage in the period of holidays, for then one can say merry christams and what do you expect sants claus to bring, or a firecracker went off x in the backhouse just as one sat down and a spanked baby's has nothing on ours. But there seems a terrible dearth of subject matter around spring fever time, especially when the bugs manage to get in despite the screens, xx and also despite a tight collar. Strange xx is it not that of the 4,875,329 square inches of space in the room they all find the one by three inch opening in the top of a shirt. Amazing accuracy. Fifth columnists, no doubt.</p>
<p>We did have the back of the place ploughed. It was a trifle damp, and you should have seen the fish jumping to get the worms as they were turned up. However, I think the soil will work out all right, although we did have some trouble with the mules. The old man who did the work brought along a mule colt--now that is a phenomenom, believe itor not--it didn't occur to me just now that there must have been something illegitimate or even immoral about a mule having a colt, I shall have to look into it further--but anyhow, the colt disappeared during the course of the soil tilling, and so far no trace has been found except a deep depression. We filled it with manure, and hope xx thereby the colt will grow and the mystery will be solved. I doubt it.</p>
<p>Enid says it is getting on her nerves, the day long xxx chatter of Mona-John, but I think she should take some baking soda to keep her stomach from rumbling.</p>
<p>Enid had a xxx baking binge today, and made 14 loaves of bread, three <sic>stollen</sic>, and 103 rolls. She gave some to the Harrisons, and together we ate one and one half dozen for supper, but the rest will require a bit of time to solve. One reason being that Enid has become somewhat addicted to meat and potatoes. I had thought to put in only a small patch of potatoes, but under the circumstances think I will plant most of the after half of the lot with them. I suppose it does not hurt her, but it does seem to me that three and one half pounds of steak for a meal is <sic>carrving</sic> a liking too far.</p>
<p>Our tulips are coming along nicely, and one is blooming. It is white. We hve not yet decided whether the original cream color was due to a friendly visit by a dog, which was washed out by rain, or whether age is causing the paleness. There are several wine and red buds--tulips, not trees. But our wisteria is barely showing leaves, and gives no indication that there will be flowers this exxxx year. Isn't it a bit unusual for them to bxxx bloom in April? I have seen none elsewhere, and had the impression they came along in June. Our spires is out, and so was xxx Enid until she opened a seam in her dresses. General spring budding, no doubt.</p>
<p>We have radishes up, also dahlias in a box, while the nasturtiums are outside, transplanted and doing nicely. Allyssumm also is about to bloom. Our iris have large buds, but it will be a week or so before they begin to open. And many of them will be along later. Our dwarf iris is finished blooming, and was very attractive, despite having been planted only last fall. We acquired some additional canna from my brother, axx who also brought over some more glad bulbs. Altogether we now have more than 80 glads, together with about x 100 wee small seedx bulbs, which I hope to bring to maturity this summer. Among the others are some very large ones, that should make beautiful flowers. As wtih the tulips, the Glads are good stock, for Irwin gets themxx for display purposes, and picks the colors carefully.</p>
<p>The roses in front, 15 plants, are very healthy and fine looking, adn we should have quite a few flowers this year. We now have four Gruss an Teplitz, from a single bush my brother gave us a year ago last fall. I managed to divide it twice, and each division xxx has prospered. I am going to try layering some of the radiance thsi spring, as we have several beautiful plants--and they have lovely flowers--which I would liek to increase. We bought eight additional bushes from Grand Leader, and will buy nothing more there. They are doing all right, in the back, but with about three exceptions, were cuttings instead of budded stock. All that we have bought from Famous has been budded stock.</p>
<p>The wee cherry tree that we bought forx xx 12 1/2 cents last spring is loaded with blossoms. Apples are about to bloom, and a huge army of cuculio is poised ready for the march at the foot of the plum tree. Early each morning we hear them going throu the manuel of arms, and drilling, ready for the xx blitzkreig as son as the petals fall and the small plume appears. However, as soon as Blitzkreig Adolf comes out of hibernation in the basement, we shall set him on the foe, and that will be anx end of them.</p>
<p>We have out xxxxxxx iris in front of the hedge, to grow into a bank of them. Mr. Tacke had two large boxes of purple, which he had dug to give his more room, and of course we never refuse flowers. Snapdragon and hollyhocks are coming up from seed--the hollyhock you sent-- in the attic, and will go in the rear. We also have zinnia coming up, but have still to get marigold seed planted. Altho some droppings--seed, not horse-- are coming up where the beds were last year. By the time you get up here in May, we <sic>shouldhave</sic> quite a few flowers already xxx in bloom, and many more well under way to bloom in June. I think <sic>theplace</sic> will look very attractive this year, altho not so well as I should like. There are so many things to be done, and neither immediate time nor money to do it. So the things must necessarily be done gradually.</p>
<p>It is really extremely good of you to send the encyclopedia, and I hope that does not deprive you of its use. I shall read it with interest and profit.</p>
<p>It is grand that Dad has finished Jed, but I can understand that he would be lost somewhat now. However, it should gradually make him let down, and enjoy the sense of fulfillment that he should, after all he has accomplished.</p>
<p>A war in the Balkans is rumored. But no doubt the English will stop it in a hurry.</p>
With much love
Ollie