<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection [Dec. 12? 1923] 54
[or Dec. 12, 1923]
Part of a letter from my mother, telling about her unveiling of my portrait in the Omaha Park. Library 

55
lovely to me, But I am getting ahead of my story. Mr. Masters much the presentation speech a rattling good one you would say to the point showing the significance of your work and the important part you will take in future. The important place you were taking now <unclear/> and at the age of 42. It was <unclear/> John was. Shot well a mmeber of the Library board accepted the portrait on behalf of the Library board and the public a neat concisive gracious talk. Then the Judges as master of the misling at whose side I had been sitting facing the crowd <unclear/> the ther speeches arose and made his <unclear/> that I have told you about and in the sweetest most tender <unclear/> introduce Mr. It is the finest time we all my life that I had been cheered I just bowed knowing so will that <del/> 

56
<unclear/> cheering me because they loved <unclear/> on John. It was quite enough and I was more than satisfied my cup could hold no more, after I was introduced I turned to the portrait untied the string as I had been instructed by the judge, gave a little pull to force it from the top and lifted the veil! You should have heard the cheers it was <unclear/> and gratifying. The ceramic <unclear/> there and they began to call for one to come around to the crowd. went with the judge and met people card shook hands until I wondered if they had not made a mistake. Mr. & Mrs.  <unclear/> invited me to dinner, Mrs. Shotwell to <del>well</del> well I dont' know how many invitations I had to dinner. Two old ladies came to me and invited me to the old Settlers Banquet and some other entertainment with it next Thursday night 

57
I know you will be disgusted when I tell you I declined them all. I am sure as I think of it now that they were not in farvoubly impressed with me or disgusted as many said when you come back to Omaha again we want you are have a claim or you there must have been an hours upstream after the <unclear/>. George was up from Fremont. It was nice to see how and I was so glad he could see the ovation you portrait received I think it <unclear/> him so much that he could hardly talk - I intruded I him to all that I could then I had to leave him. Mr. and Mrs. Bailey were so lovely <del/> stayed with him and tried to make him feel comfortable. the Baileys have been to lovely. Bailey said <unclear/> 

58
<unclear/> mother was the nearest they expected to get to fame. Every one would say we heard your son and to hear him and to know him is to love him I can't begin to tell you all the lovely things that were said about your work. The Longs are lovely Mrs. <unclear/> is the dearest woman. Mona dear I wish you could know her. she wants to know you
says she feels guilty <del> when she</del> likes Mr Neihardt so much and doesn't know you. I go back to Baileys this morning Mr. B. - is coming after me. Judge said I must call on Wallace the Baileys will take me this afternoon he was note at the ceremonies I must tell him he did every thing but make your talk Juddge said well he 
