<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
88 Neihardt Collection 3
<p>I sent the prayer to the Ladies "Home Journal". Be sure to tell me what you hear from them!</p>
Thursday eve.
January 1942
e. 8 or 15
Dearest Mama and Daddy!
<p>thanks so very much for your dear, dear letters. It makes me feel greatly relieved to get them.</p>
<p>I was not very ill and am now nearly all right again. I went back to work <strike/> tuesday. But, naturally, I am pleased you were think about me. It would be a joy to be ill at home.</p>
<p>Your idea of the cow and chickens is surely a real one now' and it will become more so. there is no doubt of that. Price are already sky-high and no doubt scarcity will set in later. Some say famine.</p>
<p>We are all one family, which makes it nicer and safer for us all. I never thought I could consider marrying someone who would take me away from our family, for it is more than the ordinary bond which keeps us together. Now Albert seems finer all the time to me and dearer - and as you know, his one desire is to be a part of our family. And since his ideas</p>
(over)
4
<p>are such that it is <underline>possible</underline> for <underline>me</underline> to mary him, I really have decided that I want to. You know perhps better than I that I never could or would submit to an ordinary peron's idea of a life.</p>
<p>Albert &amp; I both want to have a proper wedding <underline>with meaning</underline>, and so we leave it up to you. If it were a matter for just running away for a meaningless ceremony - then it would, so we think, be just nothing at all. We both think the usual church ceremony practically cold and without meaning. I though his sisters' weddings were almost horrible - to me, of course.</p>
-
-
<p>Albert was beginning to write his Spanish lesson the other evening at home, when his pencil was forced to the papaer, and he had to spend the rest of the evening writing the long tale which I enclose. I think it most remarkable and Albert <underline>could</underline> hardly make up such a thing. That is out of the</p>
5
2
<p>question entirely, for he was not even <underline>thinking</underline> of doing any "automatic writing". Please read the thing and then return it to me, will you?</p>
<p>Albert says he never was so excited over anything as he is over the idea of the all-Neihardt programs.</p>
-
-
<p>Sig and Max are goig to Miller's studio now to practice and write letters. I should go, but I'm retiring instead.</p>
Endless love to you both as ever,
Hilda
<p>We did not think we wanted to send the part about Mr. Miller, since it is not very nice. But you will not mind that, since it can't be serparte from the other.</p>
-
-
<p>I wonder about the page of questions from Webster's! Many things will happen now.</p>
-
-
<p>It is now Friday morning. this could not be mailed before. Albert called last evening and</p>
6
<p>said that he does want me to send the writing to you. He knows it is mixed up more or less, but he would like to hear what you say. Yesterday afternoon at his desk he had nothing much to do, so he tried it here. the same thing came through, saying in part:
"go to your lessons this evening. Spanish and Math will open great opportunities to you after the war. Then go home and concentrate a litte, and I will come to you. Remember -" and then the same signature and notes. It seems he is supposed to get a plan for the program. You will remember that basing a program on anything but the lyrics is not an idea we had spoken of.</p>
-
-
<p>After my lesson this evening I am going to the studio to help Maxine write letters. Tomorrow we are going to have a little party for Maxie.</p>
<p>I am very sorry, I left such a blank space in our correspondence, but shall do better now. I am feeling <underline>fine</underline> today.</p>
Much, much love to you both,
Hilda