<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
169
June 30, '41
Dear Mother and Dad--
<p>The jewelry arrived today, and all of it is unbelievably lovely. I have no doubt teh wub will be as fascinated with the rose quartz as I was with the stick pin, and will be reading for it constantly--incidentally it is now but two months away. The pin is a perfect piece of workmanship wxx with perfect material, adn I am more than delighted with it. I shall wear it regularly, except on hot days, for then I take off my tie at the office, and would be afraid to leave it even in my desk unguarded. But when ties become comfortable, I shall have the pin to match the ring always. The head, from the hair dress, is Roman, which of course you know far better than I, so that the combination with the sard is grand. And I am always taken with jade. At first, in a dim light, I saw at the left a second head, worked into the hair--an older man, curley haired and bearded, with heavy brows and chin resting on chest. However, under a bright light the impression disappears. Is there something of the sort there, or did I x merely imagine that? The ring for Enid is lovely, and I think that much as she liked the previous ivory, she likes this better. there must have been a lot of work involved, and we wish we could return in some way the pleasure we get from teh beauties. The quartz droplets and pendant look as if they grew that way, they are so perfect in form, so well matched and so finished.</p>
<p>Mother did a beautiful job on the bust, tho I do look forward to seeing it in the "flesh" rather than just a photo, for I like to feel the contours x with my finger tips as well as merely look at it. I am glad you all feel that it is her best work---but I hesitate to say that for that implies that what she has done before is not as good as it might be. With which I disagree. When the photos arrived, with the comment of how it was so much better x of dad than past xxxxx work, I pointed out to Enid how good a likeness was obtained in the heavy relief profile we keep on this desk, and in the bust of the two of you together--so that comparisons seem unnecessary. The new bust "got" Dad perfectly. I think Mother has done that every time. She ahs now done another excellent piece of work, of which she can be <sic>thoroly</sic> proud--to add to a series of excellent creations. But--when a sculptor turns a child's figure which, when placed in a yard, makes those entering think a xxxxx living child is before them, should she say this is the xxx best thing I have done of a later work--or feel that a <sic>numberof</sic> her creations are the best? Dad's bust is better xxxx than that of Mr. Good not because of the workmanship, because the workmanship in both is all to be desired, but because it is a bust of Dad. I think Mother should be thoroughly conceited about everything she has done. Period. If you get what I mean.</p>
<p>The weather here has been a bit chilly of late. Went down to 97.9 degrees today, and we thought of getting out the winter clothes.</p>
<p>The place must be lovely, with canna, glads adn other flowers in bloom. We are at an intermediate stage, and at times I get rather discouraged at xxx the lack of flowers. Canna and glads are getting ready to bloom, but dry weather has made thing look bare. Ramblers are thru, and the roses are at the intermediate stage of filling out buds. Enid has <sic>sveral</sic> yellow roses on a bowl, but they are few. Gailardia and coreposis, escholtzia, cornflowers, shastas, petunias, and marigolds are in bloom-- but all in all things look bare. However, Enid has canned seven quarts of beans, and a rain Saturday should bring along large numbers of them this week end. We have several acorn squash almost large enough to pick. And planted another patch of beans Saturday. Turnips doing poorly, but kolrabi,</p>
over
<p>broccoli, tomatoes, are promising, and we may have some carrots. There are a great many apples and peaches on our trees.</p>
<p>Enid has put up quite a lot of strawverry, raspberry jelly.</p>
<p>Enid has been feeling pretty well, considering the heat, which affectx her surprisingly little. I think it will be a girl--blonde, curley, round faced, gray blue eyes.</p>
<p>I can't think of much else that Enid would not have told you--you no doubt heard that England and U.S. have indignantly refused to help xx the dirty Bolskeviks fight the Nazis, and are planning to sail off xx to south africa to get away from it all. Events have overwhelmed xxxx them, as the ant said when he was caught under the south end of a cow at the wrong time.</p>
<p>It was grand beyond words to get the trinkets, and we shall enjoy and cherish them.</p>
<p>Love to all, and a <sic>smavk</sic> fo rthe Wubs down there.</p>
Ollie.