<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
165 Fink Collection 38
inc. in Jan 15, 1940
Monday noon
Dearest Eny &amp; Ol;
<p>Thanks for your swell letter. This one is firstly to wish you a happy anniversary and many more of 'em and secondly to answer your lastest.</p>
<p>I iam just being up and around from a severe attack (sp?) of the flu. I had been up just one day where the folks came home. Believe me - I'm darn glad to be over it for I never hurt so bad all over my body as I did this time. I was awful glad to see Mom for she takes hold so fast and I've been too shaky and weak to do the work. Joan had her first with a rising ni her ear adn then Elaine had a cold - then Sig took a severe case of bronchitis from which he semmed to recover rapidly - then I got <unclear/>. If it hadn't been for Mom Daisy I don't kow what I would have done. She came up everyday morning and took over for the day. Joan learned to undress herself &amp; baby 'Laine too and dress herself. But 'Laines harness'es are too complicated and she gave up. But they were so good.</p>
<p>Mom &amp; Dad drove in Sat. evening. This was the first snow they had struck - and did it snow last week?!! Our top was over 10 inches and it stayed on for days. You know how unusual that is.</p>
39
<p>Sig got a new Hamilton grand 5'2" in walnut. They gave him artist discount because they Knew he was touring around with Dad. It amounted to $265. So he got a good deal with payments running $12 monthly. the total balance was over $400 to pay out. But its worth it for he's needed one so long. It has a lifetime - no - a 20 yr. guarantee. So that makes us safe. Wish you could see it we're really proud of it. Has a beautiful tone.</p>
<p>I have been learning how to Knit and have struck various obstacles. I'll not enumerate but I wish I had you around to give me some tips.</p>
<p>I'll close now for its time to mail letters. Here's lots of love to you and Ol. Tell Ol I got a Kick out of some of the funny letters he wrote the folks about you triming Alice for her New Years Date! I nearly died. I could just see you drinking gin "orange blossoms" out of a quart stew pace!! Wish I could write like that - its so darn ridiculuous.</p>
<p>Love to Alice and tell her I'd be so happy to hear from her even in Mom's letters. Love to Hilda when you see her too.</p>
Max, &amp; Sig.