<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
53
24 Piper Collection Nov. 11, 1924 
27 Linwood Ave
Buffalo N.Y. 
BUFFALO N.Y. 5 1924 STA.C
UNITED STATES POSTAGE <FIGURE/> JEFFERSON 2CENTS2
Miss Mildred Piper 
<del>809 North Hastings Ave</del>
Hastings
Nebraska 

54
276 Linwood Ave 
Buffalo N.Y.
Nov. 16-1924
My Dear little girl;
I would not flame you if you just ignored this letter altogether, But I hope to goodness you don't, you will see by the above address that I am away off up here and you will guess why since you knew that Grace had come to Buffalo to attend School of Library science, Did I tell you that last June she graduated from the Library course and had a position in the Buffalo Public Library before she had finished so now she has a good position <del>in the</del> and then her insistence I am here with her to spend the winter, or until March 1st <del/> having reviled my home furnished until then. I think I will go by way of Mineapolis home and see Lulu. I want so much to see mother again she is living now with 

55
my sister in Grinnell Iowa. Grace and I are doing light house keeping, we have quite a large Room that serves as bed-room and living room and a good sized room that is both. Kitchen and dining room, with hot and cold water gas range the rooms are both heated, and we have the privilege of doing our own washing and ironing in the basement which is fitted out with stationary Tubes with hot and cold water and a drying room. So you see I am being very much of a lady Grace and I have been to see Niagara Falls. to-East Aurora, the town that Elbert Hubbard made famous with his wonderful Roy Croft shops. We were thru them and they are wonderful and I did so want to get somethings while there but <unclear/> the prices are prohibitive at least to me. Such wonderful hammered brass and copper, tooled leather carved wood metal things of various kinds, beauti-hand carved furniture fancy bound books. And oh so many other things, I can't mention them all, but I came away with a dozen post cards, we have been to some