<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
719 Fink Collection 71
[May 29, 1940]
Wednesday
Dearest ollie and Enid
<p>You were all about me, and very, very close on my birthday, for I wore the dress you made for the "day" and felt wonderfully lucky to have it.</p>
<p>You must know that we here appreciate your assistance - and also that we have no intentions of letting Max and the Wubs leave here until Sigurd is grad and ready to take care of them. The Piano was a bit premature <strike>but</strike> and Daddy knew that, but the fact that Hilda needed a Piano and that Sig needed to practice with her</p>
72
<p>had a lot to do with the seeming hurry. Too bad they now cannot use it.</p>
<p>I say Go to H--- to people who prefer Jazz on a Radio from morning till night to a few hours good practising - Such a state of affairs could not be guessed at by anyone who grew up in Germany, Meaning myself!---</p>
<p>Anyway the Piano is nearer where Sig will want it than if he had left it here - and it was a most difficult job to pack and suspend in the box, one Daddy could not have figured out.-- I am en</p>
73
<p>joying gorgeous Paul Scarlets now framing the Pool - baby - also a veritable profusion of sweet scented vines and shrubs to say nothing of the Iris.</p>
<p>Have you any Siberian Irises? I'd like to bring you some if you haven't. Also a specially beautiful Petunia.</p>
<p>Your Cannas are up about 2/3 of a foot high, although they did not all come up. The Holly hocks are grand and Joanie picked our first nasturtium this morning! Daddy has trimmed up all our shrubs and put order into the Wisteria vines cutting them back a lot</p>
74
<p>I have a new start in the Chinese blue Wisteria which I'd love to bring you; do you want it, dearies?</p>
<p>The pattern you sent me for Alice's costume is swell - I hope to make a second costume for her soon.</p>
<p>I so often look at your picture with the one of your home I fastened into it - and wich I might drop over.</p>
<p>I am so sorry Daddy and I cannot be present at Alice's recital. Hope you can and will go.</p>
<p>Daddy and I are going to Pa together for 2 lectures there which should bring</p>
75
<p>us enough money to pay for going__</p>
<p>We all are well although Daddy is not as well as I'd like him to be.</p>
Loving you so much 
Always your
grateful and devoted
Mama-
Mother.