<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
187 Fink Collection 99
BRANSON. 
JUN14
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis County
100
Thursday.
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your good letter about Alice's recital made us glad! We laughed about the man with the lovely voice - Indeed you have a beautiful, sympathy - overflowing voice on the Telephone Ollie - I have remarked abou tit to you Enid, haven't I?</p>
<p>I suppose Alice will get better parts next year - also I do believe that eventually it will be</p>
101
2
<p>a man teacher who will give her preference. I have often wondered about this = Tall women liek themselves but men all prefer little women! So women admire Miss Powel - but men - I have never heard one express admiration fo rher. Fortunate said that Alice had exactly the right propartions for a dancer. After all this is a Man's World, and I say little women are in luck on and off of the stage!</p>
<p>Thank you both for going - I now feel I <underline>was</underline> foolish to suffer so over not seeing Alice</p>
102
3
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>Daddy was right when he said it was not an important event in Alice's career.</p>
<p>We have made an other change in our immediate plans. We are going to Kirkwille which is North West of St Louis - then straight North East to Penn. then South to the second engagement in that State, and then around in that State, adn then around the 10th of July straight West to St Louis, where we hope</p>
103
4
<p>you will want us for several days visit. We then want Daddy to meet with Mr Dilliard as he promised to do - and also we want to bring Alice home with us for a good vacation adn for me to make her some clothers. That is as far ahead as we now can see.</p>
<p>Daddy and I are looking forward to this trip adn we will travel every after noon only, write every morning - so we should not interfere with Jed Smith at all.</p>
<p>Under separate cover I am sending you two patterns I used</p>
104
5
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>for Hilda, Enid dear. I believe you may want to use them if you don't find the other one you spoke of.</p>
<p>I have just finished another attractive dress for Max adn have helped her make over another one of mien with the navy blue net coat - which she likes so much. Then I made another dress for Baby 'Laine.</p>
<p>The Wubs have new sandals and everything they need for this Summer. I don't be</p>
105
6
<p>lieve it will be hard for them to be here while we are gone, as it is "Home" and a wonderful place to play in. -Daddy has had all the weeds cut in the pasture. He himself has gone to all Kinds of work to make the place look its very best, adn I'll have another mowing done, which means no more till we return - as this now will be dry weather. There are many flowers and Maie is going to take care of them for me - They'll need to be</p>
106
7
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>picked every day and watered twice a week.</p>
<p>Enid, Daddy says this is the wrong time of year to transplant <underline>any</underline> thing, so I think I had best be sensible and wait till Fall to dig up the various things I want you to have. but I'll surely do so then.</p>
<p>Love in heaps for you and for Sig and for Ollie</p>
from your grateful and 
devoted Mama
over
107
<p>Is this not nice paper? It is a gift to Daddy from the Seymours in Chicago.</p>