<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- missing pages 7-8 -->
61a
Thurs. May 28, 1942.
The Palmetto
110 Hancocke St. 
Detroit, Michigan
Dear Daddy, Mama, Hilda, Albert, Eny, Ollie, Sig, Max, Joan, Elaine, and Nei (or viceversa),
<p>It's been a long time now since we've had a chat together - all of us - and I feel I'd love so to talk with you now - so I will do just that.</p>
<p>We really like Detroit and our apt. very well - but we like Chicago much better as a city. Detroit has many beautiful bldgs. but the streets are queerly directed forming triangular islands of buildings between them. This naturally makes things quite confusing at first.</p>
<p>Now - to tell about our</p>
(2)
<p>job here and just what <unclear/> doing. First of all, we are busy practically every second. We have two shows - one at 9:30 or 10:00, and the other at 12:30. We get to bed about 3:30 and arise at noon. Rehearsal comes at 1:00 at a nearby studio, at which time we rehearse on our repertoire and learn new dances. At present we're working in another long gown dance and on an adorable sailor dance on the points. Now, I shall describe Larson's and our general procedure there. The place is located about 14 miles outside Detroit (How in the world <underline>did</underline> you find</p>
61b
(3)
<p>where to send the telegram and in time? You are all too dear for words - and you can't know how I appreciate it.) It is quite large and has a nice large floor to work on. The orchestra has been quite cooperative and does the best it can for us. We are part of a <underline>big</underline> floor show as this place seems to want quantity more than quality. We do three <underline>long</underline> 3 part numbers and George does two specialties. Our numbers go over quite well, but they are really too high class for this club which is very decent but valuable mostly</p>
(4)
<p>as a break - in job. <unclear/> we are feeling the effect of real <underline>performance</underline> expereince. After this, we can take dates at <underline>first</underline> class A.1. hotels and clubs in Chicago and elsewhere. Doris hurt her knee rather badly - <underline>not</underline> really seriously, but it is painfull of course. Last night we had quite a time for she couldn't do any numbers but the waltz. Tonight she must fake through the others - omitting all tricks of course. Please pray again for us in this matter for she must get over it in time for a wk. end date at a theatre next wekk and then a date at a fine club</p>
61c
(5)
<p>in Chicago. We are getting marvelous experience now - and I feel we must overcome our little obstacles in order to emerge into really calm wates. We will have to hurry now so we can get ready to leave here at 8:30 - after leaving our delicious homw cooking as usual.</p>
<p>I've already asked you to send the Social Security card - and I do hope you've been able to find it and have sent it already - for we have to give the no. on our A.G.V.A. (American Guild of Variety Artisits) blanks. I cannot get</p>
(6)
<p>paid until this no. is furnished. So you see how important this matter is. If you've been unable to find the card, <underline>please</underline> Hilda, write Wash. (or whereber you are supposed to write for it) for my number. This is <underline>terribly</underline> important and I can do nothing about it myself.</p>
<p>George has many fine plans for our act - and he is capable. The agent (partner in act) and he are going to invest much more money in it too. These palns I'll tell you as they materialize.</p>
<p>What about our home? Does Mrs. Stoker want it? How is everything else of interest coming along. How are all of you? <underline>Please, everyone</underline> do drop me just a line. I'd love it so.</p>
Love to <underline>everyone</underline>,
Alice
<margin>Sig, have you changed jobs? How is Western Auto? Eny and Ollie - please do drop me just a note whenever you can. How is Nei? Tickle him for me. Joan and Elaine, please write me soon.</margin>
61d 
(9)
<p>Besides, it has nine letters and everyone calls me Alicia anyway! Please tell me how you like the name, I don't wnat one too foreign, and yet this is not common either.</p>
<p>I do hope mrs. Stoker buys our home. Yes, I do want to buy it back some day. I have thought of that before - strange. The farm idea sounds grand too. So gald you had a lovely birthday, Mama, I kept saysing to the girls "They are all together today celebrating my Mama's birthday today." Oh! Yes I was with you, Mama - in my hear I <underline>was</underline> with you</p>
10
<p>Also, it's <underline>so</underline> nice that you are seeing people and going places with Daddy. Now is the time you should do <underline>much</underline> of that. I know you'd like George's Mother and Grandmother - and how you would enjoy speaking French together!</p>
<p>Eny, thanks <underline>ever</underline> so much, dearie, for the letter. <underline>So</underline> happy about Nei's progress. Tell him I have his name now, will you? <underline>Do</underline> send me the enlargement. It certainly means a lot to hear everything about yourself, Ollie, Nei, etc. - and to get such <underline>swell</underline> letters - so please keep it up.</p>
<p>Hilda, how are you getting along with your singing. Write me a long, <underline>detailed</underline> letter! Sylvia</p>
61e
(11)
<p>so often says "You look more like Hilda every day" So we must be twins, as you told Mama.</p>
<p>Mama, you can't know how glad I am to hear about Amama. "All's well that ends well" I do believe - and it is <underline>so</underline> good to make up and have no one with a foolish heartache. It is so <underline>good</underline> to hear about this new development.</p>
<p>We'll be on look out for the Minister. I doubt if he'll enjoy our Master of Ceremonies, however - he is a "crumb" like most at these smaller clubs.</p>
(12)
<p>Northwood Inn, whenever we work there, is a much better place for him to come see us and we'd much prefer that.</p>
<p>Ollie, your garden <underline>must</underline> be lovely now. Rewards for your labor, n'cest <unclear/>?</p>
<p>Daddy, do know how I appreciate the help you've given me <underline>all</underline> my life and just now. Do pray for me always. I <underline>know</underline> we are not alone - as you say we are not. And prayers are constantly made for all of you too.</p>
<p>Sig ho is the job? And your piano? And Max, how are you doing? Joan and Elaine - do you have lots of fun? Do you go to school Joanie?</p>
Loads of Love Everyone
dear dear people,
Alice