<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
29a
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
August 3, 1941.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Please excuse me for not writing you for several days. I write so many letters I can hardly remember who I've written last! But I love to write you and I think of you at least half my waking hours.</p>
<p>Mama, I don't need a dress slip or nighty now, but I do certainly appreciate your wanting to make me something ever so much.</p>
<p>Thanks loads for the song, the shorts too. Daddy, can you send me the words to the song? Council Ring was not last Friday because of a dashing thunderstorm, but we hope to have it Wednesday. The ceremony is all ready now - done as you have suggested, Daddy. The costumes are really effective too! I do so hope we can have Council Ring this next week! Every time I worked on those thunderbird costumes, it rained!</p>
(2)
<p>Everything here is grand. Last night we had our Jr. Song Contest. It was really remarkable what these children did, and the judges were unable to decide upon the winner. You see, one song is picked each year as a standard camp song. At the contest each bunk or two bunks together present a song with clever costuming, setting, etc. It has been decided that the whole of Senior Nakanawa Camp is coming over tonight to a repeat performance of the Song Contest, and they will help decide. Col. Rice was so impressed with what these Juniors did that he announced something very exciting to everyone. A photographer and journalist is coming from "Life" magazine to Nakanawa, having chosen it as the outstanding camp of the SOuth. When these come, Col. Rice is going to have them witness a performance of the song festival just to see what our campers can do! Hope they like it! If our campers do as well as last night they'll certainly be favorably accepted. Some mighty good girls here, even if</p>
29b
(3)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>they are "spoiled". Today as yesterday we're having photographs taken for our catalog adn the "Life" photographer may come too.</p>
<p>Thursday was free day so Willie and I with two other counselors supervised a truck trip. We rode about thirty miles over lovely Ozark county to Pleasant Hill where we ate a super delicious picnic dinner, took pictures and looked at view. Rode homoe another way, treated all thirty-five of us to coca-colas and came on home around 4:30. Thursday evening was the Amazon supper, so only Valkyries were taken on the trips. When we returned, we went about our life as usual. Then supper came. We went to the secret meeting place of the Amazons led by Amazon scouts of that "gangster" band. There each Amazon chose a Valkyrie to eat with her. The Valkyries also had to sing an Amazon song for ran</p>
(4)
<p>som for their captain, who had been kidnapped by the Amazonz. Of course all this was intensely exciting to everyone. We had a <underline>deliicious</underline> picnic supper after that, consisting of steak, homemade buns, strawberry preserves, fruit salad, punch, browned potatoes, and chocolate marshmallow ice cream cones. (Ray is a marvelous dietician and our cooks really know their stuff <strike>)</strike> They sang some negro spirituals for us, incidentally.) The sunet on the lake was too lovely for words, and the woods were beautiful as always. We had a grand time but couldn't have our fire because the rain drove us home.</p>
<p>I just received the cake and can wait no longer to tell you about it! We had been listening to Cole Young Rice reading and I just was walking up the roadway to get my mail when Sally, one of my girls ran up to me and yelled that I had received a huge cake and a package. I ran to our cabin and there opened the box to</p>
29c
(5)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>find that perfectly gorgeous cake in perfect condition, in spite of all themaneuvering it must have gone through before reaching me here. Gu Gu, one of my adorable kids, was <underline>very very</underline> thrilled and so was Clara Jane. They cannot I'm very sorry to say, have any - how I wish I could slip them a piece! Hilda sent me a perfectly adorable bathing suit, blue and white with a little blue short skirt to use instead of a robe! It is darling. Mama and Daddy, I'm so happy to have such <underline>lovely</underline> marvelous people for parents and such dear brothers and sisters! Eny and Ollie sent me lovely little cakes yesterday. Tonight after supper we're having a cake for Bitsey, my former co-counselor, and tomorrow night we're going to eat my cake!</p>
(6)
(Monday morning!)
<p>I can't wait to tell you some marvelous news! Our cabin and Willie's (my best friend here) went together on our song for the contest - and we <underline>won first place</underline>!!! Our kids are thrilld stiff! So are we! They get a special prize of some sort, and the song will, be printed in Nakanawa song book and become one of its regular camp songs! Our tune is "Whistle While You Work" - we made up different words to it. Just now the Glee Club has been learning it. Now they're singing the Indian sogn for Coucnil Ring!</p>
<p>Yesterday "Life" did come and photographed <underline>many</underline> things. They saw the performance last night and photographed it many times. Reminded me of Grand Opera! ha! So much publicity.</p>
29d
(7)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>Did I tell you I'm in a single cabin now? I took a nervous counselor's place - she has other extra duties. I love "my children". Will send you pictures of them - or Hil will.</p>
<p>Can't wait to eat that cake - everyone says it's the best they've <underline>ever</underline> seen! I <underline>bet</underline> you and Max did it together, Mom! It's a masterpiece - and of course it is the <underline>best</underline> thing I could imagine! Really you don't know how happy <underline>all</underline> of you have made me because it's from all of you - Daddy, Mama, Max, Joan, Elaine!</p>
<p>How are all of you?</p>
<p>Yesterday afternoon Cole Young Rice read to us. It was very interesting indeed - and he does read well. I liked some of his things very much "Things at</p>
(8)
<p>Twilight" - also his play "The Avenger" is very moving. He's a marvelous person - but strikes me as being a bit embittered and ironic at times. He <underline>is</underline> a <underline>gentleman</underline> at heart though isn't he Daddy? He is so nice to me, because he respects you<unclear/>.</p>
<p>Lovely weather here now!</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<p>P.S. Daddy, will you send me the words to the song? I can't thank you enough.</p>
<p>Can you suggest something to do for our Jr. Fair here next week? Maxie, I know you are so clever about such things. Your bunk stunt suggestion is adorable. I'm going to offer it to a bunk near me, as I have non to present now, since I changed bunks just at the time the new was giving it!</p>