<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
9 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 9
<strike>Possibly 39 asK dad</strike>
John G. Neihardt
Branson, Missouri
Tues, Jan 13. 1942
Dear Sig &amp; Max:
<p>Too bad about Holms! Mama &amp; I were afraid there might be an embarassing situation, for I felt sure they were hardup. And the blizzard came just at the right time to make it see as bad as possible! Be sure that, under such cruelly embarassing circumstances, they gave the worst possible impression, and quite unfair to themselves. I've been in a similar position. Old Elmer must have seemed a perfect dolt, which he really isn't; and poor Mrs. Holm must have felt crushed. If you could study their <underline>Notes</underline> to my books, you'd know how intelligent they really are.</p>
<p>But I'm sure they are not go-getters, that their ability as a gents would not be great. Their only value would have been in their devotion and conscientiousness coupled with the fact that the correspondence would have been handled <underline>in</underline> Nebraska. When I first considered then, I thought only of a more or less quiet run around or the state by myself - perhaps twenty-five high schools. I had just rec'd the Seward letter along with one from Holms, and I wrote them for aid in getting some others.</p>
<p>I do believe you can do better by working direct, and I don't see why Elmer should go to Omaha. Why not a letter from you there direct to Joslyn Memorial?</p>
<p>You should, I'm sure, try to get the endorsement and aid of</p>
(over)
<margin>I'm sure Shannon is right in judging the possiblities as he aid, so far as Holms are concerned. All I've heard of him tends to make me trust him.</margin>
10
-2-
<p>J.G. Masters, Principal of Central High School, Omaha. He is very influential &amp; has been my fan for 25 years. I got him started on orginal research in Western History, and he has been very active in that field.</p>
<p>You should also write to the State Supt. of Public Instruction, Lincoln, getting his endorsement <strike/> of the plan to tour the state &amp; help in defense.</p>
<p>I think if you wrote the Governor you'd get a friendly reply.</p>
<p>The above are really practical suggestions, and I hope you'll act on them. If you could have these endorsements to send out with your "feelers", you should do so. Sig coudl write good letters to these three.</p>
<p>I do not mean to underestimate Sahnnon in the least when I say that it would be a natural mistake to let the whole Nebraska picture be darkened by the pitiful &amp; misleading Holm affair. Psychology is a queer thing. So littler can darken one prospect &amp; illuminate another, when the truth is the opposite. I am sure of this, whatever else may prove true: Our only <underline>reasonable immediate hope</underline> (yours &amp; mine, Sig) is in the Nebraska scheme. I mean that there's more in <strike/> it upon which to base a hope than in anything else <underline>just now in view</underline>. Other things will inevitably work out, but as to that we have far less data to build on <underline>now</underline> than in the Nebraska scheme.</p>
<margin>I think , today, that the "feeler" idea is OK. At first, while at the P.O., I wondered.</margin>
11
-3-
John G. Neihardt
Branson, Missouri
<p>It may not turn out as well as we'd like; but how often does anything do that? There are a few solid facts to work on up there, and at worst we should do reasonably well. As between summer schools and the Nebraska tour, I'd base more on the latter' altho' I hope, for the farmer.</p>
<p>The fact that Armin visited mrs. Boyles between <strike/> Dec 31 and Jan 7 explains the second letter nicely. I naturally supposed Sig had contacted her, but had entered. She even suggests <strike/> the nature of the program <stirke/> that you had in mind before he went there. It's amusing. This is no criticism of either Sig or Armin. I'm thinking only of the way Mrs. Boyle's mind worked. Surely she sinverely cares for us; and we know that when she is right she can be wonderful. I hope to God she's right this time in either the letters, and who knows? She may be, bless her!</p>
<p>Anyway, I'll bet that, in some way we can't see now, we'll be more fortunate than we, any of us, secretly hope. What do you bet?</p>
(over)
12
-4-
<p>Mama &amp; I are heart &amp; soul for you four in your plans! If the world situation allows (and it might keep) Your plans could work out. Why not? You'd certainly have the genuine stuff to offer. Imagine how Mama and I would feel in one of your audiences! I want to be down there looking up at you all! I <underline>do</underline> wnat that more than you can know, and so does Mama. Even the war must end, and at worst there should be time enough for you all.</p>
<p>I know that, if it's possible, we should be together. Maybe, this home may still serve us, if the program plans <strike/> develop at all. As good a place as any to leave from! And this place somehow cares for us, whatever the feeling may mean. A blink of the eye ago, all you youngsters were like Joan &amp; Laine here; and now you're here again in Joan and Laine. Same old song, and a sweet one!</p>
Love always,
Dad
<p>How about Tom Murphy in Omaha? You'd refer to Mellett's letter (which you have there) in which he quotes Lient. Bingham. You'll know what to do about this.</p>
<p>Sig, old noble is "crazy" about <underline>Jed</underline>. Just heart.</p>