<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
13 
Fink Collection 
Sunday, Jan 21st 1923. 
My own Darling: 
I feel so sad because you married over not bearing from me- my own, darling Hubly - I was foolish to address you at Page instead of at O'Neill or Neligh but I thought I must be sure my letter does not get to any given place too late - and so allowed for too many days ahead. I am so awfully sorry dearie, please forgive me. 
You do know that we are. 
thinking of you or talking of you all the time; and also you know that I have been busy at home all the time. I went down town twice in the morning to mail your pack age and some letters, and got back in time to get dinner - I have had mother and Grandma over to 3 dinners, and spent one evening over there while Mother went with Enid to a Pie-Supper under <unclear/>." I had Mrs boxhelp

14
the washing once - and for the rest the days have gone as you know dearest one. Sigurd was sick and had to be home all of last week-and that cured him but nearly killed me! 
Now my dearest Hubby I love you so very, very much that I could not love more, nor could you wish to be loved more than you are! I am so sorry you got tied up over the strain at that <unclear/> little place, Columbus - you surely must not made yourself that way. That is far worse than sitting at home re-viewing. I know you will make good money dear, but hope to think of those little tours drawing on your strengths, which is too precious for "just people" Darling, I am writing this with a million <unclear/>, our own

15
and other people's kids are <unclear/> it hard, but Alice is asleep and so I thought I might not have a better chance till God knows when. 
You must not htink for one minute that I feel the least bit dissatisfied with my lot! Indeed I don't. I know how lucky I am to be your wife, darling, great, good man that you are. I often wish I were prettier, and "this and that" for 
you - sweetheart - and I know my limitations. But when I think that you are satisfied with me, there I am always happy. 
We are all very harmonious. Sig needs some more jacking up - Poor kid how he does hate to be useful! 
Much much love to you dearest Husband - and oh, I am so 

16
sorry you worried about me. I love you, Darling, more than I saw ever tell you - and I'll be so happy when you get back. 
Your Girl
Mona. 