<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
54cc
42-60 Bowne St.,
Flushing, L.I.,
N.Y.
March 30, 1943

Dear Mom &amp; Dad:
<p>Thanks for your letter mama.</p>
<p>Last Saturday I went for my first office appointment with Dr. Wm Katz, physician &amp; surgeon. He is a german-jew who only recently came here from the section of Germany as indicated on the enclosed slip of paper. I am sold on him and believe he is as fine as any on earth. His German-made hospital equipment is nothing short of amazing. He says to tell you folks that he knew many Neihardts, Neihardts, etc. in the towns of Rumbach &amp; Petersbachel, Germany.</p>
<p>The ailment I've had ever since June, 1939, I believe has been located, for Dr. Katz &amp; Maxine observed my upper body through the flouroscope &amp; found that owing to having no tonsils to catch the disease, the germs lodged in the bronchial glands &amp; I have badly swollen ones, so much so that the passage to my stomach is narrowed &amp; brings on a belching condition at times. Well, anyway, it is a relief to be under the care of a real <hi>master</hi> from <hi>where</hi> they <hi>do things that way</hi>! For two weeks at least, Doc is giving me a medicine that he thinks will reduce the</p>
over
-2-
<p>swollen glands &amp; eventually dry them up. He insists that "fortunately" no operation can be performed and that such a condition must be cleared up in a natural way just as it formed. My lungs, heart &amp; everything normal. The trouble is glandular. When I told Dr. about that groin that Dr. Mitchell lanced, which was a part of the lymph system, he raised hell about it &amp; said "how stupid that your physician didn't at that time insist upon finding out whether or not other glands in the system had been affected." He says I've been fighting off the oncoming of this condition for those <hi>8 years</hi>, which is obviously true.</p>
<p>Now, for some fairly good news: The company officials told me I'm in line for promotion &amp; that an official statement will be sent me on the 5th of April. So we'll see what happens.</p>
<p>Regardless of Brazil, Maxie &amp; the kids want to spend some time in Branson this Spring or Summer. We'll see what works out. At any rate it appears now that there's going to be a way for us to financially help you two.</p>
<p>I sent the Baldwin back. Company needed it, &amp; I'm low on energy for 30 days or more anyway. I'll take it easy &amp; obey my Doctor then good things will evolve in all ways. I am eager to know how things are with Dad &amp; yourself, so please write often.</p>
<p>Please be careful crossing streets etc. It wont do for the Neihardts to have a worse situation. We can &amp; must all climb upwards again as far as our hold on this silly-ass world goes.</p>
Endless love,
Sig &amp; family.
