<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
222 Fink Collection 67
BRANSON
AUG21
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co)
68
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
This Morning,
Missouri, 1940.
Dear Oddie:
<p>I'm glad you sent me your article on Krueger. It's a good job, as usual; and if I were your boss I'd keep you on features. You have a gift for that work.</p>
<p>Krueger seems unaware that the French Revolutionary period was ending when he expanded democratic socialism, and the democratic aberration belongs to that period. Just as the Christians would crucify Christ again, if the long-hoped-for second coming should occur, so do the idealistic radicals fail to recognize the long-hoped-for anti-capitalist revolution when they see it.</p>
<p>Democratic socialism! In other words, anarchic organism!! But I like Krueger anyway, since he only means that he wants human beings to be happier. Queer what a terrible word "<sic>tolalitarian</sic>" is! It only means organic, after all. I'll wager that, the most passionate democratic enthusiast wouldn't trust a watch that wasn't <sic>tolalitarian</sic>; and when any part of his anatomy goes on a democratic spree, he hunts up a doctor to suppress the outbreak.</p>
(over)
69
<p>the democratic spree may, or may not, have had its uses in an expansive age of pioneering; but it's cast was frightful, and as a result the level of our culture is far lower than is commonly suspected.</p>
<p>the centrifugal ("democratic") force of the late 18th century is spent, and it has been cyclonic. The centripetal force has begun again - and it is high time. Too bad that America must go on mouthing hypocritical phrases. But the historical process will overtake us anyway.</p>
<p>I'm having a good time with my work. I know when I'm "clicking" by a sort of eternal, invulnerable feeling that comes. It's the best experiece I know, barring love; and maybe it's a phase of that.</p>
<p>By the way, did I ever tell you about a heluva big golden topaz that's out in the Thomas Range? Two heluva, big ones, in fact! When are we going after them? And what about that big black opal, with the <unclear/> of a peacock's tail, out in the House Range? Smokes and wild <unclear/> to eat, and gully stew to drink, sweetened with alkalai!</p>
<p>Love always to you and old Enot Peanot.</p>
Dad.
<note>sentence below in margins of letter</note>
<p>Yes, Enat, This may be the best country in the world for than who have a share in it. But for the millions upon millions who have and can have no share ever again under capitalism, it is no country at all.</p>