<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
169 Fink Collection 43
Neihardt
Branson
Mo
BRANSON
JAN31
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson
Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St. Louis County.
44
Jan 30th 40
Dearest Enid:
<p>You and Ollie are indeed dear to want me up there. I appreciate that so much. However I am counting on doing a great many things here this Spring. I too am eager for a lot of flowers and the babies and I will have a lot of fun planting etc. Besides I have so much sewing to do, and I want to put clear varnish an all our surfaces here, barring our skins! All the furniture upstairs and all the woodwork there needs it. then I will feel last years' painting was properly finished with a glossy surface that will be hard to spoil. Downstairs too a lot was redoing, especially the dining room set.</p>
<p>Max and I therefore, will have our hands full.</p>
<p>Joanie went to town with me the other morning, and when I helped</p>
45
<p>her down out of the car, she said "Nannie we love each other, don't we"? - Sweet thing! Yesterday Elaine came running into the frontroom crying, and said "nannie, Joanie killed me!" -</p>
<p>We are looking for an early Spring this year. Mrs. Caut well says a severe January always brings an early Spring and besides, Easter comes early this year - late in March. The pool is frozen easily a foot deep, but there is water in the bottom, so we are hoping the fish are alive - but I am afraid they as well as the lillies may be frozen now and she makes such good whole wheat bread. Do you ever lake now a days?</p>
<p>I've been ironing this morning, and yesterday we wasched. Maxie did the indoor part, and I the outdoor; we had a huge washing. We did the bathroom curtains and the Kitchen door curtain - they were black with coal dirt. Our upstairs however is very clean looking, window curtains and all. I under</p>
46
<p>stood form your last letter that you use coal in and about St. Louis! Joanie is right close to me, adn she just said: "nannie I like your handwriting!" She is so grown up! You'd love her better than ever, as she has outgrown all that queerness she used to have. I never saw two better little children - they are so very, very good! Elaine says:"I want a <sic>hinky</sic> pill, Mama. I need one"!! They talk so much , and are too cute together. It has been less cold lately, so they go out every afternoon all dressed up warm and wtih galoshes on! You are so dear to make those toys for Elaine. Her birthday is Feb. 26th.</p>
<p>Daddy adn I go out walking together quite often. We went to Roark Sunday that recalled so many things about you girls. I was close to the spot where I found your watch! Cantwells' the (brothers) land has fine big trees, but all the rest some d-fool has but down, spoiling the beautiful wooded hillside!</p>
47
<p>I am starting a <unclear/> with sea nymph that I believe will mold easily - I do hope so. Daddy says he will maybe go down there with me when I have the model finished. We might stay at a cabin camp for a week if we like it there, and I could look into the secrets of pottery making, while Daddy writes. He is getting along nicely with Jed.-</p>
<p>Enid darling I hope you have little trouble this month, you would naturally have a <underline>slight</underline> time, after so hard a one last month.</p>
<p>Do please find out how Hilda really is. I am sure the Fln is what she has, not jsut a cold, and let me Know the facts about her. Dear, dear girls I'm so sorry she had to come down - and I hope she can take th proper care of herself. Please and Alice to tell Daddy if she received the $10.00 he sent her. It is not polite and not fair to put off acknowledging the receipt of money.</p>
Loads of love to you and to Ollie from
Mama - Mother