<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
94 Fink Collection <unclear/> Oct 31 1938 52 
Neihardt, Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON OCT311938 M.O. 
Mrs. O. F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne Ave 
Overland
St. Louis Count 
Mo 

53
Dearest Enid and Ollie: 
your good letter made me wish more than we that I might be near you to talk over the form plan and see all your plants and that lovely new carpet and blue vase - so many things that go to note How more beautiful than ever! I can picture you and your loveliness all about you - and it makes me glad - 
Yes I shall want one of those ferns dear - for our brass jardeniere - now that I can keep it nicely - and it will have more meaning for me than ever since you cared for it a while - The brass piece is down at the Christian Church here - but I can get it any time now. They kept it for me as well as the Horine jars with your begonias in them - remember? 
We just returned from a drive through this glorious Ozark country 

54
<unclear/> Mrs Melton, "we" meaning all of us of course! You cannot exaggerate the beauty of all of it now - The colors are exquisite, and that indescribable Ozark haze behind the rich golds and rose tints <del/> make the tears well up from a heart too full of grateful appreciation of such beauty to be able to talk about it. There cannot be a more lovely place to live in ^in all the world - that I know - regardles of all that can be said against it. - - I am making Joanie a coat out of Dad's old black one - it is swell! Now after this don't give <del>throw</del> any of your things away that have really good material ^in them until you have given me a chance at them, will you dear? I am going to sew a lot for these darlings because I can beat bought ar-ticles all to pieces! The coat you gave Joanie last year just fits Baby Laine this year. - I'd give a lot for some of your crabapple preserves! - I am going to some up to you Thanksgiving no matter what happens, and I hope we all can come. So now!!! 

55
am so anxious to see you all again and those snapshots just amde me hungrier than ever! <del>to see you ag</del> 
We had a marvelous chicken din-ner to day - and I did nothing about it - just ate my fill! Sig and Max did the cooking - Sig making the pumpkin pie and baking the chicken. Maxie made the cranberry sauce and the mashed potatoes and green beans - And I made only the rolls! It was swell - then afterwards Daddy and Sig washed all the dishes! So when we came home from our ride there was a nice clean house to greet us. 
Enid I'm so eager for you to see my present wort - it is so much better - thanks to what I've been learn-ing! and maybe too my health and the good light here - and last but not least Daddy's attitude towards it! Everything has worked out so wonderfully for me any way that I feel like a "materialized prayer" most of the time! We went 

56 
over to the S. of O. to see Mr Good yes terday and John thinks my bust very good - I have it in fine shape and expect to have Mr Leonard see it very soon. 
Tracy Leonard, you'll remember is well now it seems. He looks splendid and always was a likeable fellow, but now he is really nice! He brought his mother and her sister over to see my garden the other day - and we all had a lovely time - Mr L. is build-ing a home behind Horine's pottery overlooking a bit of Heaven - and I believe that is where my bust will be placed when it is done - as Mr Good does not want anything of himself put up at the school. And he will not be likely to object to its being in his friends' study. -
There is no news - for we are all very happy and well - 
Loads of love to my Enid girlie and her splendid Man from 
Mama. 
