<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
302 Fink Collection 3
Wednesday
[1942]
<p>P.S. If you receive a stump baby from an unknown party - hold it for me, I'll explain.
M.</p>
Darling Enid:
<p>Please expect Daddy and me next Monday, the 25th of Aug. I feel very close to you all the time these days - and want to be with you. If you should need us before be sure to call, as we can come the very next day, and will do so - of that be assured. However I do not believe you will need us sooner, and this gives me time to finish up my cleaning here and making ready for a spell away from home. Also I want to finish up all my models for Daddy to make the rubber molds down in your basement of all of my pieces. The Ozark baby pin tray can be sold for $1.00 this way! - I feel <underline>very</underline> hopeful of success enough to make us a good living! For a while any way Daddy cannot have to <underline>read</underline> any more for a living - neither does he want to write for the pleasant any way. Enid I have the cutest Lamp = Baby 'Laine about to throw a big ball = the bulb! You'll love it as does <underline>every</underline> one who sees it - the less</p>
4
<p>artistic people like it as much as the more poetically inclined!</p>
<p>Daddy's bust with the American flag draped about it is beautifully installed in our front room - and Frankie's statuette is a real sucess - it <strike/> <sic>tickels</sic> me to death! Mrs Cantwell is speechless! I'm leaving it for Max to take over on Frankie's birthday, Aug 31st. She is so much in hopes your baby will arrive then!</p>
<p>Do you want me to bring Mason jars along? I can easily do so if you would like to have them. tell me how many. I'll love to can your peaches and you Know what good help Daddy is at pealing etc.</p>
<p>Should I bring sheets and <unclear>pillor</unclear> cases along? Is there any other thing I should bring?</p>
<p>Love to our Ollie - and all the love you can wish for from Daddy and me is yours and your sweet baby's.</p>
Always your devoted
Mama.