<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
129b
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo
May 20, 1941.
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>Hil called up yesterday, saying she was "<underline>so</underline> sorry to be back"! Must have had a grand time down home, as one always does there. She surely didn't get much vacation! <sic>Tho't</sic> she got at least two weeks.</p>
<p>Thanks so much for the glass conver dish, Mom! Hil told me about your sending it; but she hasn't been out here yet! It was dear &amp; <sic>tho'tful</sic> of you to send it, Mom!</p>
<p>Yesterday Food Center called me up!! I had put my name in a drawing down there and so yesterday the Mgr. calls &amp; says "Hold on to something now; you won the wagon!" It's a large metal Rambler wagon full of Foo Center's brands of groceries! And <underline>I</underline> won it!! I was so surprised I couldn't believe it! I <sic>tho't</sic> there <underline>must</underline> be a catch! But Neenie H. took me down this a.m. to get it. She seemed almost as thrilled as I! I <sic>tho't</sic> it was a small wagon, but no, it's a <underline>large</underline> one! It'll be so nice to keep for our babe to play with later!! And one can pull it around in the wagon when it gets older too! I believe I should almost take a picture of the thing, as I've <underline>never won anything</underline> before!! Ha, ha!</p>
2
<p>Then, too, Thelma called me up. She &amp; her hubby &amp; little 3 1/2 yr. old boy were in Maplewood shopping. She's coming over soon &amp; visit me for a day!! I'm thrilled, as she &amp; I were such good pals! She &amp; her hubby have about 2 acres &amp; have built a stucco home. It's almost paid for too! Isn't that lovely? Gilbert Sontag is a farmer. He farms his Dad's farm &amp; they live away from same. I'd love to go out there, but won't till after our baby is here. There's nothing important enough to rick the "rabbit's" well being, we think!! Thel understood as she always did about things, so she's coming in to see me. It sounds queer to hear a dear little boy's voice say "hello", &amp; find it was Thel's son!! She says he love to talk on the phone! She asked about you &amp; Dad, Mom! Ol &amp; I are going to ask them to dinner one of these days soon. I know we could get a lot of knowledge about farming form Gilbert, as he's a true farmer of the high type - you know! Ol would probably get to liking Thelma &amp; Gilbert. It'd be a very nice connection for us now, as Ol wanted to know more about farming, of course.</p>
<p>I tried to get Neenie to take some of the groceries, but <underline>no</underline> luck!! We want Ol to see it &amp; then I'm going to force some things on her, and get Hil &amp; Al to take some, too! I <underline>do</underline></p>
129c
3
<p>wish you could be here to see the thing. I'm stil in the clouds! THere are about 18 or 20 items in the wagon. Don't you think it wise to save it for the baby, Mom &amp; Dad? Ol kidded me by saying he may use it some but I think we'll put it upstairs till the child can use it! Someone wanted <strike>the</strike> Mona - John to have a wagon all right! Ha! ha!</p>
<p>I've finished the nursery curtains &amp; am concentrating on the crib spread, about which I told you in my last. Then, too, I've ensmeled the basket, chest &amp; high chair. I'm fixing a coupld slip covers for the high chair pad, so I can keep them clean by changing them.</p>
<p>Alice got me a couple blankets on sale at Famous-Barr at my request. I paid 69<cent/> a piece for large regularly priced 1.\69 cotton crib blankets! Isn't that swell? I'm going to pick up the things I need gradually so it won't be a big "sock" all at once! I need crib sheets, pad, diapers &amp; little shirts &amp; belly bands &amp; a couple receiving blankets &amp; that's about all! I'll get those as soon as I see a "sale" on each that I think's worth the money! Alice has been dear - she picks up things, that one can't order by phone, for me. Oh that'll be <underline>one</underline> pampered kid!! It's been "wanted" for <underline>so very</underline> long!!!</p>
<p>Isn't much more to say now!</p>
4
<p>I <underline>do</underline> hope to hear from you soon.</p>
<p>Do you believe <underline>I</underline> won that wagon?!?! I <underline>did</underline>! Ha, ha!</p>
<p>Come up &amp; see us when you can.</p>
<p>Our yard looks so lovely going to seed in gorgeous blue grass! Then, we're going to cut it 2 1/2" from ground, &amp; <underline>no</underline> more, after this, so we'll have good grass from now on.</p>
<p>We'll have lots of peaches this year. I'm canning strawberries preserves right soon. Oh, I'll can a lot, by dribbles, as I don't want to work too hard!</p>
<p>Write us too soon, won't you?</p>
<p>Ol encloses the enclosed clipping he <sic>tho't</sic> you, Dad, would like to see.</p>
Enid
Enot
<p>Best to Max &amp; Joan &amp; Elaine</p>