<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Don't you hurt any more pretty snakes! I was a bad boy the other day & "popped" one with the Auburn! S.N. 121
That long nite drive is yet to come 10:30 to 7:30 next morn. 
SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
<FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. HOTEL MARQUETTE 16TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
Mon. Morning
ST. CHARLES, MO. 10-17-1932
Sweetheart - 
It is so hard to explain thru correspondence - just how terribly I am miss-ing my dear girl! I didn't receive a letter here from you, but will no doubt receive one at Fulton Missouri!(?)
I was tired & not in very good condition last nite; but was worked for lots of playing by this huge audience of girls at Lindenwood C. Had to eat supper with them; & is there is anything that "gets my 

122
SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
    <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. HOTEL MARQUETTE 16TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
 -2-
    ST. CHARLES, MO. 193
goat"-it's seeing 400-500 "other fellows" girl friends, & my sweet Max no - place around!
I wouldn't know how to tell in a letter-the feeling it gives me to all of a sudden lose my sweetheart's presence, even temporarily! 
Had a reading from Mrs. Peterson - one of St. Louis' finest mediums, she saw for me great success & made it definite that on this trip ("Omaha" I think) I'd get the full grasp on my life's work! 

123
SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
    <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. HOTEL MARQUETTE 16TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
-3-
    ST. CHARLES, MO. 193
Isn't it strange how any one of these people I've had readings from, told the same thing! Music is "amateur" with me so - they say, & my living is to be made in a technical mech. way!
This unanimously same result from mediums must indicate the truth. however a person mustn't let this effect what he himself decides is sensible!
She also said that I would be more happy & be immensely successful in a financially way after 

this trip caused me to "at least" decide on Music or mechanics! Doesn't even see me accepting Lierance's piano scholarship-because she saw something in the way of aviation as being overwhemlingly the sensible choice! Interesting isn't it? We'll see!! 
I'm going to check up on her statements! 
I love you, dear, - & noone else will I ever care for in this way! 
I just hope you will not get disgusted with this long live of talk^about "mediums";cause I"m not believing it myself 'til I see it happen! Hope you are well, & I'll hear from you soon! 
Always I love you,
Sig. 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

124
<figure/> 
HOTEL ST. CHARLES
ST. CHARLES, MO. 
SAINT CHARLES OC 117 11 AM MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
1839
<FIGURE/> 1
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 