<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
164-<strike>165</strike> Fink Collection 31
January 15, 1940
<unclear/> Management. Neihardt Programs
Bransonm , Missouri
Special Delivery
Mrs Oliver Fink 
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland, Mo.
St. Louis County
32
Branson, Mo.
Jan 15th 40.
Darling Children:
<p>Tomorrow, <underline>the great</underline> day will once more make you count over your blessings, all of them rooked in your love for each other, and the realisation that you mean more and more to each other with each recurring Jan 16th. My love for you both, and my wishes for your future wellfare, cannot be put into words; but I long for ever new opportunities to prove their reality.</p>
<p>May you spend a very happy day, and may you be spared eacher other for many, many more of them! I hope also, that next Jan. will just you the lucky parents of a most lucky youngling!</p>
<p>You may be surprised at my letter</p>
33
2
<p><unclear/> Branson - We decided not to stay out any longer for a number of good reasons. Daddy had started, and was at a a place with Jed that he Knew he could continue now that the flow had started, at home as well as else where. Then, the Albuquerque chinate kept him on the "quivive" constantly , as though he might any moment become <underline>really</underline> sick. Then too he found there was absolutely not the slightest chance for a part time job there - the fact is that the town is growing rapidly as a result of a great many small jobs, plus a lot of government employees, all of whome seem to be buying homes like rent - but the salaries are very low.</p>
<p>We found too, that what Daddy is really looking for is not there - I doubt if it is <underline>any</underline> where on Earth. The result of our trip is that our home seems awfully good to both of us, and the children are mightly glad to have us back! So we are all happy about the whole thing! Besides we are saving a good by sume by not spending it!</p>
34
3
<p>which in itself makes us feel better.</p>
<p>On our return we went quite a bit farther South, and liked the air neaer El Paso much better - but Daddy did not want to stop there. We came through Pecos, which was disappointing - touched Fort Worth and Dallas, both  of which are truly wonderful cities ( We spoke of you a lot there, and thought you would be very happy in one of the na<unclear/> lovely suburbs where homes are being built in great numbers too)</p>
<p>But of our whole trip the part I enjoyed most was Arkansas!!! Straight South from us about 200 miles is what I call Heaven on Earth! Daddy and I both loved Hot Springs - it made me think of Europe a lot! They have brilliant green grass and fine tall evergreens - forests of them! Their homes etc are more interesting than those in the Black Hills, and the business section is certainly metropolitan - I wish we could live there in the Winters - Dad</p>
35
4
<p>dy would like that too.</p>
<p>We came in contact with a <underline>very beautiful</underline> pottery "Camark Pottery" and it looks as though I may be have found in this pottery an outlet for my things! Hold your thumbs for me - I will tell you all about it when I Know more, but it surely looks <sic>promissing</sic>!</p>
<p>Daddy is feelign better than he has felt on the whole trip. He is going ahead with Jed.</p>
<p>Please tell Alice for me, that I am eagerly expecting her letter, which I don't doubt she wrote, and which is following us from El Paso or from Pecos.</p>
Love to you three and to Hilda as well, if she should be there with you, 
from your loving
Daddy and Mama
Mother.