<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
170 Fink Collection 48
Neihardt
Branson, 
Mo.
BRANSON
FEB 7
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
St Louis
County.
49
Tuesday 
Feb. 6, 1940
Darling Enid:
<p>Your good letter was so welcome dear. We all enjoyed it and talked about you up there, wishing we might pop in on you.</p>
<p>Enid dear, please be sure Alice has what she needs to be warm with in the way of proper underwear adn also in the way of a warm bathrobe. She has spent so little on clothes and she should have what is necessary. Also use your judgement about when she should return to her dancing - If she needs a prolonged rest she should come home here and remain till John and Sigurd go on their trip towards the end of this month. I'd be so happy to have her here - but of course I don't want to interfere with her progress.</p>
50
2
<p>thinkgs look <underline>very</underline> well for 1941 and well enough for 1940 so that we can hope to get through O.K. Daddy has never been really happy, so I don't Know why I should expect him to be any other way. But it does make me miserable just the same to know this truth and he entirely unable to do any thing about it. He is good and sweet, <strike>for</strike> but so terribly pessimistic about everything you know how awful it makes one feel. He is making some lovely things out of crystal and at least while he workds on them he is not unhappy. He has finished one part of Jed Smith now, but unless he feels better he'll not go on for a while now - and that means that soon he'll <underline>have</underline> to quit because of the next lecture trip. Daddy is one out of a million who can do young people so very much good, and I believe he will yet land in</p>
51
3
<p>some position where he can do this, and feel resonably happy. He says he does not really like this lecture trip going - but it surely is a great blessing to us that Sig can get them. Once Jed is finished every thing else will work out, until then we all have to just do the best we can, seeing only a little ways ahead at a time.</p>
<p>I am so glad you are seeing more of Mrs Harrison. I have those Knitting needles that you mention, end will be careful to send them to you dear. I getting along with my new <sic>seanymph</sic> and she <strike>ep</strike> expresses some thing to me at least, besides being very beautiful. I am letting the waves curl up to her<strike>e</strike> as the waves really do lap the shore. She is dreaming and her face is full of a</p>
52
4
<p>sweetness and a longing. The wave idea makes it possible to do away with under cuts. The bowl will make a gorgeous center piece empty or filled with fruits - and I would love to have it if I were a young home-maker. Daddy says the <underline>men</underline> will <underline>all</underline> want to buy it but not their wives! But I do not believe that! However I'm glad he things the men will want it!</p>
<p>I have been thinking about the possiblity of buying up near St. Louis. Sigurd would like that because he says Mr Lemke is really his friend and would help him in a musical way. There really is nothing here. <underline>I</underline> would so love to be there for</p>
53
5
<p>because of all you children. Mr <unclear>Janecky</unclear> would like to rent this place for $25.00 a month. But we do not want to consider that unless we have to. I have a plan for fixing our Kitchen so it is not so cold and inconvenient, and Daddy likes the idea. It is to divide it in two making a Kitchenette of the half nearest the house and flooring it. The other half to remain a porch as it now is with a faucet for running water and our washing machine and tubs there. This would make a place for our dirty clothes and all the things taht belong in a laundry, adn at the same time it would <unclear/> as a storm house, cutting off more than half of the cold. =Like this= Do you like this plan?</p>
<note>there is a map of the plan for the kitchen. A wall dividing the room in two.</note>
54
6
<p>Then we must fix our fireplace as we always planned. This would make a good home of this, and one Daddy and I would love to retire to when we finally <underline>are</underline> old.</p>
<p>Max and I are going to have chickens this year too. <underline>Some</underline> money is going to be spent for putting a good chicken fence around the barn part of our building down there. I'm not going to pretend I'm not really in the country, and do without such things as chickens and early garden. I Know Mrs Dawes will help me. She Knows how. After seeing as much of entirely <underline>un</underline>productive West, I am going to make the most of our opportunities here. The Kids are so thrilled over having "chickies" to feed! They are so dear.</p>
55
7
<p>Daddy just now came in and said he had been putting water in our pool for the fish - There was so much ice this year - but there also were 3 inches of water in the bottom of the pool so I'm hoping the wonderful bunch of fish we had has survived - We'll not Know for a while yet.</p>
<p>It looks as though Sig would have some Caligornia engagements in 41. That may be <underline>after</underline> Jed is done. I do hope and pray so. In the mean while, tell Ollie dear that I am still pondering as to where adn what his "Spook" really was, and I hope he died not waste any wine</p>
56
8
<p>not really! Tell him too that his spook sounded too <sic>scientifific</sic>, and that <underline>I</underline> believe when he really meets a spirit, it will not be a <sic>scientiffic</sic> experience at all - not <underline>seem</underline> to be any way!</p>
<p>Sig is practising every afternoon as Daddy must have quiet in the mornings. He does play <underline>so beautifully</underline>, and wwork so conscientiously, that he just has to win out.</p>
<p>If we all were near St Louis Sig and Hilda could do something together that might make a swell Radio Program. Baby Laine says <underline>every day</underline> "Nannie teach 'Laine the <unclear>Bylin</unclear>"! and I think Nannie may.</p>
57
9
<p>Does Ollie think the Post might want a column by Dad? We were thinking may be a syndicated column would ba a possibility as Daddy would really like to do <underline>some</underline> reviewing again, a little later on. That Social Security was a false alarm. The Government helps only those who are not able to earn <underline>any</underline> thing at all, so that's that.</p>
<p>Enid darling you do not say how <strike>to</strike> your period was this month. Won't you tell me if you did have a hard time or not? I hope not. I'm so eager for Alice's letter soon, and so releaved to Know she got the $10.00 - Please forgive this</p>
58
10
<p>terrible letter - I still have no place to write and feel all up in the air - May be I'll have a writing desk some day, somewhere!</p>
Loads of Love to my own dear, dear Enid girlie form 
her devoted
Mama.
<p>Please write again soon!</p>


