<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
81a
May 1, 1939
At School
Dear Daddy and Mama, 
<p>Hilda has been feeling bad about the last letter she wrote you, concerning my dancing, and I have been feeling somewhat guilty, for I'm afraid you'll think I'm selfish. I really didn't understand just how things are, or I shouldn't have thought of staying here most of the summer, simply spending money for you. Here's the reason Hilda wrote you. You see Mr. Fortunato is planning to leave if enough pupils don't remain here this summer to make his staying profitable enough to enable him to pay the rent on his studio. He wanted to know by this Thursday just when we'd be away and just how long etc. Therefore, since Hil was writing anyway, she wrote you instead of me. I think it will be wonderful to be in Branson with you this summer. If I had known that the plan for my staying there for 2 mos. was definite. I shouldn't have been in doubt about my plans for the summer when Mr. Fortunato asked me. I don't think two months rest will hurt me, but I do hope that Mr. Fortunato does come back next Fall. You see, its only the dwindling away of students in the summer which would make him go. Please believe me when I say that I am truly grateful for the chance you are giving me to become what I want to be - not something that does not appeal to me at all - as for instance, a teacher. I think very often of your sacrifice for me, and I know that I must and I can succeed. I spoke to Mr. <unclear>Stellwagea</unclear> the other day about taking the test for further evidence in awarding the honor scholarships. Of course, I told him I didn't intend to go to college &amp; therefore that I would</p>
81b
<p>not wish to accept a scholarship if I did earn it. He saw my point of view adn wished me great success in my dancing, although he also said he thought I could have a fine college career with the ultimate goal a teaching career. I simply don't want to do that got I know I am not fitted for a teacher's life, and I should <underline>never</underline> be happy in work of that kind. Anyway, a $1000 sholarship would not pay half of the total expenses of attending Wash. University, so I would be a great expense if I went to college, too - at least as great as if I continue with my dancing I want &amp; am planning to do. You do think I should try to get a scholaship? I simply couldn't do both, for that would be a double strain on you and me &amp; I'd never get anywhere in either. I hate to feel I'm an awful burden because I know I am more up than anyone else, but I simply can't do two things at once and do either one as well as I want to do them. If I went to college, maybe I could get a job &amp; support myself as Hil does, but I could never be a dancer, I'm afraid &amp; I know I wouldn't be happy.</p>
<p>Anyway, don't take what I've said as anything serious. I simply want you to know that I am grateful for what you're always doing for me, &amp; that I don't mean to smooch. I think your plan for the summer is swell. Please tell me just what you think.</p>
<p>Yesterday Ollie &amp; Eny, Hil &amp; I drove out on Baxter Rd. to the gorgeous picnicing spot where we went so many times last spring with Amama. Hil &amp; I brought most of the food (for once!) <unclear/> (the sweet girls) brought more than her share anyway! We had a marvelous time - ate steak, pot salad, dev. eggs, marshmallows etc, Pay in sun, picked <unclear/> &amp; then drove all over the country! It was lovely!</p>
<note>sentences below are written in margins of letter</note>
<p>Please write soon. Give our love to everyone.</p>
Loads of love,
Alice
<p>P.S. Just rec'd your letter, Dadddy, when I came home.</p>
81c
Alice Neihardt
564 5 Catres Ave.
St. Louis, Mo.
SAINT LOUIS. MO.1
MAY 1
10 -PM
1939
ADDRESS 
YOUR MAIL 
TO STREET AND
NUMBER
UNITED 
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, 
Mo.