<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
11 Thompson Collection 103
[July 10? 1942]
Darling Alice:
<p>You are so good to Keep us informed of what you are doing and where you are. I <underline>need</underline> that sort of thought fulness for my inner peace. I am so grateful for <underline>you</underline> every hour of the day!</p>
<p>Amama is very much improved and I am so glad. She has no intention of remaining with us much as I want her to do so, but one cannot do anything but wait and see, because she'll listen to no one but Ottocar - and I'm hop</p>
104
<p>ing that <underline>he</underline> may prefer her to stay here in which case she would do so.</p>
<p>She has a most intensely interesting look of "Memoirs" in her which we so wish she would talk to some one who'd take them down - a sort of loosely connected bunch of most interesting human experiences tied together like a bouquet of flowers. If she stayign with us she might yet do that - would it not be fine? She says however she'll never do it! Daddy is so wonderful and Kind and just the finest dearest Man that one could have! His bust is now</p>
105
<p>too beautiful for words - <underline>so true</underline> in <underline>every</underline> way! Every detail - and then his wonderful expression!</p>
<p>The Gen. Electric Co wrote me most encouragingly - They bought my lamp i.e. the copy I sent them and gave me Government instructions about blackout lamps - now I have something to work on that may mean <underline>money</underline>. I'll have to make an entirely new thing - but may be I <underline>can</underline>. It must have a <underline>red</underline> light that cannot spread <underline>up</underline>wards. Daddy got us a lot of peaches and we are revelling in them. The place</p>
106
<p>is now <underline>very</underline> beautiful - Wish you all might drop in - We'd take care of you somehow - and would We <undelrine>be glad</undelrine>!</p>
<p>Kindest thoughts for you and yoru associates - and all the loving devotion in the World for you our baby,</p>
from Mama.