<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
42b
Monday, January 22,
1940
Eny's &amp; Ollie's
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I received your last letter and wrote one to you soom thereafter. However, somehow or other it got lost here and so wasn't sent. Here's a line now to make up for it!</p>
<p>I'm so glad your trip together was so pleasant. It is good that you could be away together and that you, daddy, could get started again on <underline>Jed</underline>. It really doesn't matter that no place seemed satisfactory to you as a home, in fact it will probably give you more place of wind while you are in Branson.</p>
<p>I read "The Rive and I" last weekend. It is ridiculous of me not to have read it before, but I guess I was too busy getting "larnin'" out of dry schoolbooks. Anyway, I knwo I enjoyed it more now and understand the philosophy in it, etc. better than I could have previous to this time. The humor is <underline>so</underline> fascinating, and the food for thought is tremendous. There are many things in it I've heard you <underline>say</underline> before Daddy, and also much more. I am reading the <underline>Messiah</underline> as I find time in which I do it justice. What I've read of it is marvelous.</p>
<p>I also just finished ''Of Mice &amp; Men''-Steinbeck. It is wonderfully written.</p>
(2.)
<p>I think - so simply. Much of the description reminds me of your ways Daddy.</p>
<p>Dancing is coming along very nicely. Lessons are as usual, and we practice hard daily. Had two lessons both a nite good, and a practice bar today. Came home at 7:30 and had delicious steak dinner <strike>a lot</strike> par Eny! (a la wonderful!) Tongiht in class we really worked up a healthy perspiration - one, would think from looking at us that the temperature was 108<degree/> above rather than 8 below as it has been recently or 8 above as it was today. I'm going regularly to the studio to gree time a week at 9:30 (11:00 oclock lesson) and thrice about 11:00 (for practice) and evening lesson.</p>
<p>It's been beastly codl here, 14<degree/> below zero one night! We keep warm however. I sleep on the studio couch now. The other day I nearly froze waiting 15 min. for st. car. I had on snuggies, a sweater, &amp; a jacket plus my dress &amp; coat &amp; other regular clothing, too! Ollie dislikes this weather somethign terrible. To be truthful, I can't say I like it either. too darn cold for anyone less warmly attired than an eskimo or a polar bear. Now it is a good deal warmer, however, 8<degree/> above, and snow 2 ft. deep (natural snowfall). How's your winter coming along? Eny &amp; Ollie say please to write.</p>
Loas &amp; loads of love to you and to Sig. Max, Joan, and Laine
Alice
42c
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO <underline>Fink</underline>
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS M.O. 1
JAN24
5-PM
1940
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
2 CENTS 2</stamp>
BUY U.S. SAVINGS 
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMAN
Dr. &amp; Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
<underline>Taney Co.</underline>