<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
16
31
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON JUL10 3-PM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Dr. John G. Neihardt 
The Post Dispatch 
St. Louis 
Mo. 

162 
Friday 
[July 10, 1936]
My own Darling,
I have just had a good breakfast: 2 cups of coffee one piece of milk toast with scrambled eggs on top - and Virginia has washed my teeth combed my hair and washed my face and hands - This is the first thing every morning before Hilda and Alice come down, for they are sleepy heads of a morning like you used to be! I am lying in bed in your room close to the West window by the Mulberry Tree and as usual am thinking of you how much I 

163
owe to you for so much good treatment, so much good treatment, so much good care. I do not want to come out of this looking and feeling better than I did before I got sick, and the few friends who have seen me are astonished at how well I look - so you see what you have got on your hands! Hell! how these thing old women do hang on - isn't it?? 
You are having the hard end of this with city heat etc. I am so sorry and hope you and Enid can get into the far West very soon, Why put it off? Surely you cannot have worse heat later than you're having now! 

164 
3
Yes we are comfortable. The nights are pleasant and I al-ways need a blanket. The chil-dren on the porch, rolled in comforters awaken wet with dew after a sound night's sleep - not bad is it? And yet this is Branson!! 
John, the only thing that seems wrong to me is that I cannot see how, with justice so everyone else you and I we ever going to get together again, unless something un foreseen happens, for which I pray. I have not yet the strength to write it all out so you I could talk it, had I the chance. But that too is impossible. - I enjoyed 

4
165
your article in the last page and surely Bovard should find in it the seed for a good story for the P.D. enab-ling you to make the Salt <del>Lake</del> Desert trip, not? 
I'm so tickled about Ernest Thompson Seaton - he is older than you is he not? I'm so afraid Enid will go on dreaming until it is too late - but Oh I want my fears - all of them - to be wrong. - 
They made fun of the Pulitzer prize over the Radio the other morning, did you hear it? I had a good laugh! I meant to say a while ago that when the hottest days we have a good breeze in our front room. And with the use of Sigurd's
 
166
5
little electric fan and a larger new one which Virginia brought home one day we are very comfortable indeed - I do wish you were so! Junior Melton came at the last minute before leaving for St Louis and asked if we had any thing to send up. Of course my brain did not work so quickly - and we said no. Had he let usknow the day before - I would have sent Sigurd's Music up for him to get the next time he came, a beautiful fern for your Apart-ment that I love and that came from Grandma - and Alice who would have enjoyed a few days with you - with no expense for the trip - Is it not a pity? If you go West, why not give up your Apartment? John when I left she has pital the D, told Virginia and Hilda that I would be many weeks 

167
before I could walk - and at least 6 months before I could do any work. - If I can't do things I'd rather have to be, as I am entirely off of my feet - for I'd see things every where that I'd like to attend to, to say ntohing of wanting to sculp. My eyes are clear off - and I see only for short periods with these lenses - the holders are so beautiful, I love them, but they need some one who knows how to bend them to fit me. I had the old lenses put in before I left Springfield I have written this letter in three installments - Do write to your old girl who loves you mor ethan any nice fat lady would - 
Mona! 