<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
21 Sigurd neihardt Collection 62
[January 28, 1941]
Possibly '40
Day after Yesterday, MO.
Dear Ones:
<p>Those were darling letters we just rec'd - one from each of you and messages from the Wubs too!</p>
<p>I'm coming on nicely. This is the 5th day and the first time I've felt definite improvement, I'll get out of this in a few days now. The catch started 2 inches <underline>southwest</underline> of the small of the back and progressed westward across the hip &amp; then southward to the knee. The pain has been a real <unclear>wow</unclear>, and was constant for the first 3 days. I was able to crawl, but no walking yet; and no <underline>sitting</underline> until yesterday. It's <underline>not</underline> serious - just goshawful painful. I think it has been doing me some real good; and I mean that. As soon as I can walk on my hind legs, we'll start. Nanny is a dollink, and I hope she will get an <underline>awful</underline> pain so that I can take care of her as she has done with me!!!</p>
<p>Those blessed little ladies! Dog on it, Gaki does love them! Tell Joan I'll be just as good as ever pretty soon, and that she and 'Laine mustn't worry. Gaki is <underline>not</underline> broken - just a little twisted.</p>
<p>We were so sorry not to be able to get the E.St.L. station. There wasn't even static at 1500 kilocycles! But we'll hear later. I have come to hope very strongly, Sig, that</p>
63
THE MANAGEMENT OF NEIAHRDT PROGRAMS
BRANSON, MISSOURI
<p>Starck's scheme, with the stronger station may work out. On futher thought, it seems silly to object to the nature of the program. <strike/> Your sole responsiblity would pertain to the quality of your music - and we know what that is. Also, if Starck can &amp; does buck up the failing spirits of people and doesn't rob them, he <strike/> is doing a good service. Yes, I knnow you'd come running if I needed you, Old Kid!</p>
<p>I wouldn't be surprised if there is something to the idea of more time in the system, as Starck says. I'll be glad for suggestions. Nerve tension <underline>does</underline> seem to make an acid condition.</p>
<p>I want you three big fat women to know that I love you too, gluttons and slobs though you are or aren't, as the case may be. Those were <strike/> blessed letters - still are.</p>
Endless lvoe to all Six.
Dad.
<p>I'm eager to know about the possibility of a degree from the state. You don't need it, however. Anyone hearing you play, Sig, will know your quality in some degree.</p>
<note>text below is in margins of letter</note>
<p>Mitchell <underline>is</underline> interested. Just heard.</p>