<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
728 Fink Collection 17
Jan 7, [1940]
Neihardt 
El Paso, Gen. Del.
Texas.
Mr &amp; Mrs Oliver Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland
St Louis County Mo.
18
Albuquerque
Jan 7th
Enid darling and dear Ollie,
<p>Your letters have given us more happiness than I can thank you for in words. I wake up in the nights and get to laughing at your funny descriptions of Alice, Ollie dear, and I almost took the last one seriously and was shocked and scared till Daddy said "he's joking, if Alice had done such a think Ollie would not have written about it." That made me feel better, and I could then really get a Kick out of the whole thing.</p>
<p>Enid darling, you are being <underline>so wonder</underline>ful to Alice and you make me <underline>deeply</underline> grateful. I bet she looked sweet in that lovely</p>
19
2.
<p>outfit! How I used to wish I could have such lovely evening clothes for you and for Hilda - but somehow we never got to that - there were always so many bigger worries. Clothes were always things you managed somehow to get together, weren't they?</p>
<p>Daddy is getting along swell with Jed Smith - he got 1- lines yesterday.</p>
<p>Daddy spoke ot his friend here on the paper and he found there was absolutely nothing here for hime nor for Ollie. The two papers, morning and evening, though owned by <underline>different</underline> parties are using the same Office rooms and desks! The salaries paid are very small, and their men able. There is the smae dissatisfaction.</p>
20
3
<p>here that one finds everywhere, though for different reasons. The Papers <underline>are</underline> making money - but they are on a very small scale.</p>
<p>SO our whole outlook is changed once more, since there is no possible part time job here for Dad, we don't want to think of Albuquerque as a Home either since that would only futher complicate matters.</p>
<p>We like the grandness of the mountains and the desert, the many lovely Homes that are going up - but these are not reasons enough for us to locate here, so far from you dear children. We are going South Tuesday, so please send mail</p>
21
4
<p>to El Paso, Texas, Gen. Del.</p>
<p>I have always wanted Daddy to try for something down there because of an article I once read on that city, and on the endownment of the Paper. It is much warmer than this - and that will suit us, besides it is not so high. Strangely enough <underline>I</underline> have felt well here, but Daddy has had to get over a bad spell of <sic>indigetion</sic> caused by our <underline>one bought</underline> meal, a Mexican one besides he has had trouble to breathe, and has had his regular bronchila trouble too.</p>
<p>All things considered, we are sort of lost here - Branson looks as good to Dad as it always did to me - yet we are not forgetting the problems there. I</p>
22 
5
<p>think that the one good thing now is, that Daddy is really writing each morning, and we think moving So of an afternoon, will not stop him writing in the mornings. His lines are simply grand - as always, and I am so grateful we can be alone together while he works ahead. Once this Song is coupleted we can live without fear. It will not take mmuch to do that.</p>
<p>We are leaving here on Daddy's birthday and I'll certainly celebrate as you suggest whereever we many be - but the morning we will do the regular thing, i.e. he write, while I go out for a</p>
23
<p>walk, returning not before 11 oclock when he is all through for the day.</p>
<p>Many thanks to you Ollie for all your goodness - and I do hope Alice does not make Home <underline>less your home</underline> by sharing it with you.</p>
<p>If Daddy <underline>should maybe</underline> get a part time job on the Post Dispatch again, I'd be for moving into St. Louis County when our Branson home is sold.</p>
<p>I am glad we are here together, I feel this was very necessary after being separated by miles or else by people for so long. Now we Know we are one, once more, and that helps in a World like this.</p>
<p><unclear/> of love to you both from Mama- Mother.</p>