<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
143-<stirke>144</stirke> Fink Collection 22
<sic>Sumer</sic> refile? 1940
Neihardt
Branson Mo.
Mrs O.F. FInk
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis
County
23
Dearest Folks all three
<p>Your good letter telling of Sigurd's adapting himself so well, and of your own interests and friends was most welcome and we all read it a number of times. I feel we may soon have some good news with regard to selling our place as there has been a nibble lately from a lady in Florida.</p>
<p>You and Ollie will en</p>
24
<p>joy the Ballet even though it is expensive - but Alice wrote me the expenses were so great they had to charge accordingly and you who are her <strike/> night-Mama should not fail to go. I still ahve a heavy heart - but that may just be another one of those growing pains that life is so full of and that we just <underline>have</underline> to endure. I am grateful that Daddy has wanted to let Alice dance in spite of the expense of such a career and</p>
25
2
<p>I pray every day that she will not be stopped. So I <underline>ought</underline> not to car at all about my not being able to <underline>see</underline> her. She has the vitality it takes to become a success thank God - Mr Fortunato, I believe, had here right when he told me she had <underline>every</underline> thing it takes - and the biggest part of that was a strong heart and healthy body and good balance of <underline>mind and emotions</underline>. So please darling girl, <underline>write</underline> me</p>
26
<p>all about Alice in the recited - and may be you will too Ollie dear. I would so appreciate that. I do hope Sigurd can go but I fear he will <underline>not</underline> be free.</p>
<p>I have finished Joanie looking up at Nannie - and it is my <underline>first</underline> piece of sculpture worthy of the name. My eyes now see - and my heart has always done so. - I am grateful for the</p>
27
3
<p>Kind things you say about the sea nymph. I believe you will enjoy the new one more. Daddy says the first one is <underline>noth</underline>ing compared with the new one, and I Know he is right. But my eyes are good now and besides I have grown a whole lot through a sucession of failures year after year.__</p>
<p>If we do not sell her this Summer, maybe Sig and Hilda could take a house</p>
(over!)
28
<p>together and the Kids could help each other that way. That <strike>might</strike> ought to be a happy and a profitable arrangemetn. I do belive though, that we will sell.</p>
<p>The place is <underline>very</underline> beautiful and in perfect order - Just now Daddy is having a young man, who needed a good meal and some work, cut all the weeds in out pasture before</p>
29
<p>they seed. Daddy also cut all the weeds out in front of the hedge in the street and all looks lovely. My first <underline>Phlox, Marigold</underline> and Holly hockare blooming today.</p>
<p>This is not the proper time to transplant hedge - but I'll not forget to give you some at the right time. I thought you already had the Pattern you speak of Enid dear. In</p>
(over)
30
<p>fact I feel sure you have - so look away your things once more, dear girlie.</p>
<p>Some more Cannas, came up recently, the less strong ones - I should have <underline>8</underline> blooms from your bulbs this year! We are having a fine rain -</p>
Wishing you the same - always your devoted
Mama
Mother.
<p>Daddy and I will arrive the evening of the 19th.</p>