<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
722 Fink Collection 1
Sunday
afternoon.
July 2, 1939
Dearest Children:
<p>It was so wonderful to hear your dear voices at noon today, and to know you were all happily together. We were having a marvelous chicken dinner with Lache as our guest and I had been bombarding him with questions about you girls just a few minutes before you called. Now Hilda darling you must have gotten the way we all were feeling. Saturday, and Friday too over Sigs teeth. He was suffering a lot with his jaw which is still badly mutilated, owing to the dentist pulling the teeth in a brutal old fashioned manner. He was a dentist of good reputation in Springfield and charged enough to do a good up to date job, but from Sig's and Max's description he hammered the jaw when he could not extract it and then pryed adn jerked in an outlandish fashion. The result being a deep wound that is slowly healing. Yesterday we feared are <unclear/> and they drove up to Springfield again to have it looked over - Sigs</p>
2
<p><unclear/> of mind has been terrible and as a consequence we all have been upset. However I have been trying to make him realize how grateful we should all be that his arms was not paralyzed, and that his teeth were causing all the trouble, he had been having these last several weeks. <underline>How much</underline> easier it would be it we mothers could stand the physical hurts of our children! We then could be so much happier all 'round!</p>
<p>Now Sig has not been able to practice and two important engagements are to come off <crossed>Tuesday and</crossed> Wednesday and Thursday -  and Sig's jaw still is giving him pain. so that he almost wishes he did not have to go with Daddy.- HOwever I think another 24 hours will see him O.K.- his trouble is more in his state of mind than in the actual facts now, bad as it all has really been.-</p>
<p>Our new car is a pure joy, the first absolutely new car we have over had, and Daddy's payments are the same - (can you beat it?) as they would have been had he gone on with the other car and bought new tires which he needed.</p>
<p>I already wrote you that Daddy would be in Overland on the 15th to get you. Sig wrote</p>
<note>sentences below are upside down and crossed out</note>
The Programs of John G. Neihardt
AMERICAN EPIC AND LYRIC POET, LITERARY CRITIC
AND PUBLIC SPEAKER
-------
Sigurd Neihardt
BOOKING AGENT

BRANSON
MISSOURI
3
<p>you about the marvelous new engagement of $600 for a 3 weeks lecture period at University of Ilinois, not? We are simply thrilled to pieces. So now there are over $2000 worth for the new year!</p>
<p>Daddy said <underline>at once</underline> - just think, that means Alice can go right along and she is looked out for, for a whole year!</p>
<p>Dear Daddy he is so <underline>wonderfully good</underline>, bless him!</p>
<p>Hilda darling, I do hope your throat <underline>is</underline> better - and that you <underline>are</underline> taking the best care you can of yourself.</p>
<p>It is wonderful weather here so cool and pleasant - Lache said it was so hot in St. Louis and we cannot realize it because it is so cool here.</p>
<p>You must not worry about us here darling, and I know you must be terribly tired or you would not have had that bad dream about me. I am <underline>very</underline> well and happier than I have <underline>ever</underline> been, and that is saying a lot. I wan tour whole family to be reunited - and that will be Heaven on Earth!</p>
<p>Lache fits in here just as beautifully as Ollie does!</p>
4
<p>I cannot wait for your next letter. Please tell me every thing about yourself.</p>
<p>Have you bought the Shumann lieder. Those songs I named are not in the same <unclear>elevisions</unclear> as I recall them now. Can you not buy <sic>Mondnachs</sic> separately? Please remember me kindly to Mr Gerak and to Mr. Yost. Tell Alice and Enid I want a note from them soon.</p>
<p>Daddy will send you more money for Alice as soon as he returns from Cape Girardean. very soon.</p>
<p><underline>Please</underline> do not hold back on what Alice should have as Daddy can and wants to take care of her expenses.</p>
Love, more and more of it from
Mutti
<p>P.S. Sig just now tells me that he did <underline>not</underline> tell you about the wonderful deal he landed of $600 - but may be Daddy wrote of it before this. anyway you know now!</p>
M.