<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
29a
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, MO.
Aug. 7, 1939.
Dearest Mom &amp; All:-
<p>That was surely a dear letter. You always write such lovely ones!</p>
<p>We certainly join with you, Mom, in prayer for the great success of Matt's Cabin. I knwo Ol &amp; I want on e set badly, &amp; intend to drop in at Orpha's for one this fall! Ha!</p>
<p>It was very nice having the folks here, &amp; we're very happy that we could help a bit. It was pretty had on them, tho', as crowded as it had to be; but we managed okay. Wish you could stop by on your way Northwest. That'd be out of your way, tho', wouldn't it? Try &amp; find a reason.</p>
<p>Am sending Dad some copy paper I forgot to give</p>
2
<p>him before he left, also his black glasses.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Ol &amp; I &amp; Fritz had a little steak roast at the place we all went once, remember. It was lovely. Then, we went to see "Dark Victory". It was poorly handled, we tho't; should have been directed by a master for it has the stuff in it. Bette Davis of course, was the highlight.</p>
<p>I'm going to the dentist today for the last time for awhile, I hope. Have one or two more filings necessary.</p>
<p>We trust Sig is feeling finely now. Is he not? Probably is better or he wouldn't be practicing on the piano. It must be lovely _ Hilda &amp; Sig together!</p>
<p>Mom, Ol &amp; I would surely love to have you come up</p>

<gap reason ="one page"/>
29b
4
<p>Give Joanie &amp; Elanie all our love.</p>
<p>Loads of love to the best parents <underline>we</underline> know of, Mom &amp; Dad. Lots 'n lots of love to Al, Hil, Max, &amp; Sig as well!</p>
Always,
{<unclear>Eny</unclear> &amp; Ol
Enat
Enid
<underline>P.S.</underline>
<p>Max &amp; Sig: You better write. Why not?
Hil &amp; Al: Ditto</p>
<p>Our very best to Lache, Hilda</p>
29c
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO<underline> Fink</underline>
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI

SAINT LOUIS.MO.4
AUG 7
3<underline>30</underline> PM
1939

BUY U.S. SAVINGS 
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER
<stamp>UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
Thomas Jefferson 1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson
<underline>Taney Co.</underline> Missouri