<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
131 Finn Collection 117
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
SIGURD NEIHARDT, BOOKING AGENT
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON
JUN 23
3 --OM
1939
MO
Mrs Oliver Fink.
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, 
Mo.
118
Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie:
<p>Your good letter just cause and I am wondering why you thank <underline>me</underline> for Mrs Dawes's gift. Do write her a letter, she is so lost without children, will you dear?</p>
<p>She is having Sig give Enid Boswell Piano lessons in return for eggs and chicken! - I hope you are intending to come down oftener - it is after all a great deal a state of mind, whether this is very far or not - because the actual expense is really not so great. I'd sure love to go back with you again some time - I enjoyed the last trip a lot.</p>
<p>Enid, my Zimmas are blooming in quantities - mostly reds - and there are 6 hyacinths in bloom in our pool, also 5 water lilies! They should increase! Our nasturtiums are mostly orange and red and not as double as your yeelow ones. It simply poured last night. I'm afraid that nice old man who moved for us will not get his hay before it deteriorates <unclear>vuring</unclear> to so much rain - too bad!</p>
<p>Where did the old man go, who lost his home in that fire - I hope he had insurance.</p>
<p>Tell the little boy that Mr Neihardt like his can opener, and that the can you open is <underline>supposed</underline> to go round as you open it, and not stand still!</p>
<p>I am at last finishing Maz's blue <crossed>voile</crossed> crepe dress. Also I am modeling a little behind the barn. It seems to be second nature!</p>
<p>I am so glad Ollie is finishing the Piano repairs - I can't wait to hear you and Hilda together!</p>
<p>Thanks for the note - I simply can -</p>
119
<p>not think of a baby that is actually called Martha - the name sounds so practical and dried up. I'd do any thing before I'd call a baby girl that! -</p>
<p>Daddy does not seem to be very near St Louis - but he may just go there any way on his trip. The last he said he was planning to pick Hilda and Alice up at Hannibal on the 15th - but there may be other plans farming.</p>
<p>Sig has been devilled with bad teeth. He had one taken out yesterday, a wisdom tooth, and he feels much better. Daddy has been having trouble getting proper glasses - Hope Dr Carliss can fit him - otherwise he will have to go to Springfield soon.</p>
<p>This is not much of a letter just a chat, and a bearer of much much love</p>
from
Mama
Mother.