<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
335 Fink Collection 129
Box 167
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON JUL19 3 -PM 1942 M.O.
UNITED STATES POSTAL 3 CENTS 3
Mr. &amp; mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, 
Mo.
(St. Louis Co.)
130
Branson Mo.
<p>Hello, Nei! Gaki will write a letter soon. Hot do!!</p>
Dearest Children:
<p>Yes I have known that you have been very busy - and so I will understand your not writing more Enid dear. It must be a joyto see our Nei crawl. Bless his heart!</p>
<p>Amama is much better at times but in between she is not at all well. She will not have a Dr nor will she let one do any thing to help her - and she will not talk about her trouble whatever it may be. She wants to be loved and allowed to do what she wishes - and that is very easy for us but it does seem I should be doing more than I am for her. She says</p>
131
<p>she <underline>will not</underline> live at <unclear>Gwynnes'</unclear> and that her little Hotel is just fine - but I cannot feel it right for her to be away from <underline>some</underline> one who really cares for her. The fact is she'd like to be with us if we were not so far away, and she does want to remain within easy reach of Ottocar. This is natural enough - but I don't see how it can be accomplished. She gets all excited when I talk about it so have decided the best thing to do as always is just to let her have her way. She is very sweet and after all does want to do a lot of nice things for every body - so I suppose I should just be grateful and not feel responsible.</p>
<p>Daddy is so dear and good and we three are being very happy together. I</p>
132
<p>have been working hard on his bust and hope this time to find no<strike/>ting wrong with it once it is cast! I suppose there is such a thing as a <underline>perfect</underline> portrait.-</p>
<p>It has been so very hot here, that it took all the watering and petting Daddy could give our zinnias adn morning glories to make them live at all. But now it looks like rain and I hope we will yet have lovely flowers for Amama to see. She loves to sit under our big Maple tree and relax and look way up into those glorious grey green lace like leaves! That tree is now 64 feet high and the Mulberry on the other side is 67 feet <underline>across</underline> - So we have some <underline>real</underline> trees now!</p>
<p>I am getting quite a lot of stump babies and lamps and another</p>
133
<p>arrangemetn of the latter piece (as incense burner or violet <strike>holder</strike> and pansey holder) cast and ready for me to dispose of. Daddy being the official caster! And Amama is buying quite a few, so that I Know I'll have the necessary money to pay our $135.00 on the house mortgage which is due in September. Daddy has $100.00 from the lectures, adn the rest we can save from the weekly <sic>ammount</sic> Amama gives us and the pieces she is ordering.</p>
<p>We expect to hear something good from Kemper but thanks to you dear children we are not worrying, but are expecting to be with you again.</p>
<p>Enid I shall simply love to be allowed to make a coat and cap for our Nei darlin' so get the</p>
134
<p>pattern, and then let me see it and maybe I have enough good coat material here away my things in the big trunk. So don't buy the goods till I see. Send me the pattern anytime - and tell me what sort of material you'd prefer if you had your choice, and also what color, will you not?</p>
<p>This is a terrible <sic>skribble</sic> but I'm trying to make jelly at the same time as writing this - and so it's jump every few minutes!</p>
<p>Love to you three from us three and endless devotion</p>
from your
Mom.