<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
92
Chadron, Nebraska. 
July 20th '32. 
Sweetheart-
I feel so blue because it has been some time since I've heard from you, but as I told you - I have faith in you; therefore I try not to think that you have forgotten me! 
I know you have had a considerable amount of different things on your mind - being that you have the conference to attend! 
I have been doing a tre-mendous am't of driving! You dear girl - it is so far away from you that I wonder how you feel about it (1134 miles or more)! The Auburn is perfect! James Britton, and old lawyer ^ friend of Dad's & a great joker is along with us 

93
-2-
on this trip from Wayne to Manderson S.D. to the Indian reservation! 
If it weren't for him ^his jokes I'd be more blue than I am over being so awfully far from my sweet girl! I just can't explain how beautiful this trip has been & the distinctive difference between this prairie country of the "west" & the Ozarks! I have not yet been to Mr. Elliot's home to get my mail but will do so in the morning! 
It is now 9:25 "mountain time", but it is 10:25 where my sweet girl is! I do hope I'll hear from you, sweetheart (here) be-cause I love you so that I can hardly stand to miss a letter! Didn't hear from you at Valentine you know! 
(over) 

It's only six days 'til I'll be near you, & how re-lieved I'll feel!! 
Keep in mind what I told you about my always being true to you & that I will always love you dear!! 
There happens to be a carnival in this city tonite - just the same times on this merry - go - round as teh one that was in Branson, & it reminds me of being with my dear girl & so perfectly contented!!
I must say good-bye for now, & pray that you haven't quit writing me! I know you haven't but still you know how I feel - it worries me! Hope you've rec'd all my letters! I've written every place I could! 
Always I love you, 
Your Sig.
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

94
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 2CENTS2
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1732 WASHINGTON 1932 1CENT1 
CHADRON, NEBR. JUL 2: 6-PM 1962
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 
Janey County. 