<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
9f
August 2, 1942
1419 North Dearborn
Chicago, Illinois
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I was thrilled to tears when, upon returning today from Benton Harbor, I received your marvelous birthday letters and the totally unexpected gift. I could hardly dead the letters out loud to Sylvia and Doris, for my voice was chocked. Oh! how <underline>can</underline> I make you know what you mean to me, and what I wish I could do for <underline>you</underline> - how I love and admire - and miss you! You are shinning lights to me adn to all who are blessed by knowing</p>
(2)
<p>you, as well. God! People should be more open with one another more loving, more understanding - there is <underline>so</underline> much that is good if we just see it that way. And just that feeling is the one you send to me, always. You both <underline>are</underline> courage, Love, and Beauty, and I am profoundly grateful that we belong to one antoehr. By the way, I shall buy a pan of comfortable oxfords with that (or <underline>part</underline> of that), money. You can't know how timely was this gift!</p>
<p>Weather is cool here. Has been rainy, but is</p>
9K
(3)
<p>now sunshing here in Chi.</p>
<p>We left Friday morning for a week - end engagemetn at Benton Harbor - a new theatre there. It was bright and early at 6:30 A.M. that George came for us and we loaded the car, packed ourselves into it, and left for our ninety - mile distant destination! The drive along Lake Michigan is always one of extraordinary beauty, and always a surprises well, but as this special time of the early <unclear/>, the beauty and charm of it was absolutely indescribable. Like the land of the</p>
(4)
<p>midnight sun <strike>it looked</strike> was the lake - silver white and sparkling, like the scales of an enormous fish - and over it, casting the rosy-veiled organce, brilliance of its ownself, hung the huge round morning sun! As if thsi were not yet sufficiently unearthly in its beauty, layers of darkish, silver <unclear/> clouds with edgings of orange clustered about that sun - creating the perfect fram for <strike>all of its glory.</strike> it, in all its glory. Then cam sailboats into view,</p>
9g
(5)
<p>and a few early bathers and fishermen. And beyond these - that endless silver - blue - calm now but for a slight ruffled-effect. Then - the sun, and the banks of glorified clouds, and highest of all, the blue of the endless sky! Beauty exciting, <underline>charmful</underline>, and yet, comforting, and calm, and strong! We drove, after leaving the lake, through miles of lovely sand-dune country, and then the rolling Irish hills, where we entered our town of Benton Harbor. We went to the State Theatre where we were to play,</p>
(6)
<p>and had rehearsal there at 10:30. The theatre is new, and has a nice Stage, and peppy orchestra, though small. Next, we secured rooms across the street at Mary's Hotel, which, like almost every place in Benton Harbor, belongs to the House of David, a religious sect of money-making though good, hardworking people, all of the men of which wear long beards. Doubtless you know of them. We secured lovely airy rooms (ours was much nicer than George's for he</p>
9h
(7)
<p>was near the kitchen and could smell all the perfumes there from, as well as hearing all the pans being dropped!)</p>
<p>We did three shows Friday and four Saturday. We did only the Russian group, in two spots - opening and closing the show. Our dressing rooms were nice in all respects except back of runnign water. A part Chinese gil singer and her partner - a Chinese (American born) violinist were also in the show with us, besides several other variety acts. The girl was very pleasant, lovely to look at, adn make an en</p>
(8)
<p>joyable companion. We learned a lot of "jive" talk from her - which is really very amusing if taken in a light vein. It was different working on a stage instead of a night club floor - but we grew to enjoy ourselves there - as well as learning the different approach required for resenting our Russian on a stage rather than club floor. Audiences were quite small till Saturday night, when the house was nearly full - and of course that was the best performance. Between two of the shows we went out to eat - Friday at a Chinese Restaurant "Hung Fang" for chop suey - and Saturady to </p>
9i
(9)
<p>an American place for just plain chops. The cater had superb sodas made with <underline>real country cream</underline> (what a change!) ice cream, but reather impalatable dinners. Saturday morning, after a solid sleep of about 6 hrs. (We awoke in exact positions in which we went to sleep) we were awakened by George's knocking and his "Who wants to go swimming?" Of course, we all did - so we did! We drove about ten miles, up and down the hills covered with dear old homes and fields, and grazing herds to the beach on Lake Michigan (one of the hundreds along the</p>
(10)
<p>shore of that huge body of water." Now, again, we witnessed the indescribable beauty of which I've alreadey raved to you so much! That lake is the most fascinating Thing imaginable. At this special time and place we found the lakeshore deserted, the lake several shades of blue, clear and milding wavy, and the sky decorated about the horizon, with grey blue pillowy clouds. THe air was crisp, braking, and filled with that early morning smell, so we found walking</p>
9j
(11)
<p>along the beach just out of reach of the lapping waves a most thrilling pastime. Tall, sharp-pointed grass grew all along some distance from shore, and beyond this rose a bluff with high trees and much small vegetation. We found some interesting fossils and many smooth skipping rocks! The beauty about was something I'll never forget - for it, like all other examples of beauty was a Thing in Itself -, different from any other similar one. Really, a painter could barely hope to catch taht extra Something - and if he did, one would say he had</p>
(12)
<p>exagerrated George and sprinted a half mile back down the beach on the firm sand just at the water's edge, while little waves tickled our toes. WE went to the car when a sprinkle of rain came, and talked till time for dinner. That we ate at Mary's Vegetarian Restaurant, adn proceeded there from to the theatre, just across the street. Shows were really enjoyable Saturday, even though we did four, adn we got nice hands on our numbers. Ate a delicious soda after showtime at 1:30 A.M. and then we went to bed. How we slept!</p>
9L
(13)
<P>Came back here (Chi.) Sunday morning (left 9:35 - arrived noon) and slept several hrs. Then we went out for dinner.</P>
<p>Got up early this morning, ate, and went with Sylvia downtown - to <underline>shop</underline>! What a thrill to have a new pr. of lovely tan oxfords complete with ducky strap and buckle! After that, I boarded a Madison Car No. 16 and rode to the Original Art Co. What a time I had finding it! Another woman was in the same predicament as I - so we hunted about together like two stranger mouses in a ratty neighborhood!</p>
(14)
<p>Found the place, at last, <unclear/> explained my visit. The man has a <underline>huge</underline> collection of mediocre, over showy stuff - but not a thing with any degree of sweetness in it - or subtlety. It seems he received your pieces without your first writing him of their being sent - so therefore he felt no need of ackowledging the same. The paint on the Stump Baby was a bit wet when you sent it, for paper was stuck to it. That is the reason he gave for not being able to use your work. I <underline>do</underline> think the coloring on my Stump Baby</p>
9m
(15)
<p>is much better tahn the one you <sic>send</sic> him. Why is this? I took the two pieces and shall send them to you insured.</p>
<p>Thanks so for the drawing! Maybe I can use it when the time comes.</p>
<p>You think of me as what I look like, Mama, when you speak of "my type" being the dooll. Yes, that is true - and I do love and feel such a role. But I also feel <underline>much</underline> that is entirely different from the sweet lightness of a doll - you shall be surprised soem day.</p>
(16)
<p>I must go now!</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice