<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
9a
Aug 1
Dear Folks--
<p>I started <sic>towrite</sic> about last Tuesday or Wednesday, but was unable to finish because Nei demanded attention, and we have been tied up evenings since. You may understand some when I tell you that Enid five minutes ago tightened the lids on seven jars of blackberries, a half hour after taking seven pints of corn from the boiler. The berries were quarts. I went in back this morning and picked until I was fairly blue, getting about three gallons. We gave Mrs. H. four quarts, since they came from her lots. The new batch of canned corn makes fourteen pints. The berries are the first to be canned, as previously they had not been reipening in quantity sufficient to make a canner. However, now there are so many, I cannot keep up with them, altho I have been picking about every other night. Usually only about three or four quarts, as it gets dark among the snakes, berries, poison ivy and mosquitoes. And, of course, black widow spiders.</p>
<p>Picking berries is great sport, whether carries on during the day or <sic>atdusk</sic>. The weeds and grass are so high, that one just barges throu and hopes for the best. My hide has become a beautiful network of red lines, and moccasins. When something hisses one hopes it is merely a frightened turtle or rustling weeds, and not an angry copperhead. Those black spiders with the stripes (red) on the bellies, I have convinced myself are harmless, or just as frightened of me as I am of them. Every time I get down on my knees to poke my head among the saggin briars to get at a particularly luscious bunch of berries, I trust my grandfather will not let me look into a pair of small beady eyes and a coiled piece of garden hose that is not hose.</p>
<p>Thus far I have seen but one snake, a nice little black snake, and it slithered off into the grass over my moccasin where <strike/> our septic tank empties next to the driveway. In fact, my chief concern has been turning out a mess of wasps--so far I have stepped on but one nest, and the inhabitants buzzed angrily, started merrily for me as I backed off, gave one look and decided I was <strike/> probably posion, so returned home.</p>
<p>Nei is doing very <sic>weel</sic>, thank you, and has acquired a grand passion for eating everything but normal food. Grass is his weaknesss, with dried leaves a close second. However, he will not scorn a nice hunk of dried clay. Enid has just had him in the tub, but he squawked wildly, altho mostly he gets a tremendous kick out of sitting in the tub and <sic>slpashing</sic> all over the place. He crawls all over the place, looking startlingly like a small puppy, and sometimes he barks loudly as a puppy. He prefers to roar, however. Also, he stands now, by pulling himselfup on a chair or such. Or on my <strike/> pants leg. He greets us with "Hot do" every morning, and is getting to <sic>fwowers, blobble, sppch</sic> (spinach) and a number of words that he repeats after us. He is buzzing about the floor now, trying at times to breat the <strike/> barricade of chairs at the doors, and right now trying to climb the desk next to me. Enid has cleaned out most of the <sic>upsettables</sic> from the living room.</p>
<p>This evenign we had him out on the lawn a while, but he refused to stay on the blanket, and headed for the pretty flowers. Flowers fascinate him, (He is standing at my chair now, fascinated by the <strike>typewrite.) of an evein before dark, I carry him outside, and</strike></p>
9b
2
<p>typewriter) Of an evening, before dark, I carry him around the yard to see all the pretty flowers. He gets very excited, and ohs and ahs, and reaches out his finger to touch them. I held him close to the rose of sharon, and he reached out, <sic>touchingit</sic> <strike/> gently. Then he grabbed, and I warned him that it would not be pretty any more if he pulled at it. He seemed to understand, for he took his hand away, looked straight into my face (you probably remember the way he has of doing that) and then just stroked the flower with the tip of his finger.</p>
<p>Enid has put up great quantities of blackberry jelly, until she has used up the sugar ration until far along in August, and we have just a small amount left. However, we bought a five pound jug of syrup, and it makes a nice sweetening. The baby gets honey, also bought five pounds at a time, because of the tremendous saving, so we are nto greatly worried. Enid also has canned ten quarts of tomatoes.</p>
<p>The crops are doing pretty well, with snap beans dormant now, but a new crop coming on. Two rows, 85 feet, in the blooming <strike/> stage, and another 50 feet just sprouting. The limas have not yet started real production, yield to date being about two pints, but the bushes are bery <sic>havily</sic> laden, and seem to be filling out. The last crop of potatoes is coming up, some 380 feet of row, good for about six bushels with moderate luck. Also have in 150 feet of a navt beans, coming up, for drying. Put in two rows of beets today, and the carrots already planted will give us a bushel or more to store. Cabbage is doing well, as are beets, although I wish we had lustily, with 25 pounds or better grown from sets drying in the attic, another ten or 15 pounds ready to harvest and dry. Have <strike/> still two rows of early potatoes to dig, and should have gone at them today, but spent too much time picking berries. I dount that the two rows will give mroe than a bushel, but that will mean four bushel form the early crop. The edible soys are just blooming, the other soys are <strike/> laden with pods in spots, but some where the weeds got away from me are rather poorly. Next year I shall plant nothing out the large green soys,. Corn we ahve been eating almost every day, in addition to what Enid canned, and the patch is not yet exhausted. More corn is coming up among teh tomatoes, and I think we shall get a late stand from that.</p>
<p>Strangely, the tomatoes, usually the easiest and most prolific crop, are doing the most poorly. The wilt killed off some plants, and the rest look pretty poor. Part of the reason may have been that wet weather prevented my from keeping them properly cultivated, and now they are too heavy to get through well, without knocking off much of the fruit. However, I did get them pretty well weeded, and worked up around the plants with the hand cultivator, but they are not prospering. Next year I shall put them all on stakes, and try to train <sic>theplants</sic> as vinces rather than as bushes. Pickles and squash also are not doing too well, which may be caused by hot weather. There has been rain, off and on, during July, but no really soaking amount, and the past week or so has been up in the nineties.</p>
<p>We ahve acquired a bicycle, from Bill Coup, for ten dollars. A bargain, even tho the one tire is bad. It is light weight, in good condition, one tire is practically new, and while it has no coaster brake, it has a hand brake. I think we shall try to trade in the <sic>rea</sic> wheel for one with a coaster, <strike/> giving a bit in</p>
9c
3
<p>addition. The bike will be very handy for errands and things, as we can ride to the store, and get things we need.</p>
<p>I have been laving the ground work for some pictures of MacArthur, and hope to send some along during the coming week, I hope that will not be too late. I want to get actual photographs it <strike/> possible, rather than reproductions.</p>
<p>Many thanks for sending along the Wallace book. I have started it, but am not yet far along. Greer is very anxious to read it also. Will it be all right if I loan if to him? Later I would like Ickes book-- and sometime I would like to read that Stream of History Dad spoke about.</p>
<p>But I do not understand why you should be thrilled at the idea of my wanting to do Dad's life. I have been hoping someday <sic>c</sic> to try it, for several years, and we have <sic>beening</sic> keeping letts, and I have been <sic>makingquite</sic> a few notes. Frankly, I do feel inadequate to the job. I think it should contain not only the story of your life, but an analysis of the relation between your life and your work, and the relation of your work to the stream of literature, and to the life stream. Also to underlying spiritual forces of mankind. I have been rather disgusted--sometimes decidely disgusted-- by teh lack of comprehension of all the "criticisms" and commentaries on your work, by <sic>menpresumed</sic> to be the berries in American literature, which I have read.</p>
<p>I feel that whatever is done must be rather stupendous, worked out and perfected as Flaubert worked out his novels, as Spengler worked out his book. And I do hesitate to undertake it, tho it would be something to which to give five or ten years of one's life.</p>
<p>Nei is going off to bed, so the typewriter must be silenced.</p>
<p>I wish you were here so we could talk it over. Of course we wish you were with us anyway. Perhaps you will be this Winter, I have ordered 5 tons of coal, $5.50 per, to be delivered in Sept., but will increase the amount before then, 40 ten tons. The dealer - who sells to Mrs. Harrison- trucks it himself from the illinois mines &amp; says therefore we need not lay it in now. Can't get <unclear/> anymore.</p>
<p>Schwartz, up the Street, have bought two milkgoats &amp; two kids - probably as a milk supply far their boy. Don't know if they intend to batcher the kids; We might get some - they would feed on the weeds, keep the lawn mowed, &amp; on the winter we could</p>
over
<p>butcher a young one. To say nothing of making some garg and old cheese!</p>
<p>We are making some wine - wild cherries &amp; blackberries, which is a grand rich juice. Hope to get about two gallons going.</p>
<p>Is there anyway to clean a Sawer Krant barrel, to get out the fumes? Wondered if the Scent would leave by scalding then soaking with much baking soda a week or so.</p>
<p>Looks as if we will ahve a few peaches, after all. Perhaps <sic>enuf</sic> even to can a few?</p>
<p>Nei is asleep.</p>
Love to all from all
Ollie
9d
July 28
Dear Folks-
<p>Nei is crawling about with his flowered sunsuit sliding up to his waist and his diaper getting to his ankles. He gets into every thing, &amp; is all over the place. We are thinking of getting him some garden pads for his knees. Now he is hedded for the bathroom, probably to swim in the bowl.</p>
<p>It was extremely sweet of you to remember my birthday. I had a very happy day. Enid gave me some excellent moccasins of a type I have long wanted. &amp; Hilda &amp; Albert gave me three <unclear/>. We ahd chicken &amp; corn for dinner, &amp; a birthday cake.</p>
9e
O Fink
9917 Emerson
Overland, MO.

SAINT LOUIS, MO. 4 
AUG3
1030AM
1942

BUY DEFENSE SAVINGS BONDS AND STAMPS

Dr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson,
Missouri
Taney County