<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
97 Neihardt Collection 62
Man hesset (Gwynne's Home!) L.I.
Saturday Sept 5/'42
My dearly loved Ones:
<p>Sometimes when things all seem wrong, &amp; the sad, old weight on ones heart - <unclear>or</unclear> is it solar plexis, or what - is "back again," I'm wondering whether the wrong is just ME inside, &amp; then the weeping begins again, because all I've done, all I try to do, seems impossible to make the wrong in me - Right. Its killing by terrible!!</p>
<p>Well, <unclear/>, bless &amp; guide &amp; keep him well &amp; happy, great Spirit! planned shortly after I had reached my hotel, after a comfortable a trip as could be, having two, side by side chairs, &amp; pillows, to be stretched out or upon, therefore less tired than I had feared, &amp; said be - &amp; Gwynne - wanted me to spend weekend, &amp; Monday - labor-day, with them, he had his car, would fetch me around 5 P.M. &amp; bring me back Tuesday A.M. when he went to business I took hot folk, ate a bite in dining-room where 3 waiters delighted to see me, threatened to hug me, went to my old room, where Housekeeper-Hostess cam eto ask "Had she remembered</p>
63
<p>just how I wanted Everything, kind, good Soul! packed til nausea came - lay down - got up, went to lobby to sit quietly &amp; await my Son-of-Sons fetching me. Gwynne, in dinner-gown-very much fatter (I dare not tell her this!) borrowed, pretty bit too matronly, gave me one of ehr affectionate Southern welcomes, thebade me make rooms for her, we were dining in a fine <unclear>elk</unclear> chef, in Great Neck, where money-folk reside. It was - or should have been pleasant had the weight-of-wrong in me not <unclear>begnse</unclear>. Anyhow I slept quite well considering. And we motored to Post Office to fetch "Dreaming" <unclear>arrived</unclear> earlier &amp; addressed to Ottocar. He at once exclaimed: What a <unclear>badly</unclear> packed buy, who did it?! I was unafraid, but Dreaming was broken straight thru the waist line - &amp; <unclear/>, when I asked him to at least look at it said - its like ehr other figure, only <unclear/> body, beautiful, face, same as Black Out - poor, like Mona's work, a math like face - not the face of a real human being - like, for instance, a very small, miniature Goose Girl figurine made in Germany, selling once at $15.00 no at <unclear>$9.00</unclear>- Mona just</p>
64
<p><unclear/> create perfect, artistic faces. Ec. Ec. I begged him to write &amp; be frank, but, and so <unclear/> my bless Son-of-Sons, be answered irritatedly. I have business to attend to - plenty at office - &amp; when home for awhile, other things to attend to - I can't write such letters. And so I'm finding courage to be truthful with my loved, ownly Dang litre, hot burning tears adding to my Wrong inside me - not <unclear/>. Well <unclear/> &amp; <unclear>I</unclear> motored at once with boy to Post Office, where, being Saturday &amp; closing one o'clock he could but leave the boy, take printed claim to fill out - &amp; even this, Monday labor-day, Sunday never open, can only be given possible postman if letters come until Tuesday. Now I'm letting you know, so that John, with receipt he must have, can <unclear/> once put in the claim was it for $25.00 as I hope?! at Branson P.D. And surely he can &amp; will get it! Ottocar explained - that anything so badly packed must be a miracle to arrive unbroken - that every, all articles must be tightly wrapped in <unclear/>-paper, that did take up the jars, when will, nightly room a about article. And wrapped <unclear/>article, <unclear/> put</p>
65
<p>in corrugated-boy-well packed with <unclear/> &amp; paper. Ec. Please take notice, &amp; follow same - &amp; send, <unclear/> her parcel-post - or express - your creations otherwise packed. I think my darling Girlie, you should use a beautiful living model here after for faces - not rely on faces created in your vivid imagination. And I feel, that whilst <unclear/> honest opinion will momentarily hurt, it may be just what you<underline> need</underline> to profit from. But it hurts your old Mammie to hurt you - God pity me!</p>
<p>I wish I had done the selfless thing - &amp; remained thru Sept-Oct-&amp; November maybe with my loved children, whose ideals &amp; lives seem close to my own, who helped me with their generous priceless love - &amp; <unclear/> to understand that only this could, did, can help my lonely-aloneness to live on. I'm tempted to return - but cannot handle either the expensive trip -<unclear/> know whether best for you - wisest for my poor Heart, that cannot even think of being long at a <unclear/> from Ottocar, <unclear/> miles I can make it <unclear/> it will be best for <unclear/> my adored <unclear type="cutoff"/></p>
66
<p>Great Spirit - help me to understand to do the selfless, wise thing - help! help me - help me!</p>
<p>My own little figurine also was broken, hands <unclear/> in broken tiny pieces, I don't believe, even if returned to you can be made good. Never mind - I'll use it as it is - &amp; love it for your dear, fine, loving <unclear/> selves, my ownly Daughter, my sweet kind, gentle, good son John. I so deeply miss you both - &amp; it hurts me so <unclear/> - I can't bear it - I cant - this heartaching, broken, love-needing Heart of mine - I cant! </p>
<p>But - I must. John forgive - but I've lost somehow, somewhere - the Black &amp; wonderful prayer, as well as the childrens both of which I received in St Louis, was sure I packed - to have <unclear>Otti</unclear> read too. Can you, will you send copies of both in your sympathetic handwriting, to Woodstock, &amp; I'll never, never lose them again. <underline>Please</underline>! And add that fine Review on Hemmingway, &amp; I'll promise</p>
67
<p>to return it. Have not seen nor heard yet from <unclear/> but left <unclear/> of Ottocars taking me with him - <unclear/> phone number <unclear/> in Hotel, &amp; I must soon to see &amp; hear him. Enid &amp; Baby were adorably sweet. I tried to say farewell before leaving Thurs. A.M. - but could get no answer. Tell Enid please. And Hilda well she was &amp; is too loving, charming, <underline>dear</underline> for her Amama to express - &amp; she <underline>made</underline> me - believe &amp; <unclear>trust</unclear> her love, oh, thank God! thank God for water to a thirsting old Heart - thank God! And so thanks again to my idealistic - spiritually precious children, &amp; please dont stop loving</p>
Your somehow heartsick old-
Mammie Mothie Amama