<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
192
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
At Apt. July 26, 1936
Dearest Mama:-
Just had lunch, and before we pass the afternoon, I want to write to you-just a chat. 
We haven't heard from you lately; no doubt Amama and you've been catching up on your visiting. It's so nice for her to be there! It's so fine to have a mother any time, but to have one with you while you're not so well, it's one of those very rare beauties of life. I know! I told you, didn't I that I've de-cided to come home first; then I hope to go to Louisville for a bit. Lache's people may have someone in mind out that way with whom I might get in touch, to my advantage. I shall mention the fact casually that I'm going to Louisville, and every-thing will follow properly! I'm so 

JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 2
very anxious to see you all again - you, Mama, Al, and Hil, and, of course Amama. 
I'm hearing a perfectly gorgeous symphony now. Tell me, is there any-thing in this world more soothing to one's soul, spirit, and body than that!? I find it a most beautiful experience each time I listen to a symphony. 
Every time I dance around the apartment I think of Amama and Hilda - wishing they could be dancing too! 
Dad and I are planning to be with you around the first of next week (wk. from tomorrow). Don't know just the exact date yet. We'll know toward the end of this com-ing week though. 
Dr. Plank was in town yesterday. He looks so clean and tan! He's just finished a canoe trip with his older son. Just stopped long enough to say hello. He's arriving to Santa Fe this Wednesday and wanted Dad to 

193
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
3 
join him. Thompson Setons have invited Dad to stay at their camp there as guest this summer. Of course, things being as they are, Dad will be in Bran-son unless he should get some sort of a practical offer to lecture there. I wish he could get to go to Santa Fe, tho' for Dad really needs his kind of a vacation. You know how Ozark weather acts on him. I hope he'll get a good much-needed rest this month for I truly feel he needs one. City life isn't the thing, but it's a great thing that happened for us in many ways. Not alone for the family's welfare, but also for teh fact that I couldn't have stayed in Branson much longer without dry-rotting. I am truly a new per-son now since being here with so many fine people. Have had some great times, too; however, I do want to meet more people in the east. 

4
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
I could settle in Branson very easily, but why should I? Dad's very much in favor of my spend-ing a couple weeks in and about Louisville; and I note you are too; so I'm planning on taking the last 2 wks. out of Branson. 
I'm dying to see the quilt. Did you see that Amama got a look at it? I'd like her to see it if she cares to. 
Tell, Hil, I'll be down before long to give her a little help, so she can kind of relax a little from dishwash-ing, pot. lifting, etc! I am bent on having an Indian back before I leave Branson. Think Hil & Lache will help me? Hope so. 
Mama, when you come up, there's a friend of ours I know you'll enjoy. You two have a lot in common. The lady plays violin and piano, the letter her specialty. She's anxious to knwo you and to play 

194
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
5
some with you when you are able to do such a thing again. She plays very well. Her husband was a re-porter on the P-D who died suddenly after they'd been married six years only. They were so much in love and she's never gotten over it. She has a dear little daughter about Al's age; woudl like to see them be together some summer. Mrs. Daw-son has a very lovely grand, she says, and you two could have such lovely times that way. I've been wanting to tell you about this per-son, so that now was as good as any time. She's the economics (home) dept. on the P.D. as well as house plan builder and travel writer - up! She and I <unclear/> lunch together. 
Tell me, are you fatter than you should be? Don't do that! Oh, by the way Savo Radulovitch, the artist (Montegram) is now do-

6
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
ing a second try on Dad's portrait. It's really good. but the first just wasn't. It takes time to catch the character in Dad's face. I needn't tell you that, do I?! Savo is 29 yrs. old and is a truly noble gentleman. One may look far and wide and find only one or two Savos! He has just naturally the most beautiful viewpoint of life; sees things in such a chaste manner. "Rob", he says, "I just don't want to hear or see any of it!" I'm sure you'd love his soul! He's a beautiful character. -And so very sweet and gentle along with his strength! I haven't fallen in love with him, but I could if -. He is so fine in such atti-tudes as this, for instance; he says he'll give up everything, sacrificing what he most desires, if necessary for his art. And he's serious at heart - terribly serious! And yesterday, Savo said to Dad while sketching, "There is nothing more beautiful than a fine wife!" Just the loveliness of his spirit is heart breaking, if you know what I mean!? He's so interested in 

195
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
7
Dad's work is going to read "The Messiah" and "Indian Wars" at once. I'm very anxious to see what sort of a batch will come out of his dream as a result of reading "The Messiah". Yes, botik is just what you think. Savo wants so much to go west with Dad they may arrange to do it. There's one thing, Mama, if one had avo for a husband, she'd never worry or be jealous - he's so absolutely fine beyond any doubt. You must meet Savo. He was so sweetly interested in how you and Dad met! I don't know, of course, but I'm making this prophecy that Savo will be a rich and famous man someday. Just watch. He's so modest and so fine - also, noble to look at! No, he's not very dark. he has bluish-green eyes, dark brown hair. Maybe I'm in love and don't know it! Could that possibly be? No, I be-lieve it's just deep admiration. 
More later. 
Love in <unclear/>, always, 
Eny 