<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
60d
Donato Guerra
Departamento 16
May 2, 1943.
Dear Mama and Daddy (if he is home now),
<p>it has now been several days since I last wrote you - in French. I am happy to hear from you soon. It seems so long since I received your letter - and I have received absolutely <hi>no</hi> other letters from the U.S. than your one. I understand you are busy, but I do not see why someone else does not write. If you would only drop a few lines <hi>often</hi>, I'd be <hi>so</hi> happy, Mama dear.</p>
<p>It has been lovely here - with rain storms almost every day, however - for an hour or more. Several days have been actually cold and not, but for the main the weather has been all one could ask. The sky is a <hi>light</hi>, never a tropical, blue, and frequently we are surrounded by a thin strata of fog, which hides the lovely mountains. It is all the more fascinating, therefore, to discover on a suhshiny morning that one <hi>can</hi> see these.</p>
<p>The other day I had a most fascinating experience. Having gotten dressed to go see the American Consul (whom it seems had been transformed since the Countess had been here, and finding her was not the same man ,men-</p>
(2)
<p>tioned on our letter of introduction we decided not to go - That left us all dressed up with "no place to go" - that day, at least herefore I decided on a "happing" expedition (The (")indicate <hi>ho</hi> intention to <hi>buy</hi> only to <hi>look</hi>) I took a bus to the Zoralo in downtown Mexico and there, last myself in the maze of little shops which border the lively, historical square of the old Cathedral and the Palace. I went up and down the little calles to search of "Jeyerirs"- jewelry shop, where I hoped to find some small gemstones afar Daddy. I had no luck till I sighted a small shop, a silver factory, and a smiling gentleman standing in the door. There I went at once and was told that the stones I desired would be secured for me. Don't say anything to Daddy - but I do hope to get some really nice things for him. Leaving that shopping district, I proceeded to the square, and bargained awhile at the many stands in the arcade. Wasn't in a buying mood, and besides most of the stores were closed by that time for siesta (noon to 4:00 daily). I found a little bookstore open and arranged for a Spanish</p>
60e
(3)
<p>to be secured for me that I may learn verbs in earnest. I was received there with many smiles, for they could see I was interested in learning the language of Mexico (como no?) In Spanish I was directed to the entrance of the Cathedral, which was soon to re-open. A storm was brewing, and great black clouds allowed the escape of scattered drops of rain - each of which seemed to seek out a flower on my lovely "chapeon verlet brun i la maman"! This I did not mind, however, for the terrible beauty of a storm bends itself perfectly to such a scene as an ancient Cathedral and any ancient Palace. While standing before this huge, wonderfully carved, historically - rich edifice, I <hi>felt</hi> as dwarfed (in <hi>various</hi> ways) as I actually was - and I was aroused from this train of thought only by the approach of a kindly, tall, keen-faced stranger, who informed me that he was a guide and desired to show me about. From that moment on I was in a trance. As the church was not yet open we went first to see the Palace. The guide spoke both fluent and highly descriptive English &amp; if with a bit of his original Spanish accent and furthermore, seemed to possess a soul. He explained in great detail each room in the Palace - the many offices</p>
(4)
<p>of Mexican rulers, the huge library (<unclear/> occupied by monks etc. Then we <unclear/> the staircase at the top of which oen may view at best advantage the huge murals of Diego Rivera, picturing the entire history of Mexico. these murals are unusually fine in that they actually encompass everything of importance in what they attempt to portray. The guide told me that the artist comes every morning (9:00 till 1:00) to work on the new murals and these I saw in their unfinished condition. Descending we walked through Carlota's Garden, and I learned many new and interesting highlights of the career of Mademeliano and Carlota in Mexico. In spite of or perhaps more because of the rain, I continued to enjoy my excursion. We braved the storm to dash across the street to the Cathedral - and how I longed for you, Mama, from then on! The immense, dim room that we entered exceeded in size and <unclear/> any I have ever imagined, of course you have seen the fine churches of Europe, but I do believe you too would have been <hi>profoundly</hi> impressed. There we stood speechless, till the guide began as usual to impart his abundancy of knowledge, in his highly interesting and strangley un-annoying mannder.</p>




