<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
328 Fink Collection 90
Box 167
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
JUN30
3 -PM
1942
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
91
<p>Please send my other false teeth. Broke that front tooth again!!</p>
Tuesday Morning
Dear Ones:
<p>Reached Branson at noon Monday. The 1:30 A.M. bus didn't get started utnil 2:20 A.M. because of the crowd. There were three sections and I managed to crowd into the second. Didn't sleep <underline>any</underline>, but felt bully all night and ate a huge breakfast at Lebanon. Felt bully all day, too, but slept 12 hrs. last ngiht.</p>
<p>I do miss you three - felt just a bit homesick; but I'm glad to be here too. The place is beautiful and the growth of foliage is astonishing. The pasture grass is above my shoulders.</p>
<p>Amama is all right, but she is sick in spirit because of many things. Mama is in fine shape, and so is old Doc. <underline>He</underline> has taken a shine to Amama &amp; seems to look after her, following her around. Amama is sweet altho' mention of Alice caused an unpleasant ten mintues. Too bad! But she is sweet &amp; very heart - sick.</p>
<p>I wonder if old Nei will be coonversing fluently when I see him again! Golly, golly! What a people he is! I think I've never known a baby like him. Dog on it! Gaki wants to see him right now.</p>
<p>I think of you two with a soft warm glow. You are good - and very dear. Who knows? Maybe we'll have Capt. Penick's form or another is good!</p>
<p>Ollie, strangely enough, I saw better corn on the way down here - from Springfield on - than I saw in Illinois &amp; Indiana. Considerably taller &amp; rich in color. The rainy season in a well drained country, no doubt - and lime-stone soil - may have something to do with, this. Ordinarily it wouldn't be so.</p>
<p>Say, Ollie, I forgot to say that the mould must be well soaked before you pour the cement. Fill the <sic>mould</sic> with water &amp; let it stand, say, 24 hrs. before you cast. Drain the <sic>mould</sic> before you pour the cement.</p>
Endless lvoe to all Three,
Dad.
