<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<figure/> 
Hotel Muehlebach 
Kansas City, Mo. 
Missouri Collection 
[October 10, 1938]
12
Monday Night 11 o'clock 
Dear Ladies:
This is for both of you. Had a lovely time this afternoon and evening. The University of Kansas City is a surprisingly beautiful place. It is, only five years old and was Built on the old Dickey estate - 60 acres of woodland. Really lordly. The faculty seems exceptional and I like the President. had dinner at his home - not as good a dinner as we usually have but good. The cocktail preceding it helped a lot. (You remember Mona, how lovely the ratty farms looked after you had that glass of beer last summer!) 
Had a darling audience - loto of old fans. They were eager for more and more, and 

-2- 
13 
when I was through a gang came up & insisted on several poems they liked. We had a second session with a smaller group, and there was a lot of autobiographing. I wished for old Sig. He would have loved that audience. 
Pres. Decker & his wife <del/> were fine. Mrs. Decker had a lot of jewelry, & she brought it out - stuff gathered in Europe and Asia. I was able to deutify some stories for her. She was much taken with your sapphire ring, Mona x Hers, with some diamonds, was not a match for yours. 
The informal affair with the Walter League 

14
-3-
group at Hotel President was a joy. About 30 people - picked - in a big hotel room. Bully time, and they hung on until 10 o'clock at the U. of K. C. the Pres. and the Head of the English Dept. asked if I'd come back for several days to lecture to classes. Of coruse I would! So I'll probably be back. 
After the Hotel President doings, I spent an hour eating Swiss cheese & drinking two stains of beer in the Rendezvous bar of the mucklebach - all alone. Darn it! All alone! 

15
-4-
Sig & you two should have been with me. Bright lights & ladies in glad rags & gents three sheets in the wind!! God, I was sober, and wished we were all together. Mama, you could have seen such pretty farms if you had been there!! And Max could have been much thinner than she'd drunk have you girl she was! been figthing much? ) 
I forgot to say, while I was talking about my loneliness at the Rendezvous, that I saw a lady a lot fatter than even you are, Mona! That lady was actually fat! The head waiter looked at her back & shook his head so solemnly that I wanted to howl

    <figure/> 
    Hotel Muehlebach 
    Kansas City, Mo.
-5- 
16
She must have had a godawful lots of cod liver oil in her time! I don't know where and when I'm going tomorrow, but I'll be on my way by noon. I'm looking forward to meeting old Sig. Too bad he couldn't be here. I was really sorry. 
(If you girls don't right, I'll bring you an apple apiece when I come back.) 
Tell Joan Grandan is going ot kiss her very hard when he gets back and tell Lame to be faithful to her victuals and get as strong as possible because Grandan is going to hug her awful hard x 

17
-6-
Have you got the same cat yet; <del/> and do you still call him George? 
We must plan to have you share some of these trips. It would have to be one at a time, which is too bad. But it would be more fun for us if there could be sharing. Maybe we can manage it before too long. 
Have I said anything? I'll bet I haven't said a thing except that I was thinking of home. 

18
-7-
maybe I mgiht jsut as well go to bed anyway. 
Endless love
from Jno. Dad. 
Next Morning
Mona, the enclosed check can other he banked or held till I come. I'm keeping the President cash for expense and emergency. Just had breakfast - no pancakes tenderly fashioned. 
Love again 
Jno Dad 
