<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
33e
9716 Hawthorne
Overland
Mo. 
October 18
1938
Dearest Mom: 
We were so happy to hear from you yesterday. 
Sunday was the ninth month of the second year of our marriage and so we celebrated. We left here at about one or two o'clock and headed in the general direction of Arthur's place (Ol's brother), as it was Mother's birthday and we were taking her a little soemthing and a bouquet of our swell flowers. Yes, we have the most gorgeous zinnias yet and even nasturtiums as well as some of the most fragile and delight-ful cosmos in many colors. Well, on the way, we saw the sign off old highway 66, "Jedburg, so many miles" and we decided to see where that went. If you remember, Mom, Thelma used ot lvie down there. however, the road has been imporived and it goes right by their farm now! We followed the road and got to the most hilly and Ozarky country you could imagine so close to St. Louis. It has built up down there into a real settlement, as people have club houses and things there now. It is right on Meramec and is called Lincoln Beach. We went up a huge mountain range and got way up on top of a hill and turned around then and went back down. It was so steep we had to go in low! It was quite an experience for us, for we didn't dream there were mts. like that so near here. We found the wildest place to picnic and will take the girls and Fritz there perhaps next Sunday. Wish you could all be along, for you'd certainly feel right at home there. We got that Ozark feeling in a big way. Finally we got out to Art's and had the swellest birthday dinner that Maude cooked. 
Now, comes the fun. Ol wrote the other day to Wayne, telling him about a lovely little farm right out here on Dorsett Rd. & McKelvey Rd. of about 8 acres with the dearest little house of four rooms and lots of coming trees. The house has electricity, but nothing else in the way of being modern. Has a well and a cistern. Ol said the water woudl have tasted better if only it had been below the toilet! It is well planted, having red raspberries and blackberries, fruit trees, lovely yard, trees; a garage and tool shed. The owner said he made $200 just off of his sweet potato crop last year. Well, we love this place; but feel he wants too much. We could probably get it for $4500. altho' he wants $5500. 
BUT--when we told Arthur about this, he said I'll sell you my place, which incidentally is modern in eery way except gas, for $6000. It has 8 acres too, just as good ground. And that place what I mean is built. There wouldn't be any additional expense with exception of digging a well there where there would be a lot of expense at the other place. You've seen the place. Remember how sweet it looks? Of course you did n't see the lovely yard. It has a brand new furnace too; a beautiful well built fireplace, etc. 

33f
-2-
We're going to wait till the first of the year, at which time Ol will know more about the stability of his job, which I think there's no doubt about, and then we are going to find a loan company which is interested in a place of the sort just for the investment and we pay them so much each month like rent and let what the farm makes for us to go into the buy-ing of the place. We would prefer the Dorsett place becuase it is just about 1/2 mi. from the carline. You see Ol would work as usual. However, he has two days a week off. Of course driving from Fenton would be quite a problem. And, then, too, the Dorsett place is fast rising in value and will in a few years bring us twice what we pay for it now. See the joke?? if you wanted to sell it when they start making a sub-division out of that country, which is certain, the way St. Louis is spreading. 
What do you think about this? It's fun anyway. We'd love to have our own place. 
Gee, it's gorgeous out here now. Wish Max were here to go walking with me. I don't like going alone. 
We're looking forward to your coming up Thanksgiving or if it's to be down there that's even better. But the girls woudlnt' get to go down, I'm afraid, if we had it down there. 
Ol and I got a lot of persimmons out at Art's yesterday. I packed a bunch and sent to Judge yesterday. I know it'll tickle him. 
Yes, I forgot to tell you about what we did yesterday, entirely. We got hungry before we got out to Art's, so we stopped at a place long the highway called the Red Coach and got a bottle of beer and best sand-which we'd eaten for ages. We just figured we hadn't been out together to a restaurant for so long that we'd just stop and have a little fun. After it'll never be 1 3/4 yrs. again! 
Mom, we'd appreciate it if you wouldn't mind packing that violin in papers real well and sending it to xxx us express collect, insured for $50.00, xxx as you mentioned. You may be assured that Fritz will take very good care of the violin, for he has a habit of taking too good care of everything including himself! Elaine will have plenty of violin left when she wants to start. I think ti will be grand if Joan plays the piano and Elaine plays the violin. 
What are you doing in the way of sculpture now? I hope, tho', tha tyou won't let it work you to death. You know even tho' you do some lovely things, your welfare is worth just tons more; so please don't get too worn out. We're anxious to see the figure you finished recently. 
I get so lonesome for you every once in awhile. All of a sudden I'll realize with a bang how long it's been since we've seen you, Mom! It just isn't right; but perhaps someday we'll all be together again. That's why it'dbe so nice to have Thanksgiving here--we'd all beto-gether for at least one day. 
Loads of love, always, 
Write soon. 
Enid 
<figure/> 
Ltos of o' love
to Max & the kids! 
