<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
136a
SIGURG NEIHARDT COLLECTION
Mount St. Joseph
MAPLE MOUNT, KENTUCKY
November 2, 1939.

Mr. Sigurd Neihardt,
Branson, Mo.
Dear Sigurd:
<p>You and your dear father have been in our minds and hearts over since the visit that meant so very much to us. It was as an oasis in as desert to get the benefit of your most <underline>beautiful</underline> interpretation of <underline>the beautiful</underline> in music and poetry. Each day as I appear before my students in English period they recall something about the program and ask some question showing the interest aroused. they have made comparisons to early AngloSaxon, Shakespearian, Spenserian and others epochs of poetry to that presented in your father's writings. We are to study his works thoroughly. In our Loboratory School the seventh and eighth grades were in the hall that morning; they ran to their classroom and immediately took the world book to see if they could find something about Dr. Neihardt and when they did they were delighted and took it to their instructor. She was so happy over their interest that she is reading your "Song of Hugh Glass" and tells the story to them and they are delighted. They want to know all about you both, so truly to say "To live in the hearts we leave behind is not to die." It is great to create something to live forever, for God will reward us if we serve our fellowmen as we read in "Abou Ben Adam."</p>
<p>We wish to thank you again and again for coming to us and I wish to say that always on our doorstep will be written "Welcome Dr. Neihardt, welcome Sigurd." Anytime that you are in our vicinity, let your home be "Maple Mount."</p>
<p>I am going to Cincinnati this week end for a Convention and I hope to hear some wonderful speakers but none will mean to me what your program did.</p>
<p>I am enclosing a few words of appreciation; it is just a thought. Change it any way to suit your cause, nothing I could say were it the most beautiful sentences in the world would give the true appreciation I fell, in fact, what we all feel.</p>
<p>The cut came, thanks a million, it will be returned in good time. Will be waiting for yours. I am sending you a clipping from the Owensboro Messenger about your program; please forward the paper to your father. If anything suits you better in that for your folder use it.</p>
<p>God bless and keep you both is my wish and prayer!</p>
Very gratefully,
Sister M. Josephine