<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20
SAINT LOUIS, M.O. 1
SEP 8
1030 PM
1940
Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
21
Home 6235 Southbend
2:30 Sunday
Dear Mama and Daddy,
<p>Here it's been a whole week and I've just gotten around to writing you now. However, I'm going to get some penny post cards which I shall mail you at lease every other day.</p>
<p>The pictures as a whole turned out very well. We shall send you some very soon. I am enlosing 3 pictures with this letter - 2 of which were taken on the So. Laker Party Picnic last July, and one of which was taken of my legs at the studio last Spring. I thought the latter picture would perhaps help you, Mama on your figure of the dancer. The leg to the right of the picture appeared to be a little too large at the top - larger than my legs actually are, because of something in the</p>
22
(2)
<p>lighting - also it is not quite turned out enough. The leg to the left of the picture is quite good and the foot as well. Perhaps this will help you in your modeling. Madame gave me my choice of two such pictures, so I took this one.</p>
<p>I started class on Sept. 4, Wednesday morning at 11:00. Madame said my work looks very good and that I lost <underline>very little</underline> during the summer, which I will very soon catch up on. Isn't that swell? Thursday and Friday I took lessons and practiced. Yesterday, Saturday morning Mueller's came after me and we went to the Jeffla Hall where the Women Auk of the Weekly People Club (So. Labor Party_ was to give a party that night to make up and practice</p>
(3)
<p>our dance. Kay Eihert danced with us and she arranged and taught us the dance to "Waltz of the Flowers." The floor was a waxed dance floor and very slippery, so during practice, I with rosin - covered toe shoes, slipped on a jete entrelasse and met the floor near the region of my right eye, <strike>and</strike> thus giving myself a "shiner." It really was good experience, for one never knows how a floor is going to be on the night, last nigh, we had our toe shoes covered with rubber on the soles, so we didn't slip and the dance went over very well. We had to do it halfover again as an encore. I went with Muellers and Hilda and Millie came on the st cars <gap = "cutoff"/></p>
<margins>In the afternoon</margins>
21
(4)
<p>in the evening entertainment <strike/>, we worked several hrs. on the dance. Then we drove to Mueller's and had lunch. They drove me home to dinner at 5:30. Millie was here to have a delicious Maxine-made dinner with us. We had steak, salad, green beans, beats, bread and butter, ice tea, and ice cream cookies brought by Millie. After dinner Mueller's came for me and we went over our dance mentally. Hil and Millie came a little late and we all sat at a table and had a grand time, real fun. Everyone was so jolly. At about 11:00 we did our dance and were applauded and applauded. Then we redressed adn rejoined the party - had a lovely</p>
23
(5)
<p>evening. Then I stayed overnight with Julia. Slept from 3 till 11:00 this morning and they stayed for dinner. Got home at about 1:30.</p>
<p>Sig and Max are now writing lecture letters <unclear/> have been doing all morning.</p>
<p>Madame said she got a lovely letter from you Mama. She <underline>does</underline> like you very very much, and I know you feel the same way toward her.</p>
<P>I'm going to work harder than ever this winter on my dancing.</P>
<p>Sig and Max and Hil are all so dear and sweet and considerate and the kiddies are</p>
24
<p>so darling that its swell to live with them.</p>
<p>Hil has gone on a Swiss picnic and we may go out to see Eny this afternoon.</p>
Loads of Love
Daddy and Mama,
<p>Madame says I'm looking very well again - all refreshed, etc. I feel so too, thanks to you and my marvelous vacation.</p>