<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
332 Fink Collection 107
pm July 10, 1942

Branson,
Darling Hilda and Albert:
<p>Thank you two dear, dear children for your letters - you certainly <underline>are</underline> busy!</p>
<p>Am enclosing letter from Electric Co - Is it not fine? I am so glad and <unclear>grate</unclear> for it. Will try to produce a Standard War Dep. Lampp for Black outs now!</p>
<p>In the mean while I have made the Seafoam piece useful for a floating Gardenia which is quite the thing</p>
108
2
<p>now, and makes the piece mroe beautiful too. This and the stump baby should sell - and I am getting them ready to send to the Original Art Co. in Chicago.</p>
<p>Hilda you have told me nothing hardly about Alice in person - what you did together etc. - and nothing about the dresses I sent you - Were they no good for you or Alice? Please tell me.</p>
<p>I Know you are busy - but I long to hear more <underline>de</underline></p>
109
3
<p>tails.</p>
<p>Amama is better, much. Daddy is so wonderful and good and sweet - Strange is it not, that he seems ever more wonderful and beautiful and fine the older we both get?! But <sic>no</sic> that is the truth, and as it should be. We 3 are bery happy together. I want Amama to dictate her memories to some one like you who could write them down and be understan-</p>
110
4
<p>ding - Daddy says they'd make most interesting reading! She is <underline>not</underline> too old - and maybe if we hold the thought and pray, it will yet be done. She should not live in a Hotel alone <underline>any more</underline>.</p>
<p>John had a lovely letter from Kemper expressing gladness that <underline>he</underline> would accept a position in an English Department, and saying they would write again. So we are hoping and praying. - Please send the en</p>
111
5
<p>closed letter for me with proper corrections or changes you may see fit to make.</p>
<p>Loads of Love - and you'll never Know how we looked and hoped for you on the Fourth!!</p>
<p>But we do understand too your not coming. Please tell Sig and Maxie to write. I have such a lost feeling when <underline>any one</underline> of you</p>
112
<p>children does not write to your devotedly loving</p>
Mama Mutti.