<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
33d
April 30, 1940
The Management of Neihardt Programs
Branson, Missouri
Dearest Mom;
<p>My - it seems ages since I wrote for time really flys here &amp; in traveling.</p>
<p>we had a nice time at Dr. Vinings in Montgomery. There was no hotel who could take us, they were all full up! It was Monday morning and not a pleasant time to interrupt a persons house - hold out all in all we did all right. I helped Mrs. V. maKe up beds and we had a pleasant time together. Dad will tell you the details of that when we are home.</p>
<p>Today I sat in class where the students asKed Dad questions and it was indeed inspiring. Just as fine as could be in every way. I did wish for you. The students liKed it. The professors did too and there were some fine questions asKed and Dad answered so beautifully and clearly.</p>
<p>Sig has had difficulty in getting practice enough here as so many students practice on the stage at the auditorium. I had a pleasant hour at Flora McDonald Hall with the house mother and one or two other ladies connected with the college. One had lived in India and had <sic>brot</sic> ivory &amp; jad into this country - evidently she Knew the real product. She was a lovely person.</p>
<p>The programs will be at 8:00 and a 30 minute reception will follow - afterward we start our trip to Berea, Ohio and will probably drive until we reach cleveland <sic>tonite</sic>. This is the only rush.</p>
<p>I have been so grateful for your letters full of details for I too thinK it Hell to not hear the small things taht mean so much. And Know that I am enjoying myself so very much and I certainly don't worry about the <sic>wubs</sic>, but I miss them and you.</p>
<p>Last <sic>nite</sic> we had a nice double cabin and a swell fish supper, buttered peas and potatoes. A good sleep helped and we got up early to be ready for todays stunt. <strike>we wanted to</strike> we felt we shouldn't have to pay $3 for a room at the Hotel to change clothes in so we again came to the cabin camp and for a dollar got this little cabin to dress in. So we feel quite virtuous.</p>
<p>Now to rest awhile and dress for the occasion I guess I'll wear the chiffon for it is very warm here, surprisingly warm for this far North.</p>
<p>I'll try to write again soon. Too bad about the wind storm there. Its raining here a little. 'Laine, "Mamma says <underline>not</underline> to dirty her nice clean pants <underline>any</underline> more or mamma will cry." Tell Joanie I wish I had a cooKie she made, and tell both I love them.</p>
<p>Sig sends love and thanKs galore to you for everything you're doing there. He's answering the letters pertaining to business now or he woudl write too. I'll let you Know later if we stay at Krieders.</p>
Loveing you, Mom dear.
Maxie.