<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
166A-<strike>167</strike> Finn Collection 5
Neihardt
Branson
Mo.
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F.Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis County
6
Darling Alice
<p>Our letters have crossed, and so I am hoping for <unclear>on</unclear> other one from your right soon.</p>
<p>I have still no answer to my question about Mme Vassan's Ozark-Baby. <underline>Do please</underline> let me know whether or not the people on <unclear>Enchil</unclear> sent <underline>her</underline> their copy or not. It would be so easy for you to drop in there for me and find out.</p>
<p>I know you must be having a terrible time with the cold. We here are not so col as you must be, but we are having much more than we like. The White River is frozen 8 inches all the way to the <unclear>Fornythe</unclear> Dam and looks like a shiny white strip of dense cloth - All our pipes are nicely frozen, and this morning Daddy drew water out of the well to heat, then he used some of it to thaw the <sic>cystern</sic> pump. It is terribly cold in our upstairs - and terribly uncomfortable, as you may remember. I have been indulging in a little sick spell -</p>
7
<p><unclear/>are from general disgust than any real organic trouble. Everyone here is so dear, but one and all of us went away from here worse than ever. There is a decided bit of progress about the big new dam, going on here now - there are several men in town who are boarding in Branson over seeing. So we hope that means action beginning soon - and that in turn would mean that we <underline>can</underline> sell. Also there is talk of Branson becoming the county-seat instead of Torsythe. Hollister has completely "disppeared" and there is talk of <unclear/> losing its Postoffice - So there you are with regard to your hometown, Alice dear!</p>
<p>I'd give a lot if things could workout so that we could all be united again in <underline>one</underline> place instead of spread out this crazy way. I still don't Know anything but Ollie's version of your New Years' night escapade! Won't you write me the facts? Always your loving Mama.</p>