<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
183
Aztec Court.
3821 EAST Central
Albuquerque,
N.M.
Dec 28th 1939
Darling Alice:
<p>Your good letter was here when we got our mail the first time. I have read it over a number of times, and feel as I always have done, how thoroughly worth while you are.</p>
<p>As for your expenses at Enids, they are at <underline>least</underline> #2.00 but of the #5.00 per week therefore, you should be able to save between 1 and 2 for extra expenses such as shoes, lose or other necessities as your life now goes, not? Please let me know how you are planning it Also please tell me it you received the yellow and white pair of blankets and the spread I sent Enid for your bed from Branson. I already know by my own experience how entirely generous and dear Enid and Ollie are - and I know you well enough, darling, to trust that you will give</p>
184
3.
<p>Enid a <underline>real lift</underline> in the work. I think it is swell of Ollie to let you wash the dishes and make you one of his family - so many men are <underline>other</underline>wise!</p>
<p>I am glad you consider Howard &amp; John more or less uninteresting - you should, <underline>if</underline> you want to attain your main goal; however you may change your mind some day, and if you do, I will understand you then too - and love you always, no matter <underline>what</underline> you may decide.</p>
<p>Daddy is already starting to write. We have a lovely home here with everything we like and need; Please write us to the above adress.</p>
<p>The air here is marvelous, the mountains on one side are so beautiful, changing contantly with light and cloud effects, yet so much a symbol of unchanging eternity. on the other side is the fertile valley of the Grand River and the vast desert beyond reaching to the</p>
185
4.
<p>Earth's rim.</p>
<p>We want our dream home to materialize here, built about a Patio where Sig and his famiy can live on one side, Dad and I on the other, but all of it together forming the Neihardt Home, <strike>to be divided</strike> <underline>one</underline> property, to be divided into <underline>4 equal</underline> parts, when Dady and I no longer are here, for our 4 children. We may leave much, and we may leave little - but whatever it may be will be divided equally between you four children. I hope that Daddy and I have suffered enough injustices to keep us from being so unjust with our 4. The devil likes to give those of mens' children who <underline>really believe</underline> in the higher values Hell on Earth, <unclear/></p>
186
<strike>4</strike>5.
<p>maybe this is why Daddy and I both have been treated the way we have by out mothers. Had we gone after <underline>material gain</underline> and <underline>abtained</underline> it, then they would have believed in us - but that sort of belief would not have been worth anythign to us. - of this no more -</p>
<p>I will write to Hilda next, and maybe you will share letters as now have 3 places to write to, and it is hard to repeat.</p>
Loving you all so very much always your own old
Mama.