<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
33a
PROGRAMS OF POETRY AND MUSIC
LYRIC AND DRAMATIC READINGS BY JOHN G. NEIHARDT
DISTINGUISHED AMERICAN POET, LITERARY CRITIC AND PUBLIC SPEAKER
WITH 
PIANO SELECTIONS BY SIGURD NEIHARDT
<line/>
THE MANAGEMENT OF NEIHARDT PROGRAMS

BRANSON, 
MISSOURI

August 13, 1939
Dear Dad and Mom:
<p>Today is Sunday and nearing lunch time. Hilda is practically finished with her packing, and is to leave on the 1:29 afteroon bus. She'll arrive St. Louis tonight about 11:30. She will stay at the Mayfair hotel until next evening. Then she plans to locate elsewhere.</p>
<p>After you folks left, we found your note about 'Laine. So far she has not been treeing any of us. We had Lache over for afternoon home-made ice cream party. Then in the evening he drove us out to Matt's Cabin.</p>
<p>It is very warm here now. Perhaps you two are into some hot weather up there. That cool wave must-have quit us.</p>
<p>There has not been any important mail sofar. May be in a day or two, in which care I'll forward.</p>
<p>I do hope your trip has been enjoyable to date and that it will continue to be so. No reason why you shouldn't have a very nice little spree out of it, and soem cool evenings to enjoy. We are not at all worried about anything, and are looking forward to hearing all about the affair in Bison.</p>
<p>There is really so very little to write about, excepting that we all send loads of love and happiest thoughts to you.</p>
<p>There is really so very little to write about, excepting that we all send loads and happiest thoughts to you.</p>
<p>Please let us hear quite often, all about everything.</p>
<p>By the way, soon I can write you a note on our very classy new stationery. It has been approved and ready to be in print when the Sunrise bond paper arrives from Sears tomorrow.</p>
<p>We will do our best to hold expenses down as well as possible.</p>
<p>Elaine and Joan are being nice. Of course 'Laine is ruler of the roost, and manages to start a quarrel once in a while.</p>
<p>Must stop for just now. I shall be looking for further mailing intructions; that is, pertaining to where we can reach you <underline>after</underline> you leave Bison.</p>
Always our love for you two,
<signed>Sig.</signed>
Sig, Max, Joan, Elaine, Alice &amp; Hilda.