<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
18a
9716 Hawthorne 
Overland
Mo. 
October 10 
1938 
Dearest Folks: 
Mom, it was grand to get that dandy letter from you a while ago. I haven't written sooner to either of you because there just hasn't been much news here. 
It was great to see Sig again last week. I was getting supper and just about to fry the meat and I heard a noise at the back door and kitty ran as if scared. I tho't it was the dog next door, for it often comes over and scares Mitzy nutty; but, thrills, it was Sig! Then Ol came home just about ten minutes afterward and we all had a nice little chat at supper. Then Sig went into town to stay with Hil and Al over night. We had a card from him this a.m. from Galesburg, Ill. 
Yesterday Ol and I took Hil and Al in the rumble seat for a picnic. They insisted on bringing all the food. however, I did make some devil-ed eggs and some coffee. We went out to Creve Coeur Lake where there's a very nice camping place this side on Marine Ave. Remember the road? We used to go on it in the old Buick! We had a lovely time. On the way back we stopped to see the kids' apt. Since it has been painted, new curtains installed and a new innersping mattress on the bed. They really have a lovely little place there. You'll like it, Mom. 
Tonite, I'm going in and stay all nite with the kids, as Ol will be out of town again. He's going to Urbana, Ill. On a couple stories at the university there. 
Tonite I'm going in and stay all nite with teh kids, as Ol will be out of town again. He's going to Urbana, Ill. on a couple stories at the university there. 
Yesterday we bought some little crab apples. I'm making some preserves like you used to make, Mom, remember? Going to take the girls some when I go in. I have about five shirts to iron in a minute. I love to do it, though. I'm doing all the laundry, you know. It saves money, keeps me busy, and Ol likes his shirts better the way I do them. 
We had a lovely visit with Ol's mother. She stayed from Saturday until Wednesday last. She said she had a very enjoyable time iwth us and is com-ing back in the near future. She said it's so nice to have our place to come to, for sometimes she goes to bed and just cries out there. You see, she feels more at home with us! Even tho' she doens't know me very well. She thinks I'm okay and thinks I'm doing wonderfully well in every way. She's a sweet person. Never thinks of bothering you like most mother-in-laws do. Ol and I feel most fortunate in our mothers-in-law! 
What's this I hear about the possibility of you all being here on Thanks-giving? I hope you do decide to come up--all of you. Since Dad has an engagement around that time, we could have the Thanksgiving here at our place. 

18b 
-2-
We can put boards in our table, you know. Ol and I were figuring the thing out last nite, and we, with Hil and Al helping in the sheltering problem, can take care of the whole mess! I do wish we could do this. Because we should be together on Thanksgiving. You know I have a window seat in the bedroom that is well upholstered and one of the kids could sleep on it. Studio couch takes care of two or three and the spare bed takes care of two, as affectionate as Ol and Me, anyway. 
Glad Joanie had such a nice birthday. The birds are singing and the leaves are falling. There's a mystery in the air. I agree with Max, I love the fall. 
Must write to Max now, so will close. 
Dad, Ol andI will have a letter at Wayne for you and Sig when you get there. But write us in the meantime, won't you? 
Mom, I do hope you'll be coming up here soon now. There's nobody at our place now and I'm changing the sheets on the guest bed! So come on up for awhile. 
Loads of love always, 
Enot 
Enid (Enot) 
& Ol 
Mom - It's just been too long since we've seen you! Why don't you come up? 
The latest is that I've practically quit smoking. Trying it out for a month - and believe it's quits for good! 