<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<del>713 714</del> 
Fink Collection 
September 26, 1928
67
Neihardt Branson Mo 
Mr & Mrs O. F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne Ave. 
Overland, Mo. 

September 26 
68 
Dearest Children
Your letter was eagerly read Enid dear, not only for news from you but for a bit from my two babies who are so busy. Hilda is being very considerate and is writing every week but Alice did not write htis week at all and naturally I wonder if just being busy is the answer, or if she might be sick too. ? I'd be so glad if you real-ly could see those two sisters oftener. I should think you could combine your duty to Francis with a burried "peep". 

69
at our girls! 
Those are most interesting stories of Ol's - you surely know how to hold my interest for one - I always enjoy hat you say Ollie - and most es-pecially I enjoyed your Pfister.- Please continue to send them here. I'd like to pass a few on to Dick, who seems to have discovered lately that blood is thicker than water - and I am glad for the consequent result, ie: he writes to me! I hope he continues. - - Most interesting to hear Hitler over the Radio today! I wished for Hilda to be listening in with me! 

3
70
Daddy's and my German blood pounded in our veins as we heard that mar-velous man of a marvelous people state clearly and simply what he intended to do - And what was that? No more or less than an old hen would do for her own distressed chickens. He wants Germans to again belong to Germany as they do by rights, and as they did before the crazy Versailles Treaty - I must say his talk was to the point not senti-mental but yet full of the real old German sense of justice mixed with underlying sentiment for his 

4
71
ace.-
Daddy and Sig leave for Warrensburg tomorrow - and I am hoping I don't forget to pack something - you know how I always feel! 
Daddy is carving an ivory ring now, and he will put a Jade <unclear/> in it - Swell?! he is planning to have a Lapidary whell in his shop this Winter! 
We all are very happy - all we need is to be closer in touch with you and the girls. 
Jed Smith is progressing mar velously; the first part is done. "A goading purpose and creeping pace."--
I am hoping to be in St Louis 

72
in November - I figure I can't stand it any longer - but if Daddy has a Nebraska Branson, Mo., Sep. 21, '38 trip at that time which makes it impossible - then I'll be see ing you sooner. So glad you have a room for guests - I know how good that makes one feel. 
Daddy sends the enclosed! I am tickeled over Ollies' new clothes - A woman can get along without new things, (as we know!) but a man cannot, and should not, no matter what other thing you may skimp one. - You are a 

6
73
dear to manage the way you do, but that is your duty as well as your plea sure! 
I certainly hope the P.D. conti-nues to change things around and that obligates a raise - why not? I believe he will - Don't forget Enid darling, that thoughts are things - They are powerful - and have a way of breeding "chips from teh old block," so face the future with cour-age and the belief that Good will come to you and to Ollie - 
Always loving you - 
Mama Mother. 
<del/> <del/> 