<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
71 Petri Collection 106
Sunday, Dec. 7
[1941]
Dearest Daddy and Mama!
<p>This heavenly day! Alice is arranging roses - three dozen of them - in a basket. Albert is studying, and now I shall write to you. I wish I knew how you, Daddy, are feeling. I wish we could see you both now.</p>
<p>It looks as if we (Alice and I) may get to move today from here to our new home. We are buy8ing a bedroom set. Sig and Maxie are planning to get other things for the home. Some things, of course, we already have, and some Sig and Max just bought. We (Alice, Albert &amp; I) went yesterday</p>
107
2
<p>to a railroad salvage place where one can buy fine <underline>new</underline> furniture for 1/2 price or even less. It is unclaimed freight. <strike>W</strike> I went first to Langan's and found to my pleasnt surprise that we can get the same or better things <underline>new</underline> at the r.r. salvage house for less than the used sets at Langan's! This is an unattractive store on Seventh street, but what loads of fine furniture! I am making my decisions today and plan to get the furniture tomorrow or the next day.</p>
<p>Albert wants to know when "he is going to get to move in" with us. I do have to tell him something.</p>
-
-
<p>It is now Monday morning. we moved yesterday to our lovely new home. We were fortunate that we could leave Mrs. Uthoff's when we wanted to; she rented our rooms. Our new place will be swell. You'll be amazed, I'm sure, what a really large, airy <underline>home </underline>we have.</p>
<p>Albert says I have to make a decision soon or (jokingly?) he will take matters into his own hands. He thinks we should plan to be married in Dr. <unclear/>'s church the end of January. I wish you would help me and tell me what you think. It</p>
106
<p>does seem silly to go on in this indefinite way any longer. Albert has, as you know, always of his own accord liked the idea of our all being together, so there would be no change far as that is concerned.</p>
<p>I'm sorry this is so sketchy. We are rushing off now (after a lovely dinner). I'm going to a lesson, Sig to the store, &amp; Max to Cont. Concerts.</p>
Endless lvoe as ever,
Hilda
<p>We are all trying to plan for your being here for a while from Xmas on. Could that not be arranged?</p>