<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Piper Collection 
<del/> 11
UNITED STATES POSTAGE <figure/> 2CENTS2 
DEC 31 PM 1920 
Miss Mildred PIper 
Lyons 
Nebraska 
from 
Box 145-Branson Mo. 

12
JOHN G. NEIHARDT 
Branson Mo. 
<del>BANCROFT, NEBRASKA</del>
My Dear little girl; 
your good letter and the thotful package reached us as you intended and my dear we did so appreciate it. Mona was sick before leaving Bancroft and she has been so sick ever since. That left me "chief cook and bottlewasher" no little job I assure you. But you can see how our christmas went aside from a tree for the children. I know packages at christmas never did look so good to me as they did this year. Many thank my dear many thanks. I am going to tell you that Mona is in the "family way" again, the cause for this sick spell. Mom I have something 

13
else to say. My little four room Bungalo will soon be started and by the time the school year is over I will be in it and can't you come here? Just count your trip here your summer expense and that will be much cheaper than other summers. If you are going to teach the will make your clothes and if you were to ^be married she can mek your wedding clothes and much cheaper than you could hire it done at home I won't make company of you. Will just do as we please. go to the Lake, fish, tramp been the mts. and we need nothing but big strong shoes and a dress taht will <unclear/> the wear. 

14
now think of this, it is no fool plan and I know of no one outside of my own girls I want so much. I won't' join much but when I know more about my house will tell youjust how I know I am going to have a living dining room in one. 21x13 feet with a double fire place in the middle one half in the bed room back of it there will be rainy evenings when we can live in bed and visit by the fire place fire. - There I am rambling on just as tho you would care to spend a summer with an old lady just turned 63 But if you should she would be dutifully 

15 
happy. 
Now it is time to get a Thursday dinner for Dec 30-1920 but will not forget to wish you Every thing good for the new year with love just bushels of it. 
remember me to your people. And wont' you go into the Gatea girls someday and tell them where I am and that Iwill write soon
good life
Alice M. Neihardt 