<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
54 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 47
March 5, '43
Dear Sig &amp; Max:
<p>First, many thanks for the two bucks! I've just came up form pretty deep under, or I'd have written sooner.</p>
<p>I ahd thought often that you might be needed badly at some foreign air-field, Sig; but, at worst, you wouldn't be walking against machine-guns &amp; tanks. You'd be d- well protected, if at all possible. Of the three places you mention, I hope it's <hi>Brazil</hi>. that would be a <hi>real</hi> break. There is right now a great new westward movement in Brazil (like our old West) and there'll be a huge boom there after the war, according to the wise ones - dislocated peoples migrating &amp; settling there in the vast empty country. You'd be <hi>on the spot and in fine position to take advantage of great possibilities. Presque Isle would be lonely &amp; rather gloomy, it seems - and no future. If you get a choice, <hi>do</hi> take Brazil. Maybe they'd transport your family <hi>there</hi>.</p>
<p>Wumberly's group (with <unclear>Stephanek</unclear>!) is bearing down on Gov. Griswold in my interest. The idea is to bring N- back to Neb in some state position, pending Sheldon's retirement. I'd like it.</p>
(over)
48
<p>Outside the murder &amp; destruction industry, jobs are god awful scare &amp; getting carcer. Paul Scott Mowrer of the Chicago Daily News <hi rend="strike_through"/> tried hard to <hi>find</hi> or make a please for me up there. No go. Lawrence of the Lincoln Star is trying, but he's with the group &amp; mentioned. I can get around fairly well now, altho' I dare not be careless; and I'll be after anything here. There's a chance for instructing at Washington <unclear/>.</p>
<p>The other trouble I've had all winter will hardly get really well, I'm afraid. It's very weakening; but there'll be a way - especially of Lincoln comes through. This is the hardest winter I've experienced, but I haven't been blue, &amp; refused to be. At the worst, I've lived a complete &amp; very fruitful life <hi rend="strike_through"/> already, and I'm profoundly grateful for the privilege to do what has been done. I <hi>do</hi> want to keep Mama happy. She is somebody most decidedly, and a real comrade. Bless her.</p>
<hi>Pettings for the dear little ladies</hi>, and love to each and all of you,
Dad Gaki
<p where="margins">I'll be gald if you can see Latham, Sig.</p>