<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
108
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Lock Haven
June 25th 40
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>The wonderful formal outfit simply stuns your old Mother! How is it possible that you, Ollie dear, should have wanted Enid to make me such an exquisite gift? And how could you, Enid girlie, have done such a lovely job? You may be sure Daddy will buy me the evening gloves you speak of, and I already have black potent leather sandals - so I will be dressed beautifully from my skin out! You are a wizard with your fingers Enid, and Ollies and your own heart cannot be beat</p>
109
2
<p>en in this or any other world! I am thrilled and will treasure this gift until I am able to wear it and never cut it down, because it is altogether too adorable. I have the rose <sic>quatz</sic> necklack along too, which you suggested I should wear with it. How altogether perfect!! To misquote Daddy:"Your love clings beautiful about me" Bless your dear hearts - adn many many thanks to both you darling children.--</p>
<p>I have just cleaned up in our little cabin. Daddy is in his private study, the car, writing. We had a wonderful breakfast and I have teh dishes washed and dinner planned: asparagus, tomatoes, new potatoes adn strawberries! - and now have time to write you adn Maxie this morning.</p>
<p>We are in a quiet retreat till Wednesday afternoon, getting well rested from the trip. The affair here is in the morning. So I shall wear my white suit. I have a shiny balck hat and the sandals I mentioned already - and the lovely bag you</p>
110
3
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>made me a year or so ago. So I feel I will be properly dressed. We may be invited somewhere for eveing, but I doubt it. We will be at a good Hotel here for one night before the affair, because Daddy feels he should be able to telephone from a good address, which is of course the proper thing to do when you are being paid $100.00 for a convocation <strike>address</strike> talk. This will be Thursday AM - after which we go to Shippensburg, Pa. for a similar affair. We will spend about a week in some quiet place, where Daddy can write and where we hope to get a weekly rate. So far we</p>
111
4
<p>have had to pay $1,50</p>
