<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
15 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 40
[August 3, 1940]
<p>Thanks to you Max and Hilda for the good time you gave us with you!</p>
Always devotedly
Mom 
Mutti
Nannie
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Dearest Children
<p>Just a note today to tell you that we arrived in fine shape - and that the house was so full of you darlings, that the absence of you <strike>because</strike> was too heartachy to Keep my promise to Joan <underline>not</underline> to cry! But I immediately began to put things in order and dispel the loneliness that made the tears come. So today noon I am feeling</p>
41
<p>quite constructive, and happy. I will have the big back room in readiness for one of you adn the small front room as well for any two of you - and maybe some morning I'll awaken to find you here! <underline>Whoever can</underline> come down <underline>any</underline> weekend, without even telling us beforehand please, please <underline>do so</underline>.</p>
<p>Alice, you adn the babies having been here <underline>last</underline> - left the sorest places! I'll write you all a little later when there is more to say. Thanks so much for all your goodness Sigurd! I'll be using the varnish as soon as it quits raining</p>
42
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>This letter starts <underline>any</underline> place and ends every where!</p>
<p><unclear>Mon Daisy</unclear> was so dear to Keep the Wubs Saturday evening for a couple of hours while Millers took us to the Show!</p>
<p>Joanie wanted to be sure that we would come after her and bring her Home that <underline>same</underline> night - She is like Sig was in that respect, Bless them!</p>
M.
43
<p>Joanie's letter to Mama</p>
000
N4NNNNM
<p>MAMA         ACOEFOR  KLNNNNMMNDU  VVVVVV
VUTSRPO N        MLLLLLLLL         LLLLLKJMFFFFF     FEDCBA.94321&amp;ZYXWW VUTS
                                  P OPONMLKJIHGFE R RRRRR
?4&amp;ZYXMVUTSSRQONMLKK&amp;ZYXWVUUTSSRQPSRQPPDCBJIHHGFEDB.0987651322
PONMNOPQPQRSTVUTSSRRQPONMLLLLLLLLKJKLHGFE0000000000000000000007
C CBONOCCCBB BDEFGHIJKLMNNOPQRSTUVWXYZ&amp;1234 56789000YXWNNNN</p>
NUT S R QPNP33