<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
51a
9716 Hawthorne 
Overland
Mo. 
October 24
1938
Dearest Dad & Mom & the Family:
The birthday telegram arrived at just the opportune time yesterday afternoon at about 4:30 when we were all seated around the table with the loveliest chocolate birthday cake and candles that Hilda and Alice brought to me. I cannot say how much that meant to me as well as to all of us to have those lovely thoughtful words from you. Thanks a lot! 
We spent the day at a new picnic place Ol and I found last Sunday. I think I wrote,you about it, Mom, in my last letter. It's an entirely new place where none of us have been--on the Ries Road just off of old 66 in Ballwin. The country there is like the Ozarks. We found the nicest sunny spot in a little valley and built a fire and had our picnic. We took some pictures and did some hiking and then on the way back stop-ped by the place that we want to buy on Dorsett Rd., as Hil and Al wanted to see it. They seemed to think it was swell. We like it a little bet- ter each time we see it. Alice & Francis rode in the rumble seat with blankets around them and Hil, Ol and I sat in the front. We had a lovely time, andthe only way the birthday would have been perfected would have been to have had you all with us! We missed you! I know I did for one! But it isn't long till Thanksgiving and we're all looking forward to that time with eagerness. After all, it's been a long, long time since we've seen you, Mom, and Max and the kids; we haven't seen enough of Dad and Sig either! 
Ol came home Sat. p. m. with all sorts of things, some to eat and some to use! To eat were xxxxxxx three delicacies of which I'm very fond, and which we don't get to have often, mushrooms, avocado and wine! He brought a lovely plant jar xx in which he planted a lovely orange marigold out of our yard and brought it in to me! It was the loveliest thing I've ever seen, I believe. The jar was a powder blue! I still have it here in the window. But not the same jar as originally, because while out of the room the cat got up on it formeanness and tipped the jar over, breaking it into a million pieces! Well, I couldn't get over it all evening and neither could Ol. However we replanted it. We both chased the cat all over the basement, finally giving up. She doesn't usually do such nasty things. Wehad been thinking of getting a large rug for the living room, and so I told Ol to consider it a birthday present, which he didn't want to do, as he said that was for the house. But I convinced him that I'd rather have that than anything else, such as a dress or something. Well we went down to Aalco on Lindell and got a perfectly lovely and neat looking rug for about $10.00. It's a lovely design with dark brown, cream, and green colors predominating. Hilda & Alice gave me a pair of hose which I always am happy to have! Wasn't that some birthday! 
We have taken in all of the plants of any worth and are keeping them in the sunroom. We have the two geraniums, the two lilies, the four or five pineapples, two ferns, a pandana plant, the marigold, a begonia and two ageratum, some parsely, and trying to grow an avocado plant from a seed! 

51b
-2-
I keep one of the ferns on the walnut chest in the dining room and the other in the living room to the right of the fireplace by the little window. So when you come, you may prepare yourself to see a greenery here. We like plants all over the house. We're going to pot one of the plants for Hilda and Alice. They don't want many, but there was one they were interested in. Oh, yes, We got a couple different kind of ferns when we were out yesterday and I'll have those too. 
Now, here's some really good news. The Guild has fixed it with Pulitzer that those receiving Ol's salary from Nov. first on have to be given 12 months pay ahead if they are discharged for any reason. This means that now if Ol should get fired, which he won't, as they ahve made the statement that there's to be no change in the staff of the P-D at present, he will receive $700. Ol and I got to thinking it might not be bad to be fired!! Isn't this great? By the way isn't it grand about Hilda's raise? She's really doing well, and we're so happy about it. She called us up and told us last week, immediately after she found it out. 
Mom, we would love to come down Xmas, and will try our best. We'd like to bring Fritz down with us. The only thing is that we might have to hurry away. We could come down to be there Xmas day anyway. Ol could get the Monday after Sunday off and leave here early Saturday afternoon. That way we'd get to Branson late Sat. nite and be there all day Sunday, starting back Mon. a. m. I'm thinking that he'll be able to get more days though, as they owe them to him. It would surely be a grand idea. 
Did Dad get our letter to Wayne? Dad, how about another letter from you?! 
Thanks a lot too, Mom, for seeing that we get that little violin. Fritz is seemingly anxious to start studying, altho' you can never tell how long he'll stick to it! He likes to read a lot now, I  understand. Reads every thing he can get his hands on. 
Looking forward with joy to seeing you all on Thanksgiving, 
With lots and lots of love, always, 
Enot Enid Eny Enid 
or whatever you call me. 
Ol is tickled to death we're going to do a little celebrating on Thanksgiving here, too! Sends his love. 