<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
23
[Saturday, Aug. 27, 1937]
Dear Mamma, 
Thanks very much for the letters and also for the way in which you fixed my dress. The letter fits quite nicely. I am sure I shall like it very well. 
I am certainly sorry about Daddys feeling bad be-cause of Aunt Lus letter. I cant imagine what she ex pects from him now-perhaps shes only jealous! Also, I cannot see why she is going to sell Grandmas house, un-less she needs the money. Anyway, Isuppose it really doesnt matter. 
It has been swell to have Daddy here with us, even though it isnt quite so nice for him, considering his teeth-pulling episode! Please do come with him in November, wont you Mamma? We all really miss you terribly although we wouldnt have you stay in St. Louis for any-thing in the world because we know you are very happy in Branson and couldnt be so here. 
Mom, Hilda took the proofs back, and, in addition, saw that the following change is to be made on the finished picture: the dress is to be made a deep rose and the white flowers are to be colored red as well! The refer, the Fines of the dress will be made good, for the only bad lines will be removed. Isnt that correct? Did-nt you you think the pictures were good otherwise? Y ou didn't say anything about that in your letters, so Id dont know what to think. We three here all thought they were good, but Hil and Betty both chose a different one from the one you and Max chose tehy chose the more serious one with the closed lips and faint smile. However, their second choice was the one you chose for first. The pictures H be ready September 2 I can hardly wait to see how they come out! (Or, rather, how it comes cut!) 
Our apartment is very nice. Mama It will be much nicer than rooming nad boarding, and just as cheap why room and board? 
Yesterday Daddy went out to Enids and Ollies for lunch, and then stayed overnight with them. We three here had a delicious dinner of macaroni a la fromage de la creme a la Betty-sait-tu? Anyway, it was very good and we also had oramed cabbage, spinach, and grapes. 

24
Then after dinner we listened to Major Bowes. We heard a twelve year old baritone on that program who was truly remarkable not only because f his voice, but also because of his unusual personality and talents in otherlines. He sang "Thats why Darkies were born! so beautifully that telephone calls some pouring in for an encore and he sang again. After the program, we walked up to the <del/> Tivoli theatre where we saw two extremely good pictures. They were The Rage of Paris with DanielleDarrieux in "Mayeriling", dont you? ), and "Always Goodbye" with Bar-bars Stanwyok and Herbert Marshall. Both were much above average. After the show we walked home as rapidly imposs-ible. then got ready for bed and went to bed. 
Wednesday was a very hot day here, but day before yesterday evening a cool breeze brought relief, and since then it has been quite comfortable. Day before yesterday oven-ing Daddy, Betty, Hilda, and I sat out in the back yard and watched the stars and felt the wind spring up. We thought how queer it was that all of you in Branson were seeing those very stars! 
I had quite good lesson Wednesday morning - that is, it was better than usual. This afternoon I shall go to the studio about three oclock in order to practice A couple of hours before by lesson, which is at six thirty this evening. 
Sunday afternoon Hilda, Betty, and I went walking in the park. We took a roll of very good pictures, which we will send you if you want us to do so. On the way sok we stoopped at the store on Hamilton and bought beer, op-si-ooli, Braunschweiger, salami, rye bread, potatoe chips, and then we fasted!
Loads of Love,
Alice 