<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
104
40 
Neihardt Branson Mo 
BRANSON OCT21 2 PM 1938 M.O. 
<FIGURE/>
Mrs. O. F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne Ave 
Overland, 
St. Louis County 
Mo. 
Folks arrived last night O.K. 

Thursday P.M. 
41
Enid darling: 
Your letter about your little farm home on Dorsette Road is thrilling - Yes you shoudl under no circumstances pay rent as you will remember my attitude has always been. I think it so wonderful that you and Ollie both like the idea of a little farm Home - and two days out of every week are plenty for Ollie to do the work on such a place tha tyou could not do. And oh, the fun of it all. I think when you are "wise and three as youw ill be in 3 months you will 

42
probably have started the new life. You are so good at planning and being care ful with money that I'm sure you'll make a success of it - But before that time, comes your own dear birth - day, my Enid darling - Words cannot tell you how dear you are to me and how much that is good I wish for you in this new year. I hope you and two girls will be together Sunday and that you will all have a most happy day. We are looking for Daddy and Sigurd tomorrow. They have had a won-derful time everywhere and a recep-tion at Mr Burke's hosue in Bancroft. I am so eager to see them back. 
I woke up Tuesday 

43
morning with John saying to me "I want to tell you Mona that I'm going to trade in the car" - so I jumped up and repeated my vivid dream to myself - later in the day I forgot to tell Max - but hte next day it came to me and I told Max. She looked so queer and I said "Well, what do you know about this that I don't know"? She said I know nothing but Sig told me in yesterday's letter not ot mention this but Dad was thinking about getting a new car. Funny? However I am hoping he will not do anything like 

44
that now - but I've got a hunch he is planning to do so sooner than I would want him to - maybe in Kan-sas City on his way home. You know how Sig is about new cars! 
My Baby 'Laine is in cement in the plaster mold now, am watching for Daddy to help set it up - 
I am re doing Mr Good at present - but have been varnishing and painting a lot lately instead of sculping. 
I do so want to see you. Maybe I can soon - - we are planning to come up Thanksgiving and you must be here Xmas, please 
Loads of love to you two 
Mom - Mother. 