<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
199-200-201-<strike>202</strike> Fink Collection 51
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
DEC30
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson
Overland, Mo.
52
<p>Do you listen to Fosdick Sunday afternoons - 3 o'clock, Nat-Broadcast? <underline>Please do</underline>.</p>
53
BRANSON, MISSOURI
See--
WHO'S WHO IN AMERICA
COLUMBIA ENCYCLOPEDIA
EVERYBODY'S ENCYCLOPEDIA
WEBSTER'S UNABRIDGED DICTIONARY
MACMILLIAN'S DICTIONARY, ETC.
Dearest Enid &amp; Ollie:
<p>There is not any news - but just the desire to feel close to you prompts this note. We are all getting along nicely. Joanie has 5 blocks made - on that comforter top! Daddy has a lot more lines and I have new points correctly fitted in to the composit that makes John Neihardt's face so interesting!</p>
<p>I am getting a new woold skirt and two blouses to wear with it. It is the flaring type of skirt - swell, not?</p>
<p>Today Mrs Mayclen sent us a whole pint of heavy whipping cream - was it welcome?!</p>
<p>I baked a huge baking of bread and an apple pie than which</p>
54
<p>there <sic>ain't</sic> nothing better!!</p>
<p>What do you pay for prunes? We have to pay 18 cents for a tiny package. Maybe we will soon go to Springfield again and then we can get somethings in the way of groceries.</p>
<p>We are having grand weather. Our George-Kat is a huge fellow and very beautiful - do you care for him? He sure eats a lot.</p>
Loads of Love always
to you two wonderful dear
people from
Mama. Mother
55
MR.
MRS.
O.F.FINK
<figure/>
JOAN
FOR <sic>HERDEARUNCLE</sic>
OLLY
DEAR AUNT
ENID
56
<p>I LOVE MY BETTY
LOVE
YOU WE BE SO
GOOOD TO GIVE HER TO ME i THANK YOU</p>
57
<picture>Neil Villa May Martha Lu</picture>
<p>Merry Christmas from the McDonalds</p>
58
Dear Uncle John &amp; Aunt Mona:- 
and Hilda and Alice:-
<p>Wouldn't it be grand to have a big get together &amp; get acquainted. Here a two you don't know and my the Neihardts Villa May doesn't know and even three or four I don't know and the rest I haven't seen for years.</p>
<p>We will be in Minneapolis for Chirstmas with our families. Suppose you will all be in Branson for yours.</p>
Love Neil &amp; Villa May.
