<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
160 Fink Collection 187
December 29, 1939
Neihardt
3821 E. Central
Albuquerque, N.M.
ALBUQUERQUE
DEC 30
3 -PM
1939
N.MEX.
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland, 
Missouri
(St Louis Co.)
188
3821 E. Central 
Outer Rim of the Moon.
Dec. 29, 39.
Dear Enat, Oddie and Alice:
<p>Just rec'd a lovely long letter from you all about the happy time you had together on Christmas eve and Christmas day. That sort of feeling justifies the custom. We were caught in a heck of snow storm on the high plains of the Texas Panhandle on Xmas morning, and were snowbound in Amarillo that and the next day. It was sort of fun, tho. The storm hit us about 80 or 90 miles east of Amarillo, and the visibility was bad, owing to the fog with flying snwo, often decreasing for minutes to no vision at all - just a white night. The road made it thicker. But we reached Amarillo safely in 7 inches of snow, skidding along at a funeral pace, everybody in a good humor. First had bacon, eggs, and fresh potatoes for Xmas dinner. The snow storm made it taste wonderful. Think you're smart, eating duck, don't you?</p>
<p>There was snow here at Albuquerque. It ended at the Sandia mountains which lie just east of the city. We are in a lovely cabin with automatic gas heat and everything <unclear>corkingly</unclear> nice. Mama is already a big fat slob, and I have a</p>
(over)
189
<p><unclear/> chin on the back of my neck. Mama is getting so heavy I'm afraid she'll wear her rump out riding hom in February.</p>
<p>Racing across the desert several hundred under back, we saw the darlingest little cuss of a <sic>kiote</sic>. He was being a <sic>kiote</sic> so hard that he didn't see us, and came bounding across within a foot or two of the car. I had to step on the brak and swerve a bit to keep from running over him. I've thought about him a lot. If the little fool only knew it was Gaki in the car, and I could have gotten out and petted him!</p>
<p>We've been looking at properties in the afternoons. Saw some very <underline>nice</underline> ones at reasonable prices. But this city is growing like a skin disease. Scads of residences going up. The city has <underline>doubled</underline> in population since 1930! Why, God knows. But it's eating its way fast and raggedly toward the mountains eastward. No smoke here - natural gase. Very stimulating air, of course. And, as the gals remember, a weird sort of country.</p>
<p>I'm about to begin actual writing again. Am ready, &amp; way get lines in the morning.</p>
<p>Enat &amp; Oddie, call it $2 a week for groceries. Seems kinds of nuts to pay so damned little; but it's not paying.</p>
Mama &amp; I kind of liek you three, and Hiddy too.
Dad.
