<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
189 Fink Collection 33
BRANSON
AUG1
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F. Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis
County.
34
1
Darling Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your letters are <underline>always</underline> a pleasure to receive - but your packages are even more of a treat! You have such a sweet way of remembering to remember, Enid!</p>
<p>As for the dress I left in your closet I <underline>did</underline> love it, although I Know it looks better on you than it could look on your mother who is yellowed with age! The light blue brings out that fact too much - So I am very happy over the exchange. The stronger color is good for <underline>me</underline>, and aside from the color</p>
35
2
<p>it is a splendid style. I shall Keep it to put on when I accompany Daddy to town in the car, which is quite often.</p>
<p>You'd love our garden now. The deep rose and pale pink Roses of Sharon bushes meet in a Gothic effect over the Pool entrance - and looks like a crown of roses over the baby's head. I now have the proper colors all around. Blue Ageratum in the West. White baby Zinnias in the North, pink Petuniras on the East, and yellow baby Marigolds on the South. It has never been so pretty! Your cannas are getting big and strong and so are the Zinnias.</p>
<p>The Morning Glories are</p>
36
3
<p>thriving and by Fall should cover the entire back fence with blue and red blooms.</p>
<p>We are enjoying Alice so much, in fact she is a spiritual prop for her old Mama who does not always see the Light, besides a strong helper! The babies are growing brown by slow stages, wearing playsuits instead of dresses and pants, which aside from being nicer in this very hot weather, reduce the enormous washing and ironing propositions considerably. We all go to the creek regularly - Elaine is won over, but Joanie is still struggling with her fear of bugs, of tons of water of butterfliers, of every</p>
37
4
<p>thing under the Sun - so we are letting her "be", and hope she will soon be out of her troubles which she has to overcome herself. She seems to enjoy going along in teh car and watching the others dive and swim  - and I trust that soon she will <underline>want</underline> to go in with Baby 'Laine and Gaki - or with aunt Alice - or Nannie. The latter goes in for very short but enjoyable floats cooling her off greatly.</p>
<p>Daddy is writing every A.M. and seems much more interesting in the "Place" than he used to be. He swims with boyish delight since Roark is so full and lovely. I hope to have a new</p>
Hr 189 38
5.
<p>dress made for Alice's birthday surprise by Sunday, as she is going to be away with Helen and Betty Lu(a Moran girl) at her cabin on the Lake to spend a day and two nights with them swimming and fooling about. She is having a swell vacation although she is helping me enormously with the work. We'll have the girls in on Sunday for ice-cream and a Mama-made Birthday Cake! I have not had time to sew any as yet but hope to soon.</p>
Love in Loads to you two dear dear children,
from your devoted 
Mother - Mama
39
<p>P.S. I did not mean to complain about Joanie - only tell you of her peculiarity, which is interesting to me. She shines whereever house work or personal attire is in any way concerned and she is a real helper. Gaki was amazed at her <underline>ironing</underline>. It is <underline>truly good</underline> ironing and folding of napkins etc like this: <triangle/> She does it as well as a grown up.</p>
<p>Each baby is remarkable in her own way - and both are very good dear children. M.</p>