<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Wednesday 57 
Fink Collection 
731
[September 14, 1938]
Dearest Children: 
It was good to re-ceive your letter Enid dear. 
We tried to get the P.D. last Sunday but there was none in town. I'd appreciate it so very much Ollie, if you'd send us a copy of your feature stories, or is that ask-ing too much of you, who are so very busy? I always enjoy your articles and feel proud and happy that you are Enid's Man - of this you may be sure. I do understand that things are necessarily different now from what they were when we^Daddy and I were young, and you must forgive me for expressing my self so freely. I am so glad you 

2
58
are so thoughtful of Enid - and that is another thing that is different - I be-lieve John never considered having a baby anything to waste any time or sympathy over - That was a woman job and O.K. However ^now he would feel very different over that situation if we were to go through it all again so I know that he has grown a lot in these many grasses and these many knows! The other day he said he had no idea it took so much time and work on a mother's part ot look af-ter 2 kids!! 
We get along very well here Maxie is so quiet and so capable and goes about her work with never a murmur. We are through canning - have 122 quarts or more canned. Our jars are full with exception of 2-1/2 gallons 

3
59
nd one quart! Daddy went over to the S. of O. and bought canned vegetable at a ridiculously low figure. 6 to 8 cents a can. He spent $20 odd so you can picture what a stack we have. That along with 6 tons of coal and 8 ricks of stove wood, puts us in beter shape than we have ever been at this time of year. 
Daddy says to say he is wait ing to hear from Ollie, besides he agrees perfectly with Ollie in his view of the Baby-matter-so my letter had nothing to do with him - I <del>have the</del> am to blame en-tirely, all by myself! 
I believe Sig is going to start out on a lecture hunt tomorrow in Eas tern Kansas. He accomplished quite a lot on his other trip. In 2 weeks Daddy and he have a "joint performance" in Warren burg, and Daddy has several otehr day engagements there. 

4
60
I am teaching Maxie German, as she asked me to do so. She will be good at it; nice, is it not? 
I wish you could see my baby Elaine figure! She is so cute - and so independant! Daddy is going to make the concrete reproduction for me. I will make the mold very soon if the weather allows me ot work out side. 
We have had an enormous rain and a cool spell is on now, making me shiver - but it will not last very long. 
Joannie is my Sweetheart, she says "Nannie, let me help you" So ever thing I do - and even models on Ba-by Elaine! She makes cookies, and is very much interested in "helping" with everything! The other day I was using a cake of Bon Amie and she said "how nie, What's at"? I said it is Bon Ami! 

5
61
So when she again saw me with it, she said Nannie, give Joanie the Bon A- you, will you?" Is n't that cute? 
I do hope you can really come Home soon - I wish you four might come for Thanksgiving - woudl that be swell? 
I just love Alice's picture, don't you? I have your big one ^Enid near here, and Alice's and Hilda's - all so sweet and lovely in such different ways! I'd love a good one of Ollie and you together some day! 
I know how it is in the City one cannot turn around without spending so much. Here, when you have the necessities, one can live iwth out spending so much. 
Daddy started on Jed 

62
<del>-8-</del> Smith today. It is so cool, maybe that is why. 
He loves the little bust I have been perfecting since I am here - What a difference compared with teh pattery one He is looking so very well now and his teeth make him forget his month so that he does not pull his lip down as he used to do; consequently he has the sweetest possible expression. I am so thrilled! Of I can use the new "Solo-go-ma" invention for making rubber like molds I'll be able to make several copies for all of us. Nice, not? 
Must close for now
Always, Oceans of Love 
to my two dear Children 
from 
Mama
Mother. 