<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
1936? 
33
7
Monday 
My own Darling 
Your dandy letter received last night in which you say you'll come home in August makes me so happy. Yes, we can sit out, maybe sleep out all night, and awaken to feel each other near and the sky overhead! It makes me think of the summer we slept out before Enid came by the cherry trees and the sunflowers! How wonderful that will be! I do hope nothing happens to change your place. I am having Mr Dearberry make use of the garden left by Mr Coffelt who went to Cal. Mr D. says he can raise sweet potatoes and green beans and maybe carrots and beets for me! I told him to go ahead and do what he can for his fa-mily and himself. he is oneof those object his sons of present society. Honest to a single word or penny, having worked at the hardest sort of labor about 60 years. With a family of which the last two are not normal, and his wife's mother to support most of the time - and partly deaf now, but intelligent and capable of a better kind of work - and when is there for him, or for his family if he shoudl pass out? You remember meeting Mrs D. - I have only one piece of paper, so am making it count, now that I can better control my hand.- I do feel so very grateful that you want me to have Amama she is living example of what happens when an emotional woman takes the bit in her teeth - and you need not fear her influence on me - because I think so differently - although I am just as emotions or maybe it woudl be better to say: I know I cannot think alone. I am always so happy when you make definite statements about what I should do. 

8
you surely must have been thinking rain - Be-cause we had a marvelous soaking rain yester-day afternoon, and think of it! it was very local it did not reach as far as Farsythe - and I do not know how far in the other directions Our hedge was turning brown it was so near going that I feared for it - And this morning all this well. Oh God - all the time the cooking rain came down in sheets I kept saying - Children just look at it! Are we being grateful enough for this marvelous change in everything? Oh Darling I know I have more, far more than I deserve of the blessings of life - and all thanks to you! - I am trying hard to fit into the fact, that Sigurd of all people has gone over to Jazz - I cannot feel he is doing the right thing nor can I feel that man Keller is what Sigurd writes. It looks to me like an older man were using a young man's vanity to promote his own ends. Sigurd shoudl be studying and mak-ing himself more and more exquisite in Piano playing so that he can went ally introduce. and end your Radio talks - I have always dreamed the two Neihardts shoudl do this together, some now. Because Sig in no wise detracts form you, we can invoke <del/> the mood for the appreciation of Higher Values though - for that is what real music does to people. Please tell me if Sig finished the course you helped him take with Heir Schmitt, or what? Loads of Love to my own and only Mom and love to our Enid girlie - 
from Mona 
(I am getting fat!!) 
Indian ring sent to you today. The rich-wear with sacred symbols bangs before my eye in I lie in bed. 