<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
45
Darling Enid and Ollie:
<p>So we are soon to appear at your front door again though but for a brief night's stay - but it will be wonderful to see you again. The girls tell such fine things of the good times with you, the rides and other enjoyable things you prepare for them - and not least of all they sing the praises of Enid in her capacity as "full blown rose". I hope you received the Garden book Ollie dear and that you will enjoy browsing in it - maybe it will take the place of honor in your porcelain reading - room?!</p>
<p>Daddy is getting adjusted slowly to the absence of the burden he carried for nearly thirty years, which is rather difficult, and he has been making more beautiful jewelry - the latest is a gorgeous pendant which I shall wear on my trip to show you.</p>
<p>Our nasturtiums zinnias etc are not yet up - but our cannas are - also sunflowers and poppies. The Spirea von Huttei is in full bloom now. We have several of these as well as snow balls making a grand setting for a wedding - maybe this place will some day be used <strike>every</strike> in the Spring for weddings of Neihardt girls yet unborn!</p>
<p>I am so glad you are wearing our ring Enid my darling, blessed Mother - girlie - Yes it <underline>is</underline> good luck never doubt that!</p>
<p>We have had the dining room ceiling done over, at last! It looks swell! Maxie washed all the woodwork and this makes the place look fine! She is working on a crocheted silk throw for herself now, having made one for me - and it is very lovely. I'm eager to see yours.</p>
<p>I am so glad Mrs Harrison is so truly your friend. I wish I could give her one of those Ozark babies you took to the pottery for me. Maybe I can pay for them soon and then I will certainly give her one.</p>
<p>Daddy and I send you both our love and a big hug.</p>
Always your devoted 
Mama Mother
46
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
APR30
11 -AM
1941
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809</stamp>
Mrs. O. F Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland
Mo.
St. Louis County.