<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
30-<del>31</del> Piper Collection Nov. 21, 1926 60
Nov 24 Dec 12 '26 
BRANSON NOV22 130PM
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 2CENTS2
Miss Mildred Piper 
Wayne
Nebraska. 

Branson Mo-
Nov. 21-1926 
61
My Dear little girl:-
How long oh how long has it been since I last wrote you and how many times I wonder have I thot of you and said I must write the dear girl-It was so lovely of you to write at the time of Mother's death - I so wanted to go at that time to Wayne lent was in Springfield with John's sick and was not able to go home even for several days - you have heard no doubt that John's have I would to Kirkwood Mo, and John commutes to St. Louis. He is Literary Editor of the St. Louis Post Dispatch-Kirkwood is a Suburb of St. Louis. They have a nice house on a big lot-the children are in School and are happy-Alice is in Kindergarten and thinks she is nearly as big as Hilda who is in 6a and doing fine Sigurd is in First year High School 

62
<unclear/> Enid in Second-She is taking music too but is very interested we Stenography-is very fine on the type writer-Has been doing all of her daddy's typing for the last 5 months she has only this fall taken to Shorthand Sigurd is really very wonderful in music - he has a german prof for a teacher and he is very much noter-ested in Sigurd, and surely Sigurd is very promising-I have missed them so much sometimes I think I just can't stand it. - But they want me to go to Kirkwood, and shut up my house - but I dont' want to leave my home for a while yet - I think about the 21st of Dec, which is my birthday, I will go and stay thru the cold weather-Lulu wants me to go to them thru the winter but it is so cold in Minneapolis-Grace wants me to go to Buffalo-but I want to stay home I have had invitations from Mrs. Ward. Mrs. Brown and Mrs. Graff to spend the 

63
winter in Bancroft-How I would like to see you again-I was so glad when I knew you were going to Wayne and I know how you will make them all love you - Have you been to see the Monument to John's work? I had hoped to see you there that day.-How are your father and mother and I always say "The little boys" as you used to do and I suppose they are grown up. Did you tell me one of your brothers was away from home and I thot what a pity to break the family of boys I always thot it seemed so nice - But of course you are away to - yet when you were at my house I did not think of you being away from home - you were min - Miss Piper belongs to all the Neihardts the children often speak of Miss Piper and Alice thinks she remembers when you were here- 

64
lu was home this summer and we had a good time John has a Buick and he took us Every place. Lulu thot it the most beautiful country she had Ever seen- Grace was here three years ago and I spent the winter with her in Buffalo Two years ago. 
Mona is so busy all the times, and now that she has such a big house I wonder how she Ever gets thru-but the children are all in school now. - John goes to the office at Eleven oclock, and comes home when Ever he gets ready.- I have not heard from miss "Fish" for so long lent it is because I have neg-lected writing to her. Mrs. Ward asked about you the last letter - She is still teaching. Dear girl tell me a lot about your self-address one her I will be here sometime yet much love to you my dear girl-
Alice Neihardt 