<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
156a
June 15, 1941.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Dearest Folks:-
<p><sic>Thanx</sic> for all the dear letter from you all there.</p>
<p>We had a barbecue yesterday evening. Hil, Albet &amp; Alice <sic>bro't</sic> everything - can you imagine - to their own party? They wanted to so, that I let them. It was lovely for me, tho', as Hil &amp; Alice got everything ready to eat; Albert &amp; Ol roasted the steak &amp; I sat in a chair watchin' 'em. I really enjoyed myself! I believe we all had a grand time. We stayed out till we got chilly &amp; then went in &amp; Albert &amp; Alice ran the Ouija board as you no doubt will hear from Hilda very soon. She's going to make copies of some. I've never seen a Ouija do such a good job yet.</p>
2
<p>was truly interesting. Of course, we dont' just gulp it down, but we are truly interested. The kids are coming out often now. We went to bed at 12:30. So you see we must've gotten at least a little something exciting! We were awfullly sorry Sig couldn't be with us. He had something or other he had to do for Baldwind, it seems.</p>
<p>Isn't Hil's engagement ring lovely? I watched it shine &amp; sparkle in the lighter last nite. It's nice she has it &amp; I do hope they don't prolong the engagement too long, as I'm very much against such things. I think that's why Ol &amp; I just got married without engaging ourselves! We knew then, is we now know more than ever, that we could never love again and the sooner, the sweeter! Monday, the 16<underline>th</underline>, we'll have been married 4 1/2 yrs. And, now, we are being</p>
3
<p>blessed with our very own little precious baby! We've wanted it so long that I know it realizes it - even now. When we talk about it affectionately, the little dear moves around so sweetly! It's just funny! When its little hands move around, it's the gentlest, softest, dearest feeling!! We went to the doc again this past week &amp; he says everything's okay so far. He says it's now 6 1/2 mos. along. He looks for it the last of August. I'm happy Ol can be on vacation at that time. It makes it so nice. He likes vacation in the fall anyway &amp; the bunny knows just when we want it - bless its baby heart! Then, if you, Mom, &amp; Dad can be here, it'd surely be lovely. If we have a boy "next time", we're going to call it "Oliver B.", but thsi one is to be named after its Grandad - "John N." unless the <strike>former</strike> Grandpa disappears!</p>
4
<p>And, of course, if a girl, it's to be "Mona L." We've made up our minds! Ha!</p>
<p>We hope Dad rec'd our Father's Day telegram today! I always "wonder" about the frams to Branson!!</p>
<p>Ol &amp; I've gotten to like Albert very much &amp; I believe he likes us. We really all got acquainted last nite. Albert calls us "Ollie" &amp; "Enid". &amp; now all's okay. I do wish you could've seen the Ouija <strike>thing</strike> said with Alice &amp; Albert. Hil &amp; Albert couldn't get it going! Ol &amp; I are going to try it occasionally now &amp; see what we get.</p>
<p>Three gorgeous red radiances bloomed today! Nice, on Father's Day.</p>
<p>Really is no news. So long till later.</p>
Loads o' love,
Eny &amp; Ol
<p>Ol &amp; I are both equally thrilled over the things you're a-makin' for us, Dad. Mom, Ol <gap reason="cut off"/> crazy about the bust as I am, &amp; is going to write you about it.</p>
156b
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 1
JUN16
730PM
1941
BUY U.S. SAVINGS
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER
<stamp>UNITED
STATES 
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Dr. &amp; Mrs. J.G. Neihardt
Branson,
<underline>Taney Co.</underline> Missouri