<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
44 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 7
Overland, Javn. 5, '4<hi rend="strike_through">2</hi>3
Dear Sig &amp; Max:
<p>Here's a funny one!</p>
<p>Armin's letter about the Atlantic engagement reached me from Branson yesterday, Jan 4th! It was twice stamped Oct 23, '42. Evidently it had been put in our box down there by mistake often we left. We arrived here on Oct 23rd.</p>
<p>Your letter about, the engagement hasn't turned up yet, but it way! I wrote Alexander about this.</p>
<p>Of course, he isn't to blame. One of the new assistants must have pulled a boner. Too bad! We could have used the money to good advantage.</p>
<p>I suppose you couldn't see Latham last Thurday, Sig.</p>
<p>Do you understand about the Nat. Institute of Arts &amp; Letters? It is highly exclusive, adn men like St. Gandens, MacDowell, Mark Twain, JOhn TaFarge, etc etc. were members. The American Academy of Arts &amp; Letters is the equivalent of the French Academy</p>
8
<p>of Immortals. Only 50 members in the Academy at a time, and when one dies, a successor is chosen from the membership of the Institute. Only members of the Institute can be elected to the Academy, which is regarded as the the highest recognition that is given in America. So I'm eligible now!Isn't this rather funnily nice? I was flabbergasted. It is so much harder to get than the Pulitzer Prize, so I may</p>
<p>even get that!</p>
<p>Also, Henry S. Cavby, who notified me, is one of the Literary Guild judges, and some of the others may be members.</p>
<p>The file was expressed to you yesterday.</p>
<p>The Institute publicity should be sent out soon. In the Spring is the ceremony, &amp; I do hope Mama &amp; I can attend together. It will be an impressive business.</p>
<p>I hope Sig, when you can see Latham, you'll bring up the Institute &amp; see of Macmillans intend to take advantage of the honor of the Cycle.</p>
<p>Love to each of you four, &amp; blessings on the precious Girls!</p>
Dad
<p>Institute membership limited to 250.</p>
<p>it's not <hi rend="underline">loud</hi> publicity.</p>
