<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
56a
Cresco, Iowa
September 3, 1942
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Another town - and tonight is our last night. It is a gorgeous brilliant blue - gold day, and we have just arisen adn eaten our breakfasts (<underline>or</underline> lunch).</p>
<p>As a whole, the weather has been lovely, with only enough rain to cause a little excitement.</p>
<p>We had a grand evening in Preston which I have not told you about. One evening aafter performance, most of our company, chorus, singers, soloists, went by car a mile or so from home to a lovely park - like place situated by a river</p>
(2)
<p>and - incidentally, a <unclear/> house - and a large <underline>cornfield</underline>. Geroge supervised - or rather- built the fire himself, and then several of us went through the fent and fathered aroudn forty ears of luvious corn, as quietly and as silently as possible. These were roasted in the coals, and weiners and marshmallows over the coals. What we did consume! The moon was so beautiful it is impossible to describe it - and everyone greatly enjoyed the occasiion. Little by littl ethe company decreased, and the remainder became mroe and mroe congenial. We sang, talked, laughed, and,</p>
56b
(3)
<p>finally, as a frand finale, went swimming in the coal, Poark-like River nearly - in our clothes. Of course, we were <underline>very</underline> wet - so the natural follow-up was a session of drying, about the last of our huge fire. By 5:00 A.M. we were at last home again and piled long sleep. What fun are silly, impulsive experiences such as this - when everyone is sincerely in search of pure enjoyment.</p>
<p>We rode the thirty six miles here by truck. A dusty ride - but full of song and beautiful scenery - so we cared</p>
(4)
<p>little how dirty we became.</p>
<p>Our performances have been improving right along and we are gaining so by the experience of such a stage and chorus background. We've been rehearsing too. Last night the stage was wet - and quite slick - in spite of having been burned over with gasoline. I fell once on teh rumba - but was up at once, with no hurt, kept a great deal of surprise. Several girls fell flat on their faces. When it came to the Russian, we were careful, and did really a very good</p>
56c
(5)
<p>performance. Ernie Young is very nice to us - watches our act like a hawk - and helps us arrange changes in temp with our conductor! We leave after tongiht's performance for Mason City, Iowa.</p>
<p>Monday ngiht last, was the day we came to Cresco, and we had no performance that night.Therefore, George, Sylvia, and I (Doris didn't wish to come along) found where we coudl go swimming and proceeded there by foot at about 5:00 P.M. We walked three miles to the River, which turned out to be cool,</p>
(6)
<p>clear, and quite wide3. We swam just above a dam, from a dock. Several times across and back between the three of us, a bit of swinging out over the water on a trapeze, and we were ready for soem kind fo a good primitive meal. Knowing it was our lsat chance for a hile to do so gypsy-ish a thing, we decided to buy a chicken and roast it on a spit, in the woods nearly. After some searching we finally found a farm where we could secure what we wanted.</p>
56d
(7)
<p>The people were lovely to us - gave us a four lb. chicken all dressed, sweet corn, potatoes, and mush melons for the hug sum of one dollar. It took while to wind our way back to the stream and down it one-quarter mile to what we deemed an ideal spot for a fire and a chicken roasting. George and I goraged wood - partly from an old barn nearby, and soon we were eating our entree - roasted chicken gizzard and liver. Then the potatoes and corn were placed in hot coals, and</p>
(8)
<p>the chicken was put on the stick and placed over the fire, between two stickes driven into the ground on either side of the fire. Oh! that firelight - the brown, dripping chicken, the sineel of roasting corn - and good comrades! The chicken done - it fell apart and we devoured it and all else like true gypsies do. Then, contendted and happy, we silently watched the moon rise above the low-lying mystical, clouds, and the curl of smoke disappearign into</p>
56e
(9)
<p>the moon<strike>light</strike> lit sky high above the tall, encircling trees. This we enjoyed as long as we felt we might - and then set out again on our way home. A bit of hot coffee and a foraged apple on our way home, besides final glimpse of that magical moon and we went safely home to bed (at about 1:00 A.M.)</p>
<p>I do so hpe you are happy and well - and I know you are. How about going to Eny's and Ollie's? Are you still palnning on Kemper Daddy?</p>
Love o' Always to you Dearest ones,
Your Alice