<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
144 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 24
Feb 2nd
43.
Dearest Children:
<p>Your good letters warm our hearts - because you are our <hi rend="underline">own</hi> son Sigurd, and Maxie, you are his very best possible wife and our <hi rend="underline">dear</hi> girly.</p>
<p>The tables have turned - and now Daddy is in need of <hi rend="underline">your</hi> help. - The only way you can do your part is by sending a small, regular amount of money - say 2$ a week - that would be a great help and would make Ollie feel he was not entirely alone in actually taking care of us. You Sig and he are at present the only men in our family earning a regular salary. It won't be so wrong for us to have to feel that our son in law is the only one of our children <unclear/> is really holding us up now while Daddy <hi rend="underline">is</hi> sick and actually not able to consider a trip of any sort. This state of affairs is not going</p>
25
<p>be of long duration, but for the time being it is altogether the worst state of affairs we have <hi rend="underline">ever</hi> been in. We are making good memories out of it all: Ollie's goodness, and Enid's are going to be remembered - and I don't want to have to remember that you, Sigurd, did not help us too. Dad needs you <hi rend="underline">now</hi> while he is <hi rend="underline">down</hi>, not after a while.</p>
<p>We have reason to hope that he will improve steadily - and that one or another job will work out for him. This is a time when we can really Know our true friends, and I want you children to head the list.</p>
<p>Hilda is trying to form her plans with Albert's help to get away to Chicago, and when she gets a start there she will also send us cash.</p>
<p>Alice is <hi rend="underline">aching</hi> to get started in Mexico City so that she can send us money. The last I heard from her she was</p>
26
<p><unclear/> with her troupe for delayed papers from Washington (on the Mexican Border.)</p>
<p>I feel it right for you to Know the facts here and I have <hi rend="underline">never</hi> in my bluest moments disbelieved in your fundamental goodness.</p>
<p>Sigurd boy, you are proving yourself able to hold a good job and support you dear family without help from anyone else - and you can help Dad now if you and Max will get together and budget so as to consider Dad as of real importance. When Grandma was living and Dad had a job - first on the list was the sum we sent to her - and it was a considerable one too, as compared to what I am now asking of you.</p>
<p>Please do not feel I am belittling the tremendous good you will be doing us if you do send us as much as 2$ per</p>
27
<p>wk., for indeed it will make all the difference between feeling <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> and feeling yellow in our present lives.</p>
<p>I hope you children will be glad I wrote you this letter and gave you the chance to help Dad, and lift the load Ollie is now so <hi rend="underline">super generously</hi> carrying.</p>
<p>Now to say something about myself. All I ask is that all of our dear children prove themselves as good friends to our Daddy as he has proven himself to be to them. Aside from this I <hi rend="underline">shall not ever</hi> leave him alone to face <hi rend="underline">any</hi> situation Life may yet have in store for him. The time is past when he should have to try around for a job away from Home - and Home is here at present, till we can live in Branson again in our very own dear Home. So long as Daddy is not able to walk with any degree of comfort</p>
28
<p>are better off in Enid's nice home, than in any other place.</p>
<p>I am very well and would like to sew for you Maxie, and for our <sic>prescious</sic> children, Joan and Elaine - so why not let me? You can save a lot that way, and I'd be very happy making clothes for you three if you pick out patterns, and will pay for the materials needed. I can do this for Enid and want to do the same for you.</p>
<p>A new baby will arrive in July or August here and I'll be so glad to be able to keep Nei etc. The little one will be named Mona if "it" is a girl. - Is that not wonderful for me?</p>
Loads and Loads of love to you four dear, dear children
from Mom.