<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
167
9917 Emerson Ve.
Overland, Mo.
June 30<underline>th</underline>, 41.
Dearest Dad:-
<p>I wish I were an artist, with words. Unfortunately, I'm not that, or I'd be mroe able to tell you how very beautiful &amp; exquisite I think the "nursing set" and ring are, as well as Ol's tie pin!! I am trying to figure out just how you fastened the fasteners to the quartz. It surely is neatly done. I'm certain the "wub" will love to dangle it around &amp;, if it's as active then as now, it'll have its feet up the earrings trying to pull them off! That set is surely just my idea of <strike/> gorgeous beauty - my kind of coloring &amp; everything.</p>
<p>The ring is just simply a joy to me! I think it is a truly handsome piece of work. The carbuncle is set off so</p>
2
<p>beautifully by the yellow sapphire. It's such a lovely background - the ivory. How did you fasten <underline>this</underline> on?</p>
<p>Hubby will be tickled when he sees the jade on sard tie pin. I can hardly wait till he gets home to see it! It is truly handsome &amp; will be lovely on ties with his jade ring (which he wears all the time).</p>
<p>I've gotta make some dresses suitable for nursing &amp; in the color to harmonize with the rose quartz set now! Mom, what sort of dress is adaptable to nursing best? - I suppose a Hoover apron?!</p>
<p>I made four half-pints of red raspberry jelly today.</p>
<p>Sig, Hil, Alice &amp; Albert were out yesterday. Spent part of afternoon &amp; then we had</p>
3
<p>steak roast. Albert &amp; Sig got the steak &amp;, boy, it was great! Poor Albert - he's a dear! I wish Hilda could feel a certain way about him, but <underline>I</underline> fear she doesn't love him! He says he's "in the dark" about Hilda! Too bad for both! But, of course, Hilda has to make her decision. I just hope it won't "hurt" too much when it's made. Personally, no matter was Hil thinks, <underline>I</underline> think she "needs to get married." Lots of people "need to marry"!! Others can get by without it. So much for things that are none of my business anyway! Ha!</p>
<p>Dad, thansk <underline>so much</underline> for wanting to and for making those <underline>perfectly exquisite</underline> pieces of jewelry for us! I can tell you we'll always cherish them and think of you when wearing them. Ol &amp; I wish you &amp;</p>
4
<p>Mom could visit us again. When are you coming up?</p>
<p>Ol cleaned up the basement the other day, &amp; we are seriously considering putting a bed down there! It's dry &amp; cool at nites. Ol is going to ask Sig to help him carry up the dresser from sunroom to attic when Sig's out again.</p>
<p>Has it been warm there? It surely has been here!</p>
<p>We've been having lots of string beans. If Hilda or Sig would stop by maybe I could send some down for you to sample! They're really good! I'm canning surplus ones - without vinegar! A new way, with just salt, &amp; processing 2 1/2 hrs.! they have a better taste without the vinegar. Canned 7 qts. &amp; none</p>
168
5
<p>have spoiled yet.</p>
<p>Ol &amp; I've been laying off of meat considerably of late! We feel it's too hot to eat meat. Groceries have gone up; have you noticed? We have. Not a lot on anything - but thsoe pennies add up! And, of course meat is pretty generally high.</p>
<p>Dad, what do you think about Germany &amp; Russia &amp; the possible outcome?</p>
<p>Baby says "goo-goo", meaning <underline>lots</underline> of love to grandma &amp; grandpa!! Really, won't it be a sweet thing, tho'? I can hardly wait till we have the darling pkg.!</p>
<p>Thanks again, Dad! You are the <underline>Dearest</underline> of all Dads!! I'm <underline>sure</underline> of that!</p>
Loads o' love to you &amp; Mom, the <underline>Dearest</underline> of Moms!!
Love to Max, Joan &amp; 'Laine. 
<p>Max, why not write me?</p>
Enot