<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
2a
1942
<p>I'd like to see Latham one of these times. Mon. is only day off. Hope the cycle does get published as a unit soon.</p>
42-50 BONNE, APT -1 -B
Flushing, N.Y.
<p>Please tell Mama I'll write to her soon.</p>
Dear Dad:
<p>I was very happy to hear from you again. That must have been quite a job - to paint and putty vaiour parts of the place. I note that you have advertised in Editor &amp; Publisher. There should be something you could get, through that source. If not, then you will find some other way. It is a cinch that much demand exists now for all kinds of abilities.</p>
<p>I am grateful for the mechanical background given me, if for no other reason than it is the only way a young man</p>
over
-2-
<p>can make himself a part of the scheme of things without getting into the front lines.</p>
<p>One hears many rumors among the fellows at work, such as <underline>probability</underline> of being transferred to some distant overseas base etc. Also, at present the Army is experimenting on the advisability of carrying a flight mechanic on every trans-ocean plane. I understand however, that such jobs will not be compulsory for men with families. Jesus! It is a sight how many <underline>hundred</underline>s of young &amp; single "draft-dogers" there are in this essential work. Army will get those though, &amp; before much longer. This, in turn, will make opportunity for advancement</p>
2b
-3-
<p>of men in my classification who will stay on the job &amp; do the necessary work.</p>
<p>My work is <underline>inspection</underline> of "DC-3's" &amp; "C-46's", also the repairs end of it I do extensively. The DC-3 is a Douglas-Airliner now converted into a cargo ship for Army purposes. It is exactly like those silver-colored American Airlines Flagships you see at Lambert Field, but it has that camouflage green color of U.S. Army. The C-46 is largest twin engine land plane in use for cargo work. It has <underline>two</underline> 2,000 horsepower, 18 cyclinder (two-rows) Pratt &amp; Whitney engines built by "<underline>Ford</underline>". <underline>Surprise</underline>, eh? I enclose photo of <underline>this</underline> ship.</p>
-4-
<p>A couple of days ago three of us went out on the field to "run-up" a ship, &amp; took turns taxi-ing a big DC-3 all over the runways. Ha! 'Twas loads of fun. I had no trouble at all, &amp; it seemed just as natural as driving an anutomobile.</p>
<p>Modern Aircraft is composed of a literally tremendous array of engineers' pipe-dreams. Most of the units of course are very necessary. A mechanic has to know De-icer system of propeller &amp; of wing leading-edges. He has to know hydraulic landing gear &amp; hydr. braking systems. He has to know instruments &amp; engines &amp; aircraft structure.</p>
2c
-5-
<p>Also there is the automatic pilot system, a complex thing in itself.</p>
<p>I have allready done major overhaul of landing gear &amp; retract strut systems. There is little motor work, excepting for occasional replacement of cylinders. A Line Maintenance man will often have A &amp; E (aircraft &amp; engine) licenses, &amp; not know his hind end from a hole in the ground. I find that I learn <underline>very</underline> quickly, and if I were in the work 1 yr. I should (at the rate I've learned in last 2 wk's.) become mighty well versed on the maintenance end of aviation.</p>
<p>We find that our living costs here will be just about the same as what</p>
over
-6-
<p>we've been used to in St. Louis. One has to choose the economy stores up here tho', or he'll pay exhorbitant prices for everything. Our rent is ceiled at $42. monthly. Out apt is nivest we've ever had, in every way.</p>
<p>Remember, the Neihardts now have a base in N.Y. City, and it is to be used for the purpose. Anytime you &amp; Mom want to come here, just say so.</p>
<p>In making the jump from St. Louis to N.Y. with Max &amp; the kids, I could just barely see my way clear financially. Knowing that neither you nor I could make $29. monthly payments on the car -</p>
2d
-7-
<p>I ran an ad in P-D &amp; sold it. The exact transaction was $350.<underline>00</underline>. I had a loan of $300.<underline>00</underline> to pay off on it. So this left $50. clear for us to use in connection with costs of our jump East. You had $335. against the car at the car at time I took it over. So there is a measily $15. owing you on the transaction. Cars are damned near useless owing to ration of gas in the East. To sell one in St. Louis is a hard job owing to anticipation of the gas ration there. I feel very ill over the thing. Still, with the tires very thin &amp; the coming ration to face - it seemed wrong to try to do that monthly payment &amp; pay out too on the many other</p>
over
-8-
<p>items a fellow has to consider.</p>
<p>It took all the money we could scrap up, to make this change from St. Louis. <strike>Even</strike> The lucky, <underline>big month</underline> (Sept.) at Baldwin provided me with enough sales credits to get out of the "red" &amp; give us a bonus of $51.12. Purchase of tools, uniforms, advance rent, meter deposits etc. have cost a plenty, as you might know. We'll be O.K. now, and in 3 mo's should have that St. L. bank debt paid off. I owe $67<underline>50</underline> on it, &amp; Hil has some owing. I'll send you some money on pay day; Oct. 21<underline>st</underline>.</p>
<p>Will you write soon, please? I sure as hell miss you &amp; wish that we could get together &amp; talk about <underline>things</underline>.</p>
Love always,
Sig.
<p><underline>P.S.</underline> It will be necessary that I send what I can spare. Will do as often as I can.</p>