<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
75a
6235 Southwood
St. Louis
10/20/40.
Dearest folks:
<p>Today is the first Sunday since re-joining the Baldwin Piano Co. My gosh! What a satisfation it really is to have a decent job &amp; a better set-up than I've ever had. All orgatron inquiriea both from store advertising, customer drop-ins; Everett orgatron co. National advertising etc. are turned over to me as "Representative of the Orgatron". It is the only Electronic organ (pipeless) that passes American Guild of Organists approval for Church work. It, incidentally, sells in the single manual style for $595.00, lowest price for an electric organ. &amp; honest - to = God possiblities form standpoint of selling it. The 2 - manual style, which is a full-feldged church organ (or theatre organ) sells for $1650.</p>
over
-2-
<p>It ranks far ahead of the Hammond Organ &amp; there is a field for it. When I sell one it means $165.00. Reynolds is fond of me &amp; is delighted. I'm back with him. He <underline>is</underline> a fine human being, as Dad will testify. He wants to help me make $250. or better each month, &amp; you know I'll do my <underline>very</underline> darndest.</p>
<p>Last <sic>nite</sic>, Saturday, Max &amp; I enjoyed the Baldwin Co. <underline>Barn Dance</underline>, way out past Eureka. Had splendid time out there, &amp; Max enjoyed the fun &amp; the getting acquainted with Mr. &amp; Mrs. Reynolds &amp; the many other nice folks.</p>
<p>We got home at 3:30 A.M. Such dissipation is quite funny &amp; unusual for us. We have one of the Orgatrons in our apt. Will have it</p>
75b
-3-
<p>here a coupld of weeks for purpose of learning to demonstrate it. Surprising it is I guess, but I can surely get real beauty out of the darned thing.</p>
<p>How I do wish you &amp; Dad were here today. I've memorized the Alt-Wien of Godowsky for the Organ. How <underline>terribly</underline> exquisite this gem is on the orgatron. It can be done to fullest extent of its real meaning only on a sustained tone instrument, as you will agree. We want to come home one of these Sat. afternoon. We'll all come down together. It is a shame to be away so long at a time from you two. I &amp; all of us are so glad that Dad is moving alogn well with "Jed", &amp; that your trip was fine.</p>
<p>Yesterday I went over into Caseyville, Ill. on an<p>
over
-4-
<p>Orgatron deal. Am to deliver it Tues. afternoon to a Rev. Wessler, who looking thrilled when I said "Neihardt is my neme." He said later "That name! Are you any relation to John G. Neihardt whose Easter Poem I love so much?"</p>
<p>This of course got the preacher &amp; me pretty close together. Such things help close deals.</p>
<p>I have been very busy &amp; concerned over my recent doing, &amp; therefore haven't written. Thanks for the $20 Commissions. We've surely needed it badly. Western Auto, you know, damned near starved us for 2 wks. Ha! Must stop for now.</p>
Endless love,
Sig.
<p><underline>P.S.</underline> Yes, we are continuing with lecutre possibilities. I'll make a survey of St. L. too.</p>