<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
42 Thompson Collection 115
July 12, 1942?
Sunday
My own darling Alice:
<p>You were dear to write me all you did and to offer your help as agent. Indeed I do believe that if you will take my blackout lamp and show it to those gift shops that you sent me the addresses of called "Gift and Lamp" shops, that you could place them for me in a few of them any way. But for the moment we are busy turning out new</p>
116
<p>stump babies. May be <underline>if</underline> cannot get the <strike>People who</strike> Original Art Co in Chicago to take it over, you could place some of these for me also.</p>
<p>First however, I want to see what the Mazda Lamp people do, as well as the Original Art Co. If these turn my pieces down I'll try Gift shops. Darling, our Daddy and Hilda are all enthused over you. I am <underline>so</underline> happy when I think of you, and so grateful too! Maxine</p>
3
<p>also writes so enthused and so warmly about you.</p>
<p>I do think we have a most wonderful and interesting and worthwhile - and better than all this a most <underline>loving</underline> family and my heart sings Halleluja!</p>
<p>Needless to say Amama is gradually learning to fit in, and see how fine you girls <underline>all are</underline> and is truly happy for <underline>me</underline>.</p>
<p>She is in a very hard place in her own life</p>
117
<p>and the only thing we can do is love <underline>her</underline> - and not take <underline>any other</underline> attitude.</p>
<p>What we so often do not know is this: We suffer for our own faults - that is Hell - and there is no other.</p>
<p>Alice dear, please always write me <underline>every</underline> thing - Knowing that I love and understand and admire you - and that my every breath is a prayer for your wellfare.</p>
<p>The other day I felt very strongly that my own</p>
5
<p>dear father was with me and helping me to help my mother. I had the desire all at once to give her a picture of "<sic>Catlaya</sic> Orchids" which were her favority flowers - so I did so - and afterwards it occurred to me that it was Fathers' Day and that <underline>he</underline> had influenced me to do this. Strange, not? Yet not strange when we Know as we must, that the other World <underline>is very</underline> close!</p>
<p>Daddy says Mons. George is a splendid, clean, fine</p>
118
<p>young man - and I'm <underline>so</underline> glad. I'd give a great deal for a <underline>good long</underline> look at you my baby!</p>
<p>Some day we will meet - and that is going to be wonderful.</p>
<p>Thanks so much for all you say about having me visit you - won't that be lovely? Amama expects to go through Chicago when she returns to New York. She will do what Ottocar decides for her - but I cannot <underline>make</underline> her do any thing - I'll have to just <underline>wait</underline> and <underline>hope</underline> for the best. I do Know that she should never again be <underline>alone any</underline> where.</p>
Always loving you devotedly,
Your Mama
<p>Am eager for your pictures.</p>