<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
0
Jamay, Missouri 
Branson 5, '38. 
Dear Enot and Ollie:
I bully joint letter from you! I suspect you were a lot thoughter than you drunk you were on a New Year's night; but you can tell Papa anything, and he'll understand. 
I'm fairly surging along with old Jed - 8, 10, 14 lines a day, and no compromises. I'm often surprised at what I find along the road; for although I know where the road; for, although I know where the road rims and all of its hands, I don't know what's around the next bend in the way of enriching detail. Jed's character is growing rapidly for the reader - every mental, spiritual and physical phoge of it - and yet there's no mere telling; you just overhear three guys gassing and getting tighter slowly, and the three are so many steps on teh way up to the final relevation of the essential Jed, this method allows a lightness of touch that is often far more effective than any <del/> <del/> 

admitted seriousness ^could be; and poetry breaks through between the common words that very seldom exceed two syllables. 
I'm much pleased, Oddie, with what you say about the protests, Pulitzer, Please, and good old sister Fay. (Our love to her - Mona's and me!) 
They did me an excellent turn when they dropped me just then, for they forced me into Jed Smith. Nevertheless, I'm well under way now, and if they should decide to talk with me, I'd have a proposition to make which would involve Enot, if she coudl be interested. I'd enjoy editing, & proofing from here, and Enot knows the office stuff as well as I do. Her pay would, of course, be boasted. You see, I'm with Jed only till noon. Afternoons I'd edit and make jewelry. Could manage occasional lecture trips 
Soon I'll be at the amethyst ring again, as my outfit will soon be assembled completely I'll have the gold today. 
Ps Endless love, Dad 
2990 
26
_____
17) 17940 (105
5980
94
85
________________
90
17) 77740 (45
68
____
97
85
____
124
119
____
50
<figure/> 
This is none of your damn business! I was figurin' revolutions of wheels and surface feet for minute
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

Neihardt
Branson, 
Mo. 
0a
BRANSON JAN 5 3-PM 1938 MO. 
Mr. and Mrs. O. F. Fink, 
9716 Hawthorne,
Overland, 
Mo. 