<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
271- <strike>272</strike> Fink Collection 103
Neihardt,
Branson, Mo.
<stamp>BRANSON
APR10
3 -PM
1941
M.O.</stamp>
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
Saint Louis 
County
104
Tuesday 
evening
Darling Enid and <strike>Ollie</strike>,
<p>When you get this I hope you will have your dear Mother with you. It is fine for you to have her, and for her to get a change. Your furniture will all be beautiful when you get through with it, but I do not think you need two coats of enamel, as one coat covers a lot on that wicker wear since you have to brush <underline>back</underline> and <underline>forth</underline> on it to get it into the holes; Ollie will find this out, and use the enamel fairly thin - this has been my experience. I wish I could be helping!</p>
<p>We took Mrs Cantwell in our car to look at the "farms." They</p>
105
2
<p>were quite impossible. We looked at Gillespies again and found it entirely without "plan" - and with most incredible extravagance of details, such as had hewn doors several inches thick of beautiful wood with wrought iron locks etc that must have caused several hundred dollars per door! Gorgeous fire places and wood work throughout. I do not like the place - it has nothing in common with <underlin>e</underlin> It is a rich man's folly - not a <underline>home</underline> in <underline>any</underline> sense of the word. Maxie felt the same as I did.</p>
<p>Our Home is so beautiful now The Forsythia at the back should be pictured in a flower catalogue it is so very perfect in <strike/> color and form. Our Wisteria is loaded with blooms that should be out in about 2 weeks The pear is in full bloom and the</p>
104
3
<p>small variety of Spirea is a mountain of white on both sides of the front steps. The hug Japonica is still a "fire bush" and the wild current row in front of the farage is full of yellow blooms. Our pool has never been so beautiful as it now is since Daddy remade it putting a flower pot in each of the six corners, and a circular lining inside; this has made the design for more rich and has stopped the leaking entirely.</p>
<p>I have fixed my hair differently, parting it way over on one side and this I did because you Ollie advised me not to have a part in the middle! It has helped me and my looks very much. So this old Mother is much obliged to you for yoru interest!</p>
<p>Daddy cut down a dead tree and has been suffering from doing too much with his poor side. I hope it will not be serious or long</p>
105
4
<p>He is doing wonders on Jed Smith - and we feel very hopeful.</p>
<p>I wish the girls could get out to see you oftener but as you say they are terribly busy. Alice is really going to be in an Opera, and I will not be able to see her!-</p>
<p>Daddy's bust pleases me very much indeed - I have done what I set out to do so long ago - and feel it is worth all the effort it has cost. I hope to finish it when Dad finishes Jed - nice, not?</p>
<p>The Wubs are so happy and look so well and their Mama is dear and such a comfort to have around. She did a huge washing We used <underline>3</underline> washers full of fresh water - and Grandma's rugs are <underline>absolutely</underline> clean and beautiful once more, as well as blankets comforter etc and the regular things. I wish I had <underline>your</underline> rug here to wash for you!</p>
104
<p>Loads of Love to you all 3</p>
from Mother - Mama.