<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
58a
<p>P.S. I've heard nothing more about <unclear>natal</unclear>. This outfit usually gives short notice. I don't expect to go for sometime.</p>
April 15, 1943,
42-60 Bowne St.,
Flushign, L.I.,
N.Y.
Dear Dad:
<p>it was wonderful to hear today form you. So glad that you are getting results from the doctor's treatments.</p>
<p>I keep thinking that I'll drop in by appointment to see H. S. Latham on my Tuesday off, but I've been simply starved for rest on every off day (Tuesdays) for a long while. Dr. Katz is giving me the best possible treatment and I <hi rend="underline">am</hi> clearing up in the bronchial glands quite a lot, but it is a case of much time being required to dry up the horrible condition. Faithful ol' Long Island climate brought the chronic condition to a climax. I was examined yesterday &amp; Doc says he is satisfied with everything, but that I must be under this medicine for 3 or 4 months, 6 capsules daily, before all will be normal.</p>
<p>It is great to really know you have a thing under control. So, probably you &amp; I both will be doin' allright before long.</p>
58b
-2-
<p>She's a mad rush at A.A. these days! 10 more new planes, Douglas C-54's, largest cargo in production at the moment, are now under our care. I &amp; my helpers keep <hi rend="underline">very</hi> busy. I do almost nothing but <hi rend="underline">diagnosis</hi> &amp; the seeing to it that the <hi rend="underline">remedy</hi> is carried out with strictness. The extremely complicated electrical circuits of present day aircraft are definitely understood and almost faultlessly handled by me. The lead mechanic on instruments &amp; electrical has been shifted to a different crew because our crew has no need for him. Its all in <hi rend="underline">my</hi> lap. the four electrician-instrument men under me call me 'boss' &amp; we cuss each other up &amp; down 8 hours daily, all in <hi rend="underline">fun</hi>!</p>
<p>No telling what will come of it all. Anyway, to do <hi rend="underline">well</hi> is a great satisfaction. Where one will end out in such a peculiar set-up as a today's aircraft maintenance man - <sic>noone</sic> knows.</p>
<p>The 'glamour of aviation' is</p>
over
-3-
<p>a big pile of B.S. Union graft plus the airlines taking advantage of government economy measures etc. makes it not too good from a financial point of view. However, I should have a very decent salary within a short time. A.L.M.A., airline mechanics association, to which I belong, promises a nice <hi rend="underline">raise</hi> soon in addition to the <hi rend="underline">raise</hi> which will accompany my early promotion. So, having stayed in the buggy, (altho' very disgusted at times) appears now as much worthwhile.</p>
<p>I am so happy over the cycle in one volume - now actually to materialize. Also the Book of The Month &amp; Pulitzer prize angles i feel should be <hi rend="underline">likelihoods</hi>. We shall all be hoping &amp; praying for things to 'click' in an honest-to-God way.</p>
<p>Preacher friend J. Donald Johnston &amp; wife were with us last eve, &amp; we talked about the cycle &amp; collected poems.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">This</hi> week I'll phone Latham &amp; do my best to arrange a visit with him, for the following Tuesday.</p>
<p>Please take care!</p>
All my love always
&amp; from us all. Sig.