<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
90a
-1-
Dec. 27, 1938
5540 Cates Ave. 
Dear Mama,
We were very very happy to see the lovely <unclear/> baby when we open-ed the mysterious - looking box Christmas morning, Mom, and in addition the beautiful crystal necklace, but, most of all, perhaps, the few words you put with them. We never get over thinking what marvelous, encouraging, and dear parents we have - and we are grateful! 
Betty came Saturday afternoon about 4:00. Neil went to get here at the station. It is wonderful to have her with us - she's just like a sister - so fine and yet so sweet and full of fun. We had a nice supper <unclear/>

-4-
was a legal holiday & Hil had no work. We ate a light breakfast about 11:00, Then we got dressed & took us to <unclear/>'s to see two excelling shows. They were Charles Dicken's "A Christmas Carol" and Gary Casper and Merle Oberon in "The Cowboy and the Laply". The former, as perfect Christmas - time picture was marvelously done, with Reginald Owen portraying old Scrooge in a masterful manner and with the true spirit of Christmas brought out beautifully. Have you read the back? The picture followed it almost exactly, even in the <unclear/> and was certainly spoken as exception ally pleasing and heart-warming a picture as lived ever seen they cowboy and the Lady has an exception ally fine idea in its <unclear/> and was beautifully acted out by 

-2-
Then we talked, and finally, after decorating our tree, which Hil & had selected that afternoon, (It's really beautiful) we put out the lights, all but the trees and turned on the radio to hear Christmas carols Final ly, about 11:00, we went to bed. 
We got up about 8:30 Christmas <unclear/>. Then, we had a nice breakfast, and afterwards, opened our packages. Hilda gave one a ticket in the orchestra section for the Ballet Russe Saturday afternoon Isn't that marvelous! Betty gave one some lovely Avon lipstick! I felt so lucky I certainly didn't expect anything! About 10:00 Hilda stuffed our duck and we got a marvelous <unclear/>! 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER
-3-
We had duck dressing, white & sweet potatoes gravy, broccoli, orange salad, cran-berries, and to top it off, some of the best pumpkin pie I've ever eaten. Hilda made it Sat. evening in a glass baking dish pie dish which we got at the Apollo Theatre on Tuesday evening. We also had some of Hilda's choclates which she rec'd from Mr. Aisler - a 2lb box of Amy Smith choclates, and some real <unclear/> cookies from a swiss lady - delicious ones! In the afternoon, we got dressed & went to see the <unclear/> the <unclear/> - very good shows. Then, about 8:00, we came home, listened to the radio, etc. ate a light supper, and went to bed about 10:30. 
We got in very late - about 9:00 Monday morning, for it 

90b
-4-
was really quite a success except for the fact that one of the trees fell down! I think, from various reports, that our opening <unclear/> owe snow ballet was the biggest bit of the whole Pageant. 
I must end this messy note now - for Betty is ready to go down town & is going to take it with her to mail. 
Loads of love to every one there from all of us here! 
Alice 
I have no time now to write Yan. But I want to say Hello at least and Thank you for the beautiful Xmas presents. We are both very happy about them. 
Loads of love, 
Hilda 
-5-
all its players. I'd like very much for you to see them both if you can. We thought they were both very, very good pictures. You'd love the joyful enthusiasm in the former, and the fine acting and idea in the latter I'm sure Both are vastly entertaining! What's a new meaning for <unclear/>!
Today, Betty is going down-town to meet Hilda and have lunch with her, etc. I am going over to the studio to practice at 11:00 Then at 5:00 this evening I have practice for the ballet tomorrow & afterwards , my lesson today. too, & Betty's going to go to it with her! 
I've been going fast all week. I wish it all, I've been 

-6-
practicing for the ballet & Eny has been getting my costume fitted, etc. Next, I've been working & rehearsing with a group of ballet girl of 9 & a group of toe of 4 fox our Christmas assembly program at school, which was this last Friday morning. Another girl, Harriet, & I were they spirits of the snow. We did at duo-toesols to Chopin's "Grande Valse Brilliante. We came Dec from opposite sides & worked opposite each other part of the dance and together the other part. At the end of our short dance, we woke up the "snow" which really consisted of the mine ballet girls, who were dressed in white costumes & <unclear/> upon <unclear/> "stairs" between two fir trees is such a manner that they were fooled the audience they 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
-7-
really did look exactly like snow! Then we "santed" off the stage, (the snow spirits) and the "snow" ballet girls did a soft waltzy dance to Wilham Garonis's "Valse Bleue". After that, they pound in a slimy circle against the back of the stage, & the four morning sun beams - toe dancers dressed in rose - colored tarletan skirts & leotards came out & danced to "Tales of the Vienna Woods" by Strauss. In the finale Harriet & J, the snow spirits came out, bowile-d <unclear/> the toe dancers & finally posed with the others who stopped just when we did. The stage was lighted with blue, green and red lights & our dance 