<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
61f
110 E. Hancock
Sunday, June 1, 1942.
4:00 in afternoon
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
Dear Daddy, Mama, and Everyone Else There,
<p>I was so very thrilled and happy to get your dear, long letters filled with such good news that I was happier even than usual all day. <underline>Do</underline> continue to write, all of you - Max, you too if you find time. I know you and Sig and Albert adn Ollie are all <underline>very</underline> busy, however.</p>
<p>At present, we are all sitting in our lovely clean apt., having walked and put up our hair, writing to you - our people at home. How supremely grateful we are to you and happy that everything is O.K. with you. I think and yes - dream of you each and every day.</p>
<p>Tongiht is our last night at Larson's. It's been a week of excellent</p>
(2)
<p>experience in many <unclear/> and we're gaining something each night. I told you about Doris hurting her keens. We think it best that she rest it for several days before taking any more engagements. You see, our contract at Larson's calls for four people, and if less than that dance, it may be cancelled, and we wouldn't be paid. Therefore, Doris has had to continue performing in all our numbers, although it has been quite difficult for her to do so. Four days of rest this next week will be a god-send for her. The knee <underline>has</underline> been improving nicely and we put packs and albatum and alcohol on it regularly to hasten healing. One week at Laron's is really plenty to receive what it can give us in expereince, anyway - so this is just as well. Besides this, we</p>
61g
(3)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>have several things of great importance to do, which could not be done were we working. We'll rehearse harder than every thses next four days, and will attend to other matters of which I shall tell you later. We shall take a theatre engagement here for the week end. Then we'll perhaps dance in Flint Mich. or at the Northwood Inn for several weeks. Our date for Colossimo's in Chicago (one of <underline>the</underline> largest and best known theatre resturants there) is set for the middle of June. This place gives grand publicity, so we must be well versed on our numbers by then. We get paid to night - whee! George will fake my Social Security no. till you can get it for me, Hilda.</p>
(4)
<p>We are learning an adorable sailor and girl dance now to two French sailor tunes - all done on the point. Sylvia is the street flapper and Doris and I all the slightly over - happy sailors. It really will be clever when we get it worked up well. The patomime is quite difficult at first but adorable too.</p>
<p>Yesterday was Memorial Day - and a glorious, breezy, rather sultry, cloudy and sunny, (alternately) day it was. "Just right for swimming" George remarked as we three girls jumped off the bus on Robson, a suburban Detroit street, and were met by the head of our little troupe. We were, you see, invited to lunch at his Mother's home "our in the sticks" as she had told us be-</p>
61h
(5)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>forehand. Poor George had to wait several minutes for us - because, as usual, we had had a hard time finding our way around in this most unusually constructed city. He was energetic and gay as usual, however, and his Mother as well, for their temerament is <underline>so</underline> typically French (as I conveice it, anyway) Mrs. Leon (She now has remarried, but that is the only name I know) is really very lovely - talks with an adorable accent (none of which George has), and has a fluffy French poodle which she calls "Bebe" and "Nanette". We were royally yet very spontanceously entertained. After a delicious lunch we listened to all sorts fo music on records, both</p>
(6)
<p>old and new, classical and popular. We sang and listened to gorgeous waltzes and symphonies to our hearts content and enjoyed ourselves immensely. Mrs. Leon suggested a slight tint for Doris' and my hair - darker for Doris and reddish for me. History repeats itself - I was born with reddish hair - remember? You see, blonde hair simply fades out under lights, while hair with a reddish cast catches all the gleam and has definite highlights. It <underline>won't</underline> be dyed - only done with "Egyptian" a tint unharmfull to hair. We will also have our hair machinelessly permanented before the tinting. This is absolutely necessary for hair <underline>must</underline> be lovely for dancing - it is a definite part of a dance's appeal.</p>
61i
(7)
The Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>Mrs. Leon used to be a hairdresser - so she is hoping to be able to do all this for us in our apt. Isn't that nice? I do hope she can. So we'll do that thesee next four days, besides shopping a bit, catching up on washing, and rehearsing hard. What think you of this? To continue with yesterday, we came home about 4:30, ate, reted, dressed and were called for by George at 8:00. The shows were at 9:30 and 12:30 (some days at 10:00) and we were wringing wet throughout. Then in the midst of our Jungle number came crashes of thunger - and it poured and lightened marvelously. Just as we were leaving, the lights all went off in the club - and I've ever seen such an electrical storm as we had then.</p>
(8)
<p>George braved it to go for the car - and we waited till he came back before venturing outside into the torrents of rain. On our way home, we <underline>forded</underline> several foot and a half deep rivers running accross low places in the street, and pushed a stalidear besides. George said we could use a little such experience to get ready for bombings. Detroit will be first when this happens! We're not afriad - and besides, stoms are <underline>so</underline> beautiful. Another one is going on nowas I write - and it is almost pitch dark at 5:00! We must go on the bus this eveing, so must leave at 7:30.</p>
<p>I have changed my name for the stage to Alicia Nye - how do you like it? It is very similar to my real name, has a nice sound, and is short</p>

