<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
55 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 95
4920 Blackstone Ave.,
Chicago, Ill.
June 4 '43
<note>You must think of me as being fundamentally happy &amp; very hopeful for us <hi rend="underline">all</hi>! <hi rend="underline">Really</hi>.</note>
Dear Sig, Max and blessed Wubs',
<p>I rec'd Max's truly happy letter of congratulation nearly a month ago, and it must have seemed that I didn't care. But I did care and was truly glad. I <hi rend="underline">thought</hi> letters, but didn't write, probably because things were strange and new here. You know how that is as well as I. I thank you now, old lady, for your expression of the old fine feeling that I know well and deeply appreciate.</p>
<p>Now we have Sig's letter, just arrived. You're right, it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> too bud for us to be apart - and that we should grow vaguer. You know what your trouble is, Sig - I mean the deeper trouble. It's the spirit frustrated by the present state of affairs, and I'm not wise enough to preach about it. I know well how that works - you will be able to control it - more or less, I know. Praying <hi rend="underline">can</hi> help, as you know.</p>
(over)
96
-2-
<p>You have such a fine ability already very highly developed, and you can give thanks for that much - and it is so very much. It seems that you will be preserved through this addled period - and afterward You'll blossom, I feel sure. But It's hard to wait &amp; to feel that you may be losing for lack of fracture. <hi rend="underline">Do</hi> hold down that deep feeling that hurts you - as best you possibly can. And do continue <hi rend="underline">believing</hi> in your destiny?</p>
<p>I'm in a heluva quandary. I've been having eye trouble, of course - reading steadily 8 hrs per day. Have been trying 3 wks to get glasses. The first doctor <hi rend="underline">fumbled</hi> twice. Now I'm with the great specialist, Dr. Gradle. The first doc Gradle says had me in danger of cataract (!). Gradle says my vision is better than normal, "but how in hell do you see as well as you do" with hose specks "like a snowstorm" in your eyes? I take the final exam tomorrow &amp; should have glasses by next Wednesday I <hi rend="underline">see</hi> clearly, but the nerve shock is great.</p>
97
-3-
<p>I have a job I can take tomorrow at 18 44 per week &amp; no eyes strain. Have agreed to begin. But heres the probability that Esquire will boost me to $75 per wk. I can't know until Monday - and I'm due at the new job Monday! Is <hi rend="underline">that</hi> pretty funny!! My quandary is increased by the horror I have of eye strain. Isn't it a vow? I was off all this wk. trying to get glasses, &amp; today I get paid in full as though I'd been working! <hi rend="underline">That</hi> makes me feel under obligation to Esquire.</p>
<p>I never did read 8 hrs per day - not even in my most strenuous book review days I'm afraid I'm foolish to think I <hi rend="underline">can</hi> read that much.</p>
<p>I'm debating this minute as to which job I shall take. I <hi rend="underline">may</hi> just throw Esquire over &amp; go to work where there's no eye-strain. I'd have the telephone desk for the I ran Frenian Stoker to just directing the mechanics to trouble-shooting jobs - nothing more. That's amusing too, and I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> believe I could learn how!!!</p>
<p>Golly, gosh, damn, dog on it!</p>
98
-4-
<p>anyway, I've surely got two jobs, &amp; no kidding. I have three counting K.C., which I can't take for 3 was.</p>
<p>The Macmillan business is thus. Publishing order given in April. Then a new gov't order regarding paper. Cycle held up for further consideration this Fall. The Company really seriously desiring to publish. The B- of the M Club now considering the complete Cycle as a project. Might go through. If so, Micmillan would be allowed to publish. Ain't it unnusink?</p>
<p>Well, Let's keep our sense of humor and cherish it along with our real affection for each other. By God we're nice people and we like each other!</p>
<p>I think of our Girls - the dear dear little ladies! Hasten the day when Gaki and Nanny can be with them again! Hello Joan - and Elaine! Love &amp; kisses to you, bless your hearts!</p>
Endless love
Dad
<p>When I speak of you four to outsiders, I'm always proud. I wish you could hear. I'm proud of all you kids - so proud.</p>









