<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
133 122
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
SIGURD NEIHARDT, BOOKING AGENT
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON
JUN30
3--PM
1939
MO
Mr. &amp; Mrs Oliver Fink
9716 Hawthorne 
Overland,
Missouri
<unclear/>
123
Branson the 29th, 1939
Dear Enat:
<p>Don't mind the loss of the opal. If you don't find it, there'll be a better stone to mount on the ring. Perhaps I loosened the claws in polishing, but there are so many claws I can't see how that happened. I have a fine carved topaz that might fit the ring. If not I can cut another stone to fit.</p>
<p>It looks as though the Bison affair happened so that I could be out of the country here for August work. When the steams heat is turned on here, there's not much to do but lie around and wonder what the heck. It seems mama and I will go together &amp; probably camp for three weeks or more. You remember the well and camping ground in the Slim Buttes! - or the south side of the road? That's where, probably.</p>
Love to both
Dad
<p>see you July 15th.</p>
<underline>over</underline>
<note>sentences below are in margins of letter</note>
<p>Maybe you should send the ring - or shall I get it on July 15th?</p>
<p>I'm glad the ivory-amethyst ring gives satisfaction. Your <unclear>money back</unclear> at anytime, if you're not pleased.</p>
<p>Stove seems tight, does it? Should hold forever.</p>
124
Friday noon
<p>Sig just now got a $600 engagement for me at Knox College under the William <unclear>Honnald</unclear> Lectureship. The South is coming through very satisfactorily, &amp; so are <unclear/> and the Southwest. Knox will keep Alice going next year.</p>
<p>We hace a brand new Hudson - got it day before yesterday. I trade with no down pay &amp;, no increase in monthly installments. Ours was perfect, but had over 18000 unles &amp; tries thin. We got the 112 model which should save us $5 or more per month on gas, not to mention tires. Now we have 5 new tires! I'm <unclear>pizen</unclear> in buying - no good in selling.</p>
<p>We have to assume, in our business, that long drives are normal, and we know exactly what the total cost per mile is - car rent included. There's no such thing as really owning a constantly vanishing value like that of a car. We call it rent, &amp; will have a new car every year so long as this business continues no repairs, no tires to buy.</p>