<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
13
80 
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO 
COVERED WAGON CAMP 
GREEN RIVER, WYOMING
GREENMER, WYO. JUL 25 7-AM 1937. 
Mrs Enid Fink 
Branson 
Mo 
<figure/> 

14
COVERED WAGON CAMP 
J. D. Mager, Prop. 
GREEN RIVER, WYOMING 
7 Miles West of City on U.S. 30
Saturday evening 
Sunday A.M. 
Enid and Ruth darlings! 
It was so good to receive your letter, Newe at Green River We all ate it up - I read it out loud twice. We have been on the go and are tired, but have not found the proper place at which to stay. Paddy has seen South Pass at last and it was a most interes ting voyage of discovery - now he wants to see Henry's Ford today - and after that we will get our mail here at Green River once more and then go straight to Salt Lake City. I have sent you a card every day - Hope you received them O.K. Daddy thinks Wichita is the very nicest place possible for your Ollie and you. He inquired at other towns - at Colorado Springs there was no chance and Denver is just one more horrible city - they are all sores as far as I am concerned. We are so happy that you both are feeling happy and are improving and I am so grateful for any thing you do on the place - the more I see of places the better I love our home! If we could all be together there for Xmas, and if Ollie had a job in Wichita so you and Sig's coudl come home in his car - I would feel that living was indeed a rare privilege! Lache is a 

15
boy, I can never appreciate his considerate kindness to me last year enough, and now you must feel the same. I think Hilda half wishes she were there with him, although she is fully en joying this trip. Especially since she is driving a lot now. She is very good at it, and that relieves Daddy.- I am anxious to know about the water at home, what could have been the matter? The water was drained before we left - I don't see how the pipe could have burst as it seems to have done. Do you sleep out on the porch? I hope you do. part of the time anyhow! I dreamed about pillows last night, and that reminded me of the fact that you must be sure and send a couple to your home address - If Ollie does go to see the news paper man in Wichita he'll have to go 300 Miles West. I wish he would tho'! Must see about breakfast now as the folks are getting up Loads of love to you and beset wishes to Lache
from Mamma. 