<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
0e
Jr. Camp Nakanawa
Mayland, Tenn.
July 10, 1941.
<p>Maxie, this is for you too. I absolutely will write you soon. I know you can't believe me, but I'll show ya!</p>
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I was very thrilled to get your dear letters of Sunday. Really, letters from you are a true inspiration. When people believe in you the way you do in me, one simply has to do well and be good.</p>
<p>In case you didn't receive my letter of Sunday, Daddy, I want to ask you again if you will send the drum. Annie Hays (Everyone is called by first names here to make all feel eqyal. There is no disrespect in it at all, and it does give everyone a companionable feeling.) O'Neil is simply thrilled with the idea of the ceremony and the drum. We plan to give each of the four tribes one Council Ring ceremony of it's own and save the ceremony you worked out for me fo rthe final Council Ring, in which all four tribes will take part. We want to use the</p>
(2)
<p>drum for each ceremony. Will you please send it as soon as possible, so we can use it next Friday? Tomorrow we'll not have a regular ceremony, but we must have our first one next Friday. Since the custom in Council Ring (as held before) is to have a dramatic skit, we thought a short Indian play would be a good thing to put on for the individual tribe Council Rings. We have a little play which is along the <sic>Cinderalla</sic> theme with Indian characters and it contains the rainbow as a sort of symbol. Therefore, I thought this coudl be used by the tribe representing the West. Is that right? Please do send me the words to "See where the sacred sun is walking" etc., as we want definitely to use it. Do you think we should have a different song for each tribe or should they each have the same one? You see, each tribe will meet separately to decide upon and learn it's ceremony and we'd like each tribe to have something different. Should</p>
0f
(3)
<p>would be O.K. since the headbands would show their quarter. Is this alright? We plan to costume <strike/> six (Should it be six or would four do?) of each tribe and simply have headbands for the rest. We want one chief, two firebuilders, and what should we call the other, or if we really should have six, the others? We'll make a big feather headdress for the chief, for such is what they want to do. Is this alright? What is the meaning of the other song "Sheek Sioux "Yaowaoway"? (I don't knwo how to spell those words!) Maybe we could use it for one tribe. I hope you don't mine too much answering this mob of questions and sending the drum and your words to the song, Daddy. You must know how I'll appreciate it. We're going to use makeup on the girls (brown grease paint?) and braid their hair. Most of them have braids now. If we could use those wigs we had in Branson it would be swell too</p>
<note>text below in margin of letter</note>
<p>Daddy, do you know of Col Rice's sonnets? His sister-in-law is allice Hagen (?) Rice, author of "Mrs. Wiggs of the Cabbage Parch." Col Rice is of Nakanawa</p>
(4)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tenessee
<p>We, do you think, do the rabbit dance only in the last ceremony and do some other steps for each separate tribe's ceremony? The Arts and Crafts teacher from Sr. Camp is a very experienced designer and she met with us Sunday to design the costumes. Since these tribes are supposed to be the Creeks, Choctaws, Cherokees, and Chickasaws, I thought we did not need to costume them as exclusively representing one of the four quarters, but each should have the symbols of its quarter placed on headbands of the color of the quarter. The costumes will be made of sacks, straight rectangular garments belted at the waist, as these Southern Indians wore them (the women (or would they be better loose?) on the backs are Indian designs and symbols. One of the tribes has the circle and quarter (plan of your ceremony) on its costumes, while the others have merely characteristic Indian designs, such as the eagle, lightning, etc. I thought this</p>
0g
(5)
junior camp nakanawa
mayland, tennessee
<p>Shouldn't the chief of each tribe carry the symbol of his quarter in the final ceremony? You needn't bother answering all this in list form, Daddy, but if you find things here in you consider wrong, please tell me. I hope you'll think the costumes are alright.</p>
<p>Please do write me soon, Daddy and Mama. You cannot possibly know how I love to hear from you.</p>
<p>I'm so thrilled abou the news of "Jed" Daddy.</p>
<p>Mary Broad, our Ass. Dir. is really a lovely person as are all our counselors. She was talking to me this morning in such a lovely way. She said she likes the way I mix with the children after dinner, etc., and of course I told ehr I enjoy doing so.</p>
<p>My classes are coming right along now. I'm teaching them a rythmic barre, floor exercises, and with the smaller children "creative works" as they say - that is making their work interesting by letting them apply movements they learn</p>
(6)
<p>here in class to certain happenings, such as a ceed sprouting and growing etc. They seem to like that. <strike>and</strike> Our pianist here suggested doing this since it is necessary that they don't get bored and feel it's just like dancing class in the winter at home! I think with little children this is good, because they do like to have their imaginations appealed to. If you have any suggestions along this line, please tell me. It may sound silly as I guess it really is, but for camp work among little children it is interesting, and does make them contract, stretch up , relax, etc.</p>
<p>I've been swimming nearly everyday and moonlight canoeing once. I'm also learning to dive correctly from a springboard and do the crawl correctly. This lake is just simply unearthly when the moon is shining on it. The other night I stood on the dock and saw the path of shimmering silver which the moon made across the lake. Below the moon were snow white clouds and below that the dark forms of trees bordering the lake. It was a glorious sight! We had a huge red cloud in the lake and sky several days ago at sunset such as I've never seen before.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<note>text below is in margin of letter</note>
<p>I'll be glad for the shorts, Mama! I can do my own washing and have cooks iron or sometimes, do it myself.</p>