<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Neihardt Collection 
55
(1) 
5540 Cotes Ave. 
St. Louis, MO. 
Sept. 4, 1938. 
46
Dear Daddy, 
Here we are in our new apart-ment, and are going to like it very well, I believe. 
Hil & I took Betty to the train Friday morning, and, consequently felt rather <unclear/> the rest of the day. In fact, were just now getting fixed to doing things by ourselves, again! 
Daddy, Hilda and I have taked over the problem of expenses and have decided this much. Hilda will pay for the great and you, through me, the pod and of little extra expense if eye hardly not use all the letter per<unclear/> We think wix dollars or even from you would easily cover that. Then, in addition, I will need some pocket money for various little expenses in school, etc. say one dollar. My dancing lessons will be three dollars a week if I take only two class lessons. Then, instant school I really need a pair of shoes just 

47
(2) 
badly. Hilda says I can get a good pair for school for legs than three dollars, probably two. In conclusion, I think that <del/> I will need <del/> $12 thighwell <del/> for all expenses. Hilda and I thought that if you would send a little extra each week, I could save it for a sort of clothes fund, and then when I would need some clothes I could get those. Therefore after this week, $11 or $12 will the plenty of money each week this would take in the things <unclear/> I might have to do for school and for which I coudl ask you for extra money if you were here of course, the letter is im-possible when you are not here and still I would need the money. I hope this seemed re sonable to you and Mama, Daddy It does to Hilda and <unclear/>, and I certainly hope you know how gratefully I <unclear/> for it, and for <unclear/> I shall be able to do with it. 
Hilda got two new records of Fawler the other day, and they are simply artistic <unclear/>!

48
(3) 
They are all songs which I know you would enjoy hearing him sing - and the records are much better than the other ones we have of him. 
Hilda and I are going out to Enid's and Ollie's tomorrow to spend the day, Labor Day It will be lovely its stay there awhile. 
There really isn't much more to write, except that we are happy here and hope all of pay there are the sauce, including Joannie and Laina! 
Loads of Love, 
Alice 
P.S. Daddy, we are running short of funds this week up would you please send the $12 as soon as possible? 