<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
81 Neihardt 137
Neihardt #610
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
Special 
<underline>Delivery</underline>
GALESBURG
NOV 4
9 -PM
1939
Mrs. Mona Neihardt
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overlan,
Missouri
(St. Louis County)
138
[Nov 4, 1939]
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
Nov 4, Sat. 7 A.M.
Precious Mona:
<p>I was mighty glad to see your letter in my box when I went down for breakfast - and what a good letter it was.</p>
<p>There is little or no news for me to give. I finished the series on Poetic Values in three lectures, and my rather small audience was with me at the end, I think. Anyway the room was full of friendliness. They can't know the importance of what I was getting at. Nothing but what happens inside can give that. But I read some passages from the great scientist Eddinton, supporting my thesis, and remaked that were it not for the dates on the little pages, if might be supposed that I had been doing some industrious cribbing! His passages could have fitted right into my book, and I wonder a lot if he hadn't read Poetic Values. Seems queer. Mine was published 4 years before his, and MacMillian is his publisher too.</p>
(over)
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
139
-2-
<p>Anyway, modern scientific theory is in harmony with my thesis. They <underline>did</underline> believe, however, that I knew what I was talking about, I'm sure. O God! what a dark world it is in so many ways - the human world, I mean; certainly not the other.</p>
<p>I know the feeling toward me here is kindly; I like all I've met.</p>
<p>Beginning Monday, I'll read from my Cycle - 3 lectures; and probably I can give a period to 800 <unclear/> &amp; Lyrics. There are already 3 classes scheduled. Tomorrow evening dinner with the Prof. of Astronomy a dear fellow. No formality. This P.M. the big football game of homecoming week; and tonight I'll have to do somethign at the banquet, I suppose. Things will be all right; and certainly so if something happens to waken me.</p>
<p>I do hesitate to give the talk on Literature Since 1912, as I feel that the president &amp; most of the others are rather singly fitted into the going world. It seems impossible to me. But people see in fragments - almost never in wholes.</p>
140
-3-
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
<p>Yesterday when you were having your teeth pulled, I began writing a letter to you about it, but didn't finish. I <underline>do</underline> hope there won't be a lot to stand. Still, I'm <underline>so</underline> glad you're getting fixed up. We'll see later about your coming up. It's wholly a matter of feeling prosperous about it. Sig was to come after us here, and I hope it can be that way. You'd like these people; they <underline>are</underline> dear &amp; good &amp; many are very intelligent. The youngsters I've met are fine too, in their crude way. <underline>Yes, you should look after Alice, of course.</underline></p>
<p>I do hope - or at least wish - that something might come about to give me a new grip. If I could only get the time <underline>and</underline> the sound of reasonable security so that I could</p>
(over)
WHEN IN ST. LOUIS HOTEL KINGS-WAY
SCHIMMEL HOTELS ARE DEDICATED TO YOUR COMFORT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
141
-4-
<p>complete the Cycle! I don't want to get to the place where I just let go and cease to care. I can't feel that lecturing, on the whole, <underline>is</underline> very highly remunerative. Expenses are great. But I'm sure things <underline>will</underline>work out one way or another.</p>
<p>I do love you so much - and the girls and Sig &amp; Max &amp; the Wubs. You are a precious group. And I love Oddie. He belongs to us. It is surely wonderful the way he &amp; Enat love each other. <underline>That's</underline> the greatest thing in the whole poor addled world.</p>
<p>I'll not be as unhappy as I sound in spots here. I'll waken when the night stimulus hits me.</p>
And I do love you.
Jno.