<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
57a
1425 N. Dearborn
Chicago, Ill.
May 15, 1942
Dear Daddy, Mama, Everyone,
<p>Here we are after a long day of truly great excitement in many ways, sitting about our dining room table attempting to convey our thoughts and experiences to you "dear ones at home." Supper is cooking but at present, at least, we are too excited to be hungry.</p>
<p>The day began by being rainy and cold beyond belief for a middle of May day - at least, in the ideas of a St Louisan. We arose at 9:00, breakfasted, and cleaned our little apartment. Then we</p>
(2)
<p>took advantage of a <unclear/> drawsiness by sitting on our sofa, feet up on nearby chairs, for about one-half hour. This we overcame finally, and got up enough energy for a barre. Dressing was accomplished in a flurry as usual, and we emerged from our cozy building into a wet cold dark day, protected by Sylvia's umbrella, at <unclear>precisely</unclear> half past twelve. We could actually see our breaths as we walked along, and the jerky old street car was not much warmer than the outdoors - but at least it was dry. How glad I</p>
57b
(3)
<p>was that my Spring suit is made of good <underline>heavy</underline> wool, wind and rain resistant, Hilda! We arrived at the Kimball Bldg. 25 East Jackson, in time ot make our 1:00 o'clock rehearsal. George met us at the door, announcing that the pianist, Theresa, and the agent had not yet arrived, but that the Countess was already there. Surely enough, when we entered the rehearsal hall, there sat the Countess, and newr her stood George Leon's dear Grandmother. Both greeted us effusively though genuinely, but i was the</p>
(4)
<p>sharp-witted althought intensely human Countess Korsyiska who added comissally. "Hurry up and dress now - you're late!"</p>
<p>First we ran thorugh the Viennese waltz, which is to be done in turquoise princess fitting evening gownish costumes in the black lace bustle effects and very full skirts. This was much better with the added stimulus of music, than we had anticipated. Next, we dressed in our elaborated Russian costumes and did our Russian number. The Countess said</p>
57c
(5)
<p>"Bravo" and the Grandmother energitically discussed points of interest with her George (a laecent francais). The Jungle Number came after an encore of the Russian done for the agent, a very practical, high class woman. She liked the Russian very much and also the Jungle, with a few suggestions of her own thrown in to the latter. We felt the mood of the music and thoroughly enjoyed our dancing. George too was pleased, both with us and with the agent's reaction. It seems</p>
(6)
<p>now that we <underline>may</underline> leave Sunday - if not, the middle of next week. <underline>Do</underline> keep on praying for us - that we may do well in our opening and thereafter.</p>
<p>Now, to continue with our day, the Countess took us from rehearsal to tea at one of the nicest Dept. Store tearooms - Mandel's. This we shall always remember as an unforgettable stimulus and joy. First, however, I'd like to tell you a remark the Countess made to George upon our leaving. She said I had the best histrionic talent - that my</p>
57d
(7)
<p>expressions changed - didn't remain in a fixed smile as the other girls' were subject to. I was amazed, for I've alwasy felt so much that I've held back and haven't shown on my face and it's been a great grief to me - both because of my own feeling - and others' comments. So you can see the Countess' frank remark is encouraging. So we went to tea, and spent over an hour eating crisp waffles and coffee - and talking <underline>and</underline> talk about <underline>real</underline> things. She is so like you, Daddy and Mama. You <underline>must</underline> meet</p>
(8)
<p>her, for you will love <unclear/> other. Her ideas of the sound system and world conditions are yours to a "t" Daddy. Besides, she is dear and human, and passionate, and warm - a real patron saintess! She has plans for us too! She has painted many rich people in Detroit and Cleveland. Then she will write giving a long "song and dance" about how lovely we are - and to be sure to see us, suggesting that we will be glad</p>
57e
(9)
<p>to do a performance at one of their dinner parties. This might help us greatly - who knows - and it certainly shows the dearness of the Countess.</p>
<p>We came home at 6:00, ate supper, and prepared for George - who came with all the kinds of make-up to create personality make-ups for us. You should see the new "me." My forehead is made darker to reduce height, my nose is classic-ified by light grease paint on ridge, shadow on sides, and my eyes are greatly enlarged and</p>
(10)
<p>Do pray for me.</p>
<p>made more expressive. This is only for dancing of course. Sylvia said "You look <underline>so</underline> much like Hilda now. Mama, is my hair - do O.K. is I have curls on forehead? You have no idea how much of an art make-up is. -But on 2nd thought - I know you do! Oh! Yes. The Countess liked George immensely. Said we were very lucky to work with a boy so inately "gentle." We were glad of this, naturally.</p>
<p>I rec'd the letter, package and, $10 just this morning (Sat.) Thansk beyond words.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice