<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.19.12-15_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John Myers O'Hara to John G. Neihardt, December 15, 1941</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.19.12-15_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John Myers O'Hara to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1941-12-15">December 15, 1941</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.19.12-15_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>New York, Dec. 15, 1941</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was delighted to get your prompt and deeply appreciated reply to my letter. But I did not receive your letter of some years ago, to my great regret. This was undoubtedly due to the fact that it was not forwarded to me from an old address. I have been a veritable gipsy for the last seven or eight years, living at a dozen or more different places. It is the result of having fallen on evil days. The long depression, after the panic of 1929, and the practical abolition of the Stock Exchange as a speculat<unclear>ion</unclear> institution, not only wiped me out of a large amount of money, but took away my means of making a living. I had been in Wall St. for over thirty years, nearly all of the time with unusual success, and had the best, from a material standpoint, of all that life could give. Now I am getting the "ebb of the tide," but am trying to take it with equanimit<unclear>y</unclear> of a Greek philosopher. It is difficult, however, at my extreme age, to contend with adversity or be reconciled to it. I had made provision for old age but, unfortunately, the securities I had set aside for income declined to nothing and became worthles<unclear>s</unclear> under the New Deal. Necessity was so sharp that
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.19.12-15_0002"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">2</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
                    
                    <unclear/> compelled me, five or six years ago, to sell at auction about forty thousand dollars' worth of paintings, rare books, and objets d'art that I had been collecting for over a quarter of a century. And I only realized about one-fifth of what it was <add>all</add> actually worth. I still hopw, however, in spite of the debacle, to retrieve the fortune of the <unclear>past</unclear>. It cheered me immensely to read, in your letter, the magnificent praise that you gave my sonnets. Such commendation, coming from one of the greatest poets that America has produced, goes straight <sic>to</sic> my heart. I was deeply interested in what you said about your friend, the young poet, who was such an admirer of the sonnet. I deeply regret that I have no copy of "Pagan Sonnets" left, or I would send it to him at once. All my books are gone, except a few in storage, and these are impossible for me to get at. Among them, I do not think there is any copy of my sonnets. I was sorry to hear that you were no longer with the "Post-Dispatch". But your kind offer to write something, either for the "Dispatch" or some other paper, about Hervey's book made me happier than any words can express. And if you can see your way to do it, I shall be eternally grateful to you. Hervey is one of the finest fellows in the world &#8212; I wish you could meet him &#8212; and he has been a faithful friend to me through
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.19.12-15_0003"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">3</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                    
                    <unclear/> my misfortune. His sonnets are so unusually fine that I consider them superior to my own. He is an astounding genius, but modest and retiring to an exceptional degree. His book, entitled "The Conquerors" will be published in a few days, and I have written him to be sure and send you a copy at once. He sent me one of the two or three "advance copies" from the publishers, and I am as enthusiastic about his sonnets, after seeing them in print, as I was when I first read them in manuscript. I was a notice recently in the "Times Book Review" about the last volume of <add>your</add> great "Cycle of The West," and I intend to get the volume at once and read it &#8212; as I have all those other mighty epics of yours. I come from that great west which you so incomparably describe in supreme song. I was born on a thousand acre farm in Winn Co., Iowa, owned by father &#8212; who, by the way, was born in Vermont. My father was one of the pioneer railroad builders and, when I was a boy, on my summer vacation, I saw some wild life with him on the plains. I was in that "old beloved Nebraska" of yours when I was a little boy of eight &#8212; my father, at that
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.19.12-15_0004"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">4</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
                
                    <unclear>time</unclear>, was building the road from Valentine, Neb. into the Black Hills for the Northwestern. I can remember the coyotes howling at night, and the catamounts crying in the trees down along the Elkhorn river, not forgetting many terrible cyclones. And I used to play with the Indian papooses, putting pennies on the stumps of trees for them to shoot at with their bows and arrows. From that to Wall St. is a long way &#8212; but such are the strange chances of life. Yes, I sincerely echo your wish that we could get together for a long talk. It is a supreme regret to me that I have never met you. If you ever come to <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi>, don't fail to look me up. I was delighted to hear that Hilda, the brilliant little girl, of years gone by, was now a lovely young lady, with extraordinary singing talent. Give her my kindest regards &#8212; and with them, my best wishes for a Merry Christmas and Happy New Year &#8212; to her, to you, and to all your family.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Ever sincerely yours,</salute>
                    <signed>John Myers O'Hara</signed>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Hotel Imperial</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>32nd St. and Broadway,</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>New York.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>