<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.J4.28.1-2">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Evelyn Vogt to John G. Neihardt, 1965</title>
<author>Vogt, Evelyn</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>j4a.28.1</idno> 
<availability>
<p> </p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>


<notesStmt><note>Date based on Florence T. Ward's death.</note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Vogt, Evelyn </author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Evelyn Vogt to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1965">1965</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>University of Missouri, Western Historical Manuscripts Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>2-typed pages</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kivett, Marvin F.</term>
<term>Ward, Florence T.</term>
<term>Canarsky, Ruth</term>
<term>Abendroth, Fern</term>
<term>Buchholz, Martha</term>
<term>Munderloh, Lillian</term>
<term>Nottlemann, Diane</term>
<term>Wiig, Hilmer</term>
<term>Sorensen, Roy</term>
<term>Martin</term>
<term>Ockander, Edna</term>
<term>Ockander, Pete</term>
<term>Ockander, Bill</term>
<term>Leriger, Henry</term>
<term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
<term>Thompson, Lynn</term>
<term>Thompson, Erica</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
<term>Sioux City (Iowa)</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term>Omaha World-Herald</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1965"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Vogt, Evelyn</persName>
<placeName>Bancroft (Neb.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Vogt, Evelyn</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Proofreading and encoding</change>
<change when="2016"><name xml:id="ah">Hanson, Ali</name> Transcription and Initial Encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<note type="curatorial">196?</note>
<note type="curatorial">1</note>

<note type="curatorial">Western Historical Manuscripts Collection University of Missouri Columbia, Mo.</note>

<fw>Neihardt Study Restoration Bancroft Nebraska<lb/>
"There, that ground is holy, and, a Tree shall grow and flower and fill with singing birds."<lb/>
Bancroft, Nebraska, 68004<lb/>

Committee Members from Garden Club.<lb/>
Ruth Canarsky &#8212; Chairman<lb/>
Fern Abendroth<lb/>
Martha Buchholz<lb/>
Lillian Munderloh<lb/>

Committee Members from Commercial Club<lb/>
Evelyn Vogt Chairman<lb/>
Diane Nottlemann Secretary<lb/>
Hilmer Wiig Finance<lb/>
Roy Sorensen<lb/>
</fw>

<opener>Mr John G. Neihardt<lb/>
Skyrim Farm
</opener>

 <p>Dear Mr. Neihardt: </p>

 <p>Your letter arrived Monday and I waited until after the N.S.R.P meeting to
 answer. So glad to hear the Laureate Tout was a pleasure for you. Saw the picture
 of the bust in the World Herald. That must have been a fine surprise.</p>

<p>I have a couple of items of rather sad news about Bancroft, so will tell them first, and then proceed to the more welcome information about the Study Restoration</p>

<p>First sad news, your friend, Mrs. Florence Ward passed away suddenly on Monday. She died
in a department store in Sioux City. Her husband was waiting outside for her, must have been
a terrible shock for the poor man. The funeral is today. They waited until today because there were,
funerals here on Wednesday and Thursday. Martin has been very busy.</p>

 <p>The other item of sad news, is like a death, in a way. It concerns the Old Mill and
 the Ockander property. Place of pleasant memories for all of us who recall Logan
 when it was a real River. The heirs to the property are dying one by one. Edna, Pete
 and Bill are the only ones left. They have three offers to sell the place. Edna is trying
 frantically to keep them from disposing of the house and Mill. If a farmer buys it, they
 (the two buildings) will be torn down of course. The place plowed under and only corn to
 mark the spot. A real pity. The rest of the family laugh at Edna and think she is foolish
 for wanting to preserve the old home. I wrote to Marvin Kivett (Director of Nebr Stat Hist-
 orical Society, and he told me they do not have money to restore anything of that kind.</p>

 <p> Edna (she is still, Miss Edna Ockander) wonders if you might know of someone or some
 group that would be interested in restoring the Mill. I promised to write and ask you. And

<pb/>

<note type="curatorial">2</note>

I have done so. If you know of any possible way to do something about this situation, please let me know.</p>


<p>Now to more pleasant things. The Neihardt Study Restoration. That is proceeding in a most satisfactory way. The towns best carpenter, a Mr Henry Leriger has promised to do the work on the <del>house</del> Study and told me he would donate most of his labor. Is'nt that wonderful? First thing to be done--remove that big tree stump that nestles up aginst the back wall. Then the foundation, the roof, a new porch and then paint. By that time we will check the treasury and see what is in the bottom of the sack! Am hoping to hear something from the McDonald Foundation. They wrote me that they make their decision in November. Am keeping my fingers crossed. We have decided to put a red wood retaining strip around the crushed white rock border that will edge both Prayer Garden and flower beds. Red wood because it is both attractive and indestructable. By the way, what town is copying our Garden? Suppose it is their privilege, but I dont like it. Copy Cats.</p>

<p>Their is not much more to add just now about the Study, or Bancroft, for that matter. Everyone on the Committee is in the best of health and send you their best. We are all enthused about getting things moving toward the real job of Restoration. Hope the Nebraska winter does'nt interfere too much.
</p>
 <p>Best to you, and to Alice, Lynn and Erica</p>
<p>Sincerely,</p>
<p>Evelyn Vogt</p>

 <note type="curatorial">Western Historical Manuscript Collection University of Missouri Columbia, Mo.</note>

</div1>


</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
