<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26b.36-37_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Jessie H. Erickson to John G. Neihardt, August 23, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26b.36-37_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Jessie H. Erickson to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-08-23">August 23, 1958</date>
                    <extent>1 page, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.36-37_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">36</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Arlington, Minnesota
                        August 23, 1958
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>How thoughtful you are! Willard was as pleased as I with your letter. As you see, I took the liberty of sharing it with him. Are you aware that your magnetic personality shines through every word you write? It is so easy to feel your spirit.</p>
                
                <p>Thank you for sending on the information about your coming television lecture series. It really is a pity that we are too far north here to take advantage of it.</p> 
                
                <p>Certainly happiness is an everyday business, as you put it. I believe that every human being is born with a merry heart and a valiant spirit. In the course of daily living, however, one is sometimes saddened temporarily by passing trials and tragedies, but the heart has a powerful instinct to return to its natural happy state. It takes <add>a</add> tremendous amount of pressure created by a combination of faulty human relationships and the whip-lash of circumstance before the spirit can be crushed into a state of depression. But even then, often in the face of great odds, the soul will grasp at any thin thread which offers hope, and frequently is willing to struggle long and fiercely in order to find again the miracle of happiness for which it was created. And once found, do you suppose that any person who has endured such a battle is going to let even one day slip by without savoring deeply the simple joys and pleasures of each shining hour? Believe me, I know what I am saying!</p>
                
                <p>I love to hear you talk about your grandchildren. Why don't you tell us more about your family? It would be such fun to know. Children truly are the greatest compensation of life. They are noisy and unpredictable, of course, but that only makes them interesting. Yester<del>f</del><add>d</add>ay our two boys brought home a group of <hi rend="underline">ten</hi> Mexican boys just a<del>t</del>t lunch time, to my astonishment! Being totally unprepared for that much unexpected company, I just simply seated them all in a circle on the living room floor and fed them egg salad sandwiches and lemonade on trays until they couldn't hold any more. (I couldn't help but think longingly of your buttermilk pancakes!) Only one of the boys could speak English, but it was amazing how well we all understood each other! Their parents are migrant workers who are here for the corn pack.</p>
                
                <p>My article progresses daily. There is so much to say that the task seems monumental. Do you think I am really capable of completing it? At times I have felt a bit hampered by my lack of formal education (I have only a high school diploma), so I must depend almost entirely on my own observations and experience. Believe me, that isn't easy, but the effort is quite rewarding. The word "think" has begun to assume an unsuspected depth of meaning, in my estimation! Well, at least I can handle grammar and punctuation reasonably well, so it might as well be fun!</p>
                
                <p>You are a dear friend, Dr. Neihardt. How can you know waht that means to me?</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Jessie Erickson</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.36-37_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">AFTER 5 DAYS RETURN TO</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    <add>Willard Erickson's
                    Arlington, Minnesota</add>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="recipient">Ansd</note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    ARLINGTON
                    AUG 23
                    6 PM
                    1958
                    MINN.
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
