<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Thomas W. Wright to John G. Neihardt, November 26, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Thomas W. Wright to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-11-26">November 26, 1957</date>
                    <extent>3 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0001-4"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33a</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        702 Sharp Building
                        Kansas City 6, Mo.
                
                        Nov. 26, 1957
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Farm,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route #7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>On this Thankgiving day, I want to extend my warmest wishes to you and Mrs. Neihardt and your family; and may there be beauty around you, may beauty be before you each day.</p>
                
                <p>My mother is coming to vist us in Independence this week, and we are looking forward to an enjoyable time.</p>
                
                <p>In recent weeks, I have been doing some research to learn more about Major Lemly, because his career and service interests me very much. I thought you would like to see what I have found out about Major Lemly. The data assembled points up one fact: he was, indeed an illustrious individual, by which I mean a man of varied talents.</p>
                
                <p>Major Henry Rowan Lemly, who was at Fort Robinson in 1877 as a 2nd Lieutenant with the 3rd Cavalry, and witnessed the death of Crazy Horse, was born in Bethania, North Carolina, Jan. 12, 1851. He entered the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Military Academ<del>ey</del><add>y</add> at West Point in 1868.</p>
                
                <p>Major Lemly graduated June 14, 1872. He ranked 11th in a class of 57 graduates, which speaks for high scholarship. Married Katherine Palmer on Dec. 1, 1874. Commissioned a 2nd Lieutenant (1872) to the 3rd Cavalry, which was then stationed in the Western plains. He took part in Indian combats on the Tongue River, the Rosebud, at Slim Buttes and Belle Fourche.</p>
                
                <p>In 1878 he was transferred to the 3rd Artillery; promoted to 1st Lieutenant in 1880, and Captain in 7th Artillery in 1898. From 1880 to 1883 he was commandant of cadets (by authority of Congress) at Bogota, Columbia National Military School, and instructor in the Colombiam Army from 1894 to 95.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33b</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial">page 2</fw>
                
                <p>Major Lemly was retired on April 20, 1899 at own request after over 30 years of active service. He commanded the light battery c, 7th Artillery in the <hi rend="caps">P.R.</hi> campaign in the Spanish-American War. He was ordered to active duty on May 7, 1917 in the office of the quartermaster general <hi rend="caps">U.S.A.</hi> and promoted to Major, <hi rend="caps">Q.M.</hi> Corps on April 22, 1918. He was retired on March 11, 1920 and died at Washington <hi rend="caps">D.C.</hi>, his home, on Oct. 12, 1925.</p>
                
                <p>Major Lemly was the author of a number of magazine articles including "Among the Arapahoes", "A West Point Romance", and "The Passing of Crazy Horse". He also translated into English several Spanish books of a military nature including one on strategy and tactics.</p>
                
                <p>A summary of his military career is printed in vols. 3, 4, and 7 of George <hi rend="caps">W.</hi> Cullum's <hi rend="underline">Biographical Register of the Officers and Graduates of the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Military Academy at West Point</hi>. His portrait and obituary is printed in the <hi rend="caps">Annual Report for 1929</hi>, of the Association of Graduates of the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Military Academy.</p>
                
                <p>I regret that that the above works are not at the Kansas City Public Library else I would have learned much more about Major Lemly's military career. But what little I have gleaned shows that he was indeed a distinguished officer and gentleman of the highest caliber.</p>
                
                <p>His testimony on any phase of service where he was an eye-witness can be absolutely relied on. Especially is this true in his statement about the Crazy Horse photo. I received a rather interesting letter from Henry <hi rend="caps">J.</hi> Dubester, Chief, General Reference and Bibliography Division, The Library of Congress, in reply to a query of mine. He replies as follows:
                    <lb/>
                    "The picture of "Crazy Horse in War Bonnet," as printed in v. 54 (1914) <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Military Journal, between pages 316 and 317, has not been further identified. There is nothing in the magazine to explain why this picture was included with the article by Major Henry <hi rend="caps">R.</hi> Lemly or on what grounds (or by whom) it was determined that this was an actual portrait of this Sioux chief."</p>
                
                <p>What Mr. Dubester doesn't know is that M<del>q</del><add>a</add>jor Lemly himself identified the picture being present when it was taken. He must have supplied the print for the article as he obviously knew the photographer who probably supplied him with a print from the original glass plate. This is my own considered analysis. At <del>e</del><add>t</add>he time of your interviews with Major Lemly he may have explained how he came <del>k</del><add>i</add>nto posession of the print or the source for it.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33c</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial">page 3</fw>
                
                <p>In the November-December issue of <hi rend="caps">TRUE WEST</hi>, a magazine printed at Austin, Texas, and containing factual stories on the West, is an article on the Sioux. An illustration in this article is this selfsame photo of Crazy Horse supplied by Frontier Pix of Huston, Texas. The caption beneath the photo reads: Major Wilhelm of the 8th <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Infantry took this photo of Crazy Horse. There is controversy over whether or not this is the famous Chief Crazy Horse, or the warrior (Greasy Hand) who took his wife after his death.</p>
                
                <p>This Major (Thomas) Wilhelm was a Civil war veteran from Pennsylvania (a major by brevet for gallantry in the war). His permanent rank with the 8th Infantry was 1st lieutenant. He was regimental adjutant from March, 1868 to June 7, 1879. Thus he was certainly in a position to have been at Fort Robinson in the summer of 1877.</p>
                
                <p>Since Wilhelm was an officer, the opportunity for him to know Major Lemly was excellent, and he might be the photographer Major Lemly referred to. The only noted photographer who was known to be at Fort Robinson in 1877 was <hi rend="caps">D. F.</hi> Barry, who told <hi rend="caps">E. A.</hi> Brininstool (quoted in Brininstool's book <hi rend="caps">Crazy Horse, the Invincible Ogalalla Sioux Chief</hi>) that he (Barry) had repeatedly tried to bribe Crazy Horse to sit for his photograph, but the Chief could not be bribed.</p>
                
                <p>Well, I have made this letter overlong, and I must close it for now. This Tuesday is a sunny day here, and I am sure it shines where you are. Peace and joy to you and Mrs. Neihardt.</p>
                <closer>                
                    <salute>Your friend,</salute>
                    <signed>Thomas W. Wright</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.33a-33d_0004"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33d</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Thomas <hi rend="caps">W.</hi> Wright
                    702 Sharp Bldg.
                    Kansas City 6, Mo.
                </ab>
                
                <note>Ansd</note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    12 KANSAS CITY
                    NOV 26
                    4 PM
                    1957
                    MO.
                    FIGHT <unclear/> SUPPO<unclear/> TB ASSOC<unclear/>ON
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. PO<unclear reason="missing" cert="high">STAGE</unclear> <unclear reason="missing"/> IN GOD <unclear reason="missing" cert="high">WE TRUST</unclear> LIBE<unclear reason="missing" cert="high">RTY</unclear></p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Farm,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route #7,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
