<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
7a
SRI AUROBINDO INTERNATIONAL CENTRE OF EDUCATION 
PONDICHERRY (India)
8th May, 1963
Dear Dr. Neihardt, 
I have received a letter from Dr. Olive I. Reddick, Director of the United States Educational Foundation in India, asking us to confirm our invitation to you to pay and deliver here a series of lectures. We are also asked to give them the information regarding the period of your stay at our centre and the amount of maintenance and other amenities that you will be receiving from us. 
As you probably know, we do not give any salary to the teachers of our Centre, but they are all maintained by the Ashram on the same level as other members of the Ashram. We shall therefore provide you comfortable stay and board as our guest. Also, as I had suggested to you in my last letter, January would be the most suitable month for your stay here form the point of view of your age and the climatic conditions in Pondicherry. I would therefore request you kindly to drop me a line to confirm if I should reply to Dr. Reddick that you will be staying here for a month and that youw ill be treated as our guest and thus maintained by us during your period of stay here on a decent standard. 
As we are withholding our answer to Dr. Reddick, pending your answer to this letter, I shall be grateful if you kindly write to me at the earliest. 
With kind regards, 
Yours sincerely,
<unclear/>
P.B. Saint-Hilaire
Director of Education
Dr. John G. Neihardt,
Lecturer in English, 
University of Missouri, 
Route 7, 
Columbia, Missouri

(should be Neihardt of <unclear>Neihardt</unclear> 7b
Christian neighhard     Eva N. 
born in Germany, died   born in Germany 
August 27, 1776. Private    married 1757, died
in Berks Co. Pennsylvania   1784
Militia, part of Pa. Rifle
Regiment. Served under Capt. 
Henry Shade. Residence Berks
County. Enlisted April 14, 
1776. Killed in action - re-
ported missing Battle of Long
Island, Aug. 27, 1776. Ser-
vice, 4 mo. 13 days. Reference: 
Pennsylvania in the Revolution
Page 222, Vol. II and p. 172. 
(Nihard or   nee
Conrad (<unclear>Neighhard</unclear>    Elisabeth/Kruagor
       Born 1775, married
1772 Reading, Pa., born Sept.   March 1795, died
7, 1772, died April 23,     Dec. 1862 (Center Co., Pa.)
1862. 
John Neihardt   Johanna nee Roxburg
Coal City, Indiana;     Reading, Pa., born 1809,
born January 8, 1802, 1801  married may 1826, died 
died July 1879.     May 1889.
Nicholas Neihardt   Alice nee Culler 
born July 1852,     born December 21, 1858, 
died in 1929    died F <unclear/> .12,1935
    Married march 1876. 
Near <unclear/> Ill., east of <unclear/> <unclear/> of <unclear/>. 
John Gneisenau Neihardt Mona nee Martinsen, 
born January 8, 1881,   born May 26, 1884, New
<unclear>Springfield</unclear>, Illinois.   York City 
Branson, Mo.    Married <del>1997</del> (Nov. 28)
Nov. 28, 1908
Enid    Sigurd  Hilda   Alice 
Christened; John Greenfield?
name changed to <unclear/> <unclear/> 
when <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/><unclear/><unclear/><unclear/>
<unclear/><unclear/><unclear/>