<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26a.65-68_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, May 4, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26a.65-68_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-05-04">May 4, 1958</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26a.65-68_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">65</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>May 4, 1958</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear John,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>We were very glad to have your letter, and Hilda's too. You are both certainly thoughtful to take time to write to us. We are thinking about you a great deal &#8212; aside from the study, I mean &#8212; and we appreciate your letters.</p>
                
                <p>In June we should certainly make hay. I'm glad you will have a change of scene this summer; the trip will be nice for you, and it will give you some extra time with little Maxine &#8212; or is she so little now? It will be wonderful for her, because isn't she the one grandchild who has been able to spend the least time with you? She has lived so far away this will be a real joy for her. While you are in Missouri, however, we will cover all the ground we can. Bower has written to you too, and if you would be willing to come and visit us a while we will be deeply pleased to have you. Our house is more comfortable than most in the summer because it has high ceilings, and we're a most informal household. We'll talk about it when we get to Missouri &#8212; at my rate, we must have time to visit. I have a long list of questions, and I want to ask you about books I should read. I'm reading <unclear>Woodbury's <hi rend="underline">Torch</hi></unclear> now, and I've read a lot of <unclear>Edkington</unclear> and <unclear>Haldane</unclear> and <unclear>Broke</unclear>; I see from them that I need to read more to follow your thought as fully as I want to.</p>
                
                <p>I am looking forward to hearing the important and encouraging news you may have. I hope some books are going back into print; they <hi rend="underline">all</hi> will eventually, but it would be nice to have several reappear now. It is good that you will make the speech at Cornell, too, and in South Dakota. I shall want to hear about both.</p>
                
                <p>Under separate cover I'm sending another chapter. If you don't feel like reading it I shall certainly understand. I have only two copies of this one, and I shall appreciate it if you will put this in Campus Mail to Loren Reid when you have finished with it; Loren will send it
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26a.65-68_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">6<del>8</del><add>6</add></fw>
                
                    on to Harold Moffett. It needs some revision yet for tighter style, but you can see the idea. This is the analysis of speeches according to the five canons of the Roman rhetoricians. They are <list><item>1. Inventio (invention)</item> <item>2. Dispositio (arrangement to persuade specific audiences)</item> <item>3. Elocutio (style)</item> <item>4. Memoria (preparation) and</item> <item>5 Pronuntiato (delivery).</item></list> I have the first draft of Chapter V finished now; as soon as it's edited I'll send it if you want to bother with it. It's about the lectures and the rhetorical grounds of your appeal for poetical values. <hi rend="underline">I</hi> think you have out-Platoed Plato!</p>
                
                <p>This I want to tell you. I dreamed about Mona the other night. The three of us were sitting at a round table with a lighted lamp on it and <unclear>bead</unclear> fringe on the shade. We were talking and she was sewing on something, and suddenly she looked up and smiled with that look of a soft light inside her, and I woke up feeling very good. I am so grateful for having the opportunity to know you both. The sense of pattern is stronger in me than ever before. It's a wonderful feeling, isn't it?</p>
                
                <p>One more thing &#8212; what you said of the two of you and the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi> I have felt from reading the letters. It's true; you did it together, and it's a little like old <unclear>Hugh's crawl</unclear>. It was such a monumental job it still seems a bit unbelievable that you could do it, and yet you <hi rend="underline">did.</hi> It's hard to tell from here, but you may have done something that will make a tremendous difference to the world. The one man who holds tight at the desperate deciding moment someday may have been inspired by <del/><add>the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>.</add> I have a strong conviction that you are much more important than you can know.</p>
                
                <p>Our love to all the family &#8212; and do think about taking over our guestroom for as long as you will. You can be alone when you like, and we can offer privacy or company to order. It would be a glory to us, as Sister <unclear>Madelena</unclear> once said.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Love,</salute> 
                
                    <signed>Lucile</signed>
                </closer>   
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
