<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26.66f-66h_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Bower Aly to John G. Neihardt, March 14, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26.66f-66h_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Bower Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-03-14">March 14, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66f-66h_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66f</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">UNIVERSITY OF OREGON
                        <lb/>
                    COLLEGE OF LIBERAL ARTS
                        <lb/>
                    EUGENE, OREGON
                        <lb/>
                
                    DEPARTMENT OF SPEECH
                        <lb/>
                        DRAMA
                        <lb/>
                        PUBLIC SPEAKING
                        <lb/>
                        RADIO-TELEVISION
                        <lb/>
                        SPEECH CORRECTION</hi>
                </fw>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>March 14, 1958</dateline>
                
                <address>
                    <addrLine>Professor John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Skyrim, Route 7</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear John:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I think I ought to tell you that on the first reading of your letter of March 9, Lucile was somewhat fearful that you had not appreciated fully the problems she has in doing the dissertations. After re-reading your letter in concert with me, I think she is fully convinced that you and she understand each other.. Nevertheless, I have thought it might be well for another reason to state the problem and to give you some reassurance even though I confess I think you do not need it.</p>
                
                <p>Owing partly to some German influence, which I regard as being in some ways quite unfortunate, the Ph.D. dissertation in American universities is limited by a form and a convention perhaps as restrictive as that for the Shakespearean sonnet, for example. It is almost a <hi rend="underline">genre</hi>. The writer of a dissertation must be prepared at any moment to answer the question "Vot iss de effidence?" Occasionally, a graduate student is able to transcend the limitations and to produce a dissertation which is at once within the limits prescribed and a work of genuine scholarship. In the present instance, I am inclined to regard the dissertation (and I have so advised Lucile) as merely a preliminary stepping stone to the great biography which I think she can do. Hence I would think it well for her to stay well within the limitations of the dissertation sequence and look to the biography to develop the fulness<sic>fullness</sic> of her insights.</p>
                
                <p>But all this is merely preliminary to the major question I wish to raise with you, a question which, in fact, you have already raised: on page two of your analysis you observe, "It seems unfortunate that you have only these quoted letters to indicate the reception of the column since you are bound by rules of research to document every statement....I am noting a restriction under which you must labor."</p>
                
                <p>No one who has not had a great of experience in dealing with scholarly questions involving manuscripts can understand the despair with which an interested scholar approaches questions which once were soluble and are now forever insoluble because of the loss of the document. It would not be safe for me to have my hands on
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66f-66h_0002"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">66g</fw>
                
                    <fw type="authorial">Professor John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt
                    March 14, 1958
                    Page 2</fw>
                
                    the executor of Phillip Schuyler's estate who burned a trunkful of letters and papers referring to Phillip Schuyler and his son-in-law, Alexander Hamilton.</p>
                
                <p>I live in anxiety that something may happen to the Neihardt papers, even while they are in our cottage. I am well aware that everything you ever touched is an important document and should by all means be preserved. A number of the House letters and certain others are now disintegrating. They should be photo-stated and, in my judgement, the originals should be deposited in a library where they will recieve loving care. Mrs. Ryskind has asked our recommendation concerning a depository for her collection. I am inclined to think they should be deposited at the Huntington library and, all things considered, I think that might be the best place for her collection. Would it not be a good idea to place the other letters that we have in our home also in the Huntington Library? I realize fully that they belong to you and to your children so far as propri<del>a</del><add>e</add>t<del/><add>a</add>ry rights are concerned, but from the scholar's point of view, I think even your own interest in them is only transient. They belong to the unborn generations that will need to discover and rediscover Neihardt.</p>
                
                <p>Would you and your children be willing for me to explore with the Huntington Library the questions whether the Library would receive these originals as a gift or on loan and in return supply you with a photostatic copy of each item received?</p>
                
                <p>So far as I am acquainted with the letters I have found nothing that should give offense to anyone, although Mrs. House may wish to restrict two or three of the letters in her collection. If you should feel that the letters should not be generally available during your lifetime, they could, of course, be placed under suitable restriction, and I have never known a library to violate such a restriction.</p>
                
                <p>John, I hope you will give some thought to this question and let me have your wish and judgment. I think every man of good will who knows this problem would be likely suggest,as I have done, that an effort should be made to preserve not only the poems but the documents of your life and work.</p>
                
                <p>I don't know whether I ever told you or not but I once could read aloud the entire "Song of the Indian Wars" without a text, and I once gave a two-hour program of Neihardt's poetry without the benefit of the current injunction that an interpreter should always read from the book. I knew it by heart.</p>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66f-66h_0003"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">66h</fw>
                
                    <fw type="authorial">Professor John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt
                    March 14, 1958
                    Page 3</fw>
                
                <p>Lucile is doing a great job with the dissertation, and I think that it is possible for her to do a really great biography.</p>
                
                <p>We shall look forward to seeing you next summer.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely yours, as ever,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Bower</signed>
                
                    <signed>Bower Aly</signed>
                
                    <note>BA:ml</note>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi></opener> <p>One scholar friend of mine, on reading what Lucile has written thus far, said quietly, "This is a great tribute to a great man."</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
