<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27.26">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Louise Hovde Mortensen to John G. Neihardt, January 23, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27.26</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Louise Hovde Mortensen to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-01-23">January 23, 1959</date>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27.26"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        705 Polk Blvd.
                        Des Moines 12, Iowa 
                        January 23, 1959.
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Thank you for your letter. I know how busy you are.</p>
                
                <p>I received the proof of ""'Red Cloud' as Choral Reading" just before <del>c</del><add>C</add>hristmas and returned it. They used that for the title instead of "Idea Inventory" but it is in the Idea Inventory space nevertheless.</p>
                
                <p>But I thought<del>i</del>it was too good for just column material so am glad it had an individual title, so that it can be indexed. All the Teachers' Colleges have bound volumes of the magazine.</p>
                
                <p>Dr. De Boer wrote that he had been ill and therefore the magazines are late this year. The January one has not reached me yet and this is the 23rd. The December number came at the end of the month. I think the "Red Cloud" material will be in the February number which I'm sure will be very late.</p>
                
                <p>It seems that all the English professors are overworked at the colleges.</p>
                
                <p>Dr. Dunn at Drake was sick this year, too. I believe he is all right now. He said there is a possibility that Drake may need extra Freshmen English instructors next semester and he would put my name on his list. I am hoping to be called and will plan to take part of my annual leave from this office, if possible.</p>
                
                <p>Mrs. Margarett<sic>Margarette</sic> Ball Dickson wrote that she is anxious to receive a copy of <hi rend="underline">Elementary English</hi> so that they may try the choral reading of "Red Cloud" in Staples where she leaves. By the way, I have a booklist of South Dakota books which has both your name and Mrs. Dickson's in it. It is a bibliogr<del>p</del><add>a</add>phy (1943) which can be obtained from Lora Crouch of the Sioux Falls Public Library, Sioux Falls, <hi rend="caps">S.D.</hi> As it is rather <del>l</del><add>o</add>ld now, they are in the midst of compiling another one which is limited to books about So<del/><add>u</add>th Dakota or by South Dakota authors.</p>
                
                <p>Mary Gunnett wrote that you may return to Fairmont next year. If you do, I may mention it in the May number of <hi rend="underline">Elementary English</hi>. I have a list of conferences which might interest teachers of English. However, if you are not sure, I probably won't mention it as Dr. Coleman is rather unpredictable and I really wouldn't recommend him and his conference unless I knew all about the staff he intends to have there. I plan to mention the conference at Green Lake, Wisconsin, the Religious Drama Conference at Lake Forest College, and the Ch<del>r</del>ildren's Theatre Conference in Indiana, I believe. I thought I could run them together in May and some English teachers might like to go. I keep in mind the isolated teachers who like to do something unusual and still learn something in connection with their work. I ordered the Houghton Mifflin book, <hi rend="underline">Reader and Writer</hi>, which has the story "Goodby, Little Sister," which we read in the log cabin one morning. It is a good anthology for college freshmen.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Louise Mortensen</signed> 
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute> <signed>Louise Mortensen</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
