<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.22.6">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from W. O. Cralle to Mr. and Mrs. Neihardt, May 18, 1948</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.22.6</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from W. O. Cralle to Mr. and Mrs. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1948-05-18">May 18, 1948</date>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau and Mona</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.22.6"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Neihardt Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">SOUTHWEST MISSOURI
                        <lb/>
                    STATE COLLEGE
                        <lb/>
                    SPRINGFIELD 
                        <lb/>
                
                    ROY ELLIS, PRESIDENT</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>May 18, 1948</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. and Mrs. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your news that the one volume edition of the cycle is about to be produced is the most exciting thing of the week and my heartiest congratulations. I am proceeding to place my advance order for two copies as I need one for my daughter and Indian son-in-law. The news that you are working on a prose story or novel is almost as exciting. You have so much to give to the world and such a sensitivity for real meanings that it too is something to look forward to. Some time ago I felt that you were experiencing a sensation of completion and wre somewhat at "loose ends" when the Cycle was finished and I was a bit disappointed and sorry because I felt that you should never stop. A little later I realized that it was probably only temporary and the natural result of having completed so stupendous a task but I am really glad that you are turning your hand to prose. I hope to see you before long and to learn more about what is emerging.</p>
                
                <p>I don't know the status of the plan we had talked about but I shall endeavor to find out soon and will let you know developments. I would assure you it is far from a "one man campaign". Dr. Nicholson in history; Haswell in English and Miss Woods the head of the English Department are all almsot as eager as I am if not equally so. We have no discouragement or opposition so far as I know but things not pushed aggressively have a chance of dying because of the press of must activities so I think we should start again. Haswell asked only a few days ago what had happened to the idea. My guess is, First, this is legislative year and President Ellis had a pretty active time. Our appropriations came through in great shape but as yet the Governor has not signed them. Since in Missouri he has the power to withhold any item or any amount we are marking time mostly until we hear from him. A Second factor perhaps is the fact that we are adding three men in social studies: one in political acience<sic>science</sic>, one in sociology and one in economics and since they are younger men each requires a very considerable visiting and inspection. Anyway I'll try to see what the score is.</p>
                
                <p>Life runs much the same here except that Mrs. Cralle has developed a very painful arthritis of the shoulder recently and has been more uncomfortable than usual. She has had so much of suffering and so little health anyway that this added note is pretty discouraging to her.</p>
                
                <p>I had an interesting evening last Thursday. I was asked to meet with a forum discussion group in the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Medical Center and since the authorities out there have been very helpful in my criminology work I felt I couldn't refuse though this is a very busy time. I went with little preparation and considerable misgivings; sent word that we would discuss the Instability of American Family Life. Perhaps it was not the msot brilliant choice for men forcibly detatched from family but the response was surprising to me at least. I have never had a class which discussed so freely and frankly a problem. There was of course a very considerable "folk wisdom" but a surprising amount of real reading and thinking and they were most frank about discussing their own family situations and personal problems. In short I had a great time and I practically invited them to ask me again.</p>
                
                <p>Thanks again for sharing the good news with me,</p> <closer><salute>Sincerely</salute> <signed>W.O. Cralle</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>