<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
21
5835 Vine Street 
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505 
March 16, 1969 
Professor Sanford D. Gray 
University of South Dakota 
Vermillion, South Dakota 57069 
Dear Sandy, 
I have just been hearing your letters of last May and July read aloud to me and they have made me happy. Of late I have been wondering if I had misplaced you somewhere, as I am always doing with my glasses; but you seem to be as there as ever, and I am wishing mightily that I might see you like old times. 
Since writing you last I have had the second cataract operation, and it seems that both are reasonably successful. I shall have two eyes to use instead of one. 
I have been working rather steadily on my "autobiography" in spite of the eye troubles, and I ahve now forty thousand words, which is about half of the projected work. What I have done so far is really complete in itself, being concerned with my boyhood and early youth. I have half a notion to offer this for publication now and go ahead with another section. there is so much to do even when I limit the material as much as possible that it could not be put in one volume. 
Sandy, I am always hearing form this person and that person about the lack of records of my stuff. I am wondering if there cannot be some arrangement made whereby the records you have already made may be obtainable. At the same time I should think it might be possible to make records from some of the tapes we made when I was up there last. I do think they would sell reasonably well, Sandy. I suppose that the initial cost is what spoils the deal, and I am sure there would be some way to manage that. What do you think about trying to get these things out? 
There was a feeling in your letters that made me glad. You are undoubtedly in a creative stage of your life, and you are going far with it. I wish you could include some records in your scheme of things. 
This carries affectionate thoughts for your lady and the children, as well as for you. 
Your friend, 
JGN:fmb John G. Neihardt