<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.16.33-34_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt, October 10, 1935</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.16.33-34_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1935-10-10">October 10, 1935</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.16.33-34_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">CHARLES KELLY</hi>
                    473 First Avenue
                    <hi rend="caps">SALT LAKE CITY . UTAH</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Oct. 10, 1935</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Glad to hear you got home safe and had a good trip. If I had known you were not feeling well, I certainly would not have taken you over those Skull Valley roads. Still, I know of some that are worse, and if you get out here again, we may try some of them.</p>
                
                <p>The idea of maing<sic>making</sic> a horseback trip across the Salt Flats appeals to me. It has never been done since 1850, so far as I know, and you couldn't hire any of the natives to tackle it. However, it can be done, and I'd like to do it. There won't be any "depot of supplies" half way across, if I have my way; either we'll ride that 80 miles in one jaunt, like Carson, Hastings and the others, or we'll stick to an automobile. I don't think we ought to compromise, and I'm game to make it in one trip without more than a "small powder keg filled with brackish water," if we can find some rancher who will rent us horses for such a trip. There's the rub. I'm sure the Orr's will hesitate to subject their animals to such a trip, although they are mighty good friends of mine. But let's try, anyway, even if we have to make false representations as to where we're going!</p>
                
                <p>I suppose you have read in the papers of the airplane which dropped in the lake here last Sunday with three passengers. Yesterday one body was washed up on the shore, and today another was found, on the east shore of Stansbury island. They were so covered with salt that it was only by the shape they were identified as humans. The plane hasn't been found yet. My opinion is that it landed in fairly deep water, floated for a few minutes and then sank, the men swimming, and finally giving out before reaching land. The bodies were naked. They were found just over Stansbury island from the point where we stopped and had supper that night.</p>
                
                <p>There is a great deal of history connected with this section of the country which I know you would enjoy if you had the time, and I certainly hope you can get back here next summer. If I know in advance, I can usually get away for a week or two almost any time between July 1 and September 1.</p> 
                
                <p>Apparently I did the wrong thing in sending your mail to Tombstone. It has to go in such a roundabout way to reach Flagstaff, that I figured you would be gone from there long before the mail arrived. I understood you were going to Tombstone, so sent some of it there. Hope you finally got it all right.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.16.33-34_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">CHARLES KELLY</hi>
                    473 First Avenue
                    <hi rend="caps">SALT LAKE CITY . UTAH</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <p>The weather has been beautiful for the last few weeks and I have been making a few short trips back on the old Donner trail between here and Fort Bridger. Finally found the old "tar spring" spoken of by the emigrants, and other landmarks in that vicinity, but no pioneer relics such as I found on the Salt Flats. Just received a letter from an old man who claims he has seen the name of Father DeSmet on the rocks in Idaho, so will make a trip up there as soon as I can get more detailed information. Got a list of 30 new emigrant names from a bluff above Cache Cave, the oldest dating 1849.</p>
                
                <p>Have you a book on the Oregon Trail by Dawson? Or one by Charles Hanson (title unknown) on the same subject? I understand they contain lists of names of emigrants found on the rocks, but have never been able to find a copy of either.</p>
                
                <p>I'll certainly be glad to receive a copy of your new book, and will make it my business to read some of your old ones. I am ashamed to say I never read any of yours except "Splendid Wayfaring," which I considered a very fine piece of writing.</p>
                
                <p>I am sorry we didn't have more time to talk during your visit. I have had some very peculiar experiences with psychological phenomena, but it isn't often one meets a man who understands that language, and our time was too limited to go into it. Some night around a greasewood fire, perhaps...</p>
                
                <p>Give our regards to Enid. The wife says she will write her in a few days. God! I wish I had a helper like her. You're lucky that she takes an interst in your work. Few girls of her age would.</p>
                
                <p>If the stars are right we'll be seeing you again next summer!</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours,</salute>
                    <signed>Charles Kelly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
