<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0001-8">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John Galen Howard to John G. Neihardt, June 20, 1914</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.3.27-34_0001-8</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John Galen Howard to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1914-06-20">June 20, 1914</date>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0001" />

                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>

                <note type="Neihardt">John Galen Howard</note>

                <opener>
                                                                                            <dateline>                    
                                                                                                Rose-Le Roy
                                                                                                Berkeley, Cal.
                                                                                                20 June, 1914 &#8212;
                                                                                            </dateline>

                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt.&#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Thanks for your letter. I shall surely look in on you, if only for an hour, next trip east. And I promise myself the pleasure of seeing you here, either before or after that much <unclear>desired</unclear> opportunity to shake your hand. I did indeed see the whole of your <title>"Chaff and a little Grain"</title>; and that's one reason why I was so cor-

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0002"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial"><unclear cert="medium">28</unclear></fw>

                    dially pleased with the good things you had to say of <title><foreign>"Brunelleschi"</foreign></title>. I demur at your pronouncement of bombast. I think I know the passages you mean. But do me the honor of reading them again, in their context, and see if they do not ring true, as characteristic of an extremely sensitive and over-wrought soul, tremulous with age and defeat, and softening toward surrender in the catharsis which prepares the soul for redemption. The redemption scene follows immediately in words as exceptional for their childlike simplicity

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0003"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">2<unclear cert="medium">9</unclear></fw>

                    and directness, as the preceding passage is elaborate and <unclear>breathless</unclear>. This is drama; and if inflation, or something next door to it, (inspiration, for instance,) is a part of the mood it must be a part of the expression of the mood. It may or may not be offensive in literature, according to your point of view, but it is essentially true to life. Perhaps, after all, however, I am not talking of the passages you take exception to. One other point; the awkward inversions are a part of the drama, too, &#8212; a part of <title><foreign>Brunelleschi's</foreign></title> style, as distinguished from my own, &#82121; unless I am very much

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0004"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>

                    mistaken as to mine, <title><foreign>Brunelleschi</foreign></title> was a thrower-back, as well as a plunger-forward, and in speaking <unclear>this</unclear> his mouth the man <emph><hi rend="underline">became</hi></emph> the style. I am sending you a couple of things in which I speak in <foreign>propia persona</foreign> from which you can judge whether I am right, in a measure at least, for of course a man can't wholly lose himself even in drama.</p>
    
                <p>I had ordered all your books before I got your letter, and they came just after. <unclear>Then</unclear> I took advantage of a couple of days in bed, of a cold, and

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0005"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>

                    read <unclear>four</unclear> of them with keenest relish; the fifth is now under way, as family reading aloud. i. e. <title>The Dawn Builder</title> I should find it quite impossible to tell you how poignantly these books have touched me and rejoiced me. Thank God the real thing can sometimes be received cordially, as the receipt you sent me shows has been the case with your work. Your genius has the rare chance to grow in the sunshine, and it is strong enough <unclear>to stand it</unclear>. There are many individual pieces which I like exceedingly; but the beautiful thing, the wonder

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0006"/>
                                                                                                                             <fw type="curatorial">32</fw>

                    ful thing, is the gradual sure emergence of the great soul, in the <title>Bundle of Myrrh,</title> and also in the series of books as a whole. Perhaps the <title>Bundle of Myrrh</title> most completely took me off my feet. The current runs more quietly, doubtless because more deeply, in the later books. But you have your greatest work still before you; and I think you point the way to it in the <title>River and I</title>. Rich and racy as are the early lyric outbursts, you will, I feel, gain presently in range and power by <emph><hi rend="underline">so-</hi></emph>

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0007"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>

                    <emph><hi rend="underline">cializing</hi></emph> your muse. Yet the <unclear><title>Jupertrine Glory</title></unclear> appealed to me less, perhaps, on the whole, than most of the other pieces; and I liked least of all the death of Alcibiades. Why doll him up so  beyond recognition? Something of his genuine <unclear>cussedness to</unclear> take hold of his good points by would make him so much more real. I have a personal feeling about this, for it happens, curiously enough, that I am studying him, tho<sic>though</sic> <add>only</add> as a very minor youthful figure, "in our <unclear>nest"</unclear>. I wish you would spin a yarn about some of your old Mizzoura heroes. <emph><hi rend="underline">There</hi></emph> is the right sort of stuff. And people

                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.3.27-34_0008"/>
                                                                                                                            <fw type="curatorial">34</fw>

                    are getting used to taking their stories in verse, since Moyes and Masefield <foreign>et al.</foreign> have can put on, &#8212; specially Masefield. You can do this latter one better if you will, and that is saying a lot. The author of <title>Man-Song</title>, <title>Stranger at the Gate</title>, <title>River and I</title>, and <title>Dawn Builder</title>, has <emph>all</emph> of the powers necessary to do justice, in immortal verse, to the Epic of the <unclear>West</unclear>. As for Moyes he's not in the running nowadays, and won't be till he has lived some life and tasted "the sweet forbidden wine, crushed out with bruising kisses." You know "the pathos and the joy of human dust," and you are bound to give us more and even more of it. We can't &#8212; I can't anyway, &#8212; get too much of your sort of thing.</p>
    
                <p>Come and see me and my wife and five youngsters.</p>
                <closer>
                                        <salute>Yours ever</salute>
                    
                                        <signed>J. G. Howard</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>