<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
152 Neihardt Collection 68

Hilda N. Petri
5833 Bartmer
St. Louis, Mo.

SAINT LOUIS, MO.3
SEP 5
10-PM
1942

BUY DEFENSE SAVINGS BONDS AND STAMPS

Mr. and Mrs. John Neihardt
Branson
Missouri
69
Saturday, Sept. 5.
Dearest Mama and Daddy!
<p>Many thanks for your dear letters this morning.</p>
<p>We had a lovely time with Amama - Albert and I spent two evenings with her at the Statler, listening to the music and talking. She was very dear - and, of course, charmed us both. She said many, many wonderful things about you both - which she means -, and said it was all she could do when in Springfield to key from running back to you. We were pleased to see her insuch much better health_.</p>
<p>There is so much that is fine about Amama, and this is,</p>
70
2
<p>as you know, the only side of herself she has <underline>ever</underline> shown to me.</p>
<p>We can't see how you can wish or really be able to leave Branson right now. You are both very busy with the pieces of sculpture and with other things - and the <unclear type="cutoff"/> too, this is no time of year to leave Branson <unclear type="cutoff"/> Would you not prefer to remain there for a while longer? Albert and I are now in a position to pay more on the ring. We are going to do this, so that is nothing to <unclear>talk</unclear> about. We would not buy the ring you $150. We'll send you the 15 now, and we can send you more each week if you stay there a little longer. This would not be money to burden you more, since we owe it to you on the ring. Please let us know whether you want to be there longer. Sig wants to fetch you, but he'll still want to later.</p>
<p>I earned some money. Albert cashed in a <unclear>small policy</unclear> (recently bought a large new one), and I <unclear>made</unclear> my policy smaller, so we gathered in a number of dollars. I have another 2 weeks' job coming up later this month. So, you see we are in better shape now financially, and you need not feel sorry for us!</p>
<p>Amama was <underline>at least glowing</underline> in what she said if the Bust and your other pieces, Mama. Now to learn it has been successfully cast makes me very happy, Daddy, she said you are the </p>
69
3
<p>only man she ever knew who never said a cross or hasty word. She said you are the sweetest and kindest man she ever knew. She said you two are the most truly and beautifully <underline>married</underline> people she ever heard of. Amama - who <underline>really</underline> doesn't say anything she does not mean - is surely, as I said before "sold" on you both - as individuals and as a pair. I'll tell you more when we are together.</p>
<p>we are all well - and happy, too. Albert and I seem to have so much fun, even though we've had to be sparing, etc. Albert is surely the exception that proves a rule or two. He looks with clear eyes on the world about, and his honest and <unclear/> desire is only for good. - But, how will you know this.</p>
<p>Write soon - please.</p>
Endless love ever,
Hilda &amp; Albert
<p>Maxie will write soon, says to thank you for <unclear type="cutoff"/></p>

