<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0001-5">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, February 9, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26.34-38_0001-5</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-02-09">February 9, 1958</date>
                    <extent>4 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0001"/>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>February 9, 1958</dateline>
               
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <fw type="curatorial">34</fw> 
                <p>Bower and I both appreciate the good letters. I am delighted with the account of the Horse Dance pageant, and I have now reached the point where I would not be the least bit surprised at anything I discovered about you and the things you have done. I wouldn't even gasp if I found that you had led a boy scout troop up Mt. Everest in the summer of 1900, or paddled a canoe the full length of the Amazon up stream. Mr. Kelly wrote me this week that he once saw you swim across the Missouri River <hi rend="underline">and back</hi>. I <unclear>grew</unclear> up on <unclear>stories</unclear> of how dangerous the Missouri River was, and I'm impressed.</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Kelly has a little different picture of Candidate Graff too. I could only find one <unclear>cartoon</unclear>, but Mr. Kelly remembered that one, and he says the chief weapon for Graff's opponents was the devastating editorial on the front page. It is significant that he remembers those two things all those years. The editorial was powerful; I can see why a candidate would hate to have the Neihardt <unclear>rhetoric</unclear> unleashed against him. In a way it's too bad you didn't go into politics &#8212; but not really; you would never written the cycle.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">35</fw>
                
                <p>I have finished the critic section of the study and I want to talk with you this summer about criticism, because there really is a tremendous book in it &#8212; in <hi rend="underline">your criticisms</hi> I mean, not my summary of them. I would like to be sure, for example, that I've <unclear/> your sources, and the books on criticism itself that <unclear/> have <unclear>stimulated</unclear> you. You must not get too busy to write about Plato and <unclear/>, though, and the <hi rend="underline">Poetics</hi>. If I did nothing more in my life than spark the writing of Niehardt on those themes I would have justified my <unclear>potatoes</unclear> and <unclear>roofs</unclear>, I think. I would like very much, also, to know what you think of Plato's cave allegory. These things are important, perhaps more than you know, because you are one of the few people who are both Platonist and Aristotelian, Platonist in thought and desire, Aristotelian in action. Your school speech in Branson, for instance, was intended to get action, and it's right down the line of Aristotle's three kinds of persuasian, and yet what you were proposing was <unclear>basically</unclear> Platonic, as you know.  This is an exciting dissertation to write.</p>
                
                <p>I have a few very minor questions to raise, all technical. One is about the <unclear/> <unclear>Bureau</unclear>, which was to book engagements in the fall of 1928 Did they get a tour for you? The <unclear>week</unclear> in New York was 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0003"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">36</fw>
                
                    <unclear>not</unclear> their doing &#8212; it was the Poetry Society. Do you remember what happened to the plans? How did you get out of the contract? Were these people to do anything about the American Tour plan that you were working on? This <unclear>also</unclear> is <unclear>about</unclear> agencies: after <unclear>Feskins</unclear>, <hi rend="caps">E.E.</hi> Long took over as manager, isn't that right? Did you just not <unclear>renew</unclear> the <unclear>Feskins</unclear> contract, or was it <unclear>revoked</unclear> some way? The time fits a non-<unclear>renewal</unclear> if Long began in 1923. After Chicago you did no more organized work on <unclear>tours</unclear>, did you? Did you realize (this is a rhetorical question: you don't need to reply to it) that since 1916 there has not been a single year when you haven't made speeches? That is quite a reward.</p>
                
                <p>I shall write to people about the current speeches. If I can, I want to get newspaper reports of the Cornell one; that news pleases me very much. I am writing to Mrs. Longworth, and Bower is going to try to see her for me when he goes East later this month.</p>
                
                <p>Arthur Fairchild (formerly of Missouri, now retired) is very much interested in your work and you. He <unclear>writes</unclear> often and always has some question about what you think. He asked me last about your <unclear>Aeschylus</unclear> theory &#8212; man and fate, and about whether you thought a moral principle was <unclear>involved</unclear> in conquest. He is a Classicist too; in the classical tradition of literary criticism, which he used to teach at Missouri. I granted him
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0004"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
                
                    some of your letters to Sterling about genius and the work that goes with it because he didn't see how you could follow Plato and <unclear>Aeschylus</unclear> too. I told him you were not willing to separate reason and inspiration. You see why the critic book must be done. If you think I can be competent to do it afer more reading, I would love to. Just make a list of what I should read, and I'll get at it.</p>
                
                <p>This has turned out to be a volume, but I wanted to tell you all these things. I shall send a complete manuscript of the biography chapter along soon, and if you <unclear>will</unclear> write corrections right on it I shall appreciate it very much. The section on criticism and the one on speaking career are <unclear>keyed</unclear> to <unclear>speeches</unclear> and are preparation for the later chapters. I did very little with political opinions, for example, because I'll bring in the <unclear>essentials</unclear> where I write about some of the speeches. If the <unclear>focus</unclear> is wrong, though, I want to correct it.</p>
                
                <p>Our love to everybody, and please tell your young lady granddaughters that's a very pretty picture of the three of you in the January 8 Missourian.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>Your letter about John Chaffee just came. I'll write and ask if he'll see me; it's only 45 miles.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.34-38_0005"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    2094 Hilyard
                    Eugene, Oregon
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">38</fw>
                
                <note type="authorial"><hi rend="underline">Air Mail</hi></note>
                
                <note type="recipient">ansd 2-16-58</note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    EUGENE FEB 13 730 PM 1958 OREG.
                    PRAY FOR PEACE
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>6 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>AIR MAIL 6¢ U.S.POSTAGE</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
