<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- letter is incomplete -->
148a
Sunday, July 25, 1942
1418 North Dearborn
Dear Daddy, Mama, Amama,
<p>I was deeply moved by your letter, Daddy - and I <underline>shall</underline> remember it! You'll never know just how much what you say in half a dozen words means to me. To me, there must be <underline>glory</underline> in living - or all would be pointless. I can understand clearly what you mean in saying that, when one is "in connection" with the world, one <underline>has</underline> a sense of glory and well-being. That is a great thing to remember.</p>
<p>So glad you're all happy</p>
(2)
<p>there together, but I wish Amama would remain with you.</p>
<p>We have several engagements in view - one for here next week, and one for Benton Harbor Mich. next week - but neither are certain. I might well explain our position to you now. You see, we're in an "in between" stage. We are "broken in" to a certain extent, so we are able to play better spots, but we're not yet equipped with sufficient repertoire and absolute "smoothess" such as is required for the best of hotel dates. If we wished</p>
148b
(3)
<p>to work <underline>anyplace</underline> we could be doing that now - but in that case, we'd never be worth a "hoot in hell" (in the Countess' words) to the better places - so would never advance liek a demon to get <unclear/> going, and is making progress. M. C A. is to take us over when we have worked awhile longer and intends to place us in the best hotels. We are meanwhile, workign on new repertoire and attending to costumes. We now have two new numbers ready to break in, and are workign on a Spanish number, done to parts of Capriccio Espagnol</p>
(4)
<p>(danced by Ballet Russe), Espana Cani, and a Spanish farrnca. It is truly going to be exciting with heel stamps, all characteristic gypsy steps, etc - fiery and deirlmay -care! George is giving me the solo part in it with him - and I am really thrilled. Think of me in this - help me to get the right characterization - will you? I must be a wild, untamed, feeling fool gypsy girl - God, how I do know that feelign - that is what I must be in dance. Just think of me as this, will you> It will help greatly.</p>
<p>Costumes for this will be</p>
