<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27a.42-43_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from W. E. Bard to John G. Neihardt, June 21, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27a.42-43_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from W. E. Bard to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-06-21">June 21, 1959</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.42-43_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">42</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">POETRY SOCIETY OF TEXAS</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="italics">Organized November 5, 1921</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    
                    <hi rend="caps">MARTIN SHOCKLEY, PRESIDENT
                        <lb/>
                    ARTHUR SAMPLEY, VICE PRESIDENT
                        <lb/>
                    FAYE CARR ADAMS, CORRESPONDING SECRETARY
                        <lb/>
                    MARVIN DAVIS WINSETT, TREASURER
                        <lb/>
                    ODENA GLOVER BRANNAM, RECORDING SECRETARY
                        <lb/>
                    MABEL M. KUYKENDALL, DIRECTOR
                        <lb/>
                    CATHERINE CASE LUBBE, DIRECTOR
                        <lb/>
                    
                    STANDING COMMITTEE CHAIRMEN
                        <lb/>
                    WILLIAM E. BARD, ANNUAL AWARDS
                        <lb/>
                    LIBBY STOPPLE, MONTHLY AWARDS
                        <lb/>
                    C. E. SHUFORD, PUBLICITY
                        <lb/>
                    LOIS UPSHAW, YEARBOOK</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        June 21, 1959
                        
                        5119 Cedar Springs
                        Dallas, Texas
                    </dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>c/o University of Missouri,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It is requested that you act as judge in the Hilton Ross Greer Contest sponsored by the Poetry Society of Texas with closing date for entries October 1, 1959, if permitted.</p>
                
                <p>We have been greatly favored by your judgment in the past and your name has come up in the connection, with request that I write you. The enclosed announcement will explain the nature of the contest.</p>
                
                <p>Poems will be mailed shortly after that date, with complete instructions. You will be the sole judge, in case you accept. There should be some twenty entries, I should say.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With best personal wishes, I am,</salute>
                
                    <salute>Sincerely Ypurs<sic>Yours</sic>,</salute>
                
                    <signed>WE Bard</signed>
                    <signed>W. E. Bard</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.42-43_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">43</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <hi rend="caps">THE POETRY SOCIETY OF TEXAS</hi>
                </opener>
                
                <p>Annual Prizes Offered For 1959</p>
                
                <p>* Awards marked with an asterisk are open also to poets who are non-members. All others are limited to the membership.</p>
                
                <p>(All entries must conform to Rules Governing Annual Contests)</p>
                <list>
                    <item><p>*<hi rend="italics">The Dr. <hi rend="caps">A.</hi> Joseph Armstrong Memorial Award</hi>, $125.00&#8212;Offered by the Guardian Angel Group of the Armstrong Browning Library for the best poem of not more than 100 lines in the Browning tradition, that fittingly commemorates the work of Dr. <hi rend="caps">A.</hi> Joseph Armstrong of Baylor University. Open to all residents of the United States.</p>
                    
                        <p>For this Armstrong Award, <hi rend="italics">three original copies</hi> are required.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Old South Prize</hi>, $100.00&#8212;Offered by Georgia <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Lucas of Austin for the best poem of not more than 100 lines. Entries are not restricted as to subject matter or form.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Hilton Ross Greer Memorial Prize</hi>, $50.00&#8212;Offered by the Society in memory of is<sic>its</sic> first president, Hilton Ross Greer, for the best poem of not more than 36 lines on any subject in any form.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Glenn Gordon Award</hi>, $35.00&#8212;First prize, $25.00, second prize, $10.00; offered by Glenn Gordon of Dallas for the best poem of not more than 36 lines on the subject of racial harmony. <hi rend="italic">Open only to students in Texas colleges.</hi> Entries must be postmarked no later than June 1, 1959.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Vida Pifer Lyric Prize</hi>, $30.00&#8212;First prize, $15.00, second prize, $10.00; third prize, $5.00; offered by Vida Pifer of McAllen for the best lyric poem of not more than 24 lines on any subject.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p>*<hi rend="italics">The Aline <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Carter Peace Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Aline <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Carter of San Antonio for the best poem of not over 40 lines on world harmony. Open to all residents of the United States.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p>*<hi rend="italics">The Harry Kovner Memorial Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Beatrice Kovner Bobys of Corpus Christi for the best poem of not over 40 lines expressing the thought that each of us is our brother's keeper. Open to all residents of the United States.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Texan Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered for the best ballad on a Texas theme.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Narrative Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered for the best narrative poem from 40 to 60 lines on any theme.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Citizenship Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Hon <hi rend="caps">F. G.</hi> Swanson of Tyler for the best poem of not over 24 lines expressing the duties and responsibilites of citizenship in a democracy.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Alamo Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered for the best sonnet or sequence of not more than three sonnets, on any subject.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Vera Almon Sampley Memorial Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Arthur <hi rend="caps">M.</hi> Sampley of Denton for the best poem of not over 35 lines in any form portraying human character.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Crystal Hurley Memorial Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Charles Lee Hurley of College Station for the best poem of not more than 40 lines on any subject.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Edna Weedon Tobias Memorial Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Vera <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> Marshall of Franklin, Louisiana, for the best lyric poem of not more than 24 lines on any subject.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Whitney Mason Beaty Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Dr. John <hi rend="caps">O.</hi> Beaty and Josephine Powell Beaty of Barboursville, Virginia, for the best poem of not over 24 lines suitable for use as a Christian hymn.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Dallas High School Prize</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by Siddie Joe Johnson of the Dallas Public Library for the best 28 lines or less written by a High School student of Dallas County. Entries must be postmarked not later than May 31, 1959. Note: For this Prize, <hi rend="italics">three original copies</hi> are required.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Montgomery Tribute Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered anonymously for the poem of not more than 28 lines paying most fitting tribute to Whitney and Vaida Montgomery for their achievement in the creation and sponsorship of poetry in Texas.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Odessa College Award</hi>, $25.00&#8212;Offered by the Southwestern Literature Class of Odessa College for the best poem of not more than 36 lines on a theme of the Southwest.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Good Neighbors Prize</hi>, $20.00&#8212;Offered by the Friends of Mexico in Dallas for the best poem of not more than 40 lines in any form, tending to further the good will and understanding between the people of the United States and Mexico.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Aleurophile Prize</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Mary Litsey Cowan of Arlington for the best poem about a cat or cats, of the domestic species, not to exceed 32 lines.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Julia <hi rend="caps">H.</hi> Ricker Memorial Award</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by the daughters of Mrs. Julia <hi rend="caps">H.</hi> Ricker for the best nature poem in any form.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Bess Ann Motley Children's Poem Award</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Bess Ann Motley of the Texas State Library at Austin for the best poem not exceeding 24 lines written by an adult for children.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Prayer Sonnet Prize</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Cora Pritchard Dines of Dallas for the best sonnet on prayer.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Oread Award</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Gene Shuford of Denton for the poem of not more than 48 lines that is most original and incisive in form and imagery.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Globe Peace Award</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Mrs. Marjorie Morris of Odessa for the best Shakesperean sonnet on peace.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Nora Elmore Johnson Memorial Award</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Daisy Elmore Tennant of Odessa for the best poem of not more than 36 lines on the subject of the Crossroads of Life.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Christmas Prize</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Mary Hurt of Odessa for the best lyric poem of not more than 12 lines on the subject of Christmas.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Humorous Prize</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Mary Jo Vines of Dallas for the best humorous poem of not more than 16 lines.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Green Thumb Prize</hi>, $15.00&#8212;Offered by Nancy Richey Ranson of the Dallas Morning News for the best poem of not more than 32 lines on the theme of man's utilization of plants and flowers to beautify the earth.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Prose Poem Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered anonymously for the best prose poem of not over 700 words, demonstrating originality and an adequate grasp of this form.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Lone Star Prize</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered for the best poem not exceeding 40 lines based on an incident in Texas history.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Panhandle Prize</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Jessie Brown Tomas of Houston for the best poem of not over 40 lines dealing with any phase of history or folklore of the Texas Panhandle.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Toby Koon Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Toby Koon of Dallas for the best poem not to exceed 32 lines on the subject of one's love for his fellow man.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p>*<hi rend="italics">The Horse in Poetry Prize</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Ollie <hi rend="caps">L.</hi> Roediger of Breckenridge for the best poem about a horse or horses, not to exceed 60 lines. Open to all residents or former residents of Texas.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Campbell Cinquain Prize</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Ethyle <hi rend="caps">M.</hi> Campbell of Grand Prairie for the best cinquain or cinquain sequence.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Gertrude Stein Tribute Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered anonymously for the best poem of not more than 50 lines on any subject, written in the style of Miss Stein's verse.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Golden Years Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Mabel <hi rend="caps">M.</hi> Chancellor of Dallas for the best poem not to exceed 32 lines on the subject of the latter years of a long lifetime.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The William <hi rend="caps">H.</hi> Lamar Memorial Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Mrs. <hi rend="caps">W. O.</hi> Rawlins of Dallas, for the best poem of not more than 28 lines based on the life of some person in Texas history.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The John <hi rend="caps">P.</hi> Sjolander Memorial Award</hi>, 10.00&#8212;Offered by the Poetry Society of Baytown, Texas, for the best poem of 42 lines or less in the style of John Peter Sjolander concerning life at sea or tillers of the soil.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Religious Poem Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Rosalie Hulse of Dallas, for the best poem of not more than 24 lines on the subject of God within us, the incarnation of God in men.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p>*<hi rend="italics">The Lillie <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Graves Memorial Award</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by the Wichita Falls Poetry Society for the best poem of not more than 30 lines on pioneer life. Open to any member of any Poetry Group in Texas only.</p></item>
                    
                    <item><p><hi rend="italics">The Maverick Prize</hi>, $10.00&#8212;Offered by Martin Shockley, President, for the poem of his choice selected from entries failing to win a prize in another classification.</p></item>
                </list>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>&#9734;</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="italics">Rules Governing Annual Contests</hi></p>
                
                <p><hi rend="italics">Please check you entries point by point. Many good poems are disqualified, because contestant overlooked a Rule.</hi></p>
                
                <list>
                    <item>1. Annual Contests, unless otherwise specified, are open only to active members whose dues for the current year have been paid by the closing date for submissions of entries, to life members, and to officers of the Society.</item>
                    
                    <item>2. <hi rend="caps">ELIGIBILITY</hi>:
                        <list>
                            <item>a. Entries must be postmarked not later than October 1, 1959, unless otherwise specified.</item>
                            <item>b. Each entry must be the original work of the contestant.</item>
                            <item>c. Contestant may enter poems in as many classes as desired, but only one poem may be entered in any one class. A poem entered in one class may not be entered, in whole or in part, in any other class.</item>
                            <item>d. A poem may not be entered in a class in which the contestant has won the award the preceding year.</item>
                            <item>e. A poem is not eligible which, in whole or part, has been published in print, presented over radio or television, or accepted for publication; or which is in the hands of an editor for consideration, or entered in any contest running concurrently.</item>
                            <item>f. Poems, other than winners of the Critic's Award, which have been entered in monthly or special contests and are otherwise eligible, are eligible for entry in the annual contests.</item>
                            <item>g. An eligible poem may not be withdrawn after submission.</item>
                        </list>
                    </item>
                    
                    <item>3. <hi rend="caps">REQUIREMENTS</hi>:
                        <list>
                            <item>a. <p><hi rend="caps">ONE ORIGINAL TYPEWRITTEN COPY WITH CARBON COPY</hi>, unless otherwise specified. <hi rend="italics">New regulation this year</hi>. Unless otherwise specified, contestant must submit one original typwritten copy, with carbon copy, of each poem on 8½ by 11-inch paper, using one side of sheet only. Contestants should retain copies of their entries, as no manuscripts will be returned.</p></item>
                            <item>b. <p><hi rend="caps">SHOW CLASS AT TOP OF SHEET</hi>. Contestants must show the class in which a poem is entered on each copy, at top of sheet.</p>
                                <p><hi rend="caps">DO NOT SHOW NAME OF AUTHOR ON MANUSCRIPT</hi>.The author's name and address must <hi rend="caps">NOT</hi> appear on manuscript, but must be typed on a <hi rend="caps">SEPARATE</hi> sheet with the poem title (or titles), and <hi rend="italics">sealed</hi> in an Identification Envelope which accompanies the entries. On the <hi rend="caps">OUTSIDE</hi> of this Identification Envelope, list the title (or titles), with the class in which each title is entered. One Identification Envelope is sufficient, regardless of the number of poems submitted.</p></item>
                            <item>c. <p>Entries which fail to conform to the Rules will be eliminated by the Annual Contest Committee.</p></item>
                            <item>d. <p>Each class shall be judged by one competent judge, unless otherwise specified. If, in the opinion of the judge, no entry in a class measures up to the desired standard, the Society may withhold the award.</p></item>
                            <item>e. <p>Prize-winning poems may not be printed elsewhere before they appear in the Yearbook of the Society (except in special instances when a donor may wish to publish the poem he sponsored); thereafter, full rights revert to the author. The Society releases all claim to non-winning poems upon announcements of awards.</p></item>
                            <item>f. <p>All manuscripts are correspondance concerning contests must be addressed to <address><addrLine>Faye Carr Adams,</addrLine> <addrLine>Corresponding Secretary,</addrLine> <addrLine>Poetry Society of Texas,</addrLine> <addrLine>4244 Skillman,</addrLine> <addrLine>Dallas 14, Texas.</addrLine></address></p></item>
                        </list>
                    </item>
                </list>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.42-43_0003"/>
                
                <!--This page is a copy of most of j4c.27a.42-43_0002-->
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
