<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.28-30_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Jessie H. Erickson to John G. Neihardt, October 26, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.28-30_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Jessie H. Erickson to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-10-26">October 26, 1958</date>
                    <extent>2 page, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.28-30_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Arlington, Minnesota
                        October 26, 1958
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>There are always so many things I should like to discuss with you that I often find it difficult to refrain from getting up in the middle of the night to sribble a note to you. You see, you have been too kind and generous in answering my letters. It seems that the week spent at Oak Haven continues to multiply its blessings.</p>
                
                <p>You must remember Mrs. Roberts who has shown a remarkably valiant spirit in overcoming a difficult physical handicap. I have already visited twice with her in her home. I have held her four Mongoloid babies in my arms, and I have developed a most delightful association with her own two children. Twelve-year-old Bill has never spent a week-end in the country, so I invited him to our home for the four days of the <hi rend="caps">M. E. A.</hi> week-end. The young man has a bubbling, buoyant spirit which is most contagious. He is more than a match for our ten- and eleven-year-olds. Seconds after his arrival the three of them found the noisiest items in the house to help them get acquainted: the cornet, the piano, and the electric train (in that order). Since it was obviously useless to bottle the racket while the evening was yet young, I simply stuffed cotton in my ears to pad both my eardrums and my nerves. Patience paid off. They soon tired, probably exhausted by their own exuberance. Next on the agenda was an exicted examination of Fred's hoard of comic books, and after that an exchange of "spook" stories which gave them all such a happy fright that I had to bed them all down in the same room that first night. Oh, what a glorious, glorious week-end! I'm willing to bet that none of them will ever forget it! <hi rend="caps">NEITHER WILL I</hi>!</p>
                
                <p>Some time ago I wrote a query letter to the editors of the <hi rend="caps">LADIES' HOME JOURNAL</hi> in regard to the story with which I have been so concerned. To my astonishment I received a personal letter in reply instead of the usual printed rejection slip. The editor suggested that I forward my manuscript, although he offered only a very slim chance of publication since the Journal accepts very few first-person articles, and most of those only on assignment. This does not discourage me, however, since my letter must have been good enough to attract attention. I must do a good deal of rewriting, though, before I can submit the finished story, because I have changed my point o<del>t</del><add>f</add> view some, and until now I have had a bit of diff<del>f</del>iculty with the ending. Wish me luck.</p>
                
                <p>Not only Willard, but the boys as well, are most eager to become acquainted with you. And I want to see you again. As you know, this is not impossible. Perhaps something can be arranged.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.28-30_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                
                <p>Willard and I had hoped that <hi rend="caps">NET</hi> would carry your telecast. If they do, we have not been able to discover it. What a disappointment! Congratulations on the success of your series! It's very frustrating for us to have to miss it.</p>
                
                <p>Willard has registered with Mankato State College for a Physics course, part of which is telecast six days a week, and part of which he must attend at the college on Saturdays. It puts an extra burden on his work load, but he seems to like it. It will, of course, increase his chances of getting a better teaching position.</p>
                
                <p>As for me, I have been enjoying a series on creative writing called <hi rend="caps">THE QUILL</hi>. I am not working for credit, but there is a good deal to learn simply by listening. At first it was a bit of a struggle to coax the children into relinquishing a favorite cartoon program, but children are very fair-minded when they are treated fairly.</p>
                
                <p>How do my letters always get so long? Do I babble?</p>
                
                <p>Sometimes the stuggle to maintain a continuing stability of mind and spirit is both discouraging and frightening. But when I remember that I have decidedly inherited a nervous temperament with a disposition toward very high highs and very low lows, the fear subsides, because I also know that I am learning quite well how to handle periods of depression as well as periods of elation. Please, will you write to me again? Your dear letters are a real source of encouragement and pleasure to me.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>As always your friend,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Jessie Erickson</signed>
                
                    <signed>Jessie Erickson</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.28-30_0003"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Mrs. Willard Erickson
                    Arlington, Minnesota
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    ARLINGTON
                    OCT 27
                    10-AM
                    1958
                    MINN.
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>LINCOLN
                    4¢
                    U.S. POSTAGE</p>
                </figure>
                
                <note type="recipient">Ansd
                    10-30-'58</note>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>