<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.21-22_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from G. Arthur Bailey to John G. Neihardt, October 19, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.21-22_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from G. Arthur Bailey to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-10-19">October 19, 1958</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.21-22_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">318-2
                    in letter 10/06/58
                    Aly Collection</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">G. ARTHUR BAILEY
                        <lb/>
                    3875 DEWEY AVENUE
                        <lb/>
                    OMAHA 5, NEBRASKA</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>October 19, 1958</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your good letter has been on my desk for a month and I regret my tardy ackowledgement. I,too, wa s disappointed that there seemed no opportunity for a good visit when you were recently in Omaha. It was quite apparent that you were being pulled this way and that and unable to control your time.</p>
                
                <p>You mentioned the walks we used to take through the country surrounding Bancroft. I seldom drive into the town without recalling our long tramps down the railroad track toward Lyons. We often varied these trips by taking the dirt roads. I don't suppose you will recall that On<sic>on</sic> one occasion I stepped into a rut and sprained my left ankle quite badly, and that you practically carried me to the William Ward home, where I roomed. I have often wondered how you managed it for it happened near the park as we were coming into town. That ankle remained weak for a number of years.</p>
                
                <p>There were not too many kindred souls in the town in those days and I appreciated having you as a friend. At my request, you would quote from your current poetry and when A Bundle of Myrrh came out, your first published work, I believe, I liked it very much. At the time, perhaps the erotic passages appealed most, for we were young and blood was warm. I have most of your earlier books, some of which you inscribed.</p>
                
                <p>I wonder if you will recall a little monthly magazine, The Pathfinder, published by The University Press, at Sewanee, Tennessee. The November 1907 issue carried your dramatic poem, The Passing of the Lion. My enthusiasm was so great that you bound it for me in green leather with hand tooling of your own. I enjoy showing these books to my friends when the occasion offers.</p>
                
                <p>Shortly before I left for Phoenix, Arizona last winter, I received a letter from Mrs. Mrs. Bower Aly. She said that Bob Kelly suggested that she contact me. I did not return home until the middle of March and am afraid I forgot about her letter and failed to answer it. She did not say she was a friend of yours, merely that she was writing a doctoral dissertation about you and your work.</p>
                
                <note type="authorial">(paper slipped)</note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.21-22_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">G. ARTHUR BAILEY
                        <lb/>
                    3875 DEWEY AVENUE
                        <lb/>
                    OMAHA 5, NEBRASKA</hi>
                </fw>
                    
                <p><hi rend="underline">Quote</hi>-
                    <lb/>
                "If you have ever heard Mr. Neihardt speak or read his poetry, Ishould<sic>I should</sic> be pleased to have any information you can give me about it, or about the audience. In fact, anything you remember about Mr. Neihardt and his family I would find helpful."</p>
                
                <p>I felt that I should give no information without your permission and after you had censored it. She evidently wanted intimate details and I felt that it was asking a good deal of a stranger. P<del>O</del><add>o</add>ssibly, because I did not reply, they did not look me up if they passed through Omaha , enroute West.</p>
                
                <p>I trust that at some future time we shall have better luck in getting together?</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With kind regards,</salute>
                
                    <salute>Most sincerely,</salute>
                    <signed>G. Arthur Bailey</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi></opener> <p>Pardon the typed letter. Because of very poor eyesight, I seem to do a bit better this way.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
