<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35b.33-34">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, September 25, 1971</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.35b.33-34</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1971-09-25">September 25, 1971</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.33"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>September 25, 1971</dateline> 
                
                    <salute>Dear John,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was delighted to have your letter; things are happening so fast to you that every note is like a <hi rend="caps">UP</hi> bulletin. It's wonderful, wonderful, and couldn't happen to a nicer poet. Guess what! I saw the Dick Cavett Neihardt show on the University station last night, and it's better than ever the second time around. Earl Pomeroy is going to use it again this term, he told me. He always asks about you.</p>
                
                <p>We are just getting into gear from our return. England was gorgeous, but full of tourists (eight million in London!!!). I had an experience I should tell you about. On the train down to Surrey where our daughter lives I got talking to a little man who was working on a crossward<sic>crossword</sic> puzzle and asked me about a word. Then we chatted aobut my nationality (he heard my American accent) and what I was doing in England, and from that quickly to how little appreciated Meredith is. This man thought Meredith and Swinburne were the only British poets who ever wrote Greek rhythms well, a<del>d</del><add>n</add>d then I said there was one American poet who did, and when I mentioned you, <hi rend="caps">HE</hi> said, "Oh, Neihardt! Yes, he's a great writer." He had been trying to buy <hi rend="underline">Black Elk</hi> and it's out of print in England, but in the course of talking about you he said he had been after Penguin for some time to do something about you. At that point we reached the station where I had to get out, and it happened so fast I didn't find out who he was. But you"ve got an English friend who can talk to Penguin, and someday I will track him down. I cheered him up by telling him about the new editions and the reception of Black Elk in America now.</p>
                
                <p>I did talk to a British publisher, Longmans, but the agent there said it is not the time in England as yet. I have written to two publishers, now that I have the release from Nebraska; it's only by telephone so far, but Mr. Nicoll was on vacation and Virginia assured me he would send an acknowledgement. We parted friends, and Virginia said they are much disappointed, but I think a commercial publisher will be better. Houston Peterson is interested in helping 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.34"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
                
                    us too. I say "us" because I have always thought of the biography <del>w</del><add>a</add>s part of your pattern, and I am sure it will come out right. The gods are with you more than ever, and this will come out right. The gods are with you more than ever, and this will find its place in whatever is right for you. Houston Peterson has a good many connections in New York<del>l</del><add>;</add> he's the anthologist whom you once reviewed very favorably.</p>
                
                <p><add>*</add>   I'm thinking ahead, too, John. I would like to start on a collection of letters. It's a natural in a year or two, and your letters are unique and gorgeous. Would you permit? I can date most of the undated ones, and I'd love to work on them. A good many of the letters should be known to the world, and I am pretty well steeped in them. I have had this in the back of my head all along, but until now the biography was priority.</p> 
                
                <p>Let me know about the second Dick Cavett show. It will be advertised, of course, but I'd like to circulate some announcements here as Bower did last time. I'm so glad allthis<sic>all this</sic> is happening--you deserve every bit of it ten times over.</p> 
                
                <p>Our very best love. Bower says to convey his extra-special regards. And please do keep me up to date on the excitement. I can still write some things into the final chapter.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Love,</salute> 
                
                    <signed><note>Lucile Aly</note></signed> 
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
