<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
52 Thompson Collection 38
4252 McPherson Ave
St. Louis, Mo.
March 23rd, 43
Darling Alice:
<p><hi rend="underline">So long</hi> since we last heard from you - I Know you are working very hard and very constantly but still I am selfishly wishing for news from you. I want to Know if you are having bad results from being so much on your feet as a waitress has to be? Yet I believe that is <hi rend="underline">not</hi> the case, as you are on your toes so much anyway. I am so grateful for <hi rend="underline">my</hi> job, and I do so want to see Daddy <hi rend="underline">well</hi>. He is receiving very encouraging results from his Osteopathic physician, who claims to be able to completely cure him of all his troubles. He already walks so much better, and looks better as well.</p>
<p>I wonder if you realize <hi rend="underline">how down</hi> our Daddy has been? - His letters have always voiced so much good will and encouragement that you may have missed the <hi rend="underline">facts</hi>. So you can believe me when I say I am Deeply grateful <hi rend="underline">I</hi> have been able to help him <hi rend="underline">now</hi> when he <hi rend="underline">needs</hi> it!</p>
53
<p>I leave home at about 7:30 and when I return at night his dear face look, so precious to me. He has a good meal all prepared for us, and I get to read the days' mail which often means letter from our children - the dearest and best in all the World.</p>
<p>We rather expect Amama to be with us after April third, Ottis' birthday<hi rend="strike_through">next weekend</hi> - Hilda is <hi rend="underline">very</hi> happy and is making good connections. She is still staying with Seymours, who have all but adopted her! Mr Seymour plaufully calls her "that honey-haired Neihardt brat!"</p>
<p>Daddy's Lincoln hopes are nearly gone - Nebraska has always been "cheap" to <hi rend="underline">him</hi>. But Kansas City now looms bit. Richard wants us to go there and live in his mother's beautiful Home as she is so lonesome. Nice, not?</p>
Endless love
Mama
(over)
54
<p>It seems that the F.B.J. has need for linguists - and so I am applying. Maybe my French and German will yet do me some really good. Daddy has written to Mr Jenkins who is so well Known and who uses his "Easter" and "What is Xmas" every year form his pulpit - and we hope he may have a worth-while job to direct our Daddy to.</p>
<p>Sigurd has been sick - we rather hope he may fly to see us soon.</p>
<p>I'm writing this during work bows in a dull time! - <hi rend="underline">Write soon</hi> to</p>
Your devoted
Mama