<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35b.19">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Bower Aly to John G. Neihardt, August 12, 1971</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.35b.19</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Bower Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1971-08-12">August 12, 1971</date>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.19"/>
                
                <note><hi rend="caps">NEIHARDT</hi></note>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        10 Pine Walk 
                        Carshalton Beeches, Surrey 
                        England
                        August 12, 1971 
                    </dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear John:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I am writing to assure you of my concurrence in the decision Lucile has taken concerning the Neihardt biography. As a matter of fact, I advised her to request the cancellation of the Nebraska contract as soon as she received the letter from the <del>p</del><add>P</add>ress with the egregiouscomments<sic>egregious comments</sic> from their reader. In view of the previous favorable reception given the book by the Press, as well as by others, Lucile was naturally amazed--and shocked. She did not want to make a decision at once, and she was reluctant to make any decision that might concern or worry you. As you doubtless know, Lucile is a gentle spirit and she does not easily abide what might seem to be bickering or quarreling. And she has been particularly concerned not to cause you unpleasantness.</p>
                
                <p>I assume that the Nebraska Press will cancel the contract, as requested. I would then use every avenue open to me to find a publisher who will respect the author's right to express her own judgments. I believe that in due course (assuming the cancellation of the Nebraska contract) the book ca  find a publisher; but it may require close attention on my part--attention that I am willing to focus not only for Lucile (God bless her!) and for John (God bless him, too!) but also for 'the ghostly brother'--whom God has already so richly blessed!</p>
                
                <p>As for the readr<sic>reader</sic> who reported to the Nebraska Press, I can say that I have read and reported on books for publishers, and I have had mine read and reported on for publishers in advance of publication. I believe myself qualified to observe that the Nebraska Press' reader of the Neihardt biography was neither perceptive for professional. Aside from demonstrable errors of fact in his criticism, some of his comments were snide; and in general his point of view was that of a second-rate critic: "This is not the way I would have written the book; <hi rend="underline">ergo,</hi> it won't do. Aside from the counsel that the book should be condensed--a solid recommendation from the point of view of the publisher--the only worthwhile suggestions he had to offer were minor.</p>
                
                <p>I hope you will not be too much disappointed in Lucile's decision. I think it is the right one, and I shall do all I can to see that the book is brought out in due course as the author wants it and not according to the stipulations of an unknown reviewer. If you have any suggestions or recommendations conce<unclear><del/><add>rning</add></unclear> a publisher I would be glad to have them. What would you think of an approach to the University of Missouri Press? I think they are good people, but I incline to wonder whether any univeristy press is big enough for the book--certainly the Nebraska press is not. I want an <hi rend="underline">international</hi> publisher.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Affectionately, now as always,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Bower Aly</signed>
                    
                    <note><hi rend="caps">CC</hi> Mrs. Myrtle <del>y</del><add>Y</add>oung</note>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>