<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
145 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 37
Feb 16th 1943
Dearest Children:
<p>How wonderful that Joan adn Elaine are doing so well in school - Elaine must have gone ahead very fast indeed, to be so close upon big sisters' heel.</p>
<p>They must be very interesting for you now. <hi rend="underline"> Please</hi> don't neglect their separate talents. I Know that all <hi rend="underline"> my</hi> talents were for you children, not for me to excel in - and I believe both Joan and Elaine are very gifted children. Joan is a <hi rend="underline"> Poet</hi> at heart - and Elaine a <hi rend="underline"> Musician</hi>. Joan may learn to play the Piano too - but Elaine simply must do so. Am I right? Children are never too young to be helped into a good groove of their own, where no other child over shadows him or her. I believe that Joanie will write stories.</p>
38
<p>Alice <hi rend="strike_through">have</hi> has written such wonderful letters and I am saving <hi rend="underline"> every one</hi> in order, because some day she may want to come out with the "Diary of a young dancer" that would make most interesting reading. She is very amazing to say the least.</p>
<p>Hilda is starting for Chicago the first of March. She was <hi rend="underline"> very</hi> successful here lately in a public affair. She sang the "Jewel song" and "La bioletera" and was called the well Known St Louis Saprano!! She has improved immense by and <hi rend="underline"> must</hi> get going now. The Seymour have invited her to stay with them till she finds a suitable place.</p>
<p>You folks would all simply adorably Nei - He is <hi rend="underline"> too</hi> bright - he has his</p>
39
<p>Dad's quiet way of looking right through you so <hi rend="underline"> earnestly</hi> seeking to understand. It is fascinating to watch his eyes. Then again he is <hi rend="underline"> so loving</hi> - He pets us frequently and lays his little head close up to ones Knee or down on ones shoulder, saying "Nice, n-i-c-e so <hi rend="underline"> softly</hi>! He has a boy hair cut none almost <hi rend="underline"> white</hi> blonde!</p>
<p>He spells his name "N-e-i" - Nei! and then laughs! He says "<sic>Pease</sic> Mamma, <hi rend="underline"> more water</hi>"! and other lengthy things! And he Knows almost <hi rend="underline"> every</hi> thing by name all over the house! I don't Know what he will do when he gets big but I Know he is a most intelligent youngster! Enid shows her condition quite a bit now</p>
40
<p>and I am going to be with her when the new baby comes. In the mean while we want to get away if possible, so that the little family can b quiet a bit.  besides we <hi rend="underline"> must earn</hi> some money. If nothing better comes, I will take one of the many jobs I see advertised in the paper - so many couples now work, and need an "elderly woman" to Keep their Home or children. I saw one paying $50.00 a month - not bad?! We'll see what comes next in this wonderful but funny - crazy world!</p>
Loads of Love to you four from your devoted
Mom 
Nannie