<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Thompson Collection 16
<unclear type="cutoff"/> Ave.
Overland, Mo.

SAINT LOUIS, MO. 4
JAN 12
3-PM
1943

BUY 
WAR SAVINGS
BONDS AND STAMPS

Miss Alicia Nye,
4325 Dearborn St.,
Chicago,
Ill.
17
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland, Mo.
Jan. 12, '43
Precious Alicia:
<p>What a lovely surprise package for my birthday! It was so dear of you - and characteristic.</p>
<p>Now all I need is some place to go in my tie, my muffler and my socks! Evidently should go to a Chinese restaurant, if I'm to use the chopsticks!! Many thanks, precious lady!</p>
<p>I know you cannot have had time to look up an agent. Perhaps the Countess could tell you the</p>
(2)
<p>best one. "Continental Concerts" has moved to New York City and they'll try for some engagements down there. The honor from the Institute should keep. (Incidentally, I have the year book of hte National Inst. of Arts &amp; Letters, and I wish you could see the membership list - composers, sculptors, painters &amp; literary folks! Membership is limited to 250. It is the American equivalent of the French Institute, except that the latter includes scientists!</p>
18
-3-
<p>I do to hope that something may break for me soon. This is all wrong, but I do not grieve or fume over it. I continue to give thanks for everything; and as I look back I'm amazed at my good fortune.</p>
<p>Old Lady, I wish you could &amp; would try to pick up some nice semi-precious gem material for me in Mexico. There should be lovely chunks of fire opal and some nice bright garnets, <hi rend="underline">not</hi> too dark. Wet them in your mouth &amp; hold</p>
<p>to the light to see what their real shade is. There should be other materials - for instance, Mexican jade. This should be large enough to make a ring with a long marguse top, &amp; the color should not be too muddy &amp; dark. If a piece has one good patch of green that can be used for a marguise top, the rest may be any shade. You'd have to ask where gem materials are for sale. In Juarez, across from El Paso, they are sold plentifully.</p>
<p>Thanks again &amp; endless love.</p>
Dad.