<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26.11-14_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to George Sterling, March 13, 1917</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26.11-14_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1917-03-13">March 13, 1917</date>
                    <extent>3 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.11-14_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
                
                January 22, 1958
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter was most welcome, and I'm glad to learn about the talk at the Presbyterian Student Center. The things you tell me are the most useful to know, and you will never sound boastful to me. The reaction of the group is always important, and I'm glad to have the <unclear>report</unclear> of the quiet, interested <unclear>conversation</unclear> after the speech. The impression you make on students &#8212; or any audiences &#8212; should not surprise anyone; think of what is behind it all.</p>
                
                <p>When I last wrote I had not yet read the <unclear>new</unclear> set of letters <unclear>nor</unclear> seen the snapshots in the <unclear>box</unclear>. The pictures are excellent, and I want to use some of them if possible. Also, many letters as I have read, every new group opens up new areas.You have certainly had an amazing life. Now I have some new questions, specially about the <hi rend="caps">YMCA</hi> camp Duncan. How did you happen to go there? What were the pageants you put on? Did you write them? That's a whole project I hadn't heard of before.</p>
                
                <p>Also I'm having trouble pinning down the months in the Sioux City paper. It must have been the fall of 1907, but if you remember anything specific let me know. For instance, you were in 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.11-14_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
                
                    <unclear>Spearfish</unclear> canyon that summer (1907), back in September in Bancroft, then you had mentioned to <unclear>Doris</unclear> planning to camp out in the wilderness, and you came back to Bancroft "from the <unclear>north</unclear>" early in December, according to the <hi rend="underline">Blade</hi>. In February, 1908, your sister <unclear>Lulu</unclear> was married, an<del/><add>d</add> you were  at the wedding. The same month you were active in the Bancroft Athletic Association, and the problem is, when did you have the time to work in Sioux City? Did you give up that job to make the river trip? If I can get the time pinned down I'm fairly sure I can get the papers. It couldn't have been <hi rend="underline">after</hi> the river trip because there wasn't time.</p>
                
                <p>I have just read the Harriet <unclear>Monroe</unclear> letters. Most of her answers were not there unless they were typical; she didn't keep copies of her hand-written letters. Your last one (1928) was a gesture of <unclear>peace</unclear> about her article "Why not Laugh?" Did she ever reply to that? Your letter about Ezra Pound was there, and it's a good disscussion of <hi rend="underline"><unclear/> <unclear>libre</unclear></hi>. From these letters it sounds to me as if our Harriet's real trouble with you was that she admired you very much all the time down underneath. She sounds to me like a person who enjoyed fighting with people, and I don't think she understood at all that you <hi rend="underline">didn't</hi> like to fight. You must have been terribly frustrating for her.</p>
                
                <p>Mrs. Winkleman sent me a reproduction of "The Harpist" from the Wayne paper. She says it will 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.11-14_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
                
                    <unclear/> hard to treat "The <unclear>Tentiad</unclear>," which is not in any of the issues the library has. I think I will try to get to Wayne next summer, and perhaps I can turn up a copy of the right paper there. <del/><add>Mrs.</add> Winkleman is sending me also a commencement poem that may be yours. It isn't signed, but it was written by "a local poet," at the request of the editor, for the high school commencement. These verses are not for the dissertation, but they are interesting in showing how your <unclear/> were developing.</p>
                
                <p>I want to ask you about the Agamemnon translation too. In the library the folders that hold it are labeled "<hi rend="underline">portions</hi>" of the Agamemnon. I want to have it photostated next summer, and I wondered whether the <del/><add>c</add>omplete manuscript is in the library. I'd like to make a transcript and check it over with you if you're willing, because someday somebody <unclear>ought</unclear> to produce it.</p>
                
                <p>The section of the study I'm now working on is your years <unclear>as critic</unclear>. It is certainly worth a book in itself. It's like everything else you did &#8212; a big plan and care on details , or in your <unclear>words</unclear>, an epic with lyric detail. That's your idea of poetry too, isn't it &#8212; "a <unclear>goading</unclear> and a creeping pace." ? Your life is in wide circles &#8212; but you know that.</p>
                
                <p>Please give our love to everyone. I hope all the colds and twisted ankles are well in the past. Pat Yo-yo<del/> some love for me, as <unclear>Stewart</unclear> used to say.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.11-14_0004"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    2094 Hilyard
                    Eugene, Oregon
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    EUGENE
                    JAN 24
                    130 PM
                    1956
                    OREG.
                    PRAY F<unclear>OR PEACE</unclear>
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢
                    IN GOD WE TRUST
                    LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim, Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
