<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.78-80_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from M. Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt, December 13, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.78-80_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from M. Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-12-13">December 13, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.78-80_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">78</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        225 Willard Way, Ithaca, <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi>
                        Dec 13, 1958
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John: &#8212;</salute></opener> <p>I have thought of you so many times. Besides, Christmas is approaching. And so I write. How is the television going? I know wonderfully from the viewers' side. But how does it seem to you? Are you able to speak in front of the camera and under the lights or to an audience? I envy the persons who can see and hear you. I have done my best to hear your voice reading poetry. Some six weeks ago I ordered that record of the Song of the Three Friends from Mr. Gray. But <add>I</add> have not yet received it.</p>
                
                <p>Every now and then one of your Ithaca friends &#8212; and you have many here &#8212; asks me about you. I always report your conferences or last <unclear>series</unclear> of your <add>current</add> television appearances. And they marvel at your vigor as do I. Indeed, sometimes I think that the immortal spirit of you <del><unclear>soul d</unclear></del> soul not only illuminates your face but strengthens your body.</p>
                
                <p>I have been very busy with lectures this fall. Our chief speaker was Lord Attlee, a great and gracious man. He was an immense
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.78-80_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">79</fw>
                
                    success. And only recently we had a high official from the French Foreign Office, fresh from Paris. He told us all about Africa and its problems. And next month we'll hear more, for we have a series on Africa.</p>
                
                <p>The latest lecture, however, by a great scientist, that and the accompanying discussion, crystalized a thought. Sometimes I wonder where we are going with all this emphasis on science &#8212; and by "we" I mean the world. For it is a worldwide phenomenon. The <del>drift</del><add>current</add>, and a rapid one, is toward explaining everything in <unclear>mechanistic</unclear> terms and then of controlling it to our ends. There is, it seems to me, so little emphasis on the human, the <unclear>spiritual</unclear> problems of man. And we want to travel to new planets before fully adjusting to our own. I have thought so many times of what you make Sitting Bull say, "Who has forgotten their mother are forgotten at the last." I am though enclosing some thing in a different emphasis, written by the local Unitarian minister.</p>

                <p>Nita is well, and busy with her teaching. And all goes well with our children and the little grandchildren. And now I trust that you are still in good health and that despite your great loss your find continuing satisfaction in your life at work &#8212; you have so much to give. I know because of what you have done for me.</p> <closer><salute>With affectionate regards</salute>
                
                    <signed>Slade</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.78-80_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">80</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ITHACA UNITARIAN</hi>
                    
                    <dateline>Sunday, December 14, 1958 <!--dated after the letter in which it is enclosed--></dateline>
                    
                    <hi rend="caps">SEEKING GOD</hi>
                </opener>
                <p>God is not to be found in silence, yet no one ever found Him who was not silent. He is not to be found in speaking, yet no one ever found him without a deep inner communication. He is not to be found in fasting or eating or c<del>r</del><add>e</add>remony, yet no one finds Him except through a discipline of the spirit. He is not to be found in loneliness, yet only those who know the loneliness of the soul ever find Him. He is not <del>b</del><add>t</add>o be found in a crowd, yet He may not be found except in a fellowship of men. He is not to be found by reason alone, yet he who renounces his reason cannot find Him. He is not to found by faith alone, yet he who has not faith can never find Him. He cannot be found by the searching and seeking of man, yet the man who seeks not nor searches will never find Him. And there we see the truth of what the great religious prophets have said, which is only what should be said: You must seek and search and love with your total being - with your heart and mind and soul and strength. When one has this deep religious hunger there begins in his mortal being the immortal fire of insight. He finds a living response in himself of the soul in him crying for life, When one day in the holy silence he pronounces the word God he knows an ecstasy beyond flesh.</p>
                
                <p>The religious man will not say the word God often, lest the sound and the familiar ring dull his spirit to the reality. Instead he will know people and trees, dogs and brooks, bright skies and rolling seas, sorrow and tragedy, the laughter of children and the love of man and woman. He will embrace life and when he truly lives in the depths of his mind and senses and the marrow of his bones - only then will he know God. <del>T</del><add>B</add>ut then he may almost forget the word since he has God in his heart.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>RMH</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
