<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35b.18">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, August 10, 1971</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.35b.18</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1971-08-10">August 10, 1971</date>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.18"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>August 10, 1971</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I am sending you a copy of my letter to the Nebraska Press, which I have not written about before because I didn't want to worry you with it u ntil I had made a firm decision. Bower thought all along that I should try to find a commercial publisher, and now I shall. The people at the Nebraska Press are nice, and I really liked Miss Faulkner, but the reader's report followed the conventional line of the American literary scholars: everybody has to derive from Whitman and be influenced by Emerson and write like Ezra Pound. The reader's report helped me, though I didn't like the point of view; it gave me the advantage of seeing an attitude it is wise to anticipate, and in the revision I added a few blunt words about American scholarly criticism. I don't know who the reader was, but I don't think he saw what I was trying to do, and he read into my words a lot of things that weren't there. I took a while to make this decision because it wasn't one to make lightly. I think the Press will be willing to release me from the contract. This explanation is confidential to you, John; I don't want to seem to bicker with Mr. Nicoll or Virginia.</p> 
                
                <p>Your plans and excitements sound wonderful. Keep me informed about another Dick Cavett show; we can probably arrange repeats and special showings in Eugene, because you've got quite a following there. As I told you, Professor Earl Pomeroy had a special re-showing for his history classes.</p>
                
                <p>We are enjoying England; the time has gone quickly. We will be flying back on the 5th of September, to Boston first to see Susan and Stewart and your little great-grandson honorary, who is a replica of Stewart. I hoped that we would be able to stop off in Missouri or Nebraska to see you, but it looks as if we won't make it. Bower has business in Boston, and we have to make the opening of school deadline in Eugene. I would love to hear first hand about all the things you're doing, and about Neihardt Day. I got the letter from the committee just two days ago; our mail seems to travel around in a circle before it reaches us. It was too late to write or even to cable, but you know my spirit was hovering around what-ever was happening, floating in approval and joy for all good that comes to you. And since I can't get a report first hand, a letter is the next best thing. Write me all about it!</p>
                
                <p>I am sendi g Myrtle a letter also; she has been wonderful about giving me the news. You know how deep and constant is the love that flows your way from Bower and me. We thought about you on your annual day, and every other day.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very special love, all the way from England!!!!</salute> 
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>