<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
114a
1419 North Dearborn
Chicago, Illinois
July 11, 1942.
Dear Daddy, Mama, Amama,
<p>I was really very thrilled to get your letters and to hear that you are all happy together. Yourletters are a source of great encouragement, inspiration, and happiness to me - and I never lose the "goodness feeling" they always bring to me.</p>
<p>The weather here is really lovely - golden sunshine and crisp air. We have a lovely clean comfortable basement apartment and we've just had a twelve hour rest, so are</p>
(2)
<p>feeling a bit groggy <unclear/> gets used to sleeping little, and more sleep all of a sudden is too much for one. This air is bracing and exciting however - so we'll soon be our old selves again.</p>
<p>We left St. Louis Thursday, July 2<underline>nd</underline>. Daddy, I do <underline>so</underline> wish you had seen a performance such as suits us better. The difference between performing and performing is amazing - and we will show you what we mean next time you see us. Continuing with the original idea, we drove along chatting pleasantly for several hours till we reached Hillshore, where Doris Grandmother lives. There we spend several full hours of real pleasure, so highly reminiscent of days gone by - for me.</p>
114b
(3)
<p>Mr. and Mrs. Funk, Doris Grandfather and Grandmother, met us at the boulder tree at the rear end of their drive, and welcomed us warmly and sincerely. We first amused (and amazed) ourselves and them by picking quantites of delicious red raspberries, taking pictures of ourselves in old straw hats, and examining the green grapes which hung in clusters from an arbor such as our rose arbor at home. Mrs. Funk prepared a typically delicious Germanish country dinner for us which was topped off with berries (black and raspberry) and creamy and in mid-afternoon, ice cream, berries, and cake. After dinner, we played croquet to our hearts</p>
(4)
<p>content. Being in a <unclear/> mood, we played with well nigh muderous intent knocking the opponents ball out into the gutter upon each and every occasion where any such thing was possible. Honestly, we are growing younger in ways - as well as older in other ways. After repairing a tire (good it happened in Hillshoro) we left again for Springfield, arriving there at 8:30 in the evening - it was still light. Our immediate job was to find lodging and this we did discover, after much discouragent, in a tourist camp near the Gingham Gardens. We found much <sic>gayety</sic> in the answers we received for our questions - for everyone here seems a</p>
114c
(5)
<p>bit vague as to directions.<p/>
<p>Friday morning we found our Capital Tourist Camp and secured our adorable, large, two room cabin - Cabin No. 9. it was, furthermore, complete with meadow (a glorious one in six or eight shades of green, and bordered by sumac and tall elm trees. Its occupants were lovely too - several hippity hops (Hasenpfeffers we called them!) endless grasshoppers, adn countlesss lucious dewberries.) Besides this, we became the most talked of people in camp, and were a source of great amusement because of our odd hours, and habit of con-</p>
(6)
<p>tinually running back and forth to the wash house with dishes and clothes, soap and towels. Our cooking was great fun too, and we had swell meals. George is a veteran camper (was Eagle Scout, patrol leader etc.) and therefore a great help in camping duties! When we had any leisure, we went for walks barefoot in our meadow, picked berries, and sunned ourselves on the green green grass. Oh what beauty is everywhere - that meadow is only a small, small <underline>part</underline> of the beauty everywhere - and yet it is glorious - radiant in the sunlight, ghostly and enchanting under</p>
114d
(7)
<p>the moon, and <unclear>du</unclear> beyond words in the fog and crystal-cool air of dawning! There will be many more such meadows each beautiful beyond my poor power of description.</p>
<p>Now, to tell you of our work in Springfield. The Club there was very <underline>nice</underline> in every way. The floor was large and raised, with gooth lighting facilities (blue for Jungle) and the orchestra large. They had a hard time with our music at first, but gradually worked up to playing very nicely. The dressing rooms were large, clean, and comefortable, and we had no difficulty at all in making-up under these</p>
(8)
<p>cicumstances. Each night we found new thrills in performing and many <underline>many</underline> new opportunities for expression and general improvement in each of our dances. Between shows we rested and talked with George and our fellow performer, a magician from St. Louis by chance, or did barres with corrections by George. Sometimes we listened to the beat of raindrops on the roof of that solid old building, and studied the details of the several odd paintings, the cracked mirror on the bureau, the flicker of the neon lights outside our front window. This all sounds over-dramatic I'm quite sure, but this</p>
114e
(9)
<p>life of ours <underline>is</underline> dramatic. It is more so than I ever dreamed it could be. Life is so <underline>new</underline> so intense, so full of <unclear>gpsy</unclear> excitement, of hard work, of seriousness and of gaiety. We <underline>are living</underline> now and it is a great privilege. I quoted "April Theology" as we drove along yesterday - and it made vocal all that we were <underline>feeling</underline> so intensely.</p>   
<p>We had rehearsals nearly every day at the Club. George corrected our barres, which proceeded actual rehearsal of dances - and we find that he is an <underline>excellent</underline> teacher - as good fundamentally at least as any. His ideas correspond to</p>
(10)
<p>Madame's in the main part - and he has a special knack of making you work and do what he wishes. He is as exacting as a director as he is mild and pleasant as a person. That, too, is a <underline>real</underline> help - a real incentive to us in our work - classic as well as character. We are working up single numbers as soon as possible. I am going to use a lovely, not to well known waltz from France for my solo. George will furnish the costume but if you could get an idea for it, I will get the material <strike/> and have you make it - if you possibly had the time, Mama. It is</p>
114f
(11)
<p>a melancholy type of waltz, dreamy, soft. Therefore, the costume must be somethign soft, in blue or lavender, drapey, rather long. Can you suggest or create a design? I would do it on the point, and George will help arrange it. He says dancing alone is very good for us and of course its just what I need now! Please <sic>thing</sic> seriously of this Mama. I'll appreciate it greatly.</p>
<p>We were very well liked by the Manager at Club - everyone in fact was nice. And we got good hands too. We really felt sorry to leave our jbo there and our little</p>
(12)
<p>blue and white cabin too. We did go though, at 11:00 Friday morning. Had a deliciouly pleasant trip here to Chicago, as usual. Oh! Gypsy life! We'll be here about 6 days or so. Must get our new costumes for Sailor, for we'll do it <underline>and</underline> our modern plus old numbers on our next job. We'll rehearse too.</p>
<p>I'll close here, for Eddie came to take us swim. Everything's in an uproar!</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<p>So glad about your lamps! Best of everything to all of you dear ones.</p>