<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0001-5">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Elanita Frye to                , June 16, 1947</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0001-5</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Elanita Frye to                </title>
                    <date when="1947-06-16">June 16, 1947</date>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>5 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">23a</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">ELANITA FRYE
                        <lb/>
                    3621A CALIFORNIA AVE
                        <lb/>
                    ST. LOUIS 18, MO.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>June 16, 1947</dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear good friends&#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>An apology is in order for not letting you know sooner that the Chicago trip had been made much sooner than we had planned. It was this way: When I arrived at my home in Lockwood, I found my sister-in-law in the middle of her plans to visit her family in southern Wisconsin. Just like that she asked me to go along&#8212; and since it <hi rend="underline">isn't</hi> hard to push me into packing my toothbrush, I went along. Then I realized there would be a stop in Chicago, so.&#8212; then I was calling the offices of Dr. Snanely and Dr. Beatty on my return. The latter was gone and in his place I tlaked with a Mr. Danielson. He was very cordial but explained immediately that no more or promise could be made pending possible legislative action on the budget slash. He asked that I <unclear/>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0002"/>
                
                    later in July and he hoped a good answer could be given. Otherwise, if the slash was carried through, schools would be closed and those teachers transposed. &#8212; With Dr. Snanely I had an almost immediate interview on his office &#8212; He said&#8212; "Come <unclear>right</unclear> out"! I did&#8212;and I talked for Betty and the possibilities in her field. When Dr. Snavely heard I had just seen you people &#8212; I almost had to draw detailed pictures of all of you&#8212; He introduced me to two of his nurses although their names didn't stay with me. One was dark haired with a quick concise manners of speaking;- The other, quite heavy &#8212; <add>with</add> lighter complexion and a little friendlier attitude&#8212; Dr. Snavely took me down to Mrs. Frost's office- and I feel so glad and yet so humble when she heard I knew the Neihardt's. In my conversation with Dr. Snavely, I also asked him what opportuntiies there were for medical social work and he became interested in what my background was then. Boy, it was 
                
                    <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0003"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">23b</fw>
                    
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">ELANITA FRYE
                        <lb/>
                    3621A CALIFORNIA AVE
                        <lb/>
                    ST. LOUIS 18, MO.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                    fun talking and intended by his offering me a chance to help set up a social work unit for rehabilitating the Indian children in one of the hospitals! I was nearly floored. <del/>It all depends on Washington's humor and attitude. So, dear people, that is why it looks as if I "jumped the gun", but I feel I <hi rend="underline">couldn't</hi> pass up the opportunity of going in when I had a whole day in Chicago. It still appears that Betty + I will go up in August and we both are to go back for further discussions- Honestly, that is all we've really been discussing &#8212; even though we realize Betty's parents will not like the idea at once&#8212; They have always envisioned their last and yougnest girl in the nurse's white and surrounded by doctors- etc&#8212; but Betty can do a good job of selling ideas to her people &#8212; so by the time she finishes the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Public Health Course &#8212; the Savers will be "ready" too. She has written to <unclear>Univ.</unclear> Minnesota for bulletins.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0004"/> 
                
                <p>With this great idea before me, I didn't <unclear>want</unclear> to tie myself down too closely on a job, so I did something totally out of my experience. I've signed up to sell World Book Encyclopedias!! Maybe I'm sticking my neck out, but after today's first session on selling tactics, I think it will prove very interesting. It will bring me adequate income and still allow me much personal time and freedom.&#8212;</p>
                
                <p>Alice, dear&#8212; how much are the pictures- It was so thoughful of you to send them to us. Not all of our rolls are developed yet but if we have any good ones &#8212; will send them.</p>
                
                <p>You know, I didn't realize it until it was too late, but my train from Chicago to Janesville, Wisconsin, stopped for a few minutes at Gray's lab&#8212; I fairly jumped when I saw the name!!&#812;</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Neihardt, I wish there was a better way to say thank-you for yoru interest and good wishes and especially for your letters to Chicago. If and when these plans materialize I know they will be due to a large degree to your <unclear>backing</unclear>.
                    <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                    Seeing you dear people again was the "life I needed&#8212; the reassurance that ideals and dreams
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.21.23a-23c_0005"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">23c</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">ELANITA FRYE
                        <lb/>
                    3621A CALIFORNIA AVE
                        <lb/>
                    ST. LOUIS 18, MO.</hi>
                </fw>
                    
                    <hi rend="underline">are</hi> worthwhile and that persons are interested.</p>
                
                <p>I hope Dawn finds her sitation in Springfield not too disagreeable. It won't last too long.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>With love to all of you&#8212;</salute>
                    <signed>Elanita&#8212;</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi>&#8212;</opener>
                    <p>Alice, how is little "Shim" denis?&#8212;</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
