<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
50h
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
March 9, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I wrote you a card last night and mailed it this morning at 6:45 when I went out into the cool, dark morning on my way to work. Now I shall tell you all about things as they existsions our present life. First of all I have a job at the Hamilton Hotel, as a waitress in the Coffee Shoppe there. My <hi rend="underline">salary</hi> is $50 per month ($25 each 2 wks.), <hi rend="underline">but</hi> I get all my meals, <hi rend="underline">and</hi> a minimum of $1.00 tips per day. So you can see I get around the equivalent of twice my salary. I shall tell you how I happened to get this job, just a little later!</p>
<p>We <hi rend="underline">are</hi> happy, weather is lovely, and the Light <hi rend="underline">is</hi> being shown us.</p>
<p>Next, and of quite some importance to us, are several</p>
(2)
<p>engagements we are already contracted for (single night) for they may lead to several weeks work during our waiting period. This Saturday we are to dance at Fort McIntosh in the large theatre there, for some sort of army entertainment affair. This too came about very strangely, as I shall tell you. Besides this Saturday’s engagement, we have one (possibly two) for the next week. Then, if this is successful, we may have more chances, enkind I shall tell you of <hi rend="underline">when</hi> they come about.</p>
<p>It all came about like this" I was almost frantic for awhile because I could get no job and we had <hi rend="underline">no</hi> news of our papers. Then one evening I felt intensely like praying. I mentioned going to the little Catholic Chapel, and Doris told me she'd just been thinking of it, so we went together to pray. I wrote you of that</p>
50i
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>evening, didn't I? We prayed strongly and unusually <hi rend="underline">unbelievingly</hi>, which is the only way one can actually pray. Over and over "<hi rend="underline">Show us the Light</hi>" - these words blended with the chant of the nuns. Then, after all had felt the scene of the altar, the blue lights, and the candles, we went into the garden to feel the Goodness and the <hi rend="underline">Something Moving</hi> there. Somehow a new Strength crept into me - and I felt better inside. The next day, I waited for calls till mid-afternoon, wrote you, etc. Then, about 3:30 I happened to glance into the Laredo Tunes, saw an ad there for two waitresses at King Cole's Chicken House, a place some miles out of town, and decided to try to "land that job. As I stood on the corner waiting my bus, a</p>
(4)
<p>familiar personage approach me from across the street. It was a Sergeant Ryser, who is very important here at Fort McIntosh, and whom I had met several days previously while inquiring at the gate of the Fort about where abouts of the Gunnery School. You see I'd been told I might get a job there, and was misdirected to the Fort. The Ser. was dining out of camp at that very minute, and when he heard what I wanted, told me he'd he glad it I'd ride into Laredo with him and two of his co-officers who were also in the car. I did so, declining at the same time an invitation to have coffee with him. Now, to come back to my</p>
50j
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>original story, Bob "(for I've since learned that that is <hi rend="underline">also</hi> his name!) said casually, in a Gary Cooper sort of way "Why are you looking so sad?" I lied, "I'm just waiting for my bus." "Where are you going?" was the instant answer. "Oh, somewhere in the Heights" I said non-comititally. "Where?" he insisted. "3300 San Bernardo "I finally admitted. So, before I knew it, I had accepted a ride again from the Sergeant. "I hope you really <hi rend="underline">are</hi> going out there for yourself" I said. "I don't want to inconvenience you." "How Do you know I don’t <hi rend="underline">want</hi></p>
(6)
<p>to be inconvenience I was the only answer to go. SO we drove to 3300. "Where do you want to go now?" he asked. So I admitted finally that I was <hi rend="underline">also</hi> going to King Cole's, where he had told me <hi rend="underline">he</hi> way going "for coffee." "I thought so," he remarked. "Well, you are with the right person if you want the job, but you must tell me first if you really want it." To make a longer incident shorter, one word got me the job, from a nice American gentleman who is the <sic>manageral</sic> said cafe. We drank coffee together and then returned to town in Bob's delux cream colored Packard convertible! He took me home, but not before he'd promised to find out about an engagement for us at Camp. I dashed upstairs burst in our room, and was</p>
50K
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>greeted by Sylvia and Doris, who said <sic>eicitedly</sic> "Alice, you have a job" "I <hi rend="underline">know</hi>" I said "No, - at the Hamilton" they insisted, "Call there at once - and report at 7:00 tomorrow morning for work." So I had <hi rend="underline">two</hi> jobs! I was wondering what to do when the Ser. called. I told him, and he said he'd bring the Lieutenant in charge of Saturdays ceremonies to see George, and would take me out to tell the owner of King Cole's I couldn't take his job. We rode there, all of us, and, said manager, being owner of a Nite Club here, the "Victory", became interested in our act. Now we are to perform there a week hence, and more if that</p>
(8)
<p>succeeds financially. George rehearsed the orchestra and is quite happy over all. He does mean the best and I believe we can hold on now - all of us together. So we again come about Something Good - by mere chance?</p>
<p>People are interesting. My new work brings me into contact with may - it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> work, but under nice conditions, and among the best of people - officers, high class ladies, gentleman and children. My new king, Ser. Ryser, is very fine, for he is <hi rend="underline">real</hi>. Loves adventure - went to so American, Portugal, Africa as a kid of <hi rend="underline">16</hi>, has been in army 10 yrs. since then. Would like to brake a career of it for life, but an accident several years ago prevents</p>
50L
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>his passing physical exams for what he wants. Therefore, he plans to go to Buenos Aires after the war, where he will accept a job from his Uncle, owner of a large transport co. there. HE is a native of Oklahoma, speaks with Western twenty, has a bit the manner of Gary Cooper, but is much more handsome. <hi rend="underline">Whew is</hi> he handsome! Just can't help thinking what a perfect cowboy he'd make. (He loves wild country but prefers a car to a horse) About 6 ft., slim, strong, medium-dark, with sad, restless, eyes. He says he is very blue, wants to travel, to get away form here. That ("wandering) is his only unconquerable "vice," he says.</p>
(10)
<p><hi rend="underline">Many</hi> others here are interesting people, about whom I shall some day tell you. The Mexicans are strong nice, but <hi rend="underline">so</hi> different. We know how to keep them respectful of us - but oh! the catlikeness, yet extreme emotional sin of this Latin, dark-eyed race! The <hi rend="underline">real</hi> Spanish are <hi rend="underline">also</hi> like that; it is <hi rend="underline">not</hi> the influence of the Indian blood. Their ideas are <hi rend="underline">not</hi> what ours are in countless ways. We have several very attentive friends of this race who desire reality to place us, and whom we keep at a safe distance. No, they are not forceful, they are <hi rend="underline">pleading</hi> - how different from the Texan type! They are no more familiar than you allow them to be - and have many <hi rend="underline">good</hi> attribute, too.</p>
<p>Now I've told you most of our recent life. We practice</p>
50m
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>every day besides to keep up our work as best we can.</p>
<p>I'm not heavy either, as I was when I was home! I've been eating little, and hardly anything fattening. I don't even like such things - except ice cream! I can have all I want now - but I'm not eating a lot. I eat only two meals, fruit, and milk. My feet are sore from walking and running around 8 hrs. each day, but the low heels are lengthening my front-of-ankle tendons, which will help my plie! Some Good in Everything.</p>
<p>Is Hil in Chicago now? I shall write here at Seymour's Dear Girl! She will succeed now - at last she had <hi rend="underline">her</hi> chance.</p>
<p>How do you like your job, Mama? Daddy, how are you feeling now? <hi rend="underline">Much much</hi></p>
(12)
<p>better I'm sure. What you mention of possibility for Nebraska job sounds marvelous. How grand that could be.</p>
<p>Dear ones, you can see I am doing all I can, am I not? Please tell me what you think of this. Perhaps we'll hear <hi rend="underline">soon</hi> about our papers, too.</p>
<p>Give my love to Eny and Ollie and Nei, and tell them I do love them. Tell them to drop a card when they can.</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alice
