<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.37a.7-8">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Liz Ortradovsky to John G. Neihardt, J.D. and Myrtle Young, April 25, 1973</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.37a.7-8</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Liz Ortradovsky to John G. Neihardt, J.D. and Myrtle Young</title>
                    <date when="1973-04-25">April 25, 1973</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, Young, Julius D. and Myrtle</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.7"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">7</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <note type="curatorial">822 <hi rend="caps">F.</hi> Delaware
                        Grand Island <unclear/> 68801</note>
                        April 25th, 1973
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Gaki, Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi>,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Thank you so much for the card and the news of Gaki's doings. I will be looking forward to the records as they are released as I know many others will.</p>
                
                <p>I missed the April 23rd broadcast because on that day I spent nine hours in the paddle and covered about 25 miles. It was my first time out in months &#8212; because of the weather. Needless to say when I got home I was more than a little tired... to the extent that I was in bed by 9<hi rend="caps">PM</hi>. As if Monday's ride weren't enough, I spent another 2 hours rounding up about the 40 horses out of a 160 acre field so they could be brought back to Ross' farm for a few days until we check fence and provide water for the summer pasture.</p>
                
                <p>I did see the broadcast last night and was delighted with it. Robert Knoll was my instructor in Shakespeare at the university both on an undergraduate and graduate level.</p>
                
                <p>I wish I could be in Lincoln to hear Gaki tomorrow at the Student Union; however, if the weather is nice we're scheduled to take 160 rods of fence down so corn can be planted where the horses had been.</p>
                
                <p>May 2nd for us is a day we've looked forward to. With luck and good weather Nadine and I will be canoeing down the Platte River. The channel we've chosen will take us about 8 miles downstream &#8212; we are guessing that it will take us about 4 hours.</p>
                
                <p>I should report that I sent a tape recording of "Black Elk's Prayer", a copy of the sheet music to it, the first news article with the photo of Gaki, Nadine, Jocks<!--Jacques?--> and me, the news article about Ben's funeral, and a photo of Gaki and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi> taken at 
                
                <fw>1</fw> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.8"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">8</fw>
                
                    Hastings last October &#8212; to Dick Cavett. All of this was sent airmail to <hi rend="caps">ABC-TV</hi> to an address given to me by his secretary. I mailed it from here April 9th. In an accompanying letter I told Dick that Gaki and Hilda had given permission for the Prayer to be recorded or published and that Hilda would draw up the necessary legal agreements if he felt the music had enough merit to match the beautiful words. So far I have not heard anything &#8212; but rest assured that when and if I do I will let you know right away.</p> 
                
                <p>This Saturday is to be a big day at Red Cloud when Willa Cather's home is to be dedicated a national historic monument. Plans are tentative now that we may attend. If so I understand that it's just a short drive from there to Kansas &#8212; where Coors beer is available. I will see what I can do.</p>
                
                <p>Our plans for the summer call for our family to spend two weeks in New Mexico &#8212; some of that time to be spent at the Philmont Boy Scout Ranch where Fred will attend a training session. The rest of the time will be spent near by in the mountains at the cabin of some friends of ours.</p>
                
                <p>Cathy &#8212; our 12 year old has achieved a dream &#8212; her horse now has a cart to pull and our entire neighborhood has great fun when she brings him to town. She has even trained Miranda's little Shetland to pull the cart. Randy &#8212; at eight is still a bit young to take her pony out alone with the cart but seems delighted at the prospect later on.</p> 
                
                <p>We saw the sandhill cranes along the Platte and this year I was especially eager to photograph them with a new Leicaflex <hi rend="caps">SL</hi> camera and a telephoto zoom lens that goes up to 230 mm. I talked with a newspaper man who spent 7 hours hidden in a box in a grove of trees. He crawled into it at 5:30 <hi rend="caps">AM</hi> and got his first photo at 12:30 <hi rend="caps">PM</hi>. So far I haven't had that kind of time to spend. Courage and strength to you all.</p> <closer><salute>As ever,</salute> <signed>Liz <note type="curatorial">(Otradovsky)</note></signed></closer>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
