<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
51 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 1
'43
4920 Blackstone Ave, Chicago.
Dearest Joanie:
<p>You will be glad to Know that Gaki and Nanny are in Chicago, right across the street from Seymours, where aunt Hilda is staying.</p>
<p>Amama is here too with us, and we are very happy indeed, because we are together, adn because Gaki has such a very fine job with "Esquire" a very interesting magazine. Mama and Daddy will show you this magazine some time, and if it is good you can be proud because your Gaki made it so, if on the other hand it is bad or ugly, you can know that that is so because your Gaki has not yet been with the editors long enough to help them make it good and wise and beautiful.</p>
<p>I am so proud and happy that your Daddy has such a very good job, and that he is so well liked. He will always be so. Nanny quit her reading job in St. Louis, and everyone there was sorry she was leaving, because they said they never had as good a reader in their shop - and besides no one else had</p>
2
<p>any time you are sick
I will take care
of you you</p>
<p>ever been able to get along peacefully with the proofreaders <strike/> whom she was assisting.</p>
<p>You will be glad to know that is so, and you Daddy and Mama will be glad also. We are going to try to get out some of Gaki's poems on cards now, as Chicago is such a good city for that purpose, and Nanny has always wanted to do that. I have a pretty idea for the little "Prayer", and when I have it all worked out, I'll send it to you to hang up in your room.</p>
<p>Amama sends you loads of kisses. Aunt Hilda is in St Louis staying in the room there, where Gaki and Nanny were living, before they came here. Because Albert was so lonesome for her, he wanted her to remain a bit. She is returning to Chicago tomorrow however, to resume her singing lessons etc. She is going to sing for the <uclear>Boefellows</uclear> tea on May 26th, which is Nanny's birthday.</p>
<p>I love you my darling, and please Kiss Daddy and Mama and 'Laine for me.</p>
Devotedly Yours,
Nanny.