<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
1
Tempe - 01-01-71
Dear Dr. Neihardt - Flaming Rainbow! 
How Kola>! - It is too long since I have greeted you. A letter has been on my mind &amp; your address on my work table since October. Surgery for myself &amp; three deaths in the family have delayed me. Even now there is not time for the type of letter I would prefer to send, but, I can not let the holiday season 
(over) 

2
ORIGINAL PAINTING BY CHARLES M. RUSSELL
PUBLISHED IN USA BY THE LEANIN' TREE, BOULDER, COLORADO 
21
pass without at least wishing you a "Happy New Year" (of course it should be properly "toasted" &amp; a fine place would have been the place Russell depicts here on)
I have had reports of your activities up to July 1970 - through "The Foundation", Herman Chilson, and news chips sent by friends in South Dakota etc. 
Of course - your current book - is still being looked foreward to with patience 
-cont'd-
<figure>SALOON 1920</figure>

for I know that you have so very much to "remember". Also, I suppose your propensity for "living" every day "now" tends to slow up the completion of the books (I should say books &amp; for I understand it is running to two volumes at least) 
At long last - Leonard Jennewein's daughter has completed a through survey of her fathers notes and tapes and has reported to me - unfortunately the result as far as

2

we are concerned is negative 
So, we ^still do not know what he wanted to tell me about the printings and Murthly Castle in Scotland (you may recall I sent you pictures of the paintings - which were taken by Jennewin - they appear to be Miller's painted for Sir Wm <sic>Durmond</sic><corr>Drummond</corr> Stewart)
Two more Neihardt's added to my library - at last "When the Tree Flowered"; also "The Splendid Wayfaring"

3

RUEBEN H. NELSON 
10 E. ELLIS DR. 
TEMPE, ARIZ. 
85281 
PHOENIX. AZ 
PM 
4 JAN 
2B 
1971 
GIVE TO MARCH OF DIMES 
<unclear/> Christmas 6 U.S. 
5 
71
Mr. John G. Neihardt 
5835 - Vine Street 
Lincoln 
Nebraska 68505
(Mr. & Mrs. Julius D. Young 