<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.22.17-20">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, November 13, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.22.17-20</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1958-11-13">November 13, 1958</date>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>McCurdy, Francis L.</term>
<term>Durrin, Bill</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
<term>Robin</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; Validation</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0001b" />
                <note type="curatorial">26-4</note>
                
                
             <opener>   
                
                <dateline>Skyrim, Thurs., 11-13-'58</dateline>
                
                
                
                <salute>Dear Lucile:</salute>
             </opener>
                <p>As I wrote you, Dr. McCurdy brought me the bound copy of the dissertation on Tuesday, Nov. 11. I have been reading it pretty steadily ever since, except when I was illuminating the airways with dazzling pictures of myself!! Late last night I awoke, and it struck me suddenly that <hi rend="underline">you</hi> may have been expected a letter from <hi rend="underline">me</hi> about the dissertation, thinking that I must have received it several weeks ago. If this was the case, I must have seemed curiously unappreciative!</p>
               
                <p><hi rend="underline">Of course I like it</hi>! I'm human and eager to be thought well of, and you give a gratifying
                    <fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0001a"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    account of my efforts and achievements over a long period of years. Of course, <hi rend="italic">I</hi> like it; but that would be far from enough to satisfy me. On the contrary, often while reading I've felt a momentary sinking of the heart and something like shame until I became aware again that you were carefully documenting every statement, albeit with <del/> notable warm-hearted goodwill. (And is not goodwill <del/> a prime essential in criticism?)</p>
                
                <p>So that phase of my <hi rend="underline">liking</hi> is taken care of, and I can talk about 
                    <hi rend="underline">your</hi> work, not <hi rend="underline">my</hi> feeling, altho' it is hard to separate the two.
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0002a"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                    
                    My impersonal appreciation of what you have done (insofar as I'm able to be impersonal) falls under four heads. I'm greatly impressed (1) with the ingenuity and persistence shown in the collection of heterogeneous data over wide areas in space and time. (As old Prof. Durrin said to me once, 'I don't see how you do it!') It's really most remarkable. You have turned up incidents and sayings that I have quite forgotten, and you have the proof. You have have made dead years come alive for me &#8212; years that I would never have recalled but for you,
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0002b"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                    
                    and there is meaning in them.</p>
                
                <p>I'm as greatly impressed (2) with the way you have evaluated the data, (3) organized the scrambled material <del/> into significant pattern, and (4) presented in writing the pattern with its <hi rend="underline">emergent meaning</hi>. Surely the above <hi rend="underline">is</hi> an impersonal judgement. It's a bully job, excellent on all four counts. But it goes farther when certain considerable positions are regarded as <hi rend="underline">essays</hi>. Your discussions of my criticism, my social, political, aesthetic, <del/> philosophical, and religious attitudes really <hi rend="underline">get under</hi> 
                    <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0003b"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>           <note>11-13<unclear/></note>
                    
                    and come up with illumination. Often I feel 'she's writing like a house on fire', to use an expression once aimed at me by a hopeful friend! Damned good writing in extended spots when the opportunity offered!</p> 
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">And</hi>, as you and I have agreed, <hi rend="underline">you are growing</hi>. (Anyone who does a big job without  growing <hi rend="underline">hasn't done</hi> a big job). I hope 
                    <hi rend="underline">I'm</hi> growing and believe I am &#8212; but not towards worldy goals, I suspect. You must be weary after the long, hard
                    <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.4c.22.17-20_0003a"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    pull with the dissertation, but you should feel quite happy about it. I could easily understand if you were weary enough to hesitate in beginning the biography. It must not be a burden or seem in any way an obligation. But if you do go ahead with the extended dream, you will be released into a wider<add>, freer</add> realm of 
                    <hi rend="underline">story</hi>, <hi rend="underline">human</hi> story.</p>
                
                <p>So many times in the dissertation you <del/> make <hi rend="underline">brief passing</hi> references to 
                    <hi rend="underline">vital incidents</hi> by way of supporting a statement.
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0004a"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    In a biography such incidents would expand into living episodes with <hi rend="underline">story</hi> appeal; and you, as <del/> an understanding human being would be able to present them creatively as living truth beyond the fact. Anyway, Lucile,  bless you and yours &#8212; and thanks for being alive!</p>
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">Bower, hello</hi>! I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> wish you I could have an honest-to-goodness pow-wow together sometime. I do not cease to feel
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.22.17-20_0004b"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                    
                    gratitude for your faith in the best of me &#8212; and affection too.</p>
                <closer>
                <signed>John N.</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript><p>Stewart, I passed your advice on to Robin, and if that show comes to our town, we'll be there to see.</p></postscript>
              
              <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>