<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0001-10">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Rosalind M. Kolb to John G. Neihardt, November 29, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0001-10</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Rosalind M. Kolb to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-11-29">November 29, 1958</date>
                    <extent>8 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">64</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        State Hospital
                        Fulton, Missouri
                        November 29, 1958.
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John Neidhardt<sic>Neihardt</sic>, Poet</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Instructor, Missouri <hi rend="caps">U.</hi></addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neidhardt<sic>Neihardt</sic>:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It's been weeks now since we heard you on television and I'm wondering why you quit telecasting &#8212; whether you are ill, or what?</p>
                
                <p>Three of us on our ward listened to your telecast (maybe more) and, I believe, two of those have already written to you &#8212; Lucille Richeson and Lucille Wolf. I've been wanting to write all along but my varied interests and varied efforts along several lines keep me very busy and always too much behind in my correspondence.</p>
                
                <p>I was, of course, listening to
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0002"/>
                    
                    you mostly for curiosity's sake and for enlightenment and not for credit &#8212; but I felt exhilarated while listening to your reading of this poetry on Epic America: your kind, intelligent sweet face, your pleasant voice and clear enunciation, your sense of humor and your ability to inspire your listeners with a very healthy philosophy of life, gave me a "lift."</p>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
                <p>I am a teacher by profession; I've had two years of college at Warrensburg State College (1926-32) and hold a 60-hour life certificate, issued the last term such a certificate was offered. I taught for four years in two rural schools in our state when I was 17-22 years of age. My nurse sister took me to a doctor in St. 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0003"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">65</fw>
                
                    Louis when I was 18 (which I think now she shouldn't have done) and to a <hi rend="underline">different</hi> doctor when I was 22 (which I think was even worse) and, between the three of them, I feel they got my life and affairs so mixed up that I was caused to give up my last school during the last month of school to go to a tuberculosis sanatorium in Springfield, Ill. (a private San).</p>
                
                <p>I wish now I hadn't been taken away from my teaching <add>(I wish I hadn't given up my school)</add> as I never got back to it: it seems as though there are many forces in the world that work against one but too few that work for good. I have concluded, after a life of physical and mental suffering, of privation, and of seemingly fruitless struggle, that
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68-0004"/>
                    
                    "Better Schools" can, and must<unclear>,</unclear> be the answer for a better life for all and for an eventual effective (we hope) solution to the <add>world's and</add> life's problems. Let's prepare (plan) school curricula that will really prepare young people for a good, purposeful, meaningful <hi rend="underline">Christian</hi> life of service and hard work that will also prepare these same young people to endure, without complaint, sickness and suffering and hardship and the inevitable death. I think general religion and (to my mind) the gospel of Jesus Christ cannot be kept out of children's lives without detriment to our society, and I think schools, homes and churches must do much more along the line of religion and the teaching of the Ten Commandments and of a good sound 
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0005"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66</fw>
                
                    Christian ethic and Christian morals and manners if we expect our good American way of life to survive.</p>
                
                <p>I claim it was lack of Christian sympathy and understanding for me when I was teaching and a lack of understanding of my needs (by my nurse sister, mostly, and perhaps others) that caused me to develop the emotional illness which later caused me to become a patient here at this hospital where I now am. I think all this could, and should, have been avoided. I think, above all, that all children in the grade and high schools should be taught courses in psychology with the purpose in mind of getting all children and adolescents to develop a healthy attitude toward life and toward all people, and 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0006"/>
                
                    a proper understanding of such other's needs and of our duties toward one another <add>and of our duty under God, to forgive one another's faults and mistakes which I feel I haven't always done.</add> I sincerely believe that getting the proper medical and nursing care for <hi rend="underline">all</hi> individuals of all ages would go far in solving the nation's and the world's problems. Just each and every one of us taking sufficient and <hi rend="underline">proper</hi> interest in every one of our relatives and "neighbors" (every one in need) is what is needed <add>&#8212; to make everyone's life turns out right.</add></p>
                
                <p>I thank you for undertaking to offer this course on television and I pray that it may be with you, and with all of us, according to God's will. May God bless you and yours!</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>(Miss) Rosaline M. Kolb.
                    (State Hospital patient)</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0007"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">67</fw>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener>
                        Post Script &#8212; <dateline>November 30.</dateline>
                    </opener>
                    <p>I don't want you to <add>mis</add>understand what I said about medical and nursing care. I do not claim to know the correct answers to the problem of correct medical and nursing care for anyone or for all. But I do feel that common sense in everything needs to be used more often. And I think children need to be taught to express themselves and their feelings more openly than some do &#8212; I mean they should be helped to overcome their timidity when it is too outstandingly obvious <add>and to protect their own interests.</add> And I believe and think, after my own experience with illness, that all people, young and old, should be helped to stay on their feet, whenever at all possible, and at
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0008"/>
                        
                        their jobs. Just a meting out of human sympathy and understanding and kind words and a felicitous sound philosophy of life to the sick can do wonders, I imagine, in keeping people on their feet.</p>
                    
                    <p>I believe, too, that each individual's own personality (and his ideas and wishes) should be respected at all times and I think any individual (even those who are seemingly not very bright) should have a large voice at all times in decisions made concerning him and his routine and and care and destiny. For example, I think that if an individual wants medical care he should have it and if he doesn't want it he shouldn't be expected to accept it.</p>
                    <closer>
                        <signed>R. Kolb</signed>
                    </closer>
                </postscript>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.64-68_0009"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    St. Hosp. #1
                    Fulton, Mo.
                </ab>
                
                <note type="recipient">
                    ansd
                    12-3-'58
                </note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    FULTON
                    DEC-1'58
                    MO.
                
                    P.B. METER
                    165793
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp stamped onto envelope</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE
                    04</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John Neihardt, Poet</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Instructor, Missouri University</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>Columbia</addrLine>
                                    <addrLine>Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">68</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.64-68_0010"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Rosalind <hi rend="caps">M.</hi> Kolb
                    State Hospital No. 1
                    Fulton, Missouri
                </ab>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
