<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
30l
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
February 10, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>i was really happier than you can know to receive those wonderful letters with the fine news therein. It is marvelous of you to help so Daddy - and it certainly was a complete surprise to hear what you had done, for I had no idea what <hi rend="underline">could</hi> be done. Thanks again for all your trouble - and your genuine interest; somehow such things <hi rend="underline">always</hi> surprise me. Of course, coming from you, they really do not. No, we do <hi rend="underline">not</hi> have George's papers nor his Grandmother's as yet - and no one knows how long it will be till they can come. With Senator Truman's aid, they</p>
(2)
<p>should be hurried up, but even <hi rend="underline">so</hi>, it may be several more weeks. had we only <hi rend="underline">realized</hi>, or had any official in Chicago <hi rend="underline">told</hi> George how long this would take, we wouldn't have closed at Colosimo's so soon, but such is life. And we'll get over it! What ever comes, we'll make out somehow. The help you gave may make <hi rend="underline">all</hi> the difference for us in being able to go to Mexico City <hi rend="underline">at all</hi>. Now, here are our plans for the present: We shall remain here about two more weeks at the least. In that time we shall dance at as many affairs as possible to make a bit of money. During that time, George will hear from new Orleans, and if an engagement <hi rend="underline">can</hi></p>
<p place="margin">George has told me several times to thank you for all your trouble and help, Daddy! Mama, you can send the costume here! How <hi rend="underline">lovely</hi> of you!</p>
30m
(3)
<p>Tell Hil I am rejoicing for her!</p>
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>be had there soon, we shall go there at the stated time. Perhaps by then the papers will have arrived, and our transportation to Mexico City (as already promised by Valencia) will be paid from New Orleans. We will meanwhile stay here in Laredo, rehearsing, and performing at several affairs here. I am enclosing a clipping concerning our first engagement this Saturday night. Pray for us that we may have more!</p>
<p>So much for that! It is cooler here today. Lovely sunshine, nevertheless - and blue tropical sky. Last night the stars were like diamonds</p>
(4)
<p>set in the "royal robe of night". I felt like taking a long walk with you, Daddy, the way we used to do. So very often those wonderful memories come back to me and I think of what you used to say "Some day you shall <hi rend="underline">rejoice</hi> to <hi rend="underline">remember</hi>!"</p>
<p>We are working now on a brand new number, the Idol Dance. We have finished "Frankie and <unclear/>" at last - and though we <unclear/> it is interesting. Now we are working - just beginning the Idol Dance - and it shall be <hi rend="underline">very</hi> interesting. "Capriccio Espagnol" we shall do sometime - when we get it costumed' and of course I am looking forward to that!</p>
<p>Please write me here. <hi rend="underline">So</hi> glad you are better, Daddy!</p>
Loads of Love
Alicia