<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.37-38_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Norman J. Smith to John G. Neihardt, December 7, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.37-38_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Norman J. Smith to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-12-07">December 7, 1957</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus hand-written envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.37-38_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        2421 Coronado Ave.
                        Great Bend, Kas.
                
                        Sat. Dec. 7, 1957
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Doctor Niehardt<sic>Neihardt</sic>:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>At the end of a long letter writing session -- letters to various friends and relatives -- you have popped into my thoughts, as you often do, so I thought I might sieze<sic>seize</sic> the opportunity to type you a note. I know you must get many from former students, and I hope they are a source of gratification to you. May I add my letter now, to this week's pile.</p>
                
                <p>Since leaving the university, I have been mostly in the broad-casting business, and this letter comes from Great Bend, Kas. because I have a job here, as announcer, at the local <hi rend="caps">TV</hi> station. Although I am obviously not yet a g<del>e</del><add>r</add>eat big success in my chosen profession, I enjoy it. May I say that much of my personal enjoyment of the job or anything else is still captured by use of the methods that you and certain other professors were kind enough to direct me to during college days.</p>
                
                <p>You may remember me as the young man <del>e</del><add>w</add>ho visited your home one Sunday afternoon in the autumn of 1955, with his wife and son<del/> and another couple. Our visit there is still a lasting and living force in the minds of my wife and <del>I</del><add>me</add>.... We now have a d<del>ua</del><add>au</add>ghter as well the son you saw, and you will be happy to know that both seem to be growing up very normally. By 'normal' I naturally do not mean mediocre.</p>
                
                <p>Lately, since coming to Great Bend something like a month ago I have been on a sustained reading kick. My opportunity for reading and contemplation is greatly expanded here since my working hours are from 4:30<hi rend="caps">PM</hi> until midn<del/><add>i</add>ght, and I find reading good books in the quiet solitude of the late hours a most excellent way to relax after work. I think I will cap it shortly by getting out and re-reading <hi rend="underline"><del>c</del><add>C</add>ycle <del>o</del><add>O</add>f <del>t</del><add>T</add>he West.</hi> I have often meant to find and read some of your other books but, shamefully, never have. I think I would probably get a boot out of the one about y<del>l</del><add>o</add>ur Missippi<sic>Mississippi</sic> voyage. But I am an inconstant reader; my late literary adventures are uncharacteristic. How<del>l</del><add>e</add>ver, I try to excuse myself by recalling a compliment from my idol, Dr. Donald Hodges of the <hi rend="caps">M.U.</hi> philosophy department, who said that I have 'good intuitions', even though I do not read very much. And honestly, I know so many people who read all the <del>b</del><add>g</add>ood books but who still have a sad perspective to life. As I remarked to Doctor Peden the other day (is he back at <hi rend="caps">M.U.</hi>?) in a letter, I do not feel completely gratified by the books I have been reading because there is such a wide disparity between the realtively crude and in-sensitive business world in which I must now live, and the world of ideas and formalized emotions of the artist. I have the one and I want the other. It was different when I was leading the cloistered life of a student. Reading was more enjoyable and profitable then.
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.37-38_0002"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">2</fw>
                
                    But don't worry. I do not mean that I will completely give in to the life of making money, and sacrifice all claim to aesthetic pleasure or the exhilaration of abstract contemplation. My goal at this still unbridled age and stage is <add>to</add> succeed in both.</p>
                
                <p>The reason I wrote Dr. Peden was to ask him the name of an honest literary agent because I have certain writings that I consider publishable. He always urged against literary agents, even honest oenes, when I was in his classes. He said we didn't need them. But since money is not my goal in getting published, I thought perhaps an agent could at least get my material read by the publisher, who might ignore it if it came from me..... But perhaps Dr. Peden has not returned to the University. Do <hi rend="underline">you</hi> know a reliable agent?</p>
                
                <p>Well, Doctor, in closing may I again express my affection for you as a well remembered friend. And my gratitude as well. Give my regards to your charming wife. I hope you both continue in good health and happiness.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours sincerely,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Norman J. Smith</signed>
                
                    <signed>Norman J. Smith</signed>
                    <add>
                        <address>
                            <addrLine>[2421 Coronado Ave.</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Great Bend, Kan]</addrLine>
                        </address>
                    </add>
                </closer>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.37-38_0003"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">N.J.</hi> Smith
                    2421 Coronado Ave.
                    Great Bend, Kas.
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">38</fw>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    GREAT BEND
                    DEC 9
                    230PM
                    1957
                    KANS.
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢ IN GOD WE TRUST LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>English Dept.</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Missouri</addrLine>
                        <addrLine><del/>Columbia,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

