<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.28a.12-14">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Robert and Adele Leaf to John G. Neihardt, August 2, 1960</title>
<author>Leaf, Robert</author>
<author>Leaf, Adele</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.28a.12-14</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Leaf, Robert</author>
<author>Leaf, Adele</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Robert and Adele Leaf to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1960-08-02">August 2, 1960</date>
<extent>4 pages, plus envelope</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>4 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Scarsdale (N.Y.)</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term type="Neihardt">A Cycle of the West</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Leaf, Robert</persName>
<persName>Leaf, Adele</persName>
<placeName>New York (N.Y.)</placeName>
<date when="1960-08-02"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name>Weakly, Laura K.</name> transcribed and encoded</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<note type="curatorial">12</note>

<opener><dateline>Tuesday<lb/>
August 2</dateline>

<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt -</salute></opener>

<p>Bob and I were truly so delighted to return home after a weekend away and find your beautiful letter awaiting us. I was so excited that at the first opportunity today I am writing, which at this moment is the waiting room of my dentist!</p>

<p>We were so glad to hear from you since it had been so long -- mainly our fault since we are both terrible correspondents. But it is good to hear that you are healthy and happy.</p>

<p>Am I jealous of you though! Since I married Bob, I can count on one hand the number of times I've been in the saddle. With the demand of working in an office and the further

<pb/>
<fw>2</fw>

requirements of housekeeping etc., it is very seldom that I find the energy or time to spend a day at my stable in New Jersey. And I do miss Sgt. Gannon (the very fine trainer whom I mentioned when we visited) and the horses so much. What a lovely life to follow those animals around a circuit at which they show their best and are most appreciated! But it was either Bob or a horse and over the long pull Bob ran out front!</p>

<p>I do hope your daughter and her family are all well. We spent such a pleasant afternoon with all of you at Columbia and we think of it often. I do wish we could go to Columbia again, but neither funds nor time permits.</p>

<p>Bob has been working very hard this past year

<pb/>
<fw>3</fw>
<note type="curatorial">13</note>

<unclear reason="fold">he</unclear> has really established himself in his public relations firm and would represent quite a loss to them if he left. He has tremendous organizing and administrative abilities, and little by little he is applying these abilities. Most important, he is extremely happy with his business associated.<del/></p>

<p>We just ended a baby-sitting tenure over the last couple of weekends up in suburban Scarsdale. Bob's boss and wife are in Europe, so each weekend we've stayed at their home, relieving a schoolteacher friend who is with them through the week. We've had a wonderful time since the boys are sweet and bright and their home very lovely and comfortable. Bob also got a bit of writing done in the peace and coolness of a home

<pb/>
<fw>4</fw>

out of the city.</p>

<p>Bob and I were both touched by the tribute given you by your Epic America class. I wish I could have attended that class years ago with Bob. We have read the "Cycle" together. It is exciting reading it together ar home, but I can imagine the great color added when you read it, filling in with historic and pertinent data. How could that possibly be boring?</p>

<p>The paper is ending and so is my waiting period.</p>

<p>We do look forward to hearing from you soon again. In the meantime, we hope all stays well with you and your family (and more ribbons for the horses.)</p>

<closer><salute>With our love,</salute>
<signed>(Bob) &amp; Adele Leaf</signed></closer>


</div1>


<div1 type="envelope">
<ab type="return">
<address>
<addrLine>Leaf</addrLine>
<addrLine>175 W. 93</addrLine>
<addrLine>Ny 25, Ny</addrLine>
</address></ab>
<note type="curatorial">14</note>
<ab type="postmark">New York, N.Y. AUG 3 230 PM GRAND CENTRAL STATION US AIR MAIL </ab>
<figure><p>Via Air Mail 7&#162;</p></figure>
<note>Ansd 9-23-60</note>

<ab>
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. John Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>Skyrim Farm</addrLine>
<addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
<addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>

</div1>

</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
