<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.20.3-4_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alvin to John G. Neihardt, July 9, 1942</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.20.3-4_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alvin to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1942-07-09">July 9, 1942</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.3-4_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        602 <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> 10th St.
                        Lafayette, Ind.
                        9 July, 1942
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear <hi rend="caps">JGN</hi>,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your infectious vigor has made me impatient to write you earlier, but I was waiting to have a word with my wise and kindly department head. Dr. Creek, as I expected, was sympathetic and encouraging (he is consitutionally cagy--or should I say calm and collected?--and is not given to impetuousness or quick-fired enthusiasms); and promised as much aid as he himself might initiate or win. Financial aid, of course, though there is probably no chance that the university will underwrite what I think will be a great desideratum: a summerlong residence for me in Branson next year. The new "patriotic" university set-up results in certain readjustments of salary and service. As I think I explained to you, I am having to work two months of this summer to "earn" the last two salary checks under my 1941-42 contract, and I get in addition one-half of one salary check. The extent of university favor next summer would probably be its considering my work on the book a "project" respectable enough to merit waiving of teaching service during the summer. But that would be a help. What you and I want to do together will demand the intimate use of leisurely association--the more the better; and a full summer would be ideal. (I have yet to hear your ideas on this matter, of course!) So far as Dr. Creek is concerned, however, I can count on the most cordial of interest and inspiration. When you meet him you will understand why I think of him and you with the same sort of affection and respect.</p>
                
                <p>He feels with me, incidentally, that it might be wise to mention the undertaking to Macmillan's (or some other publisher), with the object of gaining in advance some commitment as regards publication, or some evidence of interest, anyway. This is an entirely practical suggestion, and one which you yourself are in the best position to follow up; but it is not at all obligatory or necessary. What do you think? The fact that I should be going at the job under the best of all possible conditions, your own guidance, cooperation, and inspiration, should influence almost any bookman. But I leave this matter for your consideration and decision.</p>
                
                <p>Meanwhile, the start. I shall for the time being set about acquainting and re-acquainting myself with your work, what we have of it here, that is. Eventually, I myself shall want to own a complete Neihardt bibliography, for convenience' sake; temporarily, however, I shall depend on our library and on whatever you can spare me. I enjoy the prospect of following your thought as Lowes did Coleridge's; I shall certainly want anything you have kept in the way of notebook records: you know, the apparatus that reflects the adventures and activities of an author's mind. Some writers have much, some little, of this; I'm sure you know what helpful materials of the personal sort you possess, and what good use I might put them to. Possibly, also, you would prefer my studying such materials when I can be with you. It's all one; the important thing is our mutual confidence and enthusiasm. You can help me in my library work by dilating upon the reading required, from time to time, if all at once is too formidable a listing, sending me the roll call of your mind's company. The extent of the work is immaterial to me; I estimate at least two years, but shall not be reluctant to go twice as long. As you remarked concerning my attitude toward the drybones drudgery of the PhD. I am not inclined to do the worldly thing.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20-3-4_0002"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">4</fw>
                
                <p>It is too early to make definite plans about being with you, but I'm the sort of bird whose present efficiency and happiness are enhanced by long-term certainties. You might estimate for me, for instance, the weekly or monthly cost of living in Branson, if that is where I could be most with you (I should have Helen with me, of course). Possibly there are small houses or apartments available near your home. You know what I mean, and can help me form some notion of next year's expenses. We should not sub-lease our apartment here (most renters are descendants of the Vandals!), and should therefore have to count on some Lafayette overhead too. We might doubtless cash a few of the bonds that represent a part of our share in the war effort, but the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> frowns on the practice, and I hate frowns! I shouldn't let a couple of hundred dollars hamstring my hopes of being close to you, but as you so reasonably pointed out, there's a lot of good sense in being practical--and in plenty of time.</p>
                
                <p>I needn't enlarge upon what must have been obvious to you during your so-short stay with us: our pleasure in your company, our appreciation of your fine gifts for living, your <hi rend="underline">genuineness</hi>. But you ought to know that others found you delightful, also; Babcock, especially, was pleased to have had his few moments with you. Dr. Creek regretted very much his missing you. (Poor man, his bronchial ailment, so marvelously cleared up in his two weeks at Colorado Springs, has already given notice of returning, and with its usual odious persistence.) The student paper slipped a cog and failed to run a story of your appearance; and the local paper, with its usual opportunism, neglected poetry for patriotism (the descriptions of the July 4 fireworks--courtesy of the American Legion--were lavish). But I've had many pleased comments from those who I had in to meet you, comments that recall the fine things my friend Griffin at Wake Forest wrote some time ago after your visit there. So any time you return here, I can assure you of a pleased group of welcomers. And of course if you swing eastward on a course anywhere near our domestic focus, plan to stop with us. Shall we agree that in the future your doing so will go without saying?</p>
                
                <p>Let me know what you've been thinking, and when you conveniently can, answer a few of my questions. Meanwhile, you are much in my thoughts, you and a certain new and fine meaning in my life. I look forward to these coming meetings and communings of ours with great interest; depend on me to do my utmost to make them satisfactory and the final work worthy.</p>
                
                <p>Our affectionate greetings to you and the dear lady your devoted descriptions have made us eager to meet. I hope that we shall be able to welcome <hi rend="underline">both</hi> of you here someday.</p>
                <closer>                
                    <salute>Yours faithfully,</salute>
                    <signed>Alvin</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>Call me Alvin, of course, or Al, as everyone here does. I shall have to call you by some special name, for I refuse to be formal with him whom I admire so much and whose spirit I feel so attuned to. Possibly we can hold a parliamentary discussion of this problem--say in late August, between semesters, when I shall have about a week off. I'll have to study timetables and rates! Keep well, and may you always feel <hi rend="caps">BULLY.</hi></p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
