<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26a.8a-8c_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Laurence A. Cummings to John G. Neihardt, April 11, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26a.8a-8c_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Laurence A. Cummings to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-04-11">April 11, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26a.8a-8c_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">8a</fw>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Neihardt Collection</note>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="italics">Yankton</hi> <hi rend="caps">COLLEGE</hi> Yankton, South Dakota
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Rte. 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Mrs. Adrian Rondileau, Chairman of the Fine Arts Conference, has asked me to write to you in the hope that you would come to Yankton C ollege during the first week in June to be our guest poet at the Conference. Last night I phoned Professor Peden to ascertain whether you were still at Missouri and whether he thought you might be interested. It has been eight years since I last talked with you when I was a graduate student at the university.</p>
                
                <p>Perhaps first I should describe our aims in offering this service to the people of the Upper Midwest and outline the week's activites in the various arts. The Fine Arts Conference was created with the purpose of encouraging artists in the Upper Midwest. High school and college students and adults, beginners, practicing amateurs, and professionals are all invited. We have workshops, seminars, classes, lectures, and private instruction in music, drama, dance, painting, literature, and creative writing. My purpose in writing you is to sketch out what we intend that our guest poet do.</p>
                
                <p>Last year our guest poet was Paul Engle of the University of Iowa, also a regional fi<del>tu</del><add>gu</add>re.</p>
                
                <p>We have good reason to think you would be especially appropriate to help us. We have this June, in addition to our aim of encouraging regional writers, an intention of inaugurating a continuing program of study of the Dakota Indian and of Dakota territorial history. There is no question about your ability to help us to improve the writing of the authors of this area, but you are also unusually qualified to speak on the Dakota. Your life here and the effect this has had on your art has made you a favorite and beloved writer in this region and a recognized spokesman for much that is old and new Dakota-red and white. The leaders in the state poetry society have indicated approval of your being our guest poet. We want to have you because you are an accomplished poet and
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26a.8a-8c"/>
                
                <fw type=" curatorial">8b</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="italics">Yankton</hi> <hi rend="caps">COLLEGE</hi> Yankton, South Dakota
                </fw>
                
                    prose artist, because you are an experienced creative writing teacher, interested in helping the beginner and the amateur, and because you are respected by both races as a student and mentor of the Dakota and the early days of this region.</p>
                
                <p>But let me sketch the mechanics of your hoped-for participation in the conference. If you could catch the 5:30 airplane out of Omaha for Yankton on <del>t</del><add>T</add>hursday June 5, you would arrive here at 7:26 in time for a panel on Dakota Literature and Myth with Miss Ella Deloria, a Dakota, who is a linguist and anthropologist who has worked and is working for the betterment of her people. The previous evening would have featured Oscar Howe, a Dakota and a painter who uses the traditional symbols of his heritage in modern context. On Friday night there will be another panel which would include other guest artists and lecturers discussing the artist in today's society; the exact topic has not been settled upon. On Saturday is Poetry Day, proc<del>al</del><add>la</add>imed the governor of South Dakota and marked in our Conference by a gathering on our campus of the annual convention of the South Dakota Poetry Society, culminating in a banquet and later a public lecture by the guest poet. Friday and Saturday afternoons (1:30-3:30) there are writer's workshops which the guest poet will visit. He will be welcome to participate in all other activities, such as the morning classes and the afternoon recreational activities. Perhaps he could join for the Contemporary Poetry Course on Friday. Informal talking over coffee cups would be beneficial to the students.</p>
                
                <p>There you have it. Our Conference is still new, this being our second year. Last year, though a success educationally if the surprisingly enthusiastic response of the people who attended is any criterion, the Conference expenses so much exceeded the modest tuition rates that one might say that Yankton C ollege sponsored the C onference. Nevertheless, the administration has encouraged us to go ahead again this year because of the desire to furnish this community service- or more specifically, this cultural stimulus to the people of this region. This year we are trying to come near to breaking even; we do not ever expect to make money on the Fine Arts Conference. Fortunately, the guest artists and lecturers who have thus far agreed to come have been content with the modest honoraria we are able to offer, perhaps motivated by our aims.</p>
    
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26a.8a08c_0003"/>

                <fw type="curatorial">8c</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="italics">Yankton</hi> <hi rend="caps">COLLEGE</hi> Yankton, South Dakota
                </fw>
                
                <p>As a result we are now able to offer you, besides air travel expenses and living expenses while here, $150 for two days and an evening. This is not commensurate with your worth to us. We would like to offer you more, but could do so only by severely pinching an already black and blue budget.</p>
                
                <p>Time is of great importance to us since we wish to have an extended publicity campaign. We have already sent out a preliminary flyer to persons who may be interested in attending or bringing other students. Since we have the printer's deadlines to consider and since we want to get on with our major publicity, you will understand the necessity of my requesting an immediate reply. Please write or telephone collect (my number is 3766) whether or not you can be our guest poet.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Laurence A. Cummings</signed>
                
                    <signed>Laurence A. C ummings</signed>
                
                    <note>LAC/wc</note>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

