<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.20e-20f_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, October 11, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.20e-20f_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-10-11">October 11, 1957</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.20e-20f_0001-2"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">20e</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>October 11, 1957</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was delighted to have your good letter. Classes sound promising, as anyone who knows you would e<del>c</del><add>x</add>pect. I hope some semester you will have Mary Ann Brentlinger in class; she is the student I sent to you three years ago when she was a freshman, and it was the high moment in her year. She has some real ability I think.</p>
                
                <p>I was so excited about the Sterling letters when I last wrote that I may not have told you all the news. I have had a nice letter from Robert Hill, who is Keeper of Manuscripts in the New York Public Library. He was not there when I was in New York, but he wrote to say he was sorry to have missed me because he heard you speak at the University of Maryland when he was a student there, and he knew Dr. House. He is conducting a search for the Ledoux letters, and he has given me several tips about others, including the Henry Holt. I am having everything I find microfilmed, because once I know a letter exists I want to see every word of it. When I can I'll have them turned into photostats, but that is a great deal more expensive. If there is anything you want, I'll make a transcript for you.</p>
                
                <p>I should like very much to hear about the afternoon with Mrs. Moody; you have not told me about it, and I hope you will. Also, I would like to hear about George Sterling's visit to Bancroft in 1914. Did you sit up till all hours? I'm very eager now to see the other half of the correspondence; these letters have statements now and then like: "Mrs. <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> does me too much honor," and I want to know what Mrs. <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> sa<del/><add>i</add>d!</p>
                
                <p>We are going down to Santa Barbara Thanksgiving, and I am making arrangements to work in the Paolo Alto and Berkeley libraries then. I may even be able to find the whole set of Present Day American Literature issues, as well as manuscripts. If I can I'd like to locate Jackson Barber's unpublished book which should have some material about you.</p>
                
                <p>I have remembered the question I wanted to ask you the last time I came out and we got onto other things. One visit, when we were discussing the Branson school 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.20e-20f_0002"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">20f</fw>
                
                    speech, Mrs. Neihardt mentioned that you used a manuscript although you did not have to look at it constantly because you felt at that time that a speaker should not speak without a script. This is an interesting point because later you did shift to just as thorough but not <hi rend="underline">written</hi> preparation, didn't you? Do you remember whether the change was conscious or just the result of long experience? There are several schools of thought on preparation, and if you recall your thinking it would be valuable to me. Churchill, for instance, much prefers to write his speeches; he speaks extempore only under great necessity. Bower will never use manuscript or notes unless some rule of the situation requires it.</p>
                
                <p>These are small questions that will clear up details: Who was Great Grandma whom everyone but Enid stayed with while Grandma and Enid went to a pie supper in 1923? Was that the grandmother you lived with as a child? Was the feature article on you that Mr. Fink wrote ever published? Was i<del>s</del><add>t</add> for the <hi rend="caps">P-D</hi>? Did you ever travel the last route Jed Smith took and recogni<del><unclear>s</unclear></del><add>z</add>e the canyon? Do you have Allen True's Denver address? Questions sound terribly abrupt when I fire them off like that. I don't mean them to be, and I'll save any more for the next time.</p>
                
                <p>I meant to tell you that I see why you thought the Sterling letters would help me. They are wonderful letters; I haven't read them all because if I read too long at a time my eyes give out in the bright glare of the reader. If you are willing someday to let me gather together a new "Straws in the Wind" some of the paragraphs in the Sterling letters ought to be included. The discussion of the "small-town mind," for example, and the persuasive one on the essential nobility of human nature.</p>
                
                <p>I will keep you up to date on what turns up, and undoubtedly there will be more questions as I read on. You are very kind to take the time to answer. I do want to do a good job of this; it must be right in the spirit as well as the letter. The material is certainly everything to make a fine study; I must do it justice. Please give my regards to everyone, and tell Alice she deserves a special citation; those diaries are pure gold. They date all sorts of things.</p>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
