<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0007-15">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from L. Rex Carey to John G. Neihardt, August 6, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0007-15</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from L. Rex Carey to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-08-06">August 6, 1959</date>
                    <extent>8 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0007"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">I.</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        <del>Nov.</del><add>Aug</add> 6 - 59.
                        Dalton, Nebr.
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John,&#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Thanks for your letter of &#8212; Aug 1st. I am happy that you enjoyed it.</p>
                
                <p>I had the feeling while I was working on it of wanting to tone them down to get what I knew would be a truer likeness and recognized the fact that <del/><add>th</add>ey were "high lighted for camera effect but had no other guide and after all the eye expression was <unclear/> by the glasses and the wrinkles are important as a record of past facial expressions and show <del>the</del> deep feeling and intense concentration. The little lines around the corners of the eyes and mouth show the keen sense of humor and the kindly compassion and tenderness that is inherent in you &#8212;</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0008"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">II.</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                
                <p>The stallion has a <hi rend="underline">majestic</hi> stance and the colt is <hi rend="underline">lovable</hi></p>
                
                <p>We are <unclear>undoubtedly</unclear> the <hi rend="underline">Gods</hi> of our animal friends and there is solemnity in the thought. I sometimes wonder, how far, in the big picture, we are above them.&#8212; if there is not somewhere in the vast universe, a strata, (or several) of life above the human.</p>
                
                <p>My dogs &#8212; (but I had better not get started on that line) &#8212;</p>
                
                <p>You see John I am taking advantage of your kin<del/>ly understanding to record thoughts I would not dare record otherwise &#8212;</p>
                
                <p>Though the details are somewhat dimmed by 50 yrs. I well recall the incident of your going to the Minneapolis Journal. I have no recollection of how I received the impression but it was very definite with me
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0009"/>
                    
                <fw type="authorial">III</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                
                    and I could not at that time understand your puzzlement.</p>
                    
                <p>If I am correct it was not long after your experience with the <del>Bee</del><add>Om</add>aha Bee&#8212;</p>
                
                <p>I am going to quote from a letter you wrote me on Febr. 4, 1909. A letter I have treasured all my life.&#8212; quote &#8212; "There is something about that last and most <unclear>viewed</unclear> paragraph of your letter that strikes me <unclear>curiously</unclear>. I have recently finsihed a story called "The Dead Man's Dog, which ends with just that scene!" Is this <hi rend="underline">telepathy, or only coincidence?</hi>"</p>
                
                <p>To me telepathy is completely logical. Man's communication of his thoughts has gradually advance through, actions, facial expressions, gestures, signs, words spoken then written, through electrical impulses, radio and television
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0010"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">IV</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                
                    waves &#8212; nerve impulses and brain activity have definitely been recorded. Surely it is a small step to believe that thought is just a little finer (impulse, wave, vibration &#8212; call it what you want &#8212; words are an imperfect colored by the recievers<sic>receiver's</sic> previous experiences) surely a condition <hi rend="underline">may</hi> exist where another {<hi rend="underline">brain</hi> personality soul} is attuned to receive these impulses. I have had experiences where there was a possibility, even a probability, but few if any where I could rule out <del>all other</del> coincidence and all contributing factors and say definitely "This is telepathy" In all things my (faith) is to<sic>too</sic> small and my (brain) requires <unclear>to</unclear> definite and <hi rend="underline">logical</hi> proof.</p>
                
                <note type="authorial">(over)</note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_00011"/>
                
                <p>I am glad to hear of your tape recordings.</p>
                
                <p>I suppose you do the reading &#8212; certainly that would be an aid to the communication of your thoughts. One difficulty you face &#8212; an audience that has the classical knowledge to receive the correct impression from many of the words you speak. I speak from <hi rend="underline">experience</hi></p>
          
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0012"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                <date>Aug. 18-57.</date>
                
                <fw type="authorial">V</fw>
                
                <p>It does not seem possible that 12 days have elapsed since I had to lay this letter aside, before I finished it. The urge to copy some scenes in water color or pastel has occupied my spare time. Work at it entirely, just for my own satisfaction and pleasure of family and friends &#8212;</p>
                
                <p>Just wanted to pass on a few of my <hi rend="underline">mental</hi> experiences &#8212;</p>
                
                <p>On a number of occsions I have stopped &#8212; overpowered by the feeling &#8212; <del/><add>I</add> have thought these thought! I have seen these scenes! <hi rend="underline">I have <hi rend="double underline">lived</hi> this moment before</hi>! The moment has always been fleeting and I have never been able to
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0013"/>
                    
                <fw type="authorial">VI</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
                    
                    think it out to any logical conclusion.&#8212; but the feeling has been over whelming.</p>
                
                <p>I wonder if you have ever had similar moments. There have also been times when after a period of deep contemplateing<sic>contemplating</sic> the riddle of existence and the universe I have almost been on the verge of some great <hi rend="underline">truth</hi> when a numbness took possession of my brain and I could not think clearly &#8212; as if some (force?) had taken possession of me and said "This far &#8212; no further &#8212; this <hi rend="underline"><del/><add>t</add>ruth is not</hi> for you." The recollection, of some moments of exala<del>t</del><add>l</add>tation<sic>exaltation</sic> over the beauty of some scene (often a moonlight scene) have been some of the high lights <del/> off my life.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0014"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">VII</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">32</fw>
                
                <p>My writing is so poor &#8212; cataracts on both eyes, though one is fairly good yet, interfere gre<del>t</del><add>a</add>tly.</p>
                
                <p>Recently enjoyed a nice visit from my nephew Jim, (Floyds boy) his wife and three adopted children. Except for <unclear>our two</unclear> dogs, we live alone in a rather large old house, surrounded by trees.</p>
                
                <p>Also <del><unclear/>o</del> about the first of the month brother Lyle <add><hi rend="underline">and wife</hi></add> w<del/><add>er</add>e here for a time. He was convalescing from a prostrate operation same as I had last month. We are comfortable, enjoy a rather <unclear>great</unclear> life.</p>
                
                <p>Our love to you, Mona, and your children</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Rex</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.26-33_0015"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">L.R.</hi> Carey
                    Dalton, Nebr.
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    DALTON
                    AUG 19
                    1 30PM
                    1957
                    NEBR.
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢
                    IN GOD WE TRUST
                    LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt,</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Skyrim Farm, Rt. 7.,</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>Columbia.</addrLine>
                                    <addrLine>Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
