<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.39-42_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, December 7, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.39-42_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-12-07">December 7, 1957</date>
                    <extent>3 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.39-42_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">39</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        2094 Hilyard
                        Eugene, Oregon
                        December 7, 1957
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I don't really like to type letters, but this time I shall, because it's faster, and I have a great deal to tell you. This is a very exciting job to do--you can't imagine how deeply satisfying and stimulating is is!</p>
                
                <p>First, I appreciate very much the statement on socialism; Bower read it too, and was impressed with it as I was. You are very kind to take the time to formulate statements for me; I keep asking you questions because I want to be sure to get things right, and I hope it is not a burden on you. I shall look forward to seeing the war-hysteria account.</p>
                
                <p>The Bob Davis film was here when we got back, and I have read the letters. I didn't <del>n</del><add>i</add>ntend to read them all at one sitting, but I did--couldn't stop, once I got into them. Do you recall the two poems in the first two letters? The first was about capons and wine, and the second ended each stanza with the refrain "I want to, want to, want to be discovered." Would you like to have copies? I'll make them if you would. I can see why Davis <add>"</add>would give anything<add>"</add> for your exuberance.</p>
                
                <p>Today I finished working through the House collection, and those letters are solid gold. They are full of material on criticism, and they give a wonderful picture of you. There are 238 Neihardt items, letters, clippings, and so on&#8212;mostly letters. Any book on your criticisms ought by all means to include the statements you make in letters. Lines like "Time is the only authentic critic" need to be published.</p>
                
                <p>I read the letter to Davis about Mignon; the reply is in the Missouri library, and I had seen it. This is a fine defense of freedom in Literature from bigotry and narrow "moral" censorship. You are not a Platonist in that respect. But didn't Davis really miss the point of th<del>t</del><add>a</add>t story? You weren't interested in bad women either, so far as I can see; if it were just a story
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.39-42_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">40</fw>
                
                    of a poor, foolish Indian duped by a little tart you would never have written it. Wasn't the real point that the Indian saw something real in Mignon and made it noble with his love? Whether it was the stronger or the weaker truth in her is not essential, is it?</p>
                
                <p>I am reading Boodin, and it's very good reading. He had a po<del>s</del><add>e</add>tic cast of thought, didn't he? His explanation draw on figures of speech constantly. I'm also reading Stevenson--about the little people who come in his sleep.</p>
                
                <p>The two Sterling letters that were in Mills College library were here too when we got home. They were photostated, and they are both good ones. The second has a charming account of Enid, aged three-and-a-half, climbing up on your lap and asking to "tell her Sterlins," which you "in a dark brown voice" because it was about the "vulshure." Did you read aloud a great deal to the children? One of the House letters mentions outdoor theatre when Mary came--probably Shakesperian comedy, and I wondered whether that was a reading hour together. Alice's diary mentions reading together too. Was it frequent?</p>
                
                <p>I have a question about the House letters. In this collection, there were only four before 1925; three of them were in 1916, and one was in 1924. In an early letter in 1925 you said the letters were at the station, and that someday they might be brough out, probably after your lifetime. Could that possibly have meant that the letters you must have written in 1917, '18, '19, '20, '21, '22, '23 and '24 were collected for possible publication? If that was it, where did they go, and who was to edit? Do you remember? I have written to Mrs. Ryskind just now to ask the same <del>w</del><add>q</add>uestion, but she would be less likely to know the answer than you.</p>
                
                <p>So far I am nowhere on the Barber manuscript and the Ledoux letters. I'm writing west-coast historial libraries about the former, but so far nobody has ever heard of Barber--not even the Bohemian Club. Columbia University doesn't have the Ledoux letters, and has no suggestions of possible places to look.</p>
                
                <p>I will be in Columbia by the 24th, and I should like to call you that afternoon to see when we can get together. If I don't get you then I will call
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.39-42_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">41</fw>
                
                    again, but I don't want to disturb you on Christmas Day. I will be there at least a week, perhaps a few days longer. We leave here on the 19th, but we are stopping in Minneapolis for a day. I am all set there with the library to look up reviews. Bower is going to help <del>,</del><add>m</add>e all day, and we will transcribe as many as possible in the hours we have. Microfilm is almost impossible, because they have to refocus for each frame, and that runs the cost up into prohibitive figures.</p>
                
                <p>Do let me know what happens about <hi rend="underline">Black Elk</hi>. I hope, I hope, I hope it will come out again; I can't find a copy anywhere. People who own Neihardt books don't sell them to second-hand stores; they hang on to them for all they're worth, and that's more money than there is in the world! I can't really blame them; any Neihardt books we own will never get out of our hands.</p>
                
                <p>Please give my regards to all the family, and specially to Mrs. Neihardt. I shall look forward to seeing you before too long.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I forgot to ask: does Hilda still have her collection of autograph letters? If so, would she let me see them? The Joseph Auslander one is with some of the letters you have lent me, but there must be more, and if they're all like that, they have fine comments in them.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.39-42_0004"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    2094 Hilyard
                    Eugene, Oregon
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">42</fw>
                
                <note type="authorial"><hi rend="underline">Air Mail</hi></note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    EUGENE
                    DE<unclear>C</unclear> 9
                    1130 AM
                    1957
                    OREG.
                    <unclear/>AT<unclear/>
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢ IN GOD WE TRUST LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢ IN GOD WE TRUST LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <note type="recipient">ansd</note>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim, Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
