<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27a.44-46_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Evelyn Vogt to John G. Neihardt, June 22, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27a.44-46_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Evelyn Vogt to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-06-22">June 22, 1959</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.44-46_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">356-2</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">44</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Bancroft, Nebr
                            June 22, 1959
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mr John <hi rend="caps">G</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia Mo</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    <salute>Dear Mr Neihardt</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The Big Celebration is all over, and Bancroft is patting itself on the back because of it's<sic>its</sic> success. Capacity crowds, as th<del>4</del><add>e</add> papers say, were on hand for both the Pageant and the Parade.</p>
                
                <p>I am sending you a program of the Pageant. Scene six is the one that will interest you and also scene seven. So many of the spectators have remarked on the beauty of the Indian scene. The Pageant was presented in our Park. For this scene the lights were covered with red cellophane. (we operated on a very small budget.) The soft light and the background music lent charm to the Legend of Blackbird Hill. I know you will be amazed and I hope you will be amused, when you read it. Now hold on to your hat--here we go--</p>
                
                <p>"Among the Omaha Chieftains who helped Neihardt in his search for Indian legends were, Shanga Ska-White Horse, and Esta Maga-Iron Eye. The legend of Blackbird Hill was one of White Horse's favorites. Here is the story he told. (in sign language.)</p>
                
                <p>The Legend of Blackbird Hill
                    <lb/>
                    Words by John Neihardt--Re-sorted and Re-arranged (for heavens sake<add>!)</add>
                        <lb/>
                        by Evelyn Vogt</p>
                
                <lg>
                    <l>Blackfeather, fierce Chief of the Omaha's. Strong in battle</l>
                    <l>Wise in council, wrong in his choice of a wife.</l>
                    <l>Was she fair--this woman? Legend keeps no answer. Yet we</l>
                    <l>Know that she was young. What need to know her features as they were?</l>
                    <l>Was she not lovely as her lovers thought, and beautiful</l>
                    <l>As that wild love she wrought was fatal?</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Now had come the time of peril. It befell in this wise, Insofar as</l>
                    <l>Tongue may tell and tongues repeat the little eyes may guess of</l>
                    <l>What may happen in that wilderness--The human heart.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>There dwealt a mighty man among the Omaha's. A leader of his clan.</l>
                    <l>A goodly sighted indeed. Upstanding, eagle-faced, and eagle-eyed.</l>
                    <l>The ease of latent power in his stride.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>How little of a story can be told. Nor shall this tale presume to <del>tell</del> guess</l>
                    <l>And tell how all night long doom quickened in the fancy of a woman</l>
                    <l>The wife of Blackfeather. How she saw, serenly moving through a</l>
                    <l>Spacious awe--that shining one--Magnificently tall. A mortal</l> 
                    <l>Brother of the sun.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>When the night was done, and morning, like an uproar in the east,</l>
                    <l>Aroused the town, all men might see the whimsic fatal bloom a dre<del>q</del><add>a</add>m had</l>
                    <l>Nourished unto blowing in the day.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Twas then the girl appeared and took her way with hesitating feet.</l>
                    <l>Unconscious of the many peeping eyes</l>
                    <l>Erect with wrapt uplifted face she stood</l>
                    <l>A miracle of shapely womanhood.</l>
                    <l>And many heard, or seemed to hear, the prayer<del>s</del> she mutters to the sky.</l>
                    <l>Then, as one who finds new courage for a task begun, she turned and</l> 
                    <l>Hastened to the dead.</l>
                </lg>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.44-46_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">45</fw>
                
                <lg>
                    <l>They say there was no dearth of gossiping that day among the lodges</l>
                    <l>Shrewish tongues there were that clacked no happy prophecies of her.</l>
                    <l>And many wondered at the Blackfeathers whim. The woman had wrought a spell on him</l>
                    <l>Why else was he silent?</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Now had the scandal, like a sudden flame fed fat with grasses.</l>
                    <l>Sufficed the keenest gossip for a theme.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Then one day, there grew along the western rim of sky</l>
                    <l>A band of cloud that had a rainy look. Then the wind began to breath</l>
                    <l>A melancholy drowse.</l>
                    <l>All afternoon the gale increased. The sun went down blood red, the</l>
                    <l>Young moon, periliously fragile, fled to early se<del>r</del><add>t</add>ting, and the long</l>
                    <l>Night roared.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Tempestuously broke the day, and when the flying noon stared down</l>
                    <l>Aghast, the tribe beheld upon the grassy marge at the foot of</l> 
                    <l>A hill. A ragged heap that should have been a woman.</l>
                    <l>And it was Blackfeathers wife.</l>
                </lg>
                <lg>
                    <l>Then growing loud a wind of horror blew among the crowd</l>
                    <l>And set it swirling round about the dead.</l>
                    <l>And over all a long hoarse wail of anguish and despair</l>
                    <l>Aroused the echoes. Answering arose, the jeering of the crows.</l>
                </lg>
                
                <p>The Narrator read this epic while John Neihardt sat at a camp fire with White Horse and Iron Eye. A group of high school boys and girls acted it in pantomime. Everyone enjoyed it, and I hope you will forgive the misuse of your beautiful wordings.You never know, when you give someone permission to quote, what will happen, do you?</p>
                
                <p>A number of old timers w<del>h</del><add>e</add>re here for the celebration. And we all had a good time Remembering when. I was so sorry to hear of Mona's death. I mentioned it to several who remember you both. We all extend our sympathy. It is such a sad thing when children are grown and gone from home for one partner in a marriage to be left alone. We have so many situations of this kind in Bancroft.</p>
                
                <p>Back to the Pageant---The title Unashta Zinga, is Omaha Indian for Little Stopping Place. According to history that is wh<del>h</del><add>a</add>t they called this way station before the town was born</p>
                
                <p>The two ladies who assisted me are my daughters, Marie Ann, Mrs Mackey, and Diane, Mrs Nottlemann. My son Jack took the part of John Turner. Appropriatly<sic>Appropriately</sic> enough--he works in the First Nar<del>i</del><add>t</add>onal<sic>National</sic> Bank. My two oldest grandchildren were also in the cast. Keep all these good things in the family, I always say.</p>
                
                <p>Many thanks for your nice letter. If you come to Bancroft in August, stop and have coffee with us. Expect many changes in the town. It is not as you remember I'm sure.</p>
                
                <p>Thanks again for your kindness</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely</salute>
                
                    <signed>Evelyn Vogt</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.44-46_0003"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <add>Mrs Martin Vogt</add>
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="italics">Demme Mortuaries</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps"><del>EMERSON PENDER</del> BANCROFT
                        <lb/>
                    NEBRASKA</hi>
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    BANCROFT
                    5 PM
                    JUN 24
                    1959
                    NEBR.
                    
                    BANC<unclear>ROFT</unclear>
                    <unclear/>
                    JUN <unclear/>
                    19<unclear cert="high">59</unclear>
                    NEB<unclear>R.</unclear>
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>ARCTIC EXPLORATIO<unclear cert="high">N</unclear>
                    1909
                    1959
                    571 571
                    U.S. POSTAGE 4¢</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Skyrim Farm</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                                    <addrLine>Columbia</addrLine>
                                        <addrLine>Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="recipient">ansd</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">46</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
