<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.15.46-48_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lieutenant Colonel Townsend Whelen to John G. Neihardt, November 8, 1932</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.15.46-48_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lieutenant Colonel Townsend Whelen to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1932-11-08">November 8, 1932</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.46-48_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">46</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Fort Meade, <hi rend="caps">S.D.</hi>
                
                        Nov 8, 1932.
                    </dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear Mr. Neihardt:-</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter and your book have come to me here where I have been staying on for a few days deer hunting after my inspection of the 4th Cavalry. I have been reading the book in the evenings after my return from hunting, and expect to finish it on my way back to Omaha as I am leaving today. I am enjoying the songs immensely. They are superb. I do not know of anyone who has so accurately set history to verse. They remind me of Virgil and Homer, and deserve to be ranked with these classics. It is a real pleasure to read them, and more than that, it is quite evident that they will bear and are worthy of very close study, both from the literary and historical standpoints.</p>
                
                <p>As I said to you, I think that rifle sight is <unclear/>. I know of nothing even approaching it in design, I am not certain, however, that it has successful commercial possibilities. Its <del/> adjustments are fixed &#8212; that is it does not adjust for zero. It would appear that adjustment for zero, that is adjustment so that it will shoot correctly at 25 yards with the sight set at 25 yards, must be made with the front sight. That is the front sight must be raised or lowered, or moved right or left until the rifle shoots correctly. Then this having been done the rear sight will then <unclear>proceed</unclear> to function properly. Now such adjustments of front sight is a difficult problem for the ordinary man. If he wishes to use a <unclear>bead</unclear> front sight (and most do) he cannot file down the front sight until it is
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.46-48_0002"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">47</fw>
                
                    the right height, but must rather have a number of heights of front <unclear>bead</unclear> sights, differing by about 1/50th inch, to try until he gets the correct height. Such adjustment cannot be made at the factory, but must be made by the shooter himself because every individual differs slightly in how he aims. Also every make of ammunition shoots slightly different, with different center of impacts, and differs on different days, and there are many varieties of .22 Long Rifle cartridges with velocities running from 1000 to 1450 f.s. and these all have different trajectories. In addition one cannot select on<sic>one</sic> specific ammunition in advance for any .22 weapon because some varieties may shoot very poorly and some very accurately in an individual arm.</p>
                
                <p>I am rather taking it for granted that to be successful a sight should cause the rifle and cartridge to shoot close to the mark at say 50 yards when the rear sight is set at 50 yards. Now our <unclear>experience</unclear> has been that with .22 <unclear>cal</unclear> weapons the only way to accomplish this is to set up a target at 50 yards each morning before one starts out shooting and zero the rifle in. That having been done by the individual shooter for that day, and that ammunition, it will remain quite constant during the day if the temperature does not change materially. But a rifle zeroed on one day may be <unclear>found</unclear> to shoot as much as 2½ inches off on another day at 50 yards, or if the ammunition be changed, as much as 6 to 8 inches. Daily zeroing seems to be essential to close and successful shooting with the .22 rifle, and that is why we who know rifle use sights adjusting to half <unclear>minutes</unclear> for elevation and <unclear>windage</unclear>.</p>
                
                <p>I hope you will stop in to see me when West in Omaha.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very sincerely</salute>
                
                    <signed>Townsend Whelen</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.46-48_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">48</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">WAR DEPARTMENT</hi>
                    Lt Col Townsend Whelen
                    <unclear/> 7th Corps Area.
                    Omaha, Nebr.
                    <hi rend="caps">OFFICIAL BUSINESS</hi>
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    PENALTY FOR <unclear/>IVAT<unclear/>
                    AVOID PAYMENT OF PO<unclear/>
                    FORT <unclear/> NO<unclear/> S. D
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>UNITED STATES POSTAGE <unclear/> <unclear cert="high">3</unclear> CENTS 3</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt, Esq.</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Branson,</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="recipient">Colonel Whelen. He was then the greatest authority on guns, in the eyes of all "gun cranks"</note>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
