<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35c.4-6">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Hilda N. Petri to John G. Neihardt, October 13, 1971</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.35c.4-6</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Hilda N. Petri to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1971-10-13">October 13, 1971</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35c.4"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">4</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    Hilda <hi rend="caps">N.</hi> Petri 
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">ATTORNEY-AT-LAW 
                        <lb/>
                    ______________________________________________________
                        <lb/>
                    110 NORTH EIGHTH STREET ∙ COLUMBIA, MISSOURI 65201 
                        <lb/>
                    PHONE</hi> (314) 449-2929 
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>October 13, 1971</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Gaki:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was surprised when I received your telephone call the other monring, particularly since I wasn't supposed to be home yet at that time. I had decided the night before to drive on in instead of stoppping off at a motel someplace. As I told Myrtle, I telephoned from Fremont to see if you were home on Saturday, because I would have stopped by for a brief visit with you. Apparently you had not yet returned from Red Cloud.</p>
                
                <p>I am very eager to receive the report on the conversation you had with Manfred. I would like to receive this just as soon as possible, because it might have some bearing on the De Witt situation. I have received another letter from Mr. De Witt, and I have sent a copy of it to the lawyer in Hollywood. For your interest I am enclosing a photocopy of De Witt's letter herewith.</p>
                
                <p>I did not receive the letter from Bruce Nicoll that he told me last week was under way. I ahve written him asking that a copy of it be sent to me, assuming that the letter went astray in the mail. I cannot reply sensibly to a letter I have not received. I did last week, after talking to Bruce Nicoll, write to Simon &amp; Schuster telling them that we were interested in working out a deal on hardback and quality paperback and that we were apparently going to get all rights in <hi rend="caps">BLACK ELK SPEAKS</hi> back. I have not heard from them yet, but there would hardly be time for a reply.</p>
                
                <p>I have just sent copy of the picture of Black Elk on Harney Peak to Pocket Books. They seem very interested in preparing the Pocket Book edition of <hi rend="caps">BLACK ELK SPEAKS</hi>, which is to come out sometime in the spring. They use the expression "we'd like to being setting it now."</p> 
                
                <p>Mr. Shir-Cliff began his letter by thanking us for the wonderful news about <hi rend="caps">WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED</hi>. He states 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35c.5"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">5</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">
                    Gaki 
                    Page 2 
                    <date>October 13, 1971</date>
                </fw>
                
                    that a contract will reach us in about three weeks time.</p>
                
                <p>It appears that I am going to have to move my office again, and this is a bit of a problem. When I left the Guitar Building and moved down here, the intention of all of us was to acquire the building next door and it seemed that that would be possible. We have not been able to get it and we do not have enough room where we are. My books are in everybody else's office, and I have my library table and other office furniture in the basement at home. Since it now appears that we cannot get either the building north or the one south of us, we have been looking around for a place to move. It seems that I may have found a place, very near, which would make a good office. It will of course require fixing and some expense. I do hope that this will work out.</p> 
                
                <p>I was certainly very sorry to learn that Myrtle is having a repeat of her trouble. I will write her.</p> 
                
                <p>In the meantime, with this letter go my very best wishes to Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J. D.</hi></p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Love always,</salute> 
                
                    <signed>Hilda</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi></opener> <p>I have not heard anything more from John Kurland. If we do not hear something very soon, we shall need to take some further action. I am certainly not ignoring the situation.</p> 
                </postscript>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                    
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35c.6"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    990 <hi rend="caps">MISSION CANYON ROAD • SANTA BARBARA • CALIFORNIA</hi> 93105 
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>October 5, 1971</dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mrs. Hilda <hi rend="caps">N.</hi> Petri</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Spencer &amp; Petri</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>517 Guitar Building</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri 65201</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mrs. Petri.</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Well, I'm back in the country without having touched Missouri. This I regret very much. It seems easy to re-schedule an air flight through Kansas City--or sometimes even in St. Louis. But Columbia becomes another matter.</p>
                
                <p>The motion picture based on the bear incident will be released Thankgiving Day in 450 theatres...I hope one is near you. The film (and the book out at the same time) has really nothing to do with Hugh Glass, except the springboard of the bear incident. The story is largely that of the expedition dragging a keel-boat with mules around shallows and rapids, driven into the hills by Indians until the rivers freeze while the man left to die after the bear mauled him (Zachary Bass) heals himself and follows. Ecology and survival are the keynotes in the episodes involving the injured hunter.</p> 
                
                <p>You're not going to like it. It is <hi rend="caps">NOT</hi> <del>h</del><add>H</add>ugh Glass. I'm rather glad I couldn't prevail on anyone to use a stanza from your father's poem over the opening titles. It just wouldn't fit.</p> 
                
                <p>Finally I read the book we discussed by Keike Fekima--he changed his name for the book--the writing is about on a par with the Feike name. I can see where he owed the poem what flavor the book had, and an episode or two. He has abandoned hope of needling our film for a handout...which was all it amounted to.</p>
                
                <p>I will mail you a copy of the book <hi rend="underline">Man in the Wilderness</hi> as soon as it is out (paperback). I played on an <hi rend="caps">INDIAN THEME</hi>, which might have your father's approval, "Not the rifle; not the cannon; not even the horse <hi rend="caps">BUT THE WHEEL</hi> doomed the American Indian and built an empire."</p> 
                
                <p>My next opus will be filmed in Algeria and the Sahara, an 1882 tale about a French Expedition into the Hoggar mountains and against the fierce and unconquered "Men of the Veil," the Tuareg.</p> 
                
                <p>Hope your father is well and all is right with you and yours.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely</salute>
                
                    <signed>Jack De Witt</signed> 
                    <signed>Jack De Witt</signed>
                    
                    <note>JDk</note>
                </closer>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
