<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.1-3_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Bob Leaf to John G. Neihardt, October, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.1-3_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note>date from envelope</note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Bob Leaf to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-10">October, 1958</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.1-3_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">1</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Just spent the evening discussing you with my wife after reading her excerpts from the Cycle (Fink's fight with Carpenter, Hugh Glass's crawl and Death of Crazy Horse). She is hoping that you will be able to come east in the near future so that we could spend some time together.</p>
                
                <p>I have been reading up on your life recently because I am going to try to sell Reader's Digest an article about you for their series on the "Most Unforgettable Character" In times like these where all people read about is deceit, hypocricy and pessimism I feel they would be refreshed by someone who epitomizes positive value<add>s</add> and whose philosophy is not fraught with despair. Of course if you have any objections, I won't embark on the project.</p>
                    
                <p>It was very interesting reading about <hi rend="caps">JGN</hi> earlier in his career  Remember this quote:
                    <lb/>
                    "Education is the process of making a man rich in the only values that cannot be acquired by accident or theft in any of its many disguises, and that cannot be lost by any such means."</p>
                
                <p>This was when you spoke before the Nebraska Legislature after becoming Poet Laureate. I also read through Julius <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> House's book, John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt, Man and Poet. It certainly was an epithalmion to your work. The only critical (in an unfriendly sense) review I encountere<del>s</del><add>d</add> was by Laura Wood in the St. Louis Review, March 25 1933. She was questioning the underlying factor in your work was egoism or humility. She seemed to side with egoism and it was an unfortunate choice. I did not know you in those days but if your attitudes were basically the same then, she mistook enthusiasm for egoism. To me overbearin<del>h</del><add>g</add> humility<del>b</del>would be a worse fault because the Cycle could not be written unless the feeling of humilitywas<sic>humility was</sic> reserved for great forces only. A writer overburdened by humility
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.1-3_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">2</fw>
                
                    could never have understood Mike Fink or Hugh Glass.</p>
                
                <p>I am interested if you could lead me to any more material about you<del>.</del><add>,</add> that is easily acces<add>s</add>ible. If you give me permission to write about you I would also like you to send me information about your children and grandchildren. (Their ages, descritions<sic>descriptions</sic> to fill in my recollections) Also I would like you to write me all about your farm and especially about the Indian prayer garden (its description and all its meanings.<add>)</add> Any other material that you would feel would be beneficial I would appreciate and I would return it shortly. Also I'd like a description of the Indian relics in your home.</p>
                
                <p>While I have been on a Neihardt Renessaince the <del>st</del><add>de</add>sire to sell "The Story of Three Friends" has been rekindled. If you still give me permission to act as your agent, I am going to try to interest independent studios as the tendency in Hollywood is to get away from the major studios.</p>
                
                <p>This flurry of activity might appear odd to you but ever since Mrs Neihardt's departure the feeling has been etched <del><unclear>in</unclear>to m<unclear>e</unclear></del> that you cannot stay still and hope that things will remain stactic. The longer I wait the more who knew you, helped live y<del>p</del><add>o</add>ur experiences, and appreciated you as a man and a poet might be gone. Pardon me if I appear treacly but my relationship with you brings out a side of my naturevthatis<sic>nature that is</sic> very little evident in my relationships with others. I hope you are well and that I will hear from you soon.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Respectfully</salute>
                
                    <signed>Bob Leaf</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.1-3_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">R.</hi> Leaf
                    175 West 93rd St.
                    New York 24, <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="authorial"><hi rend="caps">AIR MAIL</hi></note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    NEW <unclear cert="high">YOR</unclear>K, N.Y. 17
                    OCT <unclear/>
                    2-PM
                    19<unclear cert="high">5</unclear>8
                    
                    GRAND CENTRAL 
                    STATION
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>LINCOLN
                    4¢
                    U.S. POSTAGE</p>
                </figure>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>UNITED.STATES.POSTAGE THREE 3 CENTS</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>