<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.1.9-18">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Nicholas Nathan Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, June 20, 1900</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Nicholas Nathan</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.1.9-18</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Nicholas Nathan</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Nicholas Nathan Neihardt to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1900-06-20">June 20, 1900</date>
                    <extent>10 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>10 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Nicholas Nathan</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Lulu</term>
                    <term>Neihardt-Ballinger, Grace</term>
                    <term>Tommie</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Manila (Philippines)</term>
                    <term>Hong Kong (China)</term>
                    <term>Singapore</term>
                    <term>Colombo (Sri Lanka)</term>
                    <term>Calcutta (India)</term>
                    <term>Springfield (Ill.)</term>
                    <term>Canada</term>
                    <term>China</term>
                    <term>Beijing (China)</term>
                    <term>San Luis (Philippines)</term>
                    <term>Butuan (Philippines)</term>
                    <term>Cuba</term>
                    <term>Pasig River (Philippines)</term>
                    <term>Cleveland (Ohio)</term>
                    <term>Columbia (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Rio Grade River (Panama)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Manila Times</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Nicholas Nathan</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/1689144">San Luis (Philippines)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5063451">Bancroft (Neb.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1900-06-20"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">9</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <fw>
                        Missouri Collection
                    </fw> 
                    
                    <dateline>
                        6-20-'00
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Son <unclear/>, S. S.</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Mr. John G. Neihardt.</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Bancroft Nebr.</addrLine> 
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Son:</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>yours of the 1st <unclear/>, and a most welcome message, reached here on the 16th inst.</p>
                <p>Though ,dear Son, may of mention, that this very kind letter of yours might have been a little more lengthy, by a line or two in reference to your Dear and most estimable Sisters, form whom I have not heard for many months</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">10</note>
                
                <p>page two</p>
                <p>In regard to your contemplated tour, and as regards fare by sail, ship, stage <unclear/>, am not at
                this writing able to inform you; I shall however collect all the necessary infor-mation in my power
                as speedily as possible. I have written to the Manila Times, and to-day also addrefs, Smith Bell v Co.-Manila sets of Canadian Pacific Railway <unclear/> Royal Mail Steem ShipLine. At present (as you are aware) it would be extremly dangerous to travel in the Chinese Empire as there is a cruel butchery carried on by the Boxers"</p> 

                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">11</note>

                <p>However in a year or two, affairs will be different in that part of The Orient. Though by water from
                Hong Kong to Singa-pore thence to Colombo, thence to Calcutta is and shall continue to be, a very pleasurable rout. I fear that I shall not be able to accompany you, in their contemplated trip, as my salary is small, and my ravings scant. However it would be of unspeakable pleasure; as the comrades say: "a constant round of pleasure."</p> 
                <p>I am so filled with awe, and wonder, to <del/> learn of your wonderful stride in education, and your Literary work, that</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">12</note>

                <p>know scarcely what to think or write; I can think of you only as little Tommie when playing, and
                feeding the Hoo Owl, and I can see the long string which you had fastened to its leg and too, think
                of the Cable-line that you built, the grip that your Inventive Genius built invented, and we get
                remember the Raccoon and its pranks,-bit rather hard at times, I know. Can you remember of the derrick which you built in the brick store at Springfield Illis.,?></p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">13</note>

                <p>It is 1.30 p.m. for dinner we had sweet potatos, breakfast bacon, coffee, (american) gravy, and excell-ent bread very fine indeed looked up the river at Canada about twelve miles from here. We have been getting bread from Manila until recently The Rainy Season has begun; when we came to this town, the natives were gathering a crop of corn to day I can see from in the Convent another crop growing on the same ground, and the corn seems to be five or more feet tall. Rain has been falling for about three days, but we need not worry so long as we remain in these quarters, the Convent.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">14</note>

                <p>It is 1.30 p.m. for dinner we had sweet potatos, breakfast bacon, coffee, (american) gravy, and excell-ent bread very fine indeed looked up the river at Canada about twelve miles from here. We have been getting bread from Manila until recently The Rainy Season has begun; when we came to this town, the natives were gathering a crop of corn to day I can see from in the Convent another crop growing on the same ground, and the corn seems to be five or more feet tall. Rain has been falling for about three days, but we need not worry so long as we remain in these quarters, the Convent.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">15</note>

                <p>two Regiments have been ordered to China near Peking, I shoudl like to have gone there. We may be called or ordered there yet. Hong Kong is about <del/> Six Hundred Forty miles from Manila.</p> 
                <p>I have been to the City twice since we came to San Lewis, our pass calls for three days leave of
                absence. Manila is improving I visited the tomb and obelisk of The Great Magellan, who was the first
                European (accent on 3rd syllable) to set foot upon the soil of the Arcipellago, he arrived at Butuan
                on Mindanao (mindanow) on the 31st day of March 1521. From thence he went to Cuba where the King with 800 others were baptized and swore allegience to the Spanish King</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">16</note>

                <p>the intrepid navigator met this death at their hands on the 26th day of April 1521. His monument stands on the left bank of the Pasig river; just outside of the walls, of manila.</p> 
                <p>Gomez Das-marinas (1590) by him were built the walls of Manila which to-day, although covered with moss, are still in a good state of preservation, and with their parapets, moats and ponderous gates and draw bridges, constitute a most curious relic of the Middle Ages.</p> 
                <p>In the year 1641 was one of serious and volcanic actions and disturbances in these <unclear/>. Terrestrial shocks were felt</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">17</note>

                <p>The Earth rocked and plunged, trees and church spires swung to and fro, like the masts of a ship in
                a storm; heavy timbers were smashed like reeds, walls tumbled down, and the heavy tiled roofs buried
                beneath their swims over 600 victims the shocks continued to be felt for two days. During the
                following months vice regal decrees were issued from beneath the shade of palm - trees. In adjacent
                places whole towns perished and mountains were submerged.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.1.9-18"/>
                <note type="curatorial">18</note>

                <p>The steamer "Cleveland passes up this river in the Eve and down so far as Columbia which is on the
                R. R. 14 miles distant; this boat is about 40 ft. long and to it are attached or fastened, Cas-cos,
                one two and sometimes three which are as long and nearly as broad as the Cleveland:" There is also a
                gun-boat. "Napindan" flying on this the Rio Grande. Have you received the photos which I sent ?</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>My regards to Sisters</salute> 
                    <signed>N. N. Neihardt. Co. L. 22nd San Lewis Philippines.</signed>
                </closer> 
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>