<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36a.44">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alton Larsen to John G. Neihardt, Julius D. and Myrtle Young, September 6, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36a.44</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alton Larsen to John G. Neihardt, Julius D. and Myrtle Young</title>
                    <date when="1972-09-06">September 6, 1972</date>
                    <extent>1 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 type-written page</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, and Young, Julius D. and Myrtle</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.44"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">44</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Blair, Nebraska 
                        September 6, 1972
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt, Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi>----</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Betty and I stopped to see you the other day, but found no one home.</p>
                
                <p>We had had the great disappointment of missing the Neihardt Day observance at Bancroft on August 6th. That was a terribly frustrating experience--we had started out from home early--perhaps 12:30--anticipating the day with relish. We had looked forward to seeing you, and I had my sketchbook along, as I had hoped to do some drawings during the autographing period.</p>
                
                <p>About ten miles from home, at Nickerson, Nebraska, we developed car trouble. A heater hose broke, spraying water over the motor and cracking the porcelain in the sparkplugs. With the voluntary help of a very nice young man who happened to be in Nickerson that afternoon, we finally had the car in running order again, but it was 5 o'clock and too late to do anything but go home.</p>
                
                <p>We stopped in Wayne the other day (on our way home from a weekend in Santee and Yankton) to see the bust which the college owns. It was interesting to see this one which was done at a different age than the one in the Capitol building. I liked it very much.</p> 
                
                <p>We met the new head librarian and one of his staff, and had a very nice visit with them. They showed us the Neihardt material that they have, and expressed great interest in building a good Neihardt "collection."</p> 
                
                <p>The new man, Mr. Stelling, has been there just one year, I believe. He asked us for information and we told him what we could, and that he must get in touch with the Youngs! We gave him the Lincoln address so you will probably hear from him. You may want to send him your complete list of published works, as he asked us for it.</p> 
                
                <p>The Neihardt file in their Archives does include many newspaper clippings, among these, the picture of poet, painter, poodle and portrait which appeared in the Lincoln paper at the time I did the painting. The librarian seemed surprised and pleased to meet the painter there in his library!</p>
                
                <p>We would like to stop in and visit with you soon--when might be a good time? The prospects for the for the museum at Bancroft sound exciting and we want to hear more about it. I would like very much to do some more sketches of you, Dr. Neihardt--pencil or charcoal, and possibly a quick oil sketch, not posed--perhaps some time while you are working, provided this would not bother you.</p> 
                
                <p>We hope you are well, and that we may see you soon.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Alton Larsen</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <fw>2</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
