<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.24.18-21">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, May 4, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.24.18-21</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1959-05-04">May 4, 1959</date>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975</term>
<term>Hiddy</term>
<term>Skilling, Edna</term>
<term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
<term>Lockwood, Samuel Pierson, 1879-1948</term>
<term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
<term>Thompson, Lynn</term>
<term>Thompson, Erica</term>
<term>Cook, W. B. "Dick"</term>
<term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
<term>Neihardt, Maxine Melton</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>New York</term>
<term>Fulton (Mo.)</term>
<term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
<term>Lake Cormorant, Miss.</term>
<term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
<term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
<term>Kansas City (Mo.)</term>
<term>Nebraska</term>
<term>San Diego (Calif.)</term>
<term>California</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Song of Jed Smith</term>
<term>The Tribune</term>
<term>The Missourian</term>
<term>Kansas City Star</term>
<term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
<term>The Song of the Messiah</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; validation</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0001a" />
                

            <opener>    
                <dateline>Skyrim, 5-4-'59 (Mon.)</dateline>
                
                
                <salute>Dear Lucile:</salute>
            </opener>
                <p>I wish I was looking at you and talking to you instead of writing a letter. How I do wish it!</p>
                
                <p>I'm glad you can regard 17 hours of teaching a week as "fun". That means, among other things, that you are <hi rend="underline">well</hi> and <hi rend="underline">happy</hi> in the work. Bower is back now, and you'll not be so crowded. Isn't it bully that you can take his classes?! I'd be interested to know what he was doing in N. Y. for three weeks. He does get around, doesn't he? Tell him I said hello.</p>
                
                <p>You ask about the Fulton talk. It was quite worthwhile. The enclosed is from
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0001b"/>
                    <note type="curatorial">47-4</note>
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    the sponsors, whom you may know. The word "spellbound" was used. I don't like the extreme words, but the audience (small and picked &#8212; all teachers) did sit very still and stare at me while I talked.</p>
                
                <p>The Benton-Neihardt bout was a rather happy success, it seems. People liked it, I'm assured, and C. College is happy. (They made <hi rend="underline">so very</hi> much of it in their voluminous publicity). I like Benton, and I do believe he likes me. We clicked, and with me he was very kind. (You may recall that he came to Branson to see us once. He said I was then working on Jed Smith). He asked if I'd let him paint my portrait, and of
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0002a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                    
                    course I'll let him. "Your family won't like it," he said; "but you and I will." He'll do it next fall when he is through with the Truman Library murals. The Missourian report of our affair was either pathetic or comical &#8212; I don't know which. 
                    <hi rend="underline">Why</hi> did they send a green kid to report us? And <hi rend="underline">how</hi> do such things get by down there? The Tribune was <del/> slightly better, not much. The K. C. Star had a good article, evidently done by an old hand. I'll see if I can get you a copy. At least it <hi rend="underline">does</hi> give some
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0002b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                    
                    idea as to what we said. It did more. People have called Hiddy up &amp; spoken enthusiastically about the affair.</p>
                
                <p>Two C. C. people came out here Monday to bring my first editions that were on display &amp; to give me my honorarium. I signed the check over to the C. C. Alumnae Fund. That <hi rend="underline">did</hi> me more good, by far, than the cash could have done. They are a fine outfit over there. The girls are so sweet, bless their young hearts!</p>
               
                <p>You're right about Mrs. Skillings, I know; and I'll do as you
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0003a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                    
                    say. I've written her about the afghan, of course. Maybe I can find a way later to slip something over on them. That's a sad place, isn't <del/>it?</p>
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">Yes</hi>, let's have some double petunias along with the carnations!</p>
                
                <p>Mona must be pleased, if somehow she knows, that you care for the bust she made. It was, I believe, intended to be some distance from the viewer. Mona was not satisified with it &#8212; but she never <hi rend="underline">was</hi> satisfied with her work.</p>
                
                <p>Mona <hi rend="underline">did believe</hi> in you and she was <hi rend="underline">fond of you</hi>. I think I told you that she
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0003b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    classified you as a "dog", (as distinguished, of course, from the "cat" woman. She liked some cats, but didn't quite trust them!) Mona was definitely canine &#8212; <hi rend="underline">a collie</hi>, I'd say. (I think you're a collie too!) I've owned <del/><add>two</add> collie dogs, and according to me, it's a high compliment to be likened to <hi rend="underline">that</hi> breed. (Nobody has so described <hi rend="underline">me</hi>. Samuel Pierson Lockwood once insisted that I was "a cross between a horse and a leopard that the makers of mythology overlooked to their detriment"!)</p>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                
                <p>The  bubble figure in my poetry must  be of early origin. In various ways, I now realize, it has popped up throughout my stuff. It's in the <hi rend="underline">Wars</hi> and the <hi rend="underline">Messiah</hi>. I'd never thought of it as your friend does.</p>
                
                <p>Three more weeks, and then the final exams! After the grade cards are in, I'll be off for Lake Cormorant, Miss., to see Alice, Lynn, Erica, Mr. Cook and the sweet horses! I'll be back to harvest my wheat. <note type="authorial">I've been reading the dissertation a great deal. It <hi rend="underline">is</hi> a fine job!</note> And then &#8212; O my Gosh! &#8212; maybe you'ns will arrive here! Just think</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.18-21_0004b"/>
                <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                
                <p>I'll be looking at you, and <hi rend="underline">maybe</hi> we'll visit Wayne and Bancroft &#8212; and K. C. on the way! <hi rend="italic">If</hi> you make the Neb. <del/> trip, what will you do afterwards? Go home? I'm planning a trip on a coasting vessel to San Diego. So many old friends and some relatives are in So. Calif. Sig and little Maxie are there now &#8212; just arrived by car with a <add>small</add> trailer. Old Lady Max is still here, holding down the trailer home. She'll go in a month or so.</p> 
               
                <p>The new Hackney boy colt is built thus: <figure/> Very short from fore to aft, but <hi rend="underline">tall</hi>, and his neck mounts like a tower! Oh, I don't see you at all!</p> <closer><signed>John</signed></closer> <note type="authorial">Yo-Yo is still my faithful bodyguard. She sends happy woofs and arfs to Stewart.</note> <closer><signed>Jno.</signed></closer>

                
                <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>