<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.31.1-8">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, January 6, 1961</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.31.1-8</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1961-01-06">January 6, 1961</date>
                    <extent>16 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>16 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>16 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1884-1980</term>
<term>Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919</term>
<term>Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt, 1861-1933</term>
<term>Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
<term>Hodges, William</term>
<term>Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946</term>
<term>Gray, Sanford</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>New York (N.Y.)</term>
<term>Chicago (Ill.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
<term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
<term>The Roosevelt Family of Sagamore Hill</term>
<!--<term>Mr. Waters</term> later became The Dawn Builder -->
<term>The Dawn Builder</term>
<term>The Man from Home</term>
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Metadata Encoding</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0001a" />
                <note type="curatorial">121 8                   Aly Collecti</note>
                
                <opener>
                <dateline>Skyrim, 1-6-'61</dateline>
                
                
                <salute>Dear Lucile:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It <hi rend="underline">was</hi> bully to hear from you again, as always! It's always a real event.</p>
                
                <p>You evidently had a "veridical" dream &#8212; or at least, it may well be so. When you were dreaming of us all (and note that you <hi rend="underline">did</hi> seem to see us <hi rend="underline">all</hi>, or at least felt conscious of us) <hi rend="underline">we were all together at Skyrim</hi>. There were 13 of us &#8212; children, sons-in-law, and grandchildren and we were <del/> celebrating the new year. It was a champagnish evening, ending
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0001b"/>
                    <note type="curatorial">on</note>
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    after midnight! It is probable that our rejoicing <hi rend="underline">in unison</hi> somehow got to you. Anyway, it could be so. I'm <hi rend="underline">so glad</hi> you did feel us, as I <del/> believe you did. Alice &amp; Enid have seen your letter and I'll show it to Hilda. (They don't like you at all, just as this old man doesn't too!!)</p>
               
                <p>So <hi rend="underline">this</hi> is the Year of the Biography! Hurrah! I wish I could be on call at your service while you're writing, because I'm a heck
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">1</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0002a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial"><del><unclear>-3-</unclear></del>-3-</fw>
                    
                    of a good authoritative source, willing to tell anything resonably decent about my experiences! Truly, I could, and can, help you a great deal. Documents are of great value, but in some instances they are untrustworthy. I do want you to question me whenever you need my memories. And as you have noted, I <hi rend="italic">do remember</hi>. I did not realize that my remembering, as I do, was unusual; but I've come to know it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> so.</p>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0002b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                    
                    <p>I'm sending three letters on my appearances at the Westerners dinner in New York City. I showed <del><unclear>them</unclear></del><add>them</add> to old Bower. (By the way, it was a joy to be with him <del/> even for a short time. You know, I don't like him <del/> either!) You may return the letters in your next after you've copied the right paragraph from each. I may want them again. Then later you'll have them with many other letters that have been turning up.</p>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">2</fw>
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0003a"/>
                <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                
                <p>This reminds me to say that I'm deeply interested in the plan for the "Neihardt Memorial Collection" (Library and Papers) here. When you are through with the things I've given you, they will be deposited <del/> here, I know. As for the collection you've made at considerable expense, I'd hope it also might <hi rend="underline">ultimately</hi> be here, and in my will I am indicating that you are to
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0003b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    be reimbursed for your expenditures, <hi rend="italic">if</hi> you turn your collection over to Missouri. If you want your material in the Congressional Library or elsewhere, microfilm copies will come to Missouri anyway.</p>
                
                <p>I know there's something pathetic about my caring <del/> so much about this matter. I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> I'll be so far away that this will all be less than nothing
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    to me. But I did try <del/> hard to say something about life here &#8212; something worth saying and good for others like me to hear; and the "Memorial" <hi rend="underline">should help</hi> <hi rend="triple underline">awhile</hi>. <del/> I don't need to tell you, for you <hi rend="underline">know</hi>. O how you <hi rend="italic">do</hi> know, good and wise Lady!</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0004b"/>    
                    <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                    
                    <p>Here is a big idea!! Tell me what you think of it, and whether you care to follow it up. You may already know that <hi rend="underline">The Indian Wars</hi> was chosen as one of the 500 books from World Literature to be the White <del/> House Library. (This, I seem to remember, was in Hoover's <del>admin<unclear/></del> administration.) Well, Alice Roosevelt Longworth was one of the national committee that chose the 500 books for the White House Library. This committee was from all parts of <hi rend="caps">U. S.</hi> Alice Longworth is, as you know, still living.
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">4</fw>
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.18_0005a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-9-</fw>
                    
                    Would you, as my biographer, care to write her? You would want to mention the fact that her daddy, Theodore <hi rend="caps">R</hi>, knew &amp; liked <hi rend="underline">Hugh Glass</hi>, as I learned from Corinne R. Robinson at the Poetry Society banquet in 1927. Alice Longworth, I'm told, is a fine person, and perhaps she would give you something usable in <del/> your work. You'd seem to be writing
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0005b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-10-</fw>
                    
                    to learn about the White House Library, as you understand that she was a member of the committee that chose the <del><unclear>books</unclear></del> books. Could she name the others on the committee?? Did she ever speak with her daddy about <hi rend="italic">Glass</hi>? You'd know how to ask the proper questions. And you'd tell how my admiration for <hi rend="caps">T. R.</hi> has increased with the years, and
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">5</fw>
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0006a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-11-</fw>
                    
                    that I now think of him as <hi rend="underline"><del/> <add>the</add></hi> great exemplar of high virtues <del/><add>that certainly are not</add> conspicuous in our <add>troubled</add><del/> world. I read and read about <del><unclear/>and</del> him, and always I feel uplifted as I read. You might want to say that Herman Hagedorn, <hi rend="caps">T. R.</hi>'s biographer and intimate friend of the family, wrote in a presentation copy of his <hi rend="underline">The Roosevelt Family of Sagamore Hill</hi>,
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0006b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-12-</fw>
                    
                    "To John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt, a poet after <hi rend="caps">T. R.</hi>'s own heart".</p>
                
                <p>I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> want to get closer to <hi rend="caps">T. R.</hi> I should <del><unclear>have</unclear></del><add>have</add> known him. He was a <hi rend="underline">great romantic as <del/> all real aristocrats are</hi>. (And I know what <hi rend="underline">I</hi> mean by "aristocrat," and so do you.) They all believe that there are values greater than life &#8212; &#8212; <hi rend="underline">and so do I</hi>!</p>
                
                <p>Yes, you'll find some good stuff in the files of the old Smart Set.
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0007a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-13-</fw>
                    
                    You will find my novelette, "Mr. Waters" which later became "The Dawn Builder", Liebler &amp; Co. (the great impresa<del/>rios of Broadway) had me <del/><add>come</add> to Chicago to meet William Hodges who <hi rend="underline">was</hi> to be Mr. Waters in a play based on the novelette. Hodges was the rage then, as he was playing the lead in Tarkington's "The Man from <del/><add>Home</add>"
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0007b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial"><del/>-14-</fw>
                    
                    You never heard of this, did you? There is <del/><add>more</add> that I have not yet told. I need to be near you. In this episode I once again <hi rend="underline">almost</hi> <del/> won loud fame and fortune. But always I was spared that supreme test. Over &amp; over I've been on the edge of great doings, but always I've been forced back to the principal job. <hi rend="underline">This is worth considering</hi>.
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">7</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0008a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-15-</fw>
                    
                    I was <hi rend="underline">never</hi> to enjoy <del><unclear>and</unclear></del> <add>any</add> great <add>worldly</add> reward. I was to do my very best for the mere satisfaction of doing it.</p>
                
                <p>I'm glad old Stewart will use my little check for second-hand books. When he writes me about books he has bought, I'll send him another check. Book-hunting <hi rend="underline">is real adventure</hi>.</p>
                
                <p>Yes, I'd love to see those <del/> wubs you had in your home for Xmas. I know they'd like this <del>old Gaki</del> old Gaki, because I love them.</p>
                
                <p>And Perky! Precious
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.31.1-8_0008b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-16-</fw>
                    
                    sweet little people! I'd love to hug her again &amp; be thoroughly licked by her!</p>
                
                <p>Poor Sandy! I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> wish he could <hi rend="underline">act</hi>. That is a good record, and I'd like to see it out. I must write him, but will that do any good? Your blurb for the record is excellent, as I wrote you.</p>
                
                <p><del>Black Elk</del>
                    <lb/>
                    <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> will be printed in February. I did a <del/>new Preface.</p>
                
                <p>As to Xmas, did you ever see the verses I did for Hilda when she was five years old?</p>
                
                <p>Isn't this a <hi rend="underline">perfectly lovely</hi> letter??! I'll write more later.</p> <closer><salute>Love to you all.</salute>      <signed>John</signed></closer> 
                
                <fw type="curatorial">8</fw>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
