<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0001-9">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John Galen Howard to John G. Neihardt, August 14, 1921</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.8.10-18_0001-9</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John Galen Howard to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1921-08-14">August 14, 1921</date>
                    <extent>8 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisneau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0001" />
                
                <fw type="curatorial">10</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Sun 14 Aug 21</dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear John,&#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I hope you don't think too badly of me for my unconscionable inaction in correspondence. The truth is I'm no good at all at all when it comes to letter writing. You have been in my thought of thoughts all the time, yes &#8212; my heart of hearts, but other things have crowded out the <unclear>tiny</unclear> thing which should have expressed to you &#8212; so many things. Well, first, the joy I felt at knowing the poetry prize had been awarded you. It is so de-
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0002"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
                
                    served that in a way it seems almost unnoticeable &#8212; just what might be expected in the ordinary course of events &#8212; no head-line stuff. Only when one thinks how rarely great ment is recognized &#8212; both in the sense of seeing and in the sense of crowning &#8212; does one realize how well worth while (mere <unclear>mainly</unclear> apart) it is to take some notice of such a presentation. There are a lot of sane, right minded folk in this world of ours, and they are the ones you are speaking to, the ones who listen, and the ones who are not afraid to speak up and say their say in little deeds like <unclear>praises</unclear>. I was glancing over <unclear>Unter-</unclear>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0003"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
                    
                    <unclear>meyer's</unclear> book of Modern American Verse (?) on a department store counter, the other day, where I was hunting for cheap underwear or something, and turning to his Neihardt shelf of samples (as to the choices) I was made to foam at the mouth by his fore word<sic>foreword</sic>, as who should <unclear>print</unclear> the reader <hi rend="underline">away</hi> from what <del>should</del> follows. Those things he lays up <unclear>afin</unclear> you, endear you to me, but not those things alone, by a long shot. If it weren't so mean a manner of putting over propaganda to anthologise live stuff with prefaces I should urge you to anthologise back at him and all his many like. My God! What an anthology you could make, if you cared to set about it!
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0004"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
                
                    And it's legitimate, if the stuff you want to put over is legitimate. Try it, one of these days &#8212; after, but not before, you feel your fires waning, (<add>^which</add> God forbid these sixty years ar least!): "not before", I say, only because nothing must be permitted to distract you from the ardent practice of your prose, while ardency is in your veins. Not but that a change from time to time is<del/> good for ardency too. I read last month The Splendid Wayfaring &#8212; the first chance I had had &#8212; and feel again something of "the kick of The River + I. This is great stuff, John, my beloved; great art. In its 
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0005"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">2</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                
                    way as flawless as Hugh Glass and Three Friends, and those supreme felicities and finalities, your lyric masterpieces. I love these things with a <del>depth</del><add>heat</add> of love which would scorch this shut to try to express &#8212; so I won't try to, for I've gotta get it off to you or you'll think me a regular rosy a-week for manners. &#8212;The only thing about your moving to the Ozarks I don't like is that it wasn't westward. I'd so counted on your coming where I could touch you, see you, hear you. But that was just selfish &#8212; but is, not wholly, either, for I believe in California
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0006"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
                
                    and its power, its rays of freedoms. Not that you need that &#8212; you can win &#8212; have won &#8212; all of that you need, anywhere. Only it's easier here &#8212; less lost motion &#8212; for me at least. &#8212; <unclear>Fancycomo</unclear>, what a divine Italiany name for a poet's lake. was it really ready made or did you make it? &#8212; My boy Bob, the painter, has been <unclear>rusticating</unclear> at the Italian Como, after killing himself over his Road to Hell, which he got into the Salon. A wonder boy &#8212; you must hear some of his letters. Henry too has been doing magnificently at the Beaux Arts &#8212; he is the architect, you know. Chalres, No 3, is to follow literature, + 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0007"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
                    
                    goes back to Harvard this fall for graduate work. And No. 4 is devoured with wanderlust, so he will be going off somewhere, perhaps to the ends of the earth for a while. That leaves me alone with my women-folks. Even they are away for a few days &#8212; You'd think under those conditions I would have lots of time for Cézanouet. Not a bit of it. I am over <unclear/> and ears in architectural work the most creative kind, which keeps the pen in abeyance mostly the <unclear>price</unclear> still advances, slowly, and not less surely I think. But I must have a while away sometime before long and
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0008"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
                
                    throw myself into it wholly. It gets clearer and clearer and stronger in my in most being all the time. I'll send you some more of it when I have rounded up <del/> the next phase. &#8212; Did you meet the Noyes(es) (is that the plural?) George + Florence when you were here? Of course you did. They are abroad this year + George sent me this clipping. He well knows my devotion to <hi rend="caps">JGN</hi>. The Guardian is a bit flippant; but by its notice you may be said to have become "international" even according to its own standards! &#8212; Do write me soon enough to show you don't have it in for me for being so long in writing to you.</p>
                
                <p>With warm regards to Mrs Neihardt, your mother, grandmother, and children,</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours from the heart</salute>
                    
                    <signed>John Howard</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.10-18_0009"/>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    SAN FRANCISCO CALIF
                    AUG 14
                    630 PM
                    1921
                    
                    ADDRESS YOUR MAIL TO STREET AND NUMBER
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>2 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S.POSTAGE 2 CENTS 2</p>
                </figure>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt Esq</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Box 1A5</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Branson</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="authorial">See over</note>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
