<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Phil and Gail Lincoln and Children to John G. Neihardt, September 3, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Phil and Gail Lincoln and Children to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-09-03">September 3, 1959</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Neihardt Collection</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">47</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        74 Great Plain Road
                        Norwich, Connecticut
                        September 3, 1959
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>This ruptured disc of mine is apparently going to lie low and not pester me, so perhaps the Lincoln family will be able to get back into some sort of normal routine again. Actually, I've been happily back at my desk in the publications section of Electric Boat Division, General Dynamics Corporation, since the twentieth of July. And expect for a few sensations of stiffness now and then I've had no further difficulty. According to a Boston neuro-surgeon, the disc has started to heal by itself. At any rate, he decided against an operation unless it kicks up again.</p>
                
                <p>One good thing came of that three months in the hospital: I dropped from 238 pounds down to a real trim 195. This is the weight the doctor suggested I try to maintain, because every excess pound lessens the chances of making a complete recovery from that black business. Besides, it really feels great to be comparatively skinny again. Must confess I've put on about five pounds since I've been home, but it was impossible for me to ignore the sweet corn season in the face of such a plentiful local supply. And boiled lobsters, of course, particularly when you dip 'em into melted butter, aren't exactly diet fare.</p>
                
                <p>We're faithful subscribers to The Missourian, and every once in a while Gail will find something that makes her real homesick for the Midwest. And now that the football season is getting underway, Chris isn't too happy about being so far away from his beloved Missouri Tigers. We'd love to come back for
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">48</fw>
                
                    a homecoming sometime. We've already made tentative plans to drive to Pennsylvania next fall when Missouri plays Penn State away from Columbia.</p>
                
                <p>There's nothing like a good stretch of painful hospitalization to straighten out your sense of values. I decided not to worry any longer about things which are scheduled to happen sometime in the dim future. There's just too darned much going on right now. Nor are we going to let ourselves become so concerned about so many of the little annoyances of everyday living. This trip through life is a relatively short one, and we've decided not to clutter it up with non-contributing trivia.</p>
                
                <p>Right now we're comfortably settled in a three-bedroom house located about 13 miles from the plant. 'Course, it's not really big enough for us, but it'll do nicely while we're casting about for something to buy. Trouble is, every handsome old Colonial we've found that's for sale is usually 'way up in the $25.000-$35,000 price range. And even the Colonials that are in desperate need of paint and repairs are outrageously priced. Property close to the ocean is just impossible. Besides, most of it is pretty well jammed up in typical summer-cottage fashion. Our best bet, probably, will be to go inshore about 20 miles and just cruise around. That seems t'be the way most of the people we know have found the house they wanted--and could afford. We intend to buy a huge old place, preferably a Colonial, that will give us at least five or six bedrooms, plenty of elbow room all
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">49</fw>
                
                    around the house and a fine assortment of outbuildings in which the kids can play in rainy weather. And certainly we'll need lots of guest rooms to accommodate all the folks we know west of the Mississippi who've promised to come and visit us.</p>
                
                <p>I'm working with other technical editors, most of whom are English majors from Columbia, Trinity, Wesleyan, and Princeton. Happy to report that I'm more than holding up the good reputation of the University of Missouri. My technical editing job is really much more interesting than perhaps it sounds. In our particular section, each editor is assigned to a particular engineering article, proposal, report, etc., and he sticks with it right to the end. He must sit in on engineering conferences, review background material that might be useful in the current job, edit and rewrite the stuff he gets from the engineering sections involved. He's responsible, too, for setting up the report format, organizing the material, selecting appropriate drawings, photographs, illustrations, etc., and laying out the textual matter for final printing. We even punch the printed stuff and bind it with spiral plastic gadgets to make the finished product. All in all, it's a satisfying and surprisingly creative sort of thing.</p>
                
                <p>I'd like to say again that I got more out of your Critical Essay and Epic America courses than any other class I had at the University. More to the point, I got more out of <hi rend="underline">you</hi>. Thanks again, sir. I'm most grateful.</p>
                
                <p>Please remember us to all the family.</p>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I just wanted to add a line to tell you that I think of you all so often and the lovely country and beautiful animals at Skyrim Farm. Many
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.47-50_0004"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">50</fw>
                
                        of the, all too few, moments we were privileged to share there with you and your family remain among the best of our Missouri memories. We plan to make at least a short visit back there in the not too distant future &#8212; tho<sic>though</sic> it'll probably be two or three years. Do give my best to the Petri's and the Finks &#8212; and Alice &amp; girls when you see them. Tell Mona I think of her often and have guest confidence in her ability to do something fine with her talent.</p>
                
                    <p>If you ever find yourself in the vicinity for an<del/><add>y</add> reason please let us know as we'd so enjoy being with you for a good conversation again. &#8212; We always have plenty of room.</p>
                    <closer>
                        <salute>With love &amp; good wishes always,</salute>
                        
                        <signed>Phil &amp; Gail Lincoln
                            &amp; children</signed>
                    </closer>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>