<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35b.22-25">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Dr. Guy G. Becknell to John G. Neihardt, August 29, 1971</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.35b.22-25</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Guy G. Becknell to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1971-08-29">August 29, 1971</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.22"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">DR. GUY G. BECKNELL 
                        <lb/>
                    6900 DIXON AVENUE 
                        <lb/>
                    TAMPA, FLORIDA</hi> 33604 
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>August 29, 1971.</dateline> 
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt,</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska;</addrLine> 
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt: </salute>
                </opener>
                I have seen you several times on television in the last few years, the last time being the long interview on the Dick Cavitt show. So I decided to write to you, and to recall to you a meeting about 60 years ago. 
                Do you recall a nice little city in northern Ind-iana named Goshen? It must have been about the year 1910, and you were visiting our mutual friend Mr. Noble Krei-der. My parents lived in Goshen too, and there my father was a physician and surgeon. We were friends of the two doctors Kreider, one being Noble's father. 
                I was home for the summer from Clark University, Worcester, Massachusetts, where I had been appointed as research assistant to one of the greatest mathematical physicists of the world, Dr. Arthur Gordon Webster, and in 1910 and 1911 I was Senior Fellow in Physics. 
                I will say that Dr. Webster was allowed to have ten graduate students in any one year. At this time all were candidates for the Ph.D. Degree. My position was that of Senior Fellow, the top position because of what I ac-complished for him the year before. 
                In Goshen you may recall that we went walking on a couple of days along the canal and the Elkhart River, and you and Noble Kreider, and I, sat up in the big trees along the river and discussed poetry, science, philoso-phy, music and what not. Noble was a very fine pianist and composer and I have missed him very much since his death about twelve years ago. The last time my wife and I saw him was when we went to Fort Wayne about 1959, and saw him in the Veteran's Hospital. 
                Now I am past 93 in age, and in excellent health; but most of my old friends in the faculty of the University of Tampa, much younger than I, keep me alive. Many people guess my age to be in the late 60s or early 70s. 
                In 1911 there were only three of us who took our PH.D.s in mathematics and physics. They were Robert God-dard, the Rather of Rocketry and Moon memory, Solomon Lefschetz, and I. Goddard is most famous of course and I was trained with him for two years as Webster's Research Assistant and Senior Fellow, Dr. Lefschetz with whom I still correspond is retired at Princeton as America's Greatest Mathematician who received the National Medal. 
                Today I know more about the Shakespeare First Folio of 1623 than any person has ever known since Bacon's Death. 
                (over<del>(</del><add>)</add> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.23"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                
                The entire history of the Elizabethan Era was securely based on Fraud of one kind or another, beginning with the lie that Bess Tudor was the "Virgin Queen." Perhaps in her earliest days she did display a sharp mind, but her "Sweet Robin" Dudley soon led her into the most re-volting debauchery, and finally into sodomy, after his death by poisoning at the hand of Bess. 
                In 1603 ten thirty-third degree masons from Italy and England met in London to decide what to do about the sodomist monster on the throne of England. They voted unanimously that she be poisoned, and appointed her elder son, Francis Bacon, to carry out the edict. Since he was born in Windsor Castle he dressed as a demented maid servant and went into the kitchens and bedrooms of the castle picking up information about his mother's unnatural habits. He learned that she was "Hog-Fond" of rancid, rotten, suet-pudding. So he prepared a dish of pudding well saturated with ratsbane. On the second trial he succeeded. 
                Her funeral was carried out by prominent Freemasons, and her remains did not go to Westminster. Her leaden coffin with a solid gold lid did go to Westminster, but filled with cow-manure. her remains were buried at night under Bacon's barn at St. Albans. He preferred to kill his own mother, and save the honor of England. 
                In 1616 Ben Jonson heard in a law trial that Will Shaxper of Stratford had been paid to murder Marlowe. So he set out for Stratford with Michael Drayton and John Selden to call on the "London Sewer-Rat." It was not a social call, and William died soon afterward. He was also buried under Bacon's barn in 1619 by the Masons. 
                Bacon did not die in 1626 as lying history says, but became a monk writer in Rome. Stratford today is a fraudulent racket, and Francis Carr is trying to get permis-sion to open the tomb and show Bacon's remains are there on the Avon. Ben Johnson knew that Bacon was the "Sweet Swan of Avon." 
                Dr. Neihardt, of your many publications I have Man Song. Bundle of Myrrh, The Song of Hugh Glass, and The River and I. My daughter is especially fond of The River and I. 
                For my wife's wishes we held no funeral, but a memorial of poetry. Even the prayer was in poetic form. Her father, James Harcourt West, was a good poet and a young contemporary of the older Longfellow, Holmes, Lowell, Hawthorne, and Emerson; and correspond with them. He was a Bostonian, and long in charge of the Tufts College Press. 
                I hope you may live to be 100 years old. 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute> <signed>G.G. Becknell.</signed> 
                </closer>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.24"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener>Some <unclear>True</unclear> History.</opener> 
                
                In 1910 I secured some sample pages from the Oxford Facsimile Shake-speare first folio of 1623, and showed them to an uncle who had a very fine ana-lytic mind. Within a half hour of examination he thoroughly agreed with me that the folio was the most remarkable piece of work that ever same from a printing press. So he bought for me the only copy of this Facsimile made by a photographic process then available in New York. He paid $50 which was the subscription price, and only 1000 were ever printed. This Oxford masterpiece was reproduced from the Duke of Devonshire's copy which is the most perfect original in existence. After 60 years of use it is in perfect condition, and I value it at at least $10,000. 
                With the student help I built in my shop a photostatic camera 6 ft. by 6 ft. by 4 feet, with double doors for entrance. A movable shelf outside the doors tightly closed. The copies were 12 by 16 inches, and beautiful copies were made of small portions of the text magnified about five times. The size of the folio may be judged when I tell you that there are 900 pages, in double columns, with 66 lines to a column. This book made for research purposes is printed, on heavy cream-colored paper, and the pages are larger than the originals, so as to leave a nice border. 
                At present I am the only person in the world who can read masonic code which is also found in other books of the Elizabethan Era. The best cryptog-raphers int eh world were unable to find this code, and coudl not use it even if I told the rules. It takes a long trained eye, and an unusual knowledge of Tudor times. One must know Old London as well as he knows his own home town. 
                The author was born in the throne room of Windsor Castle on the night of March 7-8, 1560 to Bess Turdor as a bastard, but as the most amazing super-genius ever on earth. His father was the perfumed fop, Robert Dudley, who recorded his birth in the British record office in London under the name Thomas Tidir. Hence the Shakespeare Sonnets Dedication is signed T.T. 
                also in the base of the Shakespeare statue in Westminster are cast the date and the initals T.T. His brother, born seven years later and recorded by the Earl of Leicester under the name of Robert Stuart Tidir, grew up to be the Earl of Essex, his mother's lover. 
                The Bacons came to this boy at Windsor when nine years of age and told him they were his jparents. To save his life the Bacons agreed to claim the boy as their own, and agreed with Bess, to rename him Francis Bacon. They recorded his false date of birth as February 22, 1561, thinking that would make safe the legend of "The Virgin Queen." 
                Bacon's mental capacity and ability to work endlessly without much sleep enabled him to produce all the greatest works in literature during the Eliz-abethan reign and much of that in the reign that followed. Single handedly he translated the King James Bible. The commission appointed by Bishop Andrews was only a make-believe to throw off suspicion from Bacon by his intimate friend Bishop Lancelot Andrews. 
                The great folio of 1623 took forty years to write, and it was done at the secret headquarters of the Avon Lodge of Freemasons. That location was directly under Bess Tudor's library in the Tower of London in three of her storage rooms. She had ten such rooms, and allowed nobody to serach those rooms without her orders. That suited her son precisely, for it made secure his secret headquarters. Bacon's name for this was "The Masonic Na-bob's Residence Hall." All he needed for <del/> security was a keeper of the tower who was a dedicated Freemason. In this way he oculd use his mother's fine library whenever she was not in London. He hired a trusty boy to watch at the entrance of the tower and for any suspicious character entering, and he informed Bacon by means of a lantern hung where he could see it at his work table and be on the watch. Bess hated the masons since she rightly blamed them for anonymous notes sent her commenting on her immorality and horse incest. 
                
                <note type="curatorial">(over)</note> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.35b.25"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw> 
                <fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
                
                Jonathan Swift says, "When a true genius appears in the world, you may know him by this sign, that the dunces are all in confederacy against him." This was particularly true of Bacon all his life long, and it persists today due to the liars and perhaps criminals who maintain Stratford as a moth-eaten tourist center. Stratford should be fumigated, and prepared for recognition of the last resting place of the greatest all-round genius who ever lived. for the Masons placed his remains in the tomb at Stratford when he died in a rose-tinted old monastery in Rome, Italy. He had died a stage-death in 1626, escaped by assistance from his fellow Masons to Rome, and became a monk writer on Roman and modern law. At least that was the plan, and I am sure that the ten members of the Avon Lodge Carried out his wishes to the letter. 
                Bacon says that the early Masons were "Pen Hornets." So they were and some rascals, including the degenerate Queen, hated them to the limit. So Bacon humorously remarks that the masons of his day were not ring-weraing Masons. One of the great troubles of the modern Masons is that they are all lit-tle but a social organization, not an organization standing for truth in everything, even history. So Bacon wrote into all his works the current and some past history in a beautiful manner. When all the history secretly hidden in the folio is translated, it will make ten volumes each as large as the folio. To do this will take cetnuries, but at last we will get the upper hand of the liars who have recorded our ealse history, and false biographies in our encyclopedias. 
                Bacon for protection again his savage mother and her supporters had to bury much of his genius under straw names. The following names Bacon calls his Gin-Rat Straw-Men. He paid them enough money for Liquor to get the use of their names. First of all he changed the ignorant Willem Shaxper of Stratford to Master William Shakespeare, and introduced this sewer-rat to his mother as a great literary genius. Here is the list of Gin-rats. 
                William Shakespeare, Kit Marlowe, Sir Philip Sidney, Edmund Spenser, John Marston, Robert Burton, Thomas Nash, and Joshua Sylvester. 
                Two others who were Bacon's fellow Masons gave him the use of their names as a favor to the founder of Masonry. They were 
                Seigneur Montaigne, and Richard Hakluyt. 
                The latter was the author (pretended) of those most famous of sea stories, "The Principall Navigations, Voyages, and Discoveries of the English Nation." Bacon wrote most of these while with Drake in the East Indies. Bacon owned a third of that famous ship that circumnavigated the globe THE GOLDEN HIND. 
                At nine years of age the Bacons sent Francis to study navigation and astron-omy under Sir John Napier at Edinburgh. Napier had just developed the equa-tions used today in all navigation known as "Napier's Analogies." Bacon mastered this in a couple of months, and met Dare Devil Drake at the age of ten years. Drake was so deeply impressed with this scientific master of navigation that he took him along on his first piratical voyage to Labrador, Tampa Bay (Headquarters for a month), and the West Indies in 1570. 
                Bacon the master psychologist cleverly worked on Drake's fiendish mind until he convinced him that he would make Drake famous if he would only listen. He had a hard time convincing Drake that hand soap and laundry soap were an absolute necessity to thwart disease on such a long trip. 
                Bacon was the the Court of Navarre, but Drake took him on board as his sole adviser on the trip at Brest, France. 
                The author of Drake's very interesting biography entitled "Immortal Pirate" marvels at the fact <add>^that</add> the young highly cultured <add>Bacon and the rough sea-<unclear>rat</unclear> Drake could be close friends. They were both dare-devils.</add> 
                
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>