<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 4
youngs
FRIENDS OF THE LIBRARY
UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI
COLUMBIA, MISSOURI
65201
April 12, 1971

Dear Friend:
<p>Enclosed is your invitation and reservation blank for our Annual Dinner Meeting, Saturday, May 8.</p>
<p>At the dinner we will present the annual Stuckey Award to the high school senior who wins our essay contest.</p>
<p>Our speaker for the dinner will be Roy M. Fisher, the new Dean of the School of Journalism of the University of Missouri of Columbia.</p>
<p>Enclosed also is a ballot to be returned by April 30.</p>
<p>The Council and membership will meet in the afternoon from 2:00-3:00 in Room 105 of the University Library. From 3:30-4:30 Acting Chancellor and Mrs. Herbert W. Schooling will entertain members and their guests with a reception in the faculty lounge. The dinner will be held in the Memorial Student Union at 6:30.</p>
<p>We hope that you can join us for some or all of these events on Saturday, May 8.</p>
Cordially yours,
W. W. Dalton                            Harry A. Bulter
President                               Secretary

HAB:san
Enclosures
Serving the Libraries of the University of Missouri on Four Campuses

Page 5
youngs
2
$100 AWARD FOR DESIGN
<p>The Friends of the Library of the University of Missouri wish to announce the offer of a $100 award for the design of a bookplate to be used by the University Library to acknowledge gift books donated through the Friends organization. Friends of the Library, all students and alumni of the University of Missouri are eligible to enter this contest.</p>
<p>Entries will be judged by a jury, representing the Library, the Friends, and Art Departments of various campuses of the University. All entries become the property of the Friends organization. In the event that no design is submitted on which the judges agree, the Friends reserve the right to make no award.</p>
<p>Bookplates will be submitted on white poster board size 2 3/4" x 4" using no more than three colors. The design should incorporate the name "Friends of the Library of the University of Missouri, Columbia".</p>
<p>First prize will be $100 and a lifetime membership in the Friends of the Library organization. Second prize: a lifetime membership. Third prize:a book. Awards will be made at the annual Friend's dinner, April 15, 1972. Deadline for entries will be April 5, 1972. Submit entry to Secretary, Friends of the Library, Library, Room 103, University of Missouri, Columbia, Missouri, 65201.</p>
LIFETIME MEMBERS OF THE FRIENDS
<p>The following is a list of lifetime members of the Friends of the Library of the University of Missouri. If you know of any name that has been omitted that should be on our list, please notify the secretary of the Friends. Life memberships are based on the giving of one hundred dollars or more to the Library Development Fund of the University, or for outstanding services to the University Library.</p>
<p>Mr. Noah Alper, Dr. A. S. Artley, Dr. and Mrs. Lewis  Atherton, Professor Thomas Barclay, Professor and Mrs. R. D. M. Bauer, Dear and Mrs. Henry Bent, Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Bond, Miss Bertha Booth, Dean and Mrs. Benjamin Boyer, Miss Minnie Brashear, Mr. and Mrs. Richard J. Chamier, Miss Suzanne Chamier, Mr. and Mrs. John M. Dalton, Mr. and Mrs. W. W. Dalton, Mrs. Mary Dawson, Mr. Donn Dearing, Miss Anita Dickson, Miss Hertha Eitzen, Dr. and Mrs. Elmer Gentry, Dr. Martin Faust, Judge and Mrs. James Finch, Mr. William Gentry, Dr. and Mrs. Lawrence Giffen, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Greer, Mr. Booten Herndon, Mrs. Camie Fenton Hurley, Mr. and Mrs. John Lofgren, Mr. and Mrs. R. E. Lucas, Mr. C. N. McDavitt, Mrs. Hal McHaney, Dr. and Mrs. F. A. Middlebush, Dr. John G. Neihardt, Mr. and Mrs. R. Hartley Pollock, Mr. and Mrs. Iram Royse, Mr. and Mrs. George A. Rozier, Miss Mahala Saville, Dr. and Mrs. Gene Schillie, Dr. John W. Schwada, Mr. Ralph Shoemaker, Mr. Ralph Smith, Mr. Byron Spencer, Dr. Dan Stine, Mrs. Juanita G. Stuckey, Mr. Arthur Nesbitt Stunz, Honorable Stuart Symington, Lt. Col. John Warack, Dr. John Weaver, Mrs. Waldo Mott Wedel, Mr. and Mrs. Warren Welliver, Mrs. Caroline Werkley, Professor and Mrs. Elmer Wood, and Mr. and Mrs. William Woodruff.</p>

Page 6
3
OUTSTANDING GIFTS
<p>This past year has seen several outstanding collections contributed to the University Library. Dr. Isador Keyfitz, formerly professor in the Missouri School of Religion, now living in Jerusalem, Israel, gave about six hundred volumes of his collection of Judaica and other religious books. Dr. William H. Rubey of Los Angeles, also a former professor at UMC, contributed a large number of scientific journals earlier this year. Other donors for the year include Professor William F. Fratcher, Dr. Peter Kahane, Mrs. Lewis Kensinger, Dr. Saul D. Larks, Mr. Fred L. Lee, Mrs. Ella Pahmeier, Mr. Ralph G. Shoemaker, Mrs. Kirk Van der Reyden, Mr. Joseph Webber, Mrs. Saul Weinberg, and Mr. Roger Winters.</p>
A REMINDER ABOUT MEMBERSHIP DUES AND RESPONSIBLITIES
<p>Unless you are a lifetime member of the Friends, you hold an annual membership in the organization. Ordinarily, a contribution of five dollars or more constitutes your annual dues. A gift of one or more meritorious books or assistance in obtaining manuscript items or books for the libraries during the year are also means of continuing your membership in the Friends.</p>
<p>We would continue to encourage you to help us in locating possible sources of gifts, manuscripts, personal libraries, and donations of value to the University Library or the State Historical Society's Library. We are also happy to answer questions about any old and possibly valuable books you might have, to whatever extent the staff of these two libraries are able to help. Address inquireies to the Secretary of the Friends, University of Missouri Library, Columbia, Missouri, 65201.</p>
THE FRIEND'S BOOK FAIR
<p>This year the Friends are sponsoring a book fair at the University to be help April 22, 23, a week after the annual dinner. The purpose of the fair is to raise funds for the Library to be used in the purchase of rare books. The School of Library and Information Science is cooperating in the handling of the actual work involved. A number of students have volunteered to help. The book fair will be held in the Library Auditorium.</p>
<p>Donations of books, magazines, paperbacks, and such may be mailed to the Library at the Columbia campus very inexpensively at library rate. Or if you live in the St. Louis area or Rolla, you may find it more convenient to drop your donations at the University Libraries there, at the Library Director's office, and the books will be sent on to Columbia. Or if you are coming to the annual dinner on April 15, you may wish to bring books with you and leave them in the Columbia capus Library.</p>
<p>Please address all gift books for the Book Fair: Friends of the Library Book Fair, University of Missouri Library, Columbia, Missouri, 65201.</p>

Page 7

FRIENDS OF THE LIBRARY NOTES
UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI 
Issued Occasionally 
February, 1972
ANNUAL MEETING, April 15, 1972
<p>The annual dinner meeting of the Friends of the Library has been scheduled for Saturday, April 15, 1972. Thomas B. Curtis will be the speaker for the evening. Mr. Curtis, a native of St. Louis, is presently General Counsel for Encyclopedia Britannica. Until recently he served as a representative in Congress from the Second Congressional District. He worked in a number of committees such as the Ways and Means Comittee on the Organization of Congress, and others. He recently was appointed chairman of the Federal Rent Advisory Board, which is developing guidelines for residential rents in the Phase 2 economic program. Mr. Curtis is a life trustee of Dartmouth College and a member of the Board of Trustees of William Woods College. He is known throughout the state of Missouri as an excellent speaker and a man of many interests.</p>
SERIES OF LIBRARY EXHIBITS
<p>There is currently a series of month-long exhibits on display in the Elmer Ellis Library lobby. An exhibit on illuminated manuscripts, which included a selection from the library's collection of facsimile editions, from all periods and countries was on display in January. In February, a display of herbals from the Renaissance to the present can be seen. In March, the 22nd Annual Exhibit of Top Honor Books form the Chicago Book Clinic, a traveling show form the America Institute of Graphic Arts will be on display. In April, an exhibit on calligraphers and calligraphy. The State Historical Society, Western Historical Manuscripts, and the Museum of Art and Archaeology, also located in this building, feature other exhibits that are of interest to any Friends visiting the campus.</p>