<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.37a.14-21">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Angela Rackley to John G. Neihardt, May 12, 1973</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.37a.14-21</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Angela Rackley to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1973-05-12">May 12, 1973</date>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.14"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        1321 Ocean Fr Dr 3
                        Santa Monica, Calif. 90401
                        May 12, 1973 
                    </dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine Street</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska 68505</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I enjoyed your kind letter so much, and was very happy to hear how much the flowers pleased you!</p>
                
                <p>Bill is expected back in Los Angeles within the next day or two. I will relay your message to him, and I am sure too that you will be hearing from him soon. I arrived in Los Angeles two days ago, and have been resettling myself here. I share wholeheartedly your eagerness to have the recording completed. It is important to have it done.</p>
                
                <p>Gaki, since my departure from your home, I have been giving more and more serious thought to the concept of doing a documentary on the highlights of your life and works. I am writing you this letter to seek your written permission to make such a documentary.</p>
                
                <p>At present I have in mind a one-hour special, uninterrupted by commercials, for nationwide television broadcast, or the possibility of a two or three-hour special, also for the nationwide television broadcast, made into a two or three-part showing over a period of several weeks. The latter I mention as a possibility simply because your life has been lived so fully that a one-hour special will have to be handled very care-fully to encompass artistically all that I feel should be included in a documentary of this nature.</p>
                
                <p>If I am able to gain your permission, I hope to approach a sponsor, such as the Kodak Company, which would be both backer for raising the money and sponsoring the documentary on one of the major television networks. An alternative to this would be to approach an Indian group that would be rich enough in funds to sponsor the documentary. Although the Lakota Sioux would not have such funds, there are certain Indian groups, such as in the Palm Springs area, who may have the funds and interests. Another course would be to approach private parties and try and sell the documentary to a major network through their money-
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.15"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">2</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
                    
                    raising efforts. This approach would not be as desirable as a known-name sponsorship, but I mention it as a possibility.</p>
                
                <p>In working out the percentages, aside from the monetary payment to you, I would like some portion of the funds to be set aside for some special funding; perhaps for the Lakota Sioux on the South Dakota reservations--but the choice I would leave to your discretion. I also leave to your discretion the choice of sponsorship you feel is appropriate...as all aspects of the production would be subject to your approval, so would this matter.</p> 
                
                <p>Although I live to be a writer, and not a business-woman, I feel that we could reach practical business agreements through your lawyer and daughter, Hilda Petri. I would estimate that between $100,000. and $150,000. is needed to be raised.</p>
                
                <p>In making such a documentary, I would like to work with my first cousin, Larry Smith, and his partner, Jim Loy. I have a great deal of faith in Larry's artistic capabilities, and I enclose a resume from both him and Jim for you to go over. They are currently located in Jacksonville, Florida. Larry has expressed a great interest in working on a documentary about you.</p>
                
                <p>I have several ideas in mind, among them the idea that the film would open with a filming of the Lemmon, South Dakota commemorative honoring you, the Youngs and the 150th anniversary of the crawl of Hugh Glass. As this event takes place July 13, 1973, some six weeks away, I hope that proceedings would be far enough along to enable me to film this important event.</p> 
                
                <p>From this opening segment, and a possible freeze-frame of you, I would like to cut to nature scenes and a voice-over of excerpts from your <hi rend="caps">THE DIVINE ENCHANTMENT</hi>, a beautiful writing that has yet to come into its own. I remember our discussion of this past April 29, the Sunday that I read excerpts of your autobiography to you. I urged you to consider a republication of the book, and you too seemed to feel the time was right. Although I doubt that you woudl have any difficulty at all in having a publisher re-issue the book, perhaps some exposure of this poetry would acquaint the public with its existence.</p> 
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.16"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">3</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
                
                <p>I would like to call on Dick Cavett for partial narration of the documentary. I would also like to call on some deep-voiced actor, of Sterling Hadyn or Peter Ustinov's caliber, for partial narration.</p>
                
                <p>I would like to work in conjunction with Nick Venet and United Artists in the use of the forthcoming three-set album for partial narration and your own quotations of your various works. I have several reasons for this hopefully possible cooperation. One is mutual benefit. One can only guess as to the success of either venture in regard to the public. I feel that the use of the recordings would aid both the album and the documentary in exposure. The second reason, and certainly the more important, is that I will want to use a certain amount of quotes, depending on the length of the documentary, of your works recited by you. As I am sure that almost all of these quotes will be included in the album set, I can see no justification in asking you to do the demanding work of reciting them again, when they are already down on tape. I know how exhausted you were after the sessions with Bill, and I cannot bring myself to ask you to go through it again. Bill and Mr. Venet are good men; I feel I can get a release from them.</p> 
                
                <p>I remember Myrtle's discussion with me about the music in the background of <hi rend="caps">TV</hi> shows, and how bothersome it can become. Although I have not settled on any musical concept for the documentary, I do have an idea about the use of music. As any artistic effort, music can be exquisitively effective. For this documentary there would be very little use of music at all, as I feel the more "simple" the documentary, the more memorable it will be. However, in my own great love of music, I feel that its use in parts throughout the documentary would accomplish that "exquisitive effectiveness".</p>
                
                <p>I would like to make use of short interviews with people who have been close to you in your lifetime, or know something about you in a meaningful way. Several people would be <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi> and Myrtle, if they consent, Hilda, Florence and others I have not yet considered, again, if they consent, with your approval.</p> 
                
                <p>I would like to make use, with the author's permission,of quotes from the biography on you that is currently unpublished. A copy of it is in your home. I was able to read approximately the first 50 pages, and unfortunately did not have the time to read the rest. I thought it very well done, however, and I am eager to finish reading it. Again, perhaps this would be an endeavor of mutual benefit.</p> 
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.17"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">4</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
                    
                <p>I would like to make use of the photographs that are in the University of Missouri library, as stills to be used in the documentary.</p>
                
                <p>I would like to film several scenes of you at home, perhaps showing you at work, having dinner, walking Jacquo<sic>Jacquot</sic>, being visited by a group of school children.</p>
                
                <p>I would like to screen all filming of you that is available, for possible use within the documentary. What comes to my mind presently is use of a short segment of you teaching at the University of Missouri.</p> 
                
                <p>If I am able to realize a three-hour special, I would possibly wish to divide it into one hour devoted to you as a man, in relationship to Mona and your children, and the struggles you had to go through during your lifetime.</p> 
                
                <p>One hour I would like to devote to your relationship to the Midwest and history, your diversified talents as a man and writer.</p> 
                
                <p>One hour I would like to devote to your special relationship with the Plains Indians throughout your life.</p> 
                
                <p>If I am not able to realize a three-hour special, I would try to incorporate all of the above in a one-hour special.</p> 
                
                <p>I cannot now guess the time involved in putting together such a documentary. I would say possibly three or four months, perhaps more, perhaps less.</p> 
                
                <p>Gaki, this is a very long letter, but I hope that I have been able to include all of my basic ideas so that you will be able to make a decision by it. Again, I ask for your written permission to make a documentary on the highlights of your life and works. I welcome your suggestions in this regard, and, should I obtain your permission, all work on the documentary would be authorized by your approval.</p> 
                
                <p>I wait for your answer, and if there is any need to reach me by phone, please call me collect at 213-394-5153.</p> 
                
                    <salute>Respectfully,</salute> 
                
                    <signed>Angela Rackley</signed>
                    <signed>Angela Rackley</signed>
                
                encl. 
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.18"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="caps">QUASAR
                        <lb/>
                    PRODUCTIONS INC.</hi> 
                
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>A Border of Stars</figDesc>
                    </figure> 
                </fw>
                
                Resume 
                Jim Loy 
                Executive Producer 
                In addition to serving as executive producer for Quasar Productions, he is producer of news and public affairs for post-newsweek station wjxt-tv in Jacksonville, Florida. The success of the news programs under his supervision has brought seventy to eighty percent of news viewers in Northeast Florida to depend on wjxt for their information. 
                At 26, he has a combined television and motion picture background of seven years with two additional years in radio production. Since 1970, he has been associated with the post-newsweek organization serving as a producer and a director of public affairs. he received the Bronze Medal in the 1970 Atlanta Film Festival for the television documentary "Yesterday's Man." This production was also recognized by the Robert F. Kennedy Foundation and the Florida Associated Press Broadcasters. 
                Educated at the University of Oklahoma, in Broadcast Journalism, he also has experience in governmental affairs, serving as special assistant to the LT. Governor of Oklahoma in 1969. 
                Prior to 1969, served on news staff for WTVJ-TV, Miami, Florida, KWTV-TV, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, and the Indian Nations Network, also in Oklahoma City. 
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">PRODUCERS OF CREATIVE COMMUNICATIONS
                        <lb/>
                    408 WEST MONAGE STREET, JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA</hi> 32202, 904/355-3536
                </fw>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.19"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="caps">QUASAR
                        <lb/>
                    PRODUCTIONS INC.</hi>
                    
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>A Border of Stars</figDesc>
                    </figure> 
                </fw>
                
                Resume
                Lawrence V. Smith 
                Now President of Quasar Productions, INC., which produces a wide variety of visual communications, from television game shows to tv commercials. 
                Started in the motion picutre industry in 1953, after graduation from Illinois State University, with a degree of Bachelor of Science in Education.
                Owned and operated motion pictures in Joliet, Illinois and El Paso, Texas, prior to signing a contract with encyclo-pedia Britannica Films, as director of photography for one hundred and sixty (160) half-hour films for the Ford Founda-tions, on the teaching of general chemistry. Upon the completion of the contract, went to work with CBS-TV, where his filming in Cuba during the Cuban Revolution, 1958-59, won him his first of four Emmy Awards. Next, he joined Russell-Barton Film Company as Director of Photography, where he was responsible for photography of various types of films from political documentaries to a television series.
                Left Russell-Barton Film Company in 1963, to work with ABC-TV. Joined ABC-TV News in 1965 as staff cameraman for the production of news and special events in the far east. While with ABC-TV in the east, was director of photography on many documentaries, including "Hiroshima then and now", commemorating the twentieth anniversary of the atom bomb, and "Reflection on Viet Nam", with Frank Reynolds, which earned him his second award. 
                Formed Lawrence Smith Productions Inc. In 1965 after returning to the United States. Then worked on all forms of motion picture production: TV spots, documentaries, political films, game shows, sponsored news films, sports films and wildlife TV shows, such as "Mutual of Omaha's Wild Kingdom". While acting as director of photography on this TV show, won Emmy Awards in 1966 and 1967, for outstanding program on achievement in daytime programming; he has recently been under contract 
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">PRODUCERS OF CREATIVE COMMUNICATIONS
                        <lb/>
                    408 WEST MONAGE STREET, JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA</hi> 32202, 904/355-3536
                </fw>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.20"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
                
                as director of photography in numerous United States information agency documentaries for various agency divisions; such as "Washington Correspondent", "V.I.P.", "Ikhtaru Lakum", "Far East Division", "General Television", and "News and Special Events"; including specialized Tyler Helicopter Photography of Apollo 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16.
                In 1970 he helped organize The Jacksonville Motion Picture and Television Council, was Temporary Chairman and was then elected its First President. The Council for the first time brought together all the crafts, guilds, and related arts in the motion picture and television industry in the Jacksonville area. 
                In the past three years, TV Commercials of which he has been the director of photography as well as executive producer have won over thirty major awards of outstanding achievement and excellence. 
                Recently returned from Africa where he was producer and director of photography on a one hour hunting safari special. While handling Pre-Production responsibilities, initiated the use of the New Nagra "SN" Minature Recorders, along with Crystal Sync Camera Motors to initiate the first safari film ever to be shot totally in sync without the use of sync cables or wireless mikes; therefore eliminating any encumberance to the cameraman or the participants in the hunt achieving finally full free production techniques. 
                In February of 1973 he was elected to the New York chapter of the National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences as a voting member. 
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.21"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        5835 Vine Street 
                        Lincoln, Nebraska 68505 
                        May 16, 1973
                    </dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Miss Angela Rackley</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>1321 Ocean Fr. Dr. 3</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Santa Monica, California 90401</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Angela:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter of May 12, 1973, has been read to Dr. Neihardt. However, since he hasn't been feeling well the past few days, I am writng the reply.</p>
                
                <p>Dr. Neihardt was pleased with your outline of the documentary you would like to do. Since his daughter Hilda Petri is his attorney and agent, such matters are referred to her for approval. We therefore suggest that you submit your request and plan of the documentary on John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt to Hilda for consideration. Her address is: <address><addrLine>Mrs. Hilda Petri,</addrLine> <addrLine><hi rend="caps">P. O.</hi>  Box 1096,</addrLine> <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri 65201.</addrLine></address></p> 
                
                <p>If the project is undertaken, it must be understood that be-cause of Dr. Neihardt's age and health there is a distinct possibility that interruptions in the work could occur.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                    <signed>Myrtle Young</signed> 
                
                    <note>MY:nh</note> 
                </closer>
                        
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>