<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36.33-36">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Guy O. Karnes to John G. Neihardt, March 16, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36.33-36</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Guy O. Karnes to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-03-16">March 16, 1972</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.33"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        1115-5th St
                        Brookings, <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Dak
                        March 16, 1972
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr John Neihardt</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
               
                    <salute>Dear Mr Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Two years ago I almost met you. You lectured one night at an Indian seminar at South Dakota State University. Hearing you give your Death of Crazy Horse made that hour one of the moments I'll treasure always. I wanted very much to shake your hand but you were <unclear>mobbed</unclear> by students. I didn't have the guts to <unclear>push</unclear> in. I knew how important it was to them.</p>
                
                <p>When you were on the Dick Cavett show I was able to tape it and even got a couple of color shots of you on <hi rend="caps">T.V.</hi> Now I understand there are records you have made of "The Cycle of the West." I'll look into that. Perhaps there are tapes too.</p> 
                
                <p>I have read and reread many times your "A Cycle of the West" and Black Elk Speaks". I also read "The River and I". By nights you fellows had more than your share of luck. You were green and you took chances a man shouldn't take. Thank God you made it.</p> 
                
                <p>You are the only white man I know about whose writing convinces me that you understand the Indian and his part in that period of our history.</p> 
                
                <p>Now, maybe I better explain about myself. I am a retired high school 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.34"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
                    
                    science teacher &#8212; 45 years teaching physics and chemistry in Illinois, Minnesota and South Dakota. You wouldn't be <unclear>interested</unclear> in that, so I'll go farther back. My Grandad and his brothers moved from Ohio to Western Missouri in 1860 &#8212; brought their families and household goods in covered wagons and settled on Shoal Creek near Cameron, Mo. My Dad was a baby then. Grandad and his brothers built log cabins, plowed up a little sod and then went away to fight in the Civil War, while the Women folks kept things going on the farm. My Dad grew up there but with the itch to go west. When he was 19 he left home, went to Oregon From 1879 until he proved up on his <unclear>own</unclear> Claim in 1900 he was a cow boy and part-time lumber jack in Oregon, Idaho and Montana.</p>
                
                <p>In those years he knew many Indians. He understood them and they understood him and they liked each other. He stood up for them even them and it wasn't the popular thing to do at that Time. He had many stories about them. When he was a child in Missouri an old Indian walked into the Cabin, walked over the fireplace where a hoe-cake was baking, and stuck his foot into the hoecake. My Grandmother gave him the hoecake, which was the thing he wanted. Then there was the thing he wanted. Then there was the Chief in Oregon who took a real liking to him and insisted Dad accept his daughter as his wife. Dad managed to get out of that and 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.35"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">35</fw>
                    
                    remain friends with the Chief. In 1900 he married a PhD country school teacher who had gone west to see what it was all about. I couldn't have picked better parents. I was born on the ranch on Big Creeks, near Emigrant, on the upper Yellowsotne about 25 miles from Gardner (northern entrance to Yellowstone Park.).</p>
                
                <p>While I was a small boy Old Andy lived with us on the ranch. He was an Indian who made a great impression on me. I never even knew just how he came to be there except that Andy could call our place his home as long as he lived. The only condition was that he <del/><add>w</add>as not to drink firewater on the place. He lived up to the agreement. Old Andy could play the fiddle by ear and he played often for ranch dances. He would get on his horse with his fiddle case on his back. The mother would wrap me in a blanket and hand me up to him and we would head out across the hills to the dance. <del/><add>I</add>t was his idea. He never drank at such times and brought me back in fine shape. Of course I slept thru<sic>through</sic> the whole thing but that was what Andy wanted and my folks went along with it.</p> 
                
                <p>As a boy I picked up arrow heads and Indian hammers, even a <unclear>pemican</unclear> bowl which I still have. Near the ranch was a buffalo junp where I spent 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.36"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">36</fw>
                
                    many hours digging among the buffalo bones at the base of the <unclear>rim</unclear> rock and I would dream about what it must have been like when the Indians drove them over the rim. Then at night I would listen to the Old timers tell what it was like when the Indians and the buffalo still had the country.</p> 
                
                <p>Since I retired from teaching I have read many books about the Indians in an attempt to really understand just what took place back there. One of the best in my opinion is "I Buried my Heart at Wounded Knee."</p> 
                
                <p>Just recently I read an interesting article by Peg McMahon, "An Epic Poet for an Epic Time. From this I learned you now live on the Skyrim Farm near Colubmia, Mo. my wife and I have hopes of making a trip to Missouri and Illinois before I have eye operations (cataracts). If we do we plan to come by your place. If things work out I would like to be permitted to stop long enough to at least sha<del/><add>k</add>e hands. It would mean a lot to Mrs. Karnes and myself.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Guy O. Karnes</signed> 
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>1115-5th St</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Brookings, <hi rend="caps">S</hi> Dak</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>57006</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>