<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34a.8.11">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt, August 13, 1970</title>
<author>Thompson, Earl</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.X.X</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt, August 13, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-08-13"></date>
<extent>4 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Sitting Bull, 1831?-1890</term>
<term>Standing Bear, Luther, 1868?-1939</term>
<term>Marx, Karl, 1818-1883.</term>
<term>Crazy Horse, approximately 1842-1877</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term>Lausanne (Switzerland)</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Thompson, Earl</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5110302">Brooklyn (N.Y.)</placeName>
<date when="1970-08-13"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34a.8.11.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">8</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>
<note type="authorial">Earl Thompson</note>
<fw type="letterhead">THOMPSON/GRAPHIC 70 PROSPECT PARK WEST/BROOKLYN, NY 11215</fw>
<opener>
<dateline>August 13, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
</opener>

<p>I am so pleased to learn of your exciting plans and possible movie. Perhaps we will be in Hollywood at the same time. If such should be the case, I promise not approach any of the <unclear>starlets</unclear> except as an entry, but you must do the same.</p>

<p>The paperback rights to my book were let to New American Library week before <unclear>lort</unclear> for 250,000; movies have been calling. Putnom is now delaying publication until Jan. 5, to better prepare publicity. They have never had a ist novel that brought such</p>

<fw type="curatorial">9</fw>
<p>a response. We are renegotiating my contract. The told paper <unclear>house</unclear> they had me locked up for a 2nd book - they don't. They will, but it will cut them their half of the 250 grs. I told them from the outset I would be very agreeable until the money became significant. It's now significant.</p>

<p>Men, I am told, are put up rather tight by my book, while women really sell it. Probably because its reality once accepted is a challenge to all superfical male, and consequently social, conciets. It is a very profane book. Many will confuse that with obscene.</p>

<p>In the meantime I hope to take a house or apartment in Lausanne, Switzerland before the snow flys. It is central to <unclear>Eurghs</unclear>, healthy, blessed with pure water, air and good</p>

<fw type="curatorial">10</fw>
<p>schools. If I hadn't made too much money to live in Sweden, we would have moved there, and will spend a great deal of time there. But start thinking what beyond an invatation it will take to lure you to Europe for a nice long stay with us. The invatation is a standing one.</p>

<p>Before we leave, I must go to Kansas and see a grandmother into better straits for her remaining years and see if a cousin would be interested in running our graphics businesss for us here. I will bring my son, John II, and call on you bearing photos of Jamie, Jedediah and mama.</p>

<p>More than anything, I am grateful for the memory to move my children where they can grow in the full sunlight of an international point of view - a condition that no longer</p>

<fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
<p>4. exists in the elementary and secondary schools here except in the examples of outrageous behavior that unfortuantely is more inspired than considered. They do not need that wasteful effort. They do not have to 'belong' if they are aware that they are truly part of the whole human race.</p>

<p>Besides, we all like to ski an awful lot.</p>

<p>So let us toast our twin good fortune with some heady, peaty brew - and marvel at the workings of things that has somehow conspired to make this year the resurgance of the WASP. Lift a drop for Calvin and Knox; Stading Bear and Sitting-Bull; Karl Marx and Crazy Horse. History is such a long time hing and no confusing for men who think only in terms of battles won and lost. So, one drop for the American Homer and one drop for me, Spal!</p>

<closer>
<salute>Fondest regards</salute>
<signed>Earl</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>