<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 67
1711 CONCORD COURT APT. 303
KANSAS CITY, MO. 64110

26 May 1971

John G. Neihardt
Skyrim Farm
Columbia, Mo. 65201

Dear John Neihardt:
<p>Was sorry, young man, to have missed your stint at Rockhurst this past weekend. As things worked out for us that evening my 'calling,' unfortunately had to be elsewhere those hours.</p>
<p>My neighbor lady (in an apartment on the 2nd floor in my building) tripped and fell on an oriental rug carpet she has in her dining room. She's in her 70's and sometimes, you know, when one falls at that tender age, it can present complications.</p>
<p>About the time I was thinking about Rockhurst and our festivities that evening there came a knock at my door -- another lady informing of what had happened. By the time we got the doctor notified, by the time he got the ambulance to us, by the time we got to the hospital...by the time I eventually got back home again and called her son in Des Moines (11:30 pm) it was all over with -- the evening, I mean.</p>
<p>Am happy to say we've since gotten her home again. She's on pills to ease pain if there is any. No broken bones fortunately. Only 'bruised pride.'</p>
<p>Talked to Violet Van Zilen Sunday. She told me about the weekend. Sounds like it was a good one! Got to read about you 'doings' in the STAR that Sunday. A nice piece, I thought. Not too much 'puffery.' Mostly good reporting.</p>
<p>Had <underline>much</underline> to share with you Saturday evening. For one thing wanted to express my sincere thanks for hosting my DIVINE ENCHANTMENT for me that evening over at Mark and Judy's. I picked up the book along with the others that following Thursday as I think Mark told you. Also appreciate greatly your signing it for me. I treasure it. I promise I'll do everything I can to give it a 'good home.' It's safely tucked away with other Neihardtiana. So consider it with friends.</p>
<p>You mentioned a while back the possibility of writing a letter for me to tuck into the book explaining some of its backgroung. I would appreciate that -- particularly some of your reasons for writing it, the reasons why you decided to burn those that you did. ($200 is alot of of money to pay to have a book published. It is now and I know it was then, too.)</p>
***
<p>Didn't tell you but your stint on the Cavett show wasn't aired here locally. I had to drive up to St. Joseph (and the Ramada Inn across</p>

Page 68
2
<p>from the Holiday Inn)to see it that night. Wanted particularly to see it in color. No color TVs in the Holiday Inn, I was told --Only black and white. They booked me across the street instead.</p>
<p>Enjoyed the show much. Can understand the reasons perhaps for narrowing the interview to Black Elk. From a network standpoint, this has news-value particularly with our current ethnic emphasis so much in the news these days. Was sorry they couldn't have devoted some time to your earlier writings. These are important also. But "time" was, I suppose, a prime consideration in their decision here.</p>
<p>Have since obtained 60 minutes of the Cavett show on videotape from channel 9 in Kansas City. Am going to have this re-taped on to 16mm color film and hope eventually to ship the two reels to the Library in Columbia for inclusion in the Collection there. (A friend who is quite interested in photography said he'd do this for me 'for the cost of the film' which cuts down our expenses considerably here. He'll furnish the man-power/know-how which is really apparently the expensive thing in transactions as this).</p>
************
<p>Another favor to ask -- one of our Westerners, Tom Watson, who is our Sheriff (i.e. #1 - head - man ) asked me if I would have you sign his copy of SONG OF THE INDIAN WARS for him. Meant to do this Saturday night but, of course, didn't. If I were to send it on with enough postage, etc. would you kindly do such for him? You've got a 'fan' here, I know.</p>
<p>A busy week upcoming. The next week promises likewise. Have a meeting of our Westport Historical Society on the 4th of June with a bus trip up to historic Weston, Mo. on the 5th. (Note enclosures).</p>
<p>On the 8th of June have a Westerner meeting (note enclosure). Will have the announcement Xeroxed this Friday and will mail these out to the boys come the weekend upcoming. A weekend trip to Abilene, Kansas with a friend is scheduled for the middle of June sometime. On Friday, 10 June Mark and Judy Meadows will be over for a fondue dinner and a visit.</p>
<p>Glad you're getting some needed rest at Skyrim. Know the girls are glad to see you, too! Would hope we can keep more in touch this summer than we have before.</p>
As always, affectionate thoughts,
<signed>Fred</signed>
Fred L. Lee