<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.37a.28-30">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Ida M. Jahren to John G. Neihardt, June 5, 1973</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.37a.28-30</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Ida M. Jahren to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1973-06-05">June 5, 1973</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.28"/>
                
                <note>ans. by <unclear/> 7-12-73</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        405 5th Avenue <hi rend="caps">SW</hi>
                        Austin, Minnesota 55912
                        June 5, 1973
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Bancroft,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Nebraska 68004</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It has been over two years since I discovered your poetry and I have meant to write to you tell you so. I have enjoyed learning more about your life and work from various places ever since. I became acquainted with your work through <hi rend="underline">Lyric and Dramatic Poems</hi> and I want you to know that they still hold the original impact on a sensitive mind. Having just borne my fourth and last child I was touched especially by the Stranger At The Gate, since it catches completely the sweet pathos of the precious once in a lifetime and quick frailty of birth. Since then I have become interested in your more religious and philosophical writings. I am deeply moved by your conception of the Holy Spirit and God at work in our destiny. Imagine my surprise when I picked up an old reader of the Modern Readers' Series, Garlands' <hi rend="underline">A Son of the Middle Border</hi>, to find that your <hi rend="underline">Song of Three Friends</hi> was to be included in the series but was "preparing" (1925). It seems that now I meet you at every hand.</p> 
                
                <p>I shared your first book of poetry with some dear friends of ours just before your first appearance on the Dick Cavett Show. I am including a portion of his next sermon for you since our impressions of the program were the same. I hope you are pleased with the impact that you you have on us and the young people today.</p> 
                
                <p>I am reading the first volume of your autobiography, <hi rend="underline">All is But a Beginning</hi>. I am enjoying it very much.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.37a.29"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">2</fw>
                
                <p>I have finally decided to write this letter ot you because I have been able to formulate a question in my own mind, that I would like you to answer, in terms of your philosophy and experience.</p>
                
                <p>Even more important than your experience with meeting your wife and having a love that flourished, was your statement that--"(you) didn't pity her (Her long trip into the frontier etc.) She had a rich experience and was able to assimilate it." This to me was the very highest compl<del>e</del><add>i</add>ment possible from one human being to another, showing both respect and affection. As I read many other things you have written, I find and also <hi rend="underline">know</hi> that people don't operate on the same level. One person said to <del>th</del><add>m</add>e the other day...some people could live in the richest environment and learn nothing. My question is, why? What happens to these tiny beings who come <del>op</del><add>to</add> ust<del>tr</del><add>ra</add>iling clouds of glory behind them? Are they really born with different capacities of sensitvity, or are they broken hearted, broken spirited people who find themselves in circumstances that cloud God's destiny for them and "break the hoop"?</p> 
                
                <p>I thank you for you writings and wish you the very best on your current work.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Ida M. Jahren</signed> 
                    <signed>Mrs. Ida M. Jahren</signed> 
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                <p>Last week a nintey year old poet was interviewed on one of the late evening <hi rend="caps">TV</hi> talk shows.</p>
                
                <p>He was truly a remarkable man and the interview lasted for an hour and a half without one moment growing tedious.</p>
                
                <p>A wide range of subjects was covered, and the poet responded to all of them in a manner that combined the grace and wisdom of age with all of the enthusiasm and receptiveness of youth.</p>
                
                <p>But the most moving part of the interview came as the poet discussed his love and his marriage.</p>
                
                <p>Unbelievably, he had fallen in love with a girl from her letters, and they did not meet at all until they came together to be married.</p>
                
                <p>As he put it, "I had the wedding license in my pocket when I took her off the train."</p>
                
                <p>But it worked; and it worked for fifty years!</p>
                
                <p>And what the poet said was this: "Our love grew and grew. It just got better and better. I loved her more and more, to the very end."</p>
                
                <p>That is what marriage is all about, and that is how it can be, not just for poets and romanticists, but for all those who love each other in the framework of the love of God.</p>
                <closer>
                    --from Mr. Morgan's sermon of 5/2/71 at Westminster Presbyterian Church, Austin, Minnesota
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>