<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35a.1.3">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Bruce H. Nicoll to John G. Neihardt, April 9, 1971</title>
<author>Nicoll, Bruce H.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.35a.1.3</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Bruce H. Nicoll to John G. Neihardt, April 9, 1971</title>
<date when="1971-04-09">April 9, 1971</date>
<extent>3 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>The Mountain Men</term>
<term>The Twilight of the Sioux</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/311317741">Nicoll, Bruce Hilton (1912- )</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
<date when="1971-04-09"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.35a.1.3.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">1</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<fw type="letterhead">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA
LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 68508

OFFICE OF DIRECTOR
UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA PRESS</fw>
<opener>
<dateline>April 9, 1971
</dateline>
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. John G. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>5835 Vine</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska</addrLine>
</address>
<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>Enclosed is the agreement to publish THE MOUNTAIN MEN and. THE TWLIGHT OF THE SIOUX. Enclosed also is the invoice for the first advance payment. Will you please sign and return it to me.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Cordially,</salute>
<signed>UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA PRESS
Bruce H. Nicoll</signed>
<note>Bruce H. Nicoll
Director </note>
<note>BHN:ks
Enclosures</note>
</closer>
</div1>

<div1 type="document">

<fw type="curatorial">2</fw>
<fw type="header">MEMORANDUM OF AGREEMENT</fw>
<p>This Agreement, made this <hi rend="underline">29th</hi> day of <hi rend="underline">March, 1971</hi> by and between <hi rend="underline">John G. Neihardt</hi>, hereinafter called the SELLER, and the Board of Regents of the University of Nebraska, a public corporation organized and operating under the laws of the State of Nebraska, maintaining as one of its agencies the University of Nebraska Press, which corporation is hereinafter called the BUYER, Witnesseth</p>
<p>1. Subject to the terms and conditions herein set forth, the Seller hereby grants to the Buyer the sole and exclusive license to manufacture, including the right to photograph the Seller's edition, publish and sell, in such manner and form and under such imprint as the Buyer may deem advisable, paper reprint editions of <hi rend="underline">THE MOUNTAIN MEN AND THE TWILIGHT OF THE SIOUX (2 vol. edition of THE CYCLE OF THE WEST)</hi>, hereinafter referred to as the Work, in the English language.</p>
<p>2. Said license shall continue in effect for a minimum period of five (5) yeras after the Buyer's publication date and thereafter each succeeding twelve-month period unless the Seller gives the Buyer written notice of termination ninety days before the beginning of each such twelve-month period. Upon such termination, the Buyer shall nevertheless continue to have the right to dispose of any copies of the Work then remaining on hand or in process, subject to the payment of royalties as herein provided.</p>
<p>3. The Seller represents and warrants that it is the sole owner of the rights herein granted and that said rights are not subject to any prior agreement, lien or other rights which may interfere with the Buyer's exercise thereof. The Seller further warrants that the Work contains no libelous, obscene, plagiarized or other unlawful matter, and that it in no way infringes upon the copy right or violates any other right of any person or party whatsoever, and the Seller agrees to indemnify and hold the Buyer harmless against any claim, demand, suit, action, proceeding, prosecution or judgment, based upon the Buyer's exercise of the righs conferred by this Agreement, including all reasonable expenses, losses, fines, penalties, court costs, attorneys' fees and liablilities suffered or incurred in connection therewith. In defending any such claim, demand, suit, action, proceeding or prosecution, the Buyer shall have the right to select counsel.</p>
<p>4. The Seller agrees that during the term of this Agreement the retail and wholesale prices on copies of the Work published by the Seller shall at no time be less than the respective retail and wholesale prices for such copies in effect at date of this Agreement.</p>
<p>5. The Seller agress to supply the Buyer without charge on or about the date of this Agreement three (3) bound copies in latest jackets of the Seller's than current edition of the Work.</p>
<p>6. The Buyer agrees to pay the Seller a royalty on each copy sold by the Buyer (less returns) at the following rate, except as otherwise herein provided: 6% per copy of the retail price, on all copies sold in the United States; and same royalty percentage of the amount actually received on all copies sold in Canada and other export markets; with a minimum guarantee of $50.00 on receipt of this signed agreement and $50.00 on Buyer's publication date. All royalties beyond the minimum guarantee shall be computed as in paragraph below. The statement of sales shall be compiled by the Buyer annually as of June 30th of each year and shall be rendered by mail on August 1st accompanied by remittance for the respective amounts thereof.</p>
<fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
<p>7. If any time after the Buyer's publication date the Buyer shall find that the sale of its current edition of the Work has declined to a rate of sale per month which shall have ceased to be profitable, the Buyer may dispose of any copies then remaining on hand as "remainders" at such price as it can obtain for such copies. On all copies sold as "remainders," with respect to which no royalty had previosly been paid, the Buyer shall pay to the Seller a royalty of Ten per cent (10%) of any net amount received by the Buyer for such remainders in excess of the manufacturing cost thereof. As to any copies sold at such cost, or less, no royalty shall be paid. No royalty shall be payable with respect to copies of the Work destroyed or materially damaged before sale or while at the risk of the Buyer, nor with respect to any copies distributed without charge as promotional material.</p>
<p>8. The Buyer agress to print on the copyright page of each copy of the Work published by it copyright notices covering material copyrighted by the Seller.</p>
<p>9. In the event of the Buyer's failure to keep the Work in print for any continuous six-month period during the term of this Agreement, unless prevented from so doing by circumstances beyond its control, as set forth in Paragraph 10, the Seller shall have the option to terminate this Agreement, such termination to be effective upon the expiration of three months after the Buyer shall have received written notice of the Seller's intention to exercise such option, unless the Buyer during such three-month period shall have signified in writing his intention to resume publication of the Work.</p>
<p>10. The Buyer shall not be responsible for delay or failure in performance caused by war, riot, strikes, fires, floods, acts of God, governmental restrictions, shortage or interruption of manufacturing facilities or materials supply or other similar or dissimilar circumstances beyond its control.</p>
<p>11. The Buyer agrees to publish its edition of the Work no later than two years form the date of this agreement.</p>
<p>IN WITNESS THEREOF, The Board of Regents of the University of Nebraska has caused its name to be hereunto subscribed by its President and attested by its Corporation Secretary with the corporate seal hereto affixed, and <hi rend="underline">John G. Neihardt</hi> <hi rend="crossed">have</hi> has hereunto set <hi rend="underline">his</hi> hand the day and the year first mentioned.</p>
<closer>THE BOARD OF REGENTS OF
THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA
By <signed>Miles Tommeraasen</signed>
Miles Tommeraasen xxxxxxxx Director of Business and Finance
(BUYER)
x<signed>John G. Neihardt</signed>

ATTEST
<signed>G R ROSS</signed>
Corporation Secretary</closer>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>