<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 58

THE PALOS REGIONAL
12243 SOUTH HARLEM AVENUE PALOS HEIGHTS, ILLINOIS 60463 TELEPHONE GIBSON 8-4000

The Home Town Weekly Newspaper of Palos Heights, Palos Park, Palos Woods, Palos Hills, Palos Oaks, Palos Dells, Palos Highlands, North Palos, Hickory Hills, Palos Township.
"THE 25 YEAR VOICE OF PALOS"

May 7, 1971

John G. Neihardt
Skyrim Farm, Route 7
Columbia, Missouri 65012

Dear Mr. Neihardt:
<p>I was elated to see your interview on the Dick Cavett show recently. It is wonderful that your books are enjoying renewed interest and sales. You have lived long enough to see the truth of the saying, "Everything changes, yet nothing changes."</p>
<p>The recent public sympathy for the plight of the American Indian must bring some happiness to your heart. But it has come a little late for all the red men who have died in poverty and sorrow.</p>
<p>I enjoyed the mention of "ecology" in your interview. It seems ironic that the "savages" had a much greater insight into how to cooperate with their environment.</p>
<p>Please accept my thanks for teaching the course Epic America which I took in 1963 at the University of Missouri. It was my favorite course in college and one I never missed. Also, I have never forgotten the lessons the Indians taught me, through you.</p>
<p>I now publish a suburban weekly newspaper near Chicago and I wrote the enclosed column after seeing the Cavett show. I hope you don't mind. Also enclosed is a column from several years ago.</p>
<p>I hope this letter finds you happy and healthy.</p>
Cordially, 
<signed>Charles Richards</signed>
Charles Richards
Publisher

Page 59

PRIZE-WINNING NEWSPAPERS 448-4000
THE PALOS REGIONAL 
WORTH TOWNSHIP TIMES
CHARLES RICHARDS      12240 S. HARLEM AVE.
PUBLISHER            PALOS HEIGHTS, ILL. 60463

Thursday, December 4, 1969
<bold>Let me say this about that</bold>
by CHARLES RICHARDS
<p>I sat on the floor of an adobe temple perched on a cliff overlooking the Rio Grande River. Green mountains with white tops tickled the bright blue sky in the distance. The air was clear and clean.</p>
<p>The roof of the building was a geodetic done of polished wood and glass. A fire crackled in the adobe fireplace.</p>
<p>The room was filled with about 50 long-haired boys and girls. A few spoke in hushed tones. Soon a man in a long white robe entered the room.</p>
<p>Yogi Carl Alpert sat down on the floor and lit some incense. He uttered a silent prayer, meditated a moment, and greeted the many visitors.</p>
<p>I was at the Llama foundation in the mountains near Taos, New Mexico. I was drawn to the spot by curiosity about the subject of Yoga and the holy men who teach the discipline.</p>
<p>I have noted that many hippies have drifted into the study of Yoga. The Beatles were taken by the idea for a time.</p>
<p>There is nothing new about Yoga. Its origins go back thousands of years. Yoga is a form of Hindu mystical and ascetis philosophy which encourages withdrawal from material things and a concentration upon the Supreme Spirit.</p>
<p>The Yogi explained to me that the hippies were attracted to Yoga because they find that drugs and free love provide only temporary physical pleasure but they corrupt the spirit. The hippie feels free but incomplete. He eventually tires of the "trip" and seeks something more.</p>
<p>The Yogi said that people must strive to develop their levels of consciousness. This is an inward-directed process which necessitates the shunning of worldly distractions.</p>
<p>The Yogi explained that through this method a person could gain "inner peace" and achieve the greatest happiness-union with God.</p>
<p>The more he talked, the more I began to see the unity of all the world's religions. It's like the tent poles of a teepee. On the ground they seem far apart but they merge in the sky. They provide the framework for a protective covering that channels human energy and endeavor upward like the smoke from a campfire. They seem to all be paths leading to the common goal that man had sought since the beginning of time.</p>
<p>It is certainly something that deserves consideration.</p>
<bold>Let me say this about that</bold>
by CHARLES RICHARDS
<p>Dr. John G. Neihardt, the poet-laureate of Nebraska was interviewed on the April 27 Dick Cavett Show on channel 7.</p>
<p>Cavett was greatly impressed by the 90 year old Neihardt who is one of the foremost authorities on the Sioux Indians and writer of epic poetry on the subject.</p>
<p>He was born in Illinois and laster moved west into Indian-territory. He graduated from colleg in Nebraska at 16 and tried newspaper reporting. But his real love was writing lyric poetry.</p>
<p>His two best known books are "Black Elk Speaks" which available in paperback and "A Cycle of the West" which took 25 years to write.</p>
<p>Dr. Neihardt is very close to my heart because I studied under him at the University of Missouri a few years ago.</p>
<p>Here is a passage Neihardt wrote describing the death of Crazy Horse. There were the last words of Crazy Horse as recited from memory by Neihardt on the Cavett show.
<lg><l>"Men strained to gather what he strove to say,</l>
<l>So hard the panting labor of his words.</l>
<l>"I had my village and my pony herds</l>
<l>On Powder where the land was all my own.</l>
<l>I only wanted to be let alone.</l>
<l>I did not want to fight. The Gray Fox sent</l>
<l>His soldiers. We were poorer when they went;</l>
<l>Our babies died, for many lodges burned</l>
<l>And it was cold. We hoped again and turned</l>
<l>Our faces westward. It was just the same</l> 
<l>Out yonderon the Rosebud. Gray Fox came.</l>
<l>The dust his soldiers made was high and long.</l>
<l>I fought him and I whipped him. Was it wrong</l> 
<l>To drive him back? That country was my own.</l>
<l>I only wanted to be let alone.</l>
<l>I did not want to see my people die.</l>
<l>They say I murdered Long Hair and they lie,</l>
<l>His soldiers came to kill us and they died."</l></lg></p>
<p>After hearing the passage quoted above it seems strange that we called the Indians "savages".</p>