<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35.16">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, February 13, 1971</title>
<author></author>
<principal></principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.35.16</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, February 13, 1971</title>
<date when="1971-02-13">February 13, 1971</date>
<extent>1 page</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Cycle</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref ="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1971-02-13"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.35.16.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>February 13, 1971
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>We sure do got fun!!!! The news from you is so exciting I'm not sure I touch ground when I read your letters and Myrtle's. You must all of you by spinning faster than celestial tops on the summit of shining mountains. I'm delighted, of course, and <hi rend="underline">not surprised</hi>, at Dick Cavett's response to you; why should he be different from anyone else? I didn't see the Arthure Godfrey program because we can't get the show on the night it appeared; we've got a conflict of stations on one ABC channel and a mania for local basketball on the other. But I am watching every possible show for mentions of you. I would miss the one that <hi rend="underline">did</hi> mention you! I should say that I have the entire English department and assorted historians, friends, casual passers-by, and general public alerted to the coming of the best show on TV in many a year  You will have an audience out here, all right; I'm now scouting my friends for the ones with the best color set--our two sets are black and white only.</p>
<p>Tell me more about the Knopf plans about you; you said something about the possibility that they would take over the hardback rights. Who do you deal with at Knopf? I am excited about that, too; to get those books all back in print in good editions would be great. If they do the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>, would they replate it in consistent type? You must keep me up to date on the happenings. When I get to the next books, I'll need all this. You live up enough to fill a ten-volume set. On second thought, make it twenty.</p>
<p>This letter is a little late--I've been in bed with a throat infection that I couldn't seem to throw off. It is gone now except for a nose-ear fuzzy feeling, and I missed a day of school, but I'm navigating again. I do want you to know, however, that I have begun the rework on the manuscript and will be able to work pretty steadily. It isn't a momumental job, really; I find that I can delete phrases and some sentences without taking out chunks, and it shortens quite a bit. Fewer adjectives are generally better anyway.</p>
<p>Love to everybody, especially yourself, and keep me up to date  That takes some doing, the way you live. WE are thinking about you.</p>

<closer>
<salute></salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
