<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.32a.3-4">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, July 6, 1968</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.32a.3-4</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Aly, Lucile F.</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, July 6, 1968</title>
<date when="1968-07-06">July 6, 1968</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Agamemnon</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term>Los Angeles (Calif.)</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>When the Tree Flowered</term>
<term>Cycle</term>
<term>Odyssey</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1968-07-06"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.32a.3-4.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>July 6, 1968
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Here are the two Chapman letters. I am just back from a trip to Los Angeles I didn't know I was
going to have to make, or they would have reached you earlier. I wish I could be there for your
state Neihardt Day--I have looked forward to it all year, but I can't get away for a while; my
father is not doing well, and he is so dependent on me that I am afraid to be gone again even for a
few days. If he is better in August I will try to get out. It is very hard to see him endure what he
now endures--with a patience I'm not sure I could not muster. I wish you and he could really have
known each other; you are the same kind of men, with the old Roman <hi rend="underline">virtue</hi></p>

<p>You don't have quite all the book yet. I am now typing a chapter on <hi rend="underline">When the Tree
Flowered</hi> and the single-volume <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>; then there's a shortish section called "Laurel Decade" which describes so many honors that it's all but unbelievable. Has anyone ever told you you're a great man?</p>

<p>I am going to telephone you--I just want to hear your voice, really. Since the time is different
there, would it be best for me to call on Sunday? If you can tell me what would be a good time, I
will call on Sunday the 14th. I suspect you had better send back the chapters wiht notes if you have
any be-yond the things you mentioned, and you must have. I wanted to see what you think--as I said I
was hesitant about some of the material. I put in the weddings because I wanted to mention the
grandchildren, and I thought perhaps I out to get the parents married, abut I don't want to give
Hilda or Alice and shadow of pain. I admire them all tremendously, and I want them to feel good and
right about the book. I think one thing that bothers me is that I am so keenly aware that I am
writing only the <hi rend="underline">first</hi> biography. All this material will be searched and analyzed and mulled over like the Shakespeare sources by many many critics after we both are gone, and I sometimes put material in because I want to give it the tone and perspective it ought to have. I know all of you from</p>

<fw type="curatorial">4</fw>
<p>the inside of your letters, and I am jealous of your portrait for the world to come--and Hilda's and Alice's. If I sometimes get material in that you think is too personal it's because I don't want future writers to be able to charge that my picture is wrong because I left out things. Neither Hilda or Alice made an irresponsible Hollywood kind of marriage; they were beautiful and honest marriages, and if they didn't work out it was because fine, sen-sitive, honest girls ran into problems with them that could be solved only that way. This is what I meant to come through, but if it doesn't you are probably right about deleting.</p>

<p>Stewart wants me to give you his love. He is here this summer taking courses in Greek and Roman history and reading the Odyssey in seminar with Professor Combellack. He is loving it all, and I am sending for Zerox copies of the pages of your translation of the Agamemnon, which I should have anyway. I shall write in a discussion of it in the proper chapter; now it's just a mention. Stewart is going to assist me with an analysis of it; when I told him it's a line shorter than the original he really boggled. He is in love with Greek as you were--syntax and all.
Jingle also sends love to you and Jacques. She has led such a sheltered life that she doesn't know she's a beagle and never has learned to bay, so she can't express her wish to see you that way, but she can and does wag her white tail for you, and she would put her paws on your lap and fix loving eyes on your face if she would. She would probably lose her head ober Jacques.</p>

<closer>
<salute>My best regards ot the Youngs--I am writing Mrs. Young also.
Much love, </salute>

<note></note>
</closer>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>