<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34.27">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, June 16, 1970</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34.27</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, June 16, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-06-16">June 16, 1970</date>
<extent>1 page</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Indian Tales</term>
<term>When The Tree Flowered</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1970-06-16"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34.27.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>June 16, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Your <hi rend="underline">two</hi> letters were good news as always. Yes, I have heard from the Press; Mr. Nicoll sent me the contract to sign, and I am to get one in return signed by the Press people. Miss Faulkner sent me a blank to fill out for promotion information--What textbook possibilities has this book? and such questions. I filled it in and she wrote to say she got it. They are piled up with manuscripts that came in late like mine, for much the same recent reasons--universities are or have been in such turmoil that nobody could get work done. You wouldn't believe the time this spring I have had to spend in staff meeetings. Some of them were the soul-searching kind about what our objectives really are and what should be the role of the professor, the department, the administration, the students, etc. etc. etc.--and far, far into the night. I can understand their problem at the press; Miss Faulkner said everything came in at once. So I haven't heard anything about the reaction to the book--just that it arrived.</p>

<p>It's wonderful that all your books are coming out again. It is an absolute shame to have anything by Neihardt out of print--have you thought that your writings may <hi rend="underline">never</hi> again be out of print? I have. Every sign is encouraging for a real boom and a lasting ovation. I should have written Mr. Nicoll about <hi rend="underline">Indian Tales</hi>; last summer when I was in Lincoln I told him he ought to publish <hi rend="underline">When the Tree Flowered</hi>, because it was better than the Inidan things getting so much attention, and he siad then he would look into it and wrote down the title--so I'm glad he did. I mentionaed <hi rend="underline">Indian Tales</hi> too, but evidently not loud enough. I thnk Vylin and The Last Thunder Song are two of the best short stories about Indians ever written. Actually they aren't just about, Indians, which explains their unique power.</p>
<p>What are the/plans for Neihardt Day this year? Where is is to be--in Bancroft or in Lincoln? I am planning to come, and I want to get to Lincoln for a day or so anyway, but I should soon be making reservations. Where will <hi rend="underline">you</hi> be? You said something about going back to Missouri, and I can see that the prospect would bring some saddening memories to you. You would not try to stay at Skyrim, would you? I should think in town would be easier, at least for bad weather. Do let me know what you decide and when you'll be where. I assume that wherever you are, you'll get to Nebraska for The Day. I'm teaching this summer, and my trip will have to be short, but I'll take enough time off to be there for the celebration and to see you and the Youngs beforehadn. I wish you were coming here; we will always think of this as partly yours.</p>

<p>What do you hear of Robin? I hope all is well with him, and Nei, and all the bouncing generation of Neihardts. So young Mona got her doctorate! I was always impressed with her, and I hope she is off on a career she will love. What does she paln to do now--will she teach?</p>

<p>Please fill me in on Neihardt doings and schedules. I'll write soon again, too. Bower sends love, and so does Stewart. Jingle encloses her own most melodious arfs.</p>


<closer>
<salute>Love,</salute>
<signed></signed>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>