<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 50

Grayson, Georgia
30221
May 3, 1971

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska
68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>May I hereby acknowledge most gratefully yours of Friday, April 23rd, in response to April '71.</p>
<p>Permit my reply to your comments, please. Firstly, I wish I were able to be counted amongst those attending your unique honor on the occasion of your fiftieth year in the status of Nebraska's Poet Laureate on Wednesday, April 21st. The program pamphlet forwarded will be prized by me; while I enjoy the fact that you recited "Let Me Live Out My Years" and "L'envoi" on your special day, how difficult the task to select two because I have my favorites was the task because you have an unusual excellence from poem to poem. As I study the print of you at the June '21 presentation of the legislative resolution conferring the status of Poet Laureate upon you, I have no burden in detecting you whose vim and struggled soul shine, with every respect to those with you. And, while the honor was preserved in print for June '21, I am hopeful that the activities of April '71 at the State Capitol are available on tape audio and/or video. Secondly, therefore, I come to your splendid appearance on the American Broadcasting Company's "<sic>Dict</sic> Cavett's Show" of Tuesday, April 27th (and of Wednesday, April 28th!) because the honor was to the show by your presence. Again, I trust that every foot viewable will be given to the various educational television stations throughout the Nation; surely, it is foreordained that ABC's will be to schedule an appropriate encore of its ninety-minute telecast.</p>
<p>There is a Spirit in, of, and about you, I discover reflectively. One's lurdan would appear intellectually if one were not mindful of the Spirit. John Gneisenau Neihardt has thanked the tears' life's pain, has established the glory's life's success, and has welcomed the life's soul's soul. His has graced life <underline>form mens sana in corpore sano</underline> to <underline>suaviter in modo, fortiter in re</underline>, and the grace isn't exhausted. To look at his exterior makes one think he looks like...; nay, strike, for it is the late actor Charles Bickford who looks like him, either in the early days or the late days. But, to look at his interior makes one think he is unique. Every man, woman is unique, one knows. To asterisk his uniqueness is nowise to diminish the uniqueness of others, but to star his uniqueness is abundantly to increase the uniqueness of the human race. John Neihardt has the timber and the timbre to observe that he has just done his best in life, and one with the adaptible and adoptable wisdom knows his 'just' is beyond the most of us. Ah, that's the key to him, because he shares with others the best of himself, and momentarily we know a value on our respective uniqueness comes as much from a poet's poet as from ourselves. So, lastingly, we know his is <underline>more</underline> unique. Recognizing this, one bends to life's fortunates demanding reverence for the Spirit. What's from the Spirit: It's a wish to be about mankind, not above, to be of mankind, not apart, and to be in mankind, not beyond. Sojourning this, one stands to soul's fortunates commanding reverence for the Spirit. If mankind cares about its inner self, it cares about the Neihardt Spirit because from the demand to the command one finds that the Spirit is reflective of mankind's best. You John Neihardt: How great a Spirit. Great enough! You believed in mankind before it in you, did it not. You failed not in your race;  mankind's race appears better because of you. Yes, great-great enough, the Spirit.</p>

Page 51

Dr. John G. Neihardt
Page -2-
Monday, May 3rd

<p>Sir, pardon my palaver! I wish no burdens on your eyes. Indeed, I have no circumspection about Mrs. Young's reading my mail to you, with your approval. I, however, wish to add my tribute to your honors. Again, I suppose my words do not compare with the veridical ones from others, but again my sincerity is no less, I assure forthwith. Then, too, I think all should honor you in your life. From the masterful Scop's MUCH ADO ABOUT NORTHING's Act IV--Scene I, I believe--there is a serious passage despite the framework of the comedy; it goes as follows: "...for it falls out/That what we have we prize not to the worth/Whiles we enjoy it, but being lack'd and lost/Why, the we rack the value, then we find/The virtue that posession would not show us/Whiles it was ours." Between 91st and 110th, there will be more honors deserved. Just keep your health. The news about your six lectures, from Mrs. Young, is most meaningful to the end. Eyes can be a source of concern to older persons, especially those in your measure; for example, my friend, Mr. Carl Vinson, former Dean of the United States House of Representatives and Georgian achieving a record in the House's history for sevices beyond fifty years, has experienced trouble to the point that I requested that we await time for visits for exchanges. Beyond your eyes valuable as they are, I hope your general health good.</p>
<p>If you would, Dr. Neihardt, I would be honored if you could inscribe a large photograph, suitable for my walls, with a direct message. I would be honored to place yous amongst those representative of America's, world's greatest literary figures. A caveat: I plan no requests for a book. I am often honored with books, but I leave often to the senders' judgement. The photograph, I do wish, please. And, if you comply, I shall promise to withhold my use of Latin in my missives. Frankly, for one who studied Latin for five hours per day during your scholarship years with the "dead" language, I am not less than elated that you do not benignly reprimand my use as you could probably read it still it were written still. I have no comparable status in the wildest imagination with your status with Latin.</p>
<p>Meantime, stay well. Work still. One of your colleagues, Mr. Carl Sandburg, was considered my firend; and, while I do not wish to discuss personal exchanges with him, I would  recollect for you that he was always interested in the welfare of friends of whom he would seek in details reapitulations on problems of health and that the friends of whom he would seek in details recapitulations on problems of health and that the friends were always interested in his. Dr. Neihardt, I trust that life has years and years to travel with you; I shall always welcome a letter from you; you must never disregard the liberty extended by me for one at your personal desire. Oh, oh, as the late Mr. Sandburg would laugh and say, we won't save the world from end to end in talking but we just might help it as we enjoy ourselves in friendship.</p>
Best wishes!
<note>next few lines/words written in Latin</note>
<p>Virir antiquia nihil erat Genuinely,
quod meliur esset quem Wilmer Bentley
Virtir et sapientia - Wilmer Douglas Bentley
ADDENDUM: About the photograph, comply at your personal convenience, please.</p>
WDB:bt