<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34a.28.30">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Robert F. Sayre to John G. Neihardt, October 3, 1970 </title>
<author>Sayre, Robert F.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.28.30</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Robert F. Sayre to John G. Neihardt, September 22, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-10-03">October 3, 1970 </date>
<extent>3 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term>Columbia (Mo.)</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
<term>The Examined Self</term>
<term>Vachel Lindsay: Adventures, Rhymes, and Designs</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Sayre, Robert F.</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4862034">Iowa City (Iowa)</placeName>
<date when="1970-09-22"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34a.28.30.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>
<fw type="letterhead">THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA
IOWA CITY, IOWA 52240
FOUNDED 1847

Department of English</fw>

<opener>
<dateline>October 3, 1970 
</dateline>
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. John G. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>c/o Julius Young</addrLine>
<addrLine>5835 Vine St.</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska</addrLine>
</address>
<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>I want to thank you and Mrs. Young for your prompt answers to my recent letter and your acknowledgement of the copy of the <hi rend="underline">Iowa Review</hi>. I hope you like the <hi rend="underline"></hi>Review.</p>

<p>Would it be possible for you to authorize Mrs. Prewitt to send me a Xerox copy of the transcript immediately? Unless I can show it to Merle Brown and the editorial staff of the <hi rend="underline">Review</hi>, I can, after all, give you no assurance that they will publish it, that is, publish the portion with Black Elk's description of the Vision. Moreover, if I should come to Columbia again, I would like to have had the chance to read it over more carefully beforehadn. Then I would be in better position to discuss it with you.</p>

<p>Any conditions you wish to set on a copy being sent to me I will naturally honor. As I told you in my last letter, I would greatly appreciate having a copy for my own instruction and to improve my presentation of <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> to my classes, but those wishes must definitely come second to your wishes. So should you wish the Xerox copy returned to you or the Library after my showing it to Professor Brown, I will gladly do that. It would be treated with the traditional confidence of material sent to (or shown to) an editor. Then if further deliberations and preparations are necessary--as they well may be, though I hope not complicated ones--I will be more than happy to accept your invitation for another visit to Columbia.</p>

<p>As I said before, I think this little project could do a great deal xxxxxxx in directing a new audience towards <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> and Indian experience and culture. What I want, as a scholar, is intelligent appreciation of the Indian way. Learning what I have from your book and from my friend Chuck Storm, I want other people to learn too. And learn <hi rend="underline">from</hi>, not just <hi rend="underline">about</hi>. So I think we are on the right road, the "red road". But if you would rather wait until, say, after the publication of my essay on "Vision and Experience in <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi>," then I will be glad to hold off on this project. I have been meaning, you know, to send you a copy of the essay, but it is still not in final form.</p>

<fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
<p>Perhaps you could also have some one in Lincoln draw copies of my books <hi rend="underline">The Examined Self</hi> and <hi rend="underline">Vachel Lindsay: Adventures, Rhymes, and Designs</hi> from the University of Nebraska library; and ask Mrs. Young to read you a little from them. Our acquaintance has been hindered, I think, by our not knowing enough of each other's writing, your very, very extensive writing and my so far very limited publication; And it is, I needn't add, a part of the Indian way to be thorough about getting acquainted!</p>

<p>So please do not think that I am trying to rush you on this little project regarding the Iowa Review. From our own perspectives there is simply no need for it. But reread the conversations I would like to do, as I said, and show them to Merle Brown I would have to do before he could make a decision about publishing the description of the Vision.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Very sincerely,</salute>
<signed>Robert f. Sayre</signed>
<note>Robert F. Sayre</note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>