<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from J. E. Boodin to John G. Neihardt, May 23, 1918</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.5.23-27_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from J. E. Boodin to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1918-05-23">May 23, 1918</date>
                    <extent>5 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>5 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0001b" />
                
                <note type="curatorial">Neihardt Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>717 <hi rend="caps">E.</hi> 2nd St., Northfield, Minn., May 23, 1918.</dateline>
                
                <salute>Dear Mr. Neihart<sic>Neihardt</sic>:</salute></opener> <p>Thank you so much for your kind letter. I hope you will not forget to make me the visit you promise. Why not take a little summer vacation with me here? I expect to be here most of the summer, esp. the earlier part. Northfield is a beautiful little place, and I believe you would like it here. Perhaps you might like it so well that you would settle here. It is near the cities and yet has the atmosphere of the country.</p>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                
                <p>And now as to your generous estimate of me as a philosopher. You are quite right that
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0002b"/>
                    
                    the <unclear>comparison</unclear> with Bergson is origin<unclear/> with you. And if it did not seem immodest on my part, I would like to believe that you are right. I do believe that I possess the homely virtues of the Anglo-Saxon mind &#8212; the virtues of honesty and sanity. And it seems true that it takes those virtues to make a genuine philosophy. The Germans have been given too much to Schw‰rmerei <!--enthusiasm in German--> and have failed to keep in touch with realities. Their political philosophy; of which the world is eating the bitter fruits, is part and outcome of this fantastic and brutal Schw‰rmerei. The French, genial and delightful 
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0002a"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">(3)</fw>
                    
                    as they are, have been too fond of short cuts &#8212; intuition for example. They have not kept close enough to the prose of everyday life. As you say Bergson's approach is after all the individualistic approach which has characterized philosophy up-to-date. But truth is a social institution, and our climb upward must be a social ascent. You may be interested to know that I am burying myself <add>^ at present</add> largely with social philosophy and my next book will be along that line, which you may regard as a verification of your diagnosis.</p> 
                
                <p>It remains, however, that before a philosopher can claim a place as the leader of an age he must win the place. And that must be done by those who find him helpful. Bergson's prominence in the Anglo-American consciousness (and it is there chiefly that he has won prominence
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0001a"/>
                    
                    <note type="curatorial">232</note>
                    
                    is due chiefly to the generous Estimate by Wm. James. "Creative Evolution" had been given only secondary place among the reviews of the philosophical magazines &#8212; a notice among new books &#8212; before James' article in the Hibbert Journal. After that it was translated and articles began to appear, following James' lead. Then he became a fad. What place Bergson will have eventually is of course impossible to say; but it is safe to say that it won't <unclear>bulk</unclear> as large as it did a few years ago. In the meantime, thanks partly to James, partly of course to Bergson's own attractiveness, he has had an important influence, which is a great deal. Other philosophers, Spinoza for example, have been little known in their lifetime, but have won their place eventually through their solid merits. At best there is an element of accident about leadership in thought as in other fields, and some flowers are born to blush unseen for want of timely advertising. I am pleased and grateful for your appreciation for it is such appreciation that makes a philosopher's place. There is little chance for a philosopher to get a hearing now amidst
                  
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0003"/>
                    
                    <fw  type="curatorial">25</fw>
                
                the thunder of cannon and the <unclear>starving</unclear> to the utmost of the instinct of self-preservation. So it is all the more grateful to find a choice soul who is keeping alive to the deeper import of things amidst the terrible confusion. Genuine patriotism must mean more than beating Germany, though we <hi rend="underline">must</hi> do that. It must have in mind and help create, a world worth living in while we beat the Germans and <hi rend="underline">after</hi>. It is as a comrade in this task that I welcome you into my experience.</p>
               
                <p>I thank you again for your generous recognition and hope to see you soon.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely Yours,</salute> <signed>J.E. Boodin</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.5.23-26_0004"/>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    NORTHFIELD, 
                    May 24-18
                    3----PM
                    MINN.
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S.POSTAGE 3 CENTS 3</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mr. John G. Neihar<del>t</del><add>dt</add>,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Bancroft,</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Nebraska</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note place="bottom" type="curatorial">Found in <hi rend="underline">A Realistic Universe</hi> &#8212; John Boodin <hi rend="caps">NY</hi>. The Macmillan Co 1916</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>