<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.31.23">

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Ward to John G. Neihardt, June 30, 1967</title>
<author>Ward</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2016</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace>
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>

<idno>nei.j4a.31.23</idno>

<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>


<notesStmt>
<note></note>
</notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Ward</author>

<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Ward to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1967-06-30">June 30, 1967</date>
<extent>1 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>1 typed page</p>
</msContents>
<history>
<origin></origin>
<provenance></provenance>
<acquisition></acquisition>
</history>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fink, Oliver</term>
<term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
<term>Nei</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Poplar Bluff (Mo.)</term>
<term>Pittsburgh (Penn.)</term>
<term>Missouri</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Ward</persName>
<placeName>Poplar Bluff (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1967-06-30"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
</person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017">
<name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura</name> Proofreading and encoding
</change>

<change when="2016">
<name xml:id="rs">Styles, Ryan</name> Transcription and Initial Encoding
</change>


</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<note type="curatorial">23</note>

<opener>
<address>
<addrLine>THREE RIVERS JUNIOR COLLEGE</addrLine>
<addrLine>507 Vine Street Sunset 5-7794-A. C. 314</addrLine>
<addrLine>Poplar Bluff, Missouri 63901</addrLine>
</address>
</opener>
<dateline>30 June 1967</dateline>

<opener><salute>Dear John:</salute></opener>
<p>Your letter was awaiting us when we returned from a four-week trip east to visit longtime friend we hadn't seen for as much as a dozen years, and to spend 10 days in Pittsburgh with one of our daughters and her two youngsters.</p>

<p>Glad to hear that the work on your Memories is moving along. Think perhaps you are right to wait until it is all completed to publish. And we're awaiting its appearance, because we want to read it. The excerpts we heard a year ago when we saw you in Columbia whetter our appetite for more.</p>

<p>I'm keeping busy with small chores around the college, big chores in my yard and fishing whenever the mood <del/> develops. I find the college an interesting focus for my activities. There's always something-- a problem, a dilemma or a success-- to demand attention.</p>

<p>What you tell me about the reception of Black Elk and the reissue of other books in paperback is most interesting. It seems ironic to me that you've had a bigger audience overseas for <del/> many years than you've had in this country. But it's gratifying to know that finally the homefolks are beginning to appreciate a very rare and most talented person.</p>

<p>Have you ever speculated on why the surge of interest in your work now?</p>

<p>I ask myself why, and I wonder if it may be part of the repudiation of material values that seems to have <del/> become a hallmark of the postwar generation. Is there something in the mystical <del/> and spiritual tone of much of your writing that is appealing to a generation that sees only failure in the economic determinists and the commercial pirates who've dominated the scene for so long? Or is it just the fact that we as a people suddenly have become reponsive to the human warmth, the joy of living, and the love of man that radiates from you?</p>

<p>Well, whatever it is, we are delighted that increasing recognition is coming you <del/> way.</p>

<p>We have correspondent with Ollie and Enid, but haven't seen them since we saw you. I've been trying to get them to come down this way for a visit, but it's awfully hard to pry Ollie loose, except to go to Wisconsin to see Nei and the grandchildren.</p>

<p>If you're going to be back in Missouri anytime next fall, let us know. We may be able to get up to see you. Right now, it's too almight hot <del/> for us to contemplate any journey farther than a fishing hole.</p>

<p>We're always glad to hear from you, but we surely understand why you don't have too much time for correspondence.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Affectionately</salute>
<signed>Ward</signed>
</closer>


</div1>

</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>