<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Frank Valentine to John G. Neihardt, March 27, 1952</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.23.10-11_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Frank Valentine to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1952-03-27">March 27, 1952</date>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>7 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0001b"/>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline><hi rend="underline">March 27, 1952</hi></dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>            <fw type="authorial">Pg <hi rend="underline">1</hi></fw>
                </opener>
                <p>As I was perusing through your "Cycle of the West" a few hours ago, it suddenly occurred to me that almost a year had elapsed since I studied poetry under you. And equally, almost a year that I hadn't written to you.</p>
                
                <p>Sometimes one becomes <del/> so intimately snarled in the whirlwind of a pragmatic life, that he hasn't time to pause and ponder on his surroundings. I guess that 
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0002b"/>
                
                    <fw type="authorial"><hi rend="underline">2.</hi></fw>
                
                    is what happened to me.</p>
                
                <p>Since I graduated in June, I've led a fairly active life, working for six months on <hi rend="underline">Newsweek</hi> magazine, and at present, editing two small local weeklies in a rural section of Long Island. The work is interesting, but it isn't poetry that I'm writing. It's merely that half suspended prose that stretches in a vague space between good prose and pure "hack" writing. But it's interesting work, and will do for the present.</p>
                
                    <note type="curatorial" place="right_margin"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0002a"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial"><hi rend="underline">3.</hi></fw> 
                
                <p>I saw Reese Johnson when he visited New York City during the summer months. He didn't stay here long, returning to Missouri in a few days.</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>_____ _____</ab>
                <lg><l>A manflower, springing from 
                    the fresh green sod,</l>
                <l>While all the bushes burned with God"</l></lg>
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>_____ _____</ab>
                
                <p>Those are perhaps the most moving creative lines you wrote in the "Cycle." I never tire reading and re-reading your stuff. One morning, I was sitting on a commuter's train going into the <del><unclear>city</unclear></del>city. It was early, and I sat blinking
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0001a"/> 
                
                    tired burning eyes, first out the window and then at the sterile blankness on the faces of the passengers in my car. Then I picked up your "Cycle" and commenced to read at random. When I hit those lines, my hair stood erect, and I was conscious of a great inner feeling of exileration<sic>exhilaration</sic>. For the rest of the day, I <del><unclear/>ee</del> kept the beautiful feeling in those lines in my mind. How expressive they are! In them is the story of the world, the power of life, moving forward at massive momentum, the snuffing out of <del>one</del> not one man but of two by that one bullet, while
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0003"/>
                
                    life, ironic and persistent in its unfolding, continues onward to new creation. It is impossible to describe it in prose. It would take volumes, and in the end, it would only be prose.</p>
                
                <p>By the way, sir, if you are coming to New York any time in the future, you are most welcome to be our guest. You mentioned something last year about going to a poet's convention in <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi></p>
                
                <p>This coming Easter, my two little weeklies are going to put out an Easter edition. I wonder if you
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0004b"/>
                    
                    <fw type="authorial">5.</fw>
                
                    would allow me to print your Easter poem for the Easter editions. If so, I would appreciate it very much. But I feel that you should know that I can't afford to pay any money for this privilege. I'm only the editor, and I can't formulate the policy of the papers. So if you say no, it's perfectly alright with me. I thought it would top off a good Easter edition.</p>
                
                <p>How is "Gelty" getting along this year. Her poetry took a leap for the better around the last part of the semester.</p>
                
                    <note type="curatorial" place="right_margin"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note> 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.23.10-11_0004a"/>
                
                    <fw type="authorial">6.</fw>
                
                <p>I did a small poem in free verse that I've enclosed. I think it could stand for a lot of technical improvement, but I like the idea of it. Perhaps in the future, I'll work to fit it into verse form.</p>
                
                <p>Well sir, I imagine that about this point in my letter, you are getting tired of deciphering my scrawled English hieroglyphics, so I'll kill this letter. If you could find time to answer it, I'd appreciate it. Let me know about printing the Easter <del>Po</del>poem.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>A Former <unclear>Admiring</unclear> Student</salute>
                
                    <signed>Frank Valentine</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>