<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34.20.21">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, April 3, 1970</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F. </author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34.20.21</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, April 3, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-04-03"></date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
<term>When The Tree Flowers</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1970-04-03"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34.20.21.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>May 10, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>It was wonderful to talk with you, I'm writing you a new letter because I told you all the news
in the last one. I am mailing the contract to Mr. Nicoll tomorrow morning, and the manuscript should
be in the mail by Wednesday. The typist is making the corrections on the Bibliography and I have
some of it yet to Xerox. I don't remember the exact number, but I think it's about 1005 pages in
all; though that does not count the Table of Contents and Acknowledgements. They run just <hi
rend="crossed">three</hi> four! I'm not dedicating it to anyone--your life is to big to be written for anything or anyone but just itself.</p>

<p>I think as soon as this is out of the way your book will be in print. It's better timing, not because the Memoir isn't the real priority but because the criticism in the Biography can give people your scope before they read your memories, adn your account adds the deep emotional overtone. I'm eager to see it myself. I'm glad you're doing the adult years too; there is a great deal to remember, You can put in all the Oregon trips that I didn't elaborate because I did not want even briefly to get myself in the way of your life. Too many biographies I've read are full of the biographer and I always wish such writers would leave themselves out. So I did. People want to read about <hi rend="underline">you</hi>, not about some female they never heard of.</p>

<p>We had a quiet weekend here, but everyone expects a bad day tomorrow. Classes are supposed to resume after a two-day suspension for anti-war activities, and some of the students are determined to prolong a "strike," I shall meet my classes, but I'm not sure what will happen when I get there. Most of the students I have talked to want to go to class; they rather resent the interruption of their studies. We've had some trouble in the English Department because three of our less responsible faculty members organized a</p>

<fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
<note type="authorial">- 2 -</note>
<p>"Convocation" attended by chiefly students from other departments, and in the name of the English department they declared an indefinite strike. It is making for a great deal of confusion, because some students think it's official--the notice come out in the student paper, and so far they haven't published a retraction. There are crazy times. I could quote from you at great length about the nonsense we're seeing. Fortunately, the majority of young people are fine, as you say.</p>

<p>We, and Stewart, are really saddned today by the suicide of one of Stewart's friends--a fine and able young man with apparently everything going for him. You many have met him out here; his name was Ron Brandt. We feel specially bad because Bower and I were asked to be his guardians some years ago, in case anything happened to his parents before he came of age. Stewart knew Ron was smoking marijuana, but he thought it was a passing whim. I saw Ron on campus last week and his face lit up when he spoke to me--he looked so young and strong and alive I couldn't believe he had destroyed himself. How is such a tragedy to be understood? What cuts a young man adrift? <hi rend="underline">is</hi> it the times? Terrible, terrible.</p>
<p>Jingle is fine, and sends you a hearty tail-wag. She has a special place on the kitchen radiator where she can lie on a cushion and keep one eye on her yard, in/case a cat forgets itself as to intrude through the fence. We have some trouble convincing her that the rosebushes we have put in are not planted for her to dig up, and she should also keep her nose out of the tulips. She would love having Jacquot around to help her patrol and dig holes. She's got all sorts of gamey bones and old treasures buried all over the yard.</p>

<p>I'm delighted to hear about <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi>. I have lent a copy to the Junior High School because it's so much/in demand. We'll see you a lousy-rich Hollywood personality yet. And <hi rend="underline">I'll</hi> see you this summer; I'm really looking forward. I'll get details from Myrtle about the celebrations planned.</p>

<p>Lots of love form Alys. We think of you  every day and wish we could see you. Special love from me.</p>

<closer>
<salute></salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>