<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36.18-19">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, February 5, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36.18-19</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Dr. Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-02-05">February 5, 1972</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.18"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>February 5, 1972</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I wish you had all the letters I have <hi rend="underline">thought</hi> to you. We've had the flu here--both Bower and I, though I haven't had flu for years. This kind is treacherous; don't you get it. In fact, don't let anyone with a sore throat anywhere near you. We didn't have to go to the hospital as many of our friends did, but we were flattened at home.</p>
                
                <p>Did Robin tell you I talked with him while you were in the hospital? I hoped to catch Hilda, but she is a busy lady. It was nice to talk to Robin; I still can't believe he is so completely grown up. Just before Myrtle wrote that you had recovered and were in Lincoln I dreamed about you. I knew you had been quite ill, and that you were better, but I was still uneasy. In the dream you were talking to a small group of people, and as usual when I dream about you, you were in the center of the light, as if you were in a spotlight. You were talking animatedly, and then I heard you laugh and woke up thinking, "John's all right." And then Myrtle's letter same. I hope you are still walking around the block when you have a mind to.</p>
                
                <p>I am sending in the same mail a letter to you, really a birthday card, from a little boy in Eugene to whom you are the center of the universe. He is the son of one of my students, and he is something like you--that is, he's a genius. He went out the top of all the <hi rend="caps">IQ</hi> tests and the state board is hunting an expert to try to test him. Meanwhile he is by special a<del/><add>r</add>rangement taking courses in the university along with his elementary school work, and he is looking for a math book that will teach him enough to und<del>r</del><add>e</add>rstand Einstein. I'm sending along a poem he wrote that he is willing for you to see. This reminds me so happily of the things I know about your early life that I thought you would be interested.</p> 
                
                <p>Also, I want to tell you about the biography. I have sent it to Missouri Press, and they warned me that it would be a month or two. I also sent them a copy of the letter from Angus Cameron at Knopf because it speaks well of the book and apologizes ina<sic>in a</sic> way for not publishing it--too specialized. I do want to 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.19"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw> 
                <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                    
                    see it in print, and you are right that it doesn't compete with your book. It does something you can't do for your own work; it pitches at the scholars who eventually cement poetry and prose into permanency. I find more and more young people who light up when your name is mentioned. The public is more than ready; words to the critics are now the step. I hope you will keep me up to date, because in the final editing I can add to the last chapter. I will put the President's letter in, and anything else you do in the meantime. I get the same feeling of inspiriting astonishment when I think about your life and your work that struck me when I first started. I am also getting at the letters gradually. It's a dreadful job of selection.</p> 
                
                <p>Do please take care of yourself in the cold weather. And when you feel like writing, toss me a line to say you're all right and still love me. I'll have an Olympia beer for you by proxy. Regards to the family and to Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi> I'm sending this letter to Lincoln because I don't know which circle you are illuminating at the moment. Perhaps I'll dream again.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Love from us all---</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Lucile</signed> 
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
