<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34a.33.34">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt, Dec 4, 1972</title>
<author>Thompson, Earl</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34a.33.34</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt, Dec 4, 1972</title>
<date when="1972-12-04"></date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Kelly, Katie</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Thompson, Earl</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/3020134">Entrecasteaux (France)</placeName>
<date when="1972-12-04"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34a.33.34.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<address>
<addrLine>Earl Thompson</addrLine>
<addrLine>La Casarat</addrLine>
<addrLine>83 Entrecasteaux (Var)</addrLine>
<addrLine>France.</addrLine>
</address>
<dateline>Dec. 4, 1972
</dateline>
<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt;</salute>
</opener>

<p>Received your most welcome letter. That you are both well and have more of your work afoot in the literary jungle than damn near anyone else at the moment is twice blessed news. This same day I recieved a letter from Katie Kelly who believes the piece she did for the Saturday Review is the best thing she has written. She may be flying over here for Christmas, and promises to bring me a copy of the article. She also promises to portage a couple cans of cranberry sauce as they do not know about it in these parts.</p>

<p>I am in possession of a truly fine barrel of good wine, no small part of which will be consumed it fitting toasts to you and to what you mean to us. When the fire is on the grate and the wind around the corners of the house, we will certainly fill a cheering cup for your spirit which lives now in all lands for all time, and can pass smoke with the giants.</p>

<p>Indeed, I do often think of good days when we were together in Epic America and the meals we shared. There have been three things in my life outside of what was there at the begining which have shaped my soul more than anything else; A cussedly stubborn grandfather form who I learned perseverence in the face of the 'smart money' to pursue my own folly, and no small amount of marvelously profane history; the words and way of seeing I learned from you which gave shape and understanding which was before stubborn intuition and enormous lonely aches; then, the love I discovered through my children which teaches me so much this side of greater wisdom about how to be a good, aging warrior.</p>

<p>The new novel is quite as profane as the last. It is about a lad who for want of better alternatives follows war in search of citizenship which has through circumstance been denied him, and something like glory. He discovers ultimately there is no glory in killing other poor people and no citizenship garnered thereby worth having. A good soldier with no war worth going to. It begins at the end of WWII and ends with the disasterous early battles of The Korean War. The Seventh Cavalry rides again. This is played off against the lad's civilian alternatives of petty crime or thankless, transient employment. He could well have been a tropper with Custer. The Indians are called Gooks. I have posted 362 pages to my publisher. My editor seems satisfied so far.</p>

<p>I hope next to do a <hi rend="underline">small</hi> book for a change;of prose pieces as finely wrought as I am able, perhaps seemingly unrelated, but strung together by pervasive theme or point of view. Bold face type and lots of margin. As close as I shall ever come to poetry.</p>
<p>Switzerland: As I found I will pursue skiing as avidly as Lord Longford will follow his nose on the track of pornography, I had to get away from the mountains or no work would get done. Also, in a ski resort there are many people with whom to speak but really very few with whom one may truly talk. Here in France the ratio is reversed. It is a good place to work. I am in hardscrabble vine country -- Van Gogh country -- The light is always changing and it is always arresting. The family is</p>

<fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
<fw type="authorial">2</fw>
<p>together more. We respect and enjoy the housr we are in. If we do not always experience the joy we might, it is because of the wasteful nonsense we have brought with us. But the possibility for great joy and industry is here.</p>

<p>Today is letter writing day. Tomorrow I must get back to work.</p>

<p>There are many fine folks coming for the holidays. You will be with us as I know you will be with
so many others. When I am full of turkey and cutting into my jack-o-lantern pie, (of which there is
none better than that of Deanne's art,) I will chuckle way down deep, for if there be one man who
might appreciate <hi rend="underline">good</hi> pumpkin pie more than I, it must certainly be you.</p>

<p>So, again, our most sincere best wishes. We will stay in touch.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Your friend,</salute>
<signed>Earl Thompson</signed>
<note type="authorial">Earl Thompson</note>
<note type="authorial"><p>P.S. Wore a moustache -- a dandy -- for the better part of year until it became obvious not a soul was going to remark upon the uncanny resemblence to Mark Twain which I cut. But my hair is almost as long as yours. How do you keep it from tickling your ears?</p></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>