<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35.37.38">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Mark and Judy Meadows to John G. Neihardt, March 17, 1971</title>
<author>Meadows, Judy and Mark</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.35.37.38</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mark and Judy Meadows to John G. Neihardt, March 17, 1971</title>
<date when="1971-03-17">March 17, 1971</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Brown, Joseph Epes</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>When the Tree Flowered</term>
<term>The Sacred Pipe: Black Elk's Account of the Seven Rites of the Ogala Sioux</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Meadows, Mark and Judy</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1971-03-17"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.35.37.38.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>March 17, 1971
</dateline>
<note>Ans: 3/23/71</note>
<salute>Dear Gaki,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Happy St. Pat's Day! Neihardt IS an Irish name, isn't it? I've been meaning to write you ever since we last saw you, but somehow good intentions just don't get the job done.</p>
<p>We saw Enid and Ollie a couple of weeks ago. I had your clock working on it. The main proble was that the click spring on the winding ratchet was broken. I took it over to Enid and set it up. I guess no-one lives in the house at Skyrim, so it is good for the clock to be living with Enid. Loving clocks as I do, I hate for one to sit alone and idle.</p>
<p>We bought a copy of your new phonograph record, but have not had opportunity to hear it yet, as we have no record player. I plan to order a few more copies to save and give as gifts for next Christmas. We have heard favorable comment upon it from a friend who is blind. His wife wrote saying how much they enjoyed it and asking how to go about buying some of your books. I bought a copy of WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED and plan to send it to them. I thin kit will be especially good for her to read aloud to him. I shall also tell her about other titles available.</p>
<p>The other day I noticed a book advertised. It was by Joseph Epes Brown. It's called THE SACRED PIPE: BLACK ELK'S ACCOUNT OF THE SEVEN RITES OF THE OGALALA SIOUX, written in 1949. I guess he was one of the people who you spoke of that sought out Black Elk after you made him famous. I am going to buy a copy of the book to see if he plagiarizes from your work.</p>
<p>We were very pleased with the artical in the Kansas City Star Magazine. I suppose they sent you copies of it; if not, please let me know and I shall send you some. In case you haven't seen it, It has a color picture of you on the front of the magazine and contains a four page article with more pictures. We think it's a good article and would capture a person's attention and hold it. It did so with us, but of course we're prejudiced. I have, however, heard a number of comments about the article from people around here. All were very interested in the article, and all who had not done so said they planned to read some of your work. I expect this article and the Dick Cavett program will introduce many new people to your writings. We are very happy to see you publicized.</p>
<p>The head of the Literature Dept. at Park College, one Dr. Watson, called me the other day and was quite excited about the article in the Star magazine. He asked me if I thought there would be any chance that you could give one of your programs at Park.any time in the next couple of months. I told him that I knew you planned to be in Kansas City some time in May, but that I did not know of your exact committments at that time. I mentioned that I owed you a letter and would be glad you put the matter before you. The semester at Park ends on May 17, so if your visit to Kansas City is to be later than that, we needn't even discuss it. As I say, I don't know what your plans are for that time, but if you would consider doing one of your stunts, we would be delighted to have you come a couple of days early and stay with us. I could come to St. Joseph and pick you up and bring you to our place. Then I could take you to whatever engagements you have in K.C.</p>

<fw type="curatorial">38</fw>

<p>Or, you could stay a couple of days after your programs and go to Park. At any rate, if it is possible for you to speak at Park College and if you want to do so, we will be happy to meet you and bring you here and take you wherever you need to go. Even if you can't speak at Park, the rest of my offer always stands. We will always be tickled pink to have you stay with us at any time. We have an extra bed, and we would love to hang a sign over it saying, JOHN NEIHARDT SLEPT HERE MANY TIMES</p>
<p>Oh, one thing I forgot to mention in connection with Park College, Prof. Watson asked me to tell you that their budget only permits offering small honorariums and that they could not offer you as much as you would deserve.</p>
<p>Did I tell you that we bought a second copy of <hi rend="underline">Poetic Values</hi>, 1st ed.? A book company had the entire stock marked down 20%, so we got it for $8.00. We recently ordered a first ed. of S<hi rend="underline">ong of the Indian Wars</hi>, but it was already sold. Your first editions are really snapped up. We always order the same day we get the catalogues, but so often the book is already gone.</p>
<p>What is the current status of the youth section of your recollections? I have never gotten it quite clear whether that part will be published as a separate volume. Or, will the whole thing be put out in one large volume? We can hardly wait to get our hands on it. How far have you gotten now in telling your life's experiences? Are you going to tell about the time you <hi rend="underline">didn't</hi> visit with Mark Twain? I think that is an interesting story. Also, I was thinking the other day about the lady who gave you that beautiful blue glass vase. I can't remember her name. Are you writing about her? I hope you will not worry about making the book too long. In my opinion--the longer the better. I know that when I read it I'll be sorry there isn't more of it to read.</p>
<p>Judy occasionally goes to Omaha in connection with her job. We thought that the next time she goes, perhaps I could accompany her and we could come over to visit you. I mentioned this to Myrtle on the phone, and she was kind enough to extend an invitation. I hope that when good weather comes we might be able to see you more often. It isn't really a huge journey from here to Lincoln.</p>
<p>You mentioned to us that Mrs. Aly's book is to come out some time this year. What is the prospective month of publication? I do hope the publisher will advertise well, both on her book an don yours. There is really no substitute for effective advertising.</p>
<p>Say, I noticed an ad the other day showing the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi> available in two parts. I was surprised, as I didn't realize you were going to do that. I suppose some people will be drawn to the smaller format when they wouldn' tackle the whole <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>.</p>
<p>Please give our kindest regards to the Youngs, and to Jacquot. We think and speak of all four of you affectionately and often. We hope you are all in good health, and that your back is completely healed now.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Love, </salute>
<signed>
Mark and Judy
Meadows </signed>
<note>4433 North Winn Rd
Kansas City, Mo.</note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>