<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.28a.38-43">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, December 10, 1960</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.28a.38-43</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1960-12-10">December 10, 1960</date>
<extent>5 pages, plus envelope</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>5 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
<term>Skillings, Edna</term>
<term>Skillings, Hugh L.</term>
<term>Chaffee, John E. W.</term>
<term>Charles</term>
<term>Barbara</term>
<term>Mona</term>
<term>Miller, Joaquin, 1837-1913</term>
<term>Shakespeare</term>
<term>Hanson, Philip</term>
<term>Little, Preston</term>
<term>Sherman, L. A. (Lucius Adelno), 1847-1933</term>
<term>Stuff, Frederick A.</term>
<term>Alexander, Hartley Burr, 1873-1939</term>
<term>Conn, Ulysses Sylvester</term>
<term>Avery, Samuel</term>
<term>Hunter</term>
<term>Fink, Oliver</term>
<term>Gray, Sanford D.</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Albany (Or.)</term>
<term>St. Louis (Mo.)</term>
<term>Columbia (Mo.)</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term type="Neihardt"></term>
<term>Moby Dick</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName>Eugene (Or.)</placeName>
<date when="1960-12-10"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name>Weakly, Laura K.</name> added correspDesc</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<note type="curatorial">38</note>

<opener>
<dateline>December 10, 1960</dateline>
<salute>Dear John:</salute></opener>

<p>It can't have been that long! Every day I think about you, and you never seem far away, but I shouldn't expect thinking to take the place of letters. I have a million things to tell you, as usual.</p>

<p>Frances wrote me about your program for her, and she says everyone stood up for you at the end. That's a real tribute, because it isn't an ingrained tradition for young people today. Of course your power is undiminished, and it shouldn't surprise you. You can't really measure the effect you are having on people. I think its wonderful. Please do keep on telling me about such events. I wish I could be there.</p>

<p>Speaking of being there, it isn't possible for Stewart and me to come to St. Louis after all. I hoped we could, but it isn't going to work out. Charles and Barbara and their families want to come for Christmas, too, as its good to be here &#8212; only I do want and need to see you. Is there any chance that you might get here? The would be

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">39</note>

really wonderful! I am coming in May for the big do &#8212; Bower probably won't be able to, but I will be there whatever happens. I wouldn't miss the unveiling of the bronze bust or seeing the Neihardt wing. The contract sounds fine and I'm glad the University is doing all this properly &#8212; in fact, doing it handsomely is just as should be. They do appreciate you there, and it makes me very happy that they do.</p>

<p>I'm sending Mona a check. She has done a very good job, and if the check is not big enough, please do tell me. The letters she sent are wonderful, and now I have more questions. I won't put them in this, but I will make a list. I'm still trying to decipher the Joachin Miller lettter &#8212; his handwriting was terrible.</p>

<p>This will interest you. A young man named Philip Hanson who goes around the country presenting programs of readings &#8212; Shakepeare and Moby Dick and such performed here and was very good. I met him afterwards and conversed with him and he said he was always looking for good material. I asked him is he knew your work

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">40</note>
and he said of course, doesn't everybody? I asked him if he knew the short stories, and told him the gist of one or two, and at that point Preston Little, who teaches interpretation, spoke up and said Hanson couldn't do better than a Neihardt program. The young man was more than interested, so you may hear from him.</p>

<p>You have a solid fan I didn't know about. She is one of the English instructors and I have promised her that when you come again I will get you together. Also the Hunters, who used to be at the University of Nebraska talked to me one whole afternoon about you and all the people at Nebraska U. who knew you &#8212; Sherman and Stuff and Hartley Alexander and Avery. They also know U.S. Conn; we had a wonderful afternoon.</p>

<p>The program I'm giving on you is going to be in your words &#8212; a whale. You and your work are really impressive. Every time I stop what I'm working on and review as far this talk I am excited all over again. The world is really richer for your being in it &#8212; everyone feels it.</p>
<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">41</note>

<p>I got up to Albany two weeks ago and called on the Skillings and Mr. Chaffee. They are getting along, but both men have failed. I don't think Mr. Chaffee quite knew who I was, but he knew who you are all right. He is pretty confused a good bit of the time. Mrs. Skillings is a marvel. She is a courageous woman, and she keeps sweet in spite of all her problems. More than anything else on earth she wants a picture of you, and I haven't anything but snapshots that I could give her. Do you think Ollie could get a print of one of the good photographs the university has of you for her? If you autographed it too she would be in seventh heaven. Knowing you is one of the brightest spots in her life.</p>

<p>John, could you come this Christmas? If you are too complicated with family celebrations, could you come between semesters? I don't like to urge you since it's you who have to do the traveling, but we want you to come. Perky says so too &#8212; she wags her tail all over at the suggestion.</p>

<p>Bower will be in St. Louis. If he gets to Columbia he will probably call you. Take good care of yourself, and remember how much love for you

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">42</note>

flows out from here.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Love,</salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
</closer>
<postscript><p>P.S. Here is the copy for Sandy's record cover. Will you read it for mistakes and let Sandy know of anything you want changed. I tried to underwrite &#8212; my enthusiasm runs away with me, and also I wasn't sure what you said about the poems &#8212; I didn't hear the record. I'm going to, though!!</p></postscript>

</div1>

<div1 type="envelope">

<note type="curatorial">43</note>
<note type="authorial">Air Mail</note>
<note>Via Air Mail</note>
<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. John G. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
<addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
</address></ab>

<ab type="postmark">Eugene Oreg. Dec 10 1960 <unclear/> PM</ab>

<figure n="stamp"><p>US Air Mail 7 &#162;</p></figure>

</div1>

</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
