<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.25-27_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Mildred R. Bennett to John G. Neihardt, October 21, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.25-27_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mildred R. Bennett to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-10-21">October 21, 1958</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.25-27_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">MILDRED R. BENNETT
                        <lb/>
                    329 NORTH CEDAR
                        <lb/>
                    RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Oct. 21, 1958</dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The Myers book came a couple of weeks ago, just before I went into the hospital for a vein stripping--an operation that sounds fearful, but is actually nothing serious. As a result, I had time to read both volumes through without much interruption and I was most pleased, because I could scarcely let them alone.</p>
                
                <p>Much of the philosophy I had more or less figured out by myself, but had no idea that there were others who believed this, much less could offer proof.</p>
                
                <p>I will get the other two books as soon as I can.</p>
                
                <p>When I said I knew a little about e<del>x</del><add>cs</add>tasy I think I may have exaggerated. Once in a while, just as I am waking up, I see such beautiful landscapes that I seem to be crying--I don't know why--because I can't stay or because they are so beautiful. This is such a fleeting thing and so rare that I sometimes think I have imagined it.</p>
                
                <p>Otherwise, <del>i</del><add>I</add> don't think I am a sensitive. I was brought up in the believe that any manifestation of spirits was of the devil. Long ago, I rejected that, but I would be most skeptical of any occurence--thinking it arose out of my own mind. I was reassured by Myers continued emphasis on the fact that many healing and inspirational upsurges do come from one's own subliminal self.</p>
                
                <p>I am eager to learn more. If it is possible to open such avenues of communication (for me) I would like to do so--before the time comes when I will need them so much. It seems to me I should be stronger than this, but I am not. However, with a growing experience of the actuality of life hereafter, I think I could face the present so much better. I remember that both times I have talked with you, you have said--"But this isn't all of it."  I can begin to see what you were talking about in "The Song of the Indian Wars".</p>
                
                <p>If what we see of life is all, then the whole of our existence is a horrible, brutal hox. But for me the churches do not lead anywhere. They are so busy shutting each other out on account of some minor bit of creed.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.25-7_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curtotorail">26</fw>
                
                <p>When our son got big enough to ask questions, I told him that whatever was good in any person would live forever--that if one could choose the better way and thereby grow a little from what he originally was, he would be that much more in the hereafter. This I felt to be true, no matter what dogma might say otherwise. And it satisfied him. Even at the age of four, he could not stand the Sunday School diet of "you will go to Hell if you smoke," etc.</p>
                
                <p>Last night we were talking of age and he said, "We are all the same age, if you look at it one way. We got started at different times." Sometimes I think he reads my mind. He did when he was little.</p>
                
                <p>I wish I could make life easier for this boy. He is such a gentle boy--just sixteen--and he doesn't like hunting because he can't bear to kill anything. He doesn't like to fight--he is a lonely young man--as you can imagine. Unless I can help him with some sort of armor, the impact of the world is going to be very harsh. I don't mean he is soft--he is just sensitive, a scientific mind, but still a dreamer.</p>
                
                <p>As for the doctor, I don't worry about his ability to take care of himself in this world. He has the constant support of his subliminal self--although he attributes it to chance--yet I know that he sees things that are not visible to the senses. He is the sanest person I know--and his patients are (I think) healed just by his presence. I have known them to wait--Old people--until he came to hold their hand so that they could die with him there. You can feel his power when he comes into a room. He does not admit this--but it is true.</p>
                
                <p>So you see, my worries are really selfish. I want our son to have his father's strength, and I want to be able to endure what may come to me while I am still alive. I know I'm a coward--and I have written more freely to you than I would to anyone else. I have known from the first time I saw you that you knew something I wanted to know.</p>
                
                <p>Thank you for giving me the names of the books, and if there is any other book or magazine or contact that I could make, let me know.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Gratefully yours,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Mildred R. Bennett</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.25-27_0003"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Mildred <hi rend="caps">R.</hi> Bennett
                    Red Cloud, Nebr.
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                
                <note><hi rend="underline">ansd</hi></note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    RED CLOUD
                    OCT 21
                    5 30PM
                    1958
                    NEBR.
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p><unclear reason="missing" cert="high">LINCOLN</unclear>
                    4¢
                    U.S. POSTAGE</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
