<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0001-5">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt, September 26, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0001-5</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Earl Thompson to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-09-26">September 26, 1958</date>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>5 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">64</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Earl Thompson
                        <del>B</del><add>7</add>65 Central Blvd.
                        Brownsville, Texas
                
                        Sept. 26, 1958
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear sir;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>It has been many months since I last had the pleasure of smoking with you. I was editing a weekly newspaper in Decatur, Ill. when I learned of your wife's death. I wanted very much to write you at the time and express my own sorrow at the passing, but I had it in my mind that whatever of value I might offer would in relation to the loss be so sorry as to be worse than worthless. I have read your <hi rend="underline">Bundle of Myrrh</hi> <del/> in which you extended to yourself your own condolances years ago for all future losses...or so it seems to me.</p>
                
                <p>I have been working with purpose on my writing and fancy that I see some progress in it. I know that personally I have benefited from the work and if that is all it ever comes to, it will not have been worthless. I miss our talks very much and write you now because were I there I would hot foot it over to hear your ideas on a thing that has given me some moments of <del/> intriguing speculation. It may be that you planted the seed of this idea in my mind and I am only now recalling it. In any case...</p>
                
                <p>I wonder what would happen if we would surrender the country. Simply announce tomorro<del/><add>w</add> that the United States as nation no longer exisits<sic>exists</sic> that we now consider ourselves a world state and would like for the o<del>ur</del><add>th</add>er nations of the world to meet with us and help us decide on a system of governing ourselves and using our land and peoples to the greater advantage of the world.</p>
                
                <p>I like to think of the boy in Harlan County Kentucky coming home to his cabin and saying, "Pa, we<del>n</del> ain't the United States anymore." I like to think of the city paper processors in their tall offices being suddenly faced with actual unreality o<del>d</del><add>f</add> their occupations. I like to t<del>i</del><add>h</add>ink of
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">65</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial">2.</fw>
                    
                    the Wall Street brokers faced with the problem of the Indian <del/> peasant as really as <add>if</add> the poor brother were in the next room.</p>
                
                <p>I would like to be in Bombay when the news got there and know enough of the language to hear the comments of the grey haired pedicab boys. But even if I did not have the language the faces would be a joy to behold that <del>i</del><add>I</add> never expect to experience in my lifetime.</p>
                
                <p>I wonder what would happen to Roman Catholic Church as well as the Southern Baptist sect. I wonder if perhaps the southside intellectual in Chicago might not walk four blocks across the Chicago University campus to 69th Street and embrace his <del/> bl<del>ca</del><add>ac</add>k neighbor, out of sheer need for affection. I would like to stand in the British Parliment<sic>Parliament</sic> and observe the ge<del>b</del><add>N</add>tlemens's<sic>gentlemen's</sic> faces and hear their shocked tirades until Mr. Churchill arose and said, somewhere in his address, "Gentlemen, let us have courage to acknowledge the greatest revolution in the history of man."</p>
                
                <p>I would not like to be in the rooms where the gangsters of our time -- political, scientific, philos<del>p</del><add>o</add>phical, religious and artistic -- gather. I would not like to <add><hi rend="caps">SEE</hi></add> the faces of such men looking upon their obselescene. No, I would rather be in the streets of the world watching the intelligence of man visibly rising some levels before my very eyes. For the people of our land would be forced, many for the first time, to consider -- to <del>MM</del> consider in much the same way a soldier finding himself with other soldiers hopelessly cutoff<sic>cut off</sic> from his trenches must consider. He has been committed to a position from which there <del>is</del><add>are</add> only two things to do. He can quit or he can advance. I know that most men attempt to advance as long as it is physically possible. Perhaps war is a po<del>r</del><add>o</add>r example as it immediately calls up defeating your enemy or dying. Yet, perhaps it is best of all, if we consider that the only war truly worth fighting is the one against ignorant adherence <add>to a</add> guid<del>on</del><add>eo</add>n that no longer serves the spirit of the march.</p>
                
                <p>Let's surrender the country tomorrow and then count how much time college
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial"><del>4.</del><add>3.</add></fw>
                
                    <add>presidents</add> spend shaking hands while college professors rumple their hair in honest cogitation rather than to create a strikingly casual academic affect. Let us see how long a teacher of geology can wave aside a question of God in relation to creation because it is not in "the field" <del/> -- any old God.</p>
                
                <p>And while we are in the neighborhood we might as well drop in and see how the christians<sic>Christians</sic> are holding up with their gilded idols and gods created in their own image.</p>
                
                <p>Then, day after tomorrow, we can all start shaking hands again and come to know what that excericse<sic>exericse</sic> hone<del>z</del><add>s</add>tly profit<add>s</add> a man.</p>
                
                <p>Well, this has become a very unartis<del>i</del><add>t</add>ic tirade, much in the styleof old brother Dykes who used to drop around every fortnight or so to try and save the soul of my granddad, only making the old man onery enough to go living another year in hope of seeing the preacher get some sense, But I intend trying to put the idea into a passable essay and I was full of the stuff and wanted to get it out and found it easier to do if I addressed my words to you. I beg your forgiveness for using you as a receptacle for it if it displeases you.</p>
                
                <p>While I edited the weekly in Decatur I wrote a few articles that attracted a Miss Anna Miller, a woman of your own years, poetess, lecturer, playwright, <del>MMM</del> traveler of the Chataqua circut and brewer of a damn fine cup of tea. She knows your poetry and we spent an afternoon using it for a flight into a rewarding talk. She is very busy, doing her own "Life of Lincoln" She is a nice lady with very worthy ideas, but I cannot refrain from mentioning that I found her poetry <del/> unworthy of the woman and I felt bad about it. I was going to give your lecture on Souix<sic>Sioux</sic> religion at a meeting of her church group as best as I could because it should given everywhere it can and you were not there to do it. Fortunately
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0004"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">67</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial"><del>5</del><add>4</add>.</fw>
                
                    perhaps for the Souix<sic>Sioux</sic> I was fired from job before the date of the meeting and had to seek other employment quickly due to financial responsibilites. The brief time I spent in Decatur was very i<del/><add>n</add>teresting. It is in the heart of the Lincoln country, and I drove often to the banks of the Sangamon and walked the land where the Lincoln's<sic>Lincolns</sic> first raised a roof over<del>v</del> Illinois soil. I bellied down one spring afternoon on the banks of the river where young Lincoln floated sticks and watched muskrat swim in the water along the banks and years flipped back as pictures in a ni<add>c</add>klelodeon until I felt I had actually transcended time and in spirit savored the essences of that earlier time and the ghosts were very friendly though I never saw them -- However I am smiling now, remembering that I smiled then realizing that the earth on which I lay was alive and the same, the very same, that might have moved young Lincoln one like day in spring. I know there are few men of my acquaintence who would allow the foregoing sta<add>t</add>ement on the grounds that is is "corny and dram<del>i</del><add>a</add>tic" with the implication being that it is phoney. Well, by-God it was dramatic.<del>"</del> And if <del/><add>it</add> is embarassing to hear a 27-year-old man talk that say, I can only say to those who find it so, 'Go ahead and laugh a little if you want, <del>MMM</del> <del/> but sneer you wise sonofabitch and I'll fight you.'</p>
                
                <p>I was fired from the paper in Lincoln c<del>n</del><add>o</add>untry because the Chicago owner of sheet <del>l</del><add>a</add>lso read my articles and become suspis<add>c</add>ious of me. He said he was a reactionery and had made his pile because of it and that he couldn't afford to have a radical on his payroll. I swear to you sir that<del>b</del>is what he said. I am sending you the article he termed radical.</p>
                
                <p>I am now on the Mexican border covering the police and court house beat for a "radical" paper owned by <hi rend="caps">H.C.</hi> Hoiles who inherited his pile. My personal feeling toward today's newspaper is pretty disrespectful, but the police beat <del/> is the best end of a very short and <del/> tacky stick; people making the difference.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.64-68_0005"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">68</fw>
                
                <fw type="authorial"><del>6</del><add>5</add>.</fw>
                
                <p>The country here is also good for a man's spirit, if h<del>e</del><add>i</add>s body can survive the sun. The Mexican Revolution is just over a sand dune there beyond that goat that seems to be grazing on a ca<del>t</del><add>c</add>tus. The country clerk, an old timer named Herb Seago, <add><del>who</del></add> was here during the war and tells many good tales ab<del>o</del>out it. The Mexican laborer here never heard of the minimum wage law and will work from sun-up till after dark, cropping some man's poor shares for a dollar a day and a dirt floor shack. I do not exaggerate I know of a man with eight children who ma<del>j</del><add>k</add>es $7.50 a week crooping a racher's shares up near Harlingen. Recently one of his children died and he took in a nephew that had been orphaned. His youngest girl announced proudly after, "Now we are eight again." For five years, the rancher deducted $2.50 per week from the Mexican's $7.50 <del>i</del><add>o</add>sten<del>i</del>sibly to "pay for his tenant's naturalization."</p>
                
                <p>There is a lot to write about here.</p>
                
                <p>While I <del>MM</del> am wondering what would happen if we surrendered the country tomorrow, I cannot help but wonder what the Mexican the river would say about it. I rather like to think that he would lookover<sic>look over</sic> the hood of my car <del>MMM</del> without envy for the first time in his life and say, "Ai, now you are just like me, <del>N</del><add>n</add>o?" <del>t</del><add>T</add>o which a man should be able to reply, "Hell, comparde, I always was."</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute><del>r</del><add>R</add>espectfully,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Earl Thompson</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

