<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 30
Send photo 
See "When the Tree
            Flowered"

551 Mary Street
Marion, Ohio 43302
April 28, 1971

Dear Dr. Neihardt,
<p>For the last two years, I have been doing research on you. You can imagine my surprise to find you, and the pleasure of being able to tape you conversation with Dick Cavett, which I heard locally, last night. I am one of your most devoted fans with a fond admiration for your work, though my intentions are not as involved as your dear wife's were.</p>
<p>I became acquainted with you through a geneology search for one of your distant relatives who once lived here in Marion. He too, is a poet, but a secret perhaps I shouldn't tell, since he is a business man in the Oklahoma City area. It is evident since "Neihardt the Fox," yours is a poetic family. Between the tape, your writings, and the research material received from the Nebraska Historical Society, and the University of Nebraska, I've become as well acquainted with you as I am my own father.</p>
<p>I am a freelance writer who leans toward the "unknown" factors of thinking. As you stated in the interview, you know <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline> has caused quite an interest among the "now" generation. The young people are looking for a better understanding of religious belief. They want a meaning behind their faith that can be worn like a cloak to keep them warm in all they do.</p>
<p>This brought about an idea taken from the Indian legends, of a white man coming into their midst, and the Indian nation shall rise again. I am looking at this from a spiritual point of view with you as the "white man" in the midst. The "now" generation holds a high respect for the wisdom of age. I would be very honored to have a few words form you, your opinion, perhaps some small gems in message to the young people in antedote for my article. Being a theosopher with my own philosophy, it would please me to know yours in comparison.</p>
<p>Thank you for your time and consideration.</p>
Yours very sincerely,
<signed>S. Anne Larkin</signed>
(Mrs.) S. Anne Larkin