<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.35a.9.10">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from William G. Roundey to John G. Neihardt, April 13, 1971</title>
<author>Roundey, William G.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.35a.9.10</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from William G. Roundey to John G. Neihardt, April 13, 1971</title>
<date when="1971-04-13">April 13, 1971</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
<term>When the Tree Flowered</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Roundey, William G.</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1971-04-28"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.35a.9.10.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">9</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<note>Ans.
4-28-71</note>
<dateline>April 13, 1971
</dateline>
<salute>John Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>Greetings from Nebraska. Many years ago it was my pleasure to visit with you when you spoke at Concordia Teachers College in Seward. Following the evening program for the college students, we visited the next morning a classroom in our elementary lab school....and I remember vividly the children's faces as you spoke to them.</p>
<p>It was the memory of that occassion....and a rereading of BLACK ELK SPEAKS....and a first reading of WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED....that has prompted this letter. I am currently trying to organize a theatre company in Lincoln which will tour through Nebraska and the surrounding area. Our major focus will be on the theatre for young people. In addition to our performances, we plan to conduct workshops for teachers in creative drama and dramatic production. We hope to stress the role of the theatre in a community....and we hope to draw on stories...concerns....interests....of that community as we work with them.</p>
<p>Included in our program we hope to include a number of dramatic pieces. There will be a play for the younger audiences....several short plays for high school and adult audiences....and hopefully a series of readers theatre pieces developed from materials written by Nebraska authors. As the company develops we would like to write our own short plays drawing on local materials again.</p>
<p>I recall that the Grand Island Community Theatre group worked with BLACK ELK SPEAKS at the Stuhr Museum in Grand Island several years ago. I have lost track of some of my friends from that area....but am trying ot find a copy of that script. I am most interested in drawying on WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED for materials for a readers theatre....for our older audiences. And for possible materials for a puppet play for the younger audiences. I feel that some of the dream sequences would lend themselves to the use of very large puppets....trying to capture in a way the sense of the dream....the ritual...the bigger than life qualities of the participants. By large....I am thinking in terms of 9-12 feet tall....and I think that the spirits that size confronting a life-size actor could convey the impact that the dreams...visions...might have had on an Indian youth. It is that that we are trying to catch in our work. We obviously will be concerned with historical data....but I want our group to go deeper and find the impact of the moments in that past....and find ways of bringing that to our audience in the present.</p>
<p>I would appreciate your permission to use materials from WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED....we are a very poor group and will greatly appreciate your commments....and whatever help you care to give us.</p>
<p>My experience in child drama( 13 years as a teacher and director of child drama at Concordia) has indicated that there is a great need for good theatre based on historical materials....children need a base....not to just copy....but to experience. And I think your work provides us with a key to that type of theatre.</p>
<fw type="curatorial">10</fw>
<p>I will be happy to provide you with references concerning my experiences and background in theatre. Of special importance is our work with Tony Montanaro, a mime, who has given our group a good sense of stylized movement and mime. This should allow us to portray the vastness of the west....and the greatness of the Indian vision with care and dignity....avoiding the cliche of cute cowboys and Indiana....or the standard TV fare.</p>
<p>There are others who I have had considerable contact with:
Sara Spencer: publisher of children's plays
              Anchorage press, Anchorage, Kentucky
George Latshaw: American puppeteer
                New York
James Hull Miller: theatre designer and free standing scenery designer</p>
<p>I do hope that we will be able to continue to talk with you concerning this project. Looking forward to hearing from you.</p>

<closer>
<salute></salute>
<signed>William Roundey</signed>
<note>William G. Roundey
EXIT.....Experience in theatre
2635 N. 61 St.
Lincoln, Nebraska 68507</note>
<note>phone-</note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>