<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34a.3">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, July 18, 1970</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34a.3</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, July 18, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-07-18">July 18, 1970</date>
<extent>1 page</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Sterling, George, 1869-1926 </term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Bundle of Myrrh</term>
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
<term>Agememnon</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1970-07-18"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34a.3.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>July 18, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Who all will be coming for Neihardt Day? Hilda? Enid and Ollie? Alice? My reservations are made and I have my plane tickets. I will get to Lincoln on Thursday night, the 30th, quite late, and will call you on Friday. I want to see the Press people, and I will see you that day too. Would it be possible for me to ride to Bancroft with somebody going from there? I can get a bus probably, but as I recall Bancroft is a little awkward to reach. That can wait till I get there; some way I'll make it to Bancroft.</p>

<p>WE will have a lot to talk about. Can I hear some of the records you have made? I hope you are doing all of at least most of the lyrics, including some of the <hi rend="underline">Bundle of Myrrh</hi> ones that you didn't republish.</p>

<p>I have two bits of rather interesting news from the University. One item is that I see <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> on the shelves in the book store; it's a required text for one of the courses. The second is that a friend of mine in the School of Librarianship says that on her final exam in one.of the courses a question was: Where is the Neihardt Collection? You're on MA exams now--how about that? To say nothing of being required reading!! I only wish every student could know you and be able to ask you questions and hear you read. Recordings will help; I'm very glad you are making tapes.</p>

<p>Stewart and Susan send love. And guess what? You Greek grammar is really in use these days; Stewart is teaching me and two friends Greek! We meet two afternoons a week and I have arrived at the point where the words look to me like what they are--I no longer look at yap and think yap. I shall keep this up now, even after Stewart leaves. We're just starting verbs and those wild third declension nouns, so I'm not far enough along for Sappho and Aeschylus in the original--but I'll get there. Are you <hi rend="underline">sure</hi> you didn't want to finsih the <hi rend="underline">Agamemnon</hi>? I am typing it up, by the way, to show Professor Combellack; in the xerox copy of the manuscript the pages were all mixed up and I've just got it in order with the lines where they belong. I am liking Greek as well as you said I would; it's a "wonderland," just as you told George Sterling. Stewart says we will be ready for some of the simpler Plato by September; in fact, he thinks we will learn faster than children, who are supposed to get languages most easily, because we are really interested and we have some sense of language formats. Greek syntax (simple clauses, that is) is a little like Hawaiian "frames." They aren't so tied to the verb <hi rend="underline">is</hi>.</p>

<p>Bower also sends regards. I will save any news for our talk in Lincoln, and it will be a gorgeous treat to see you. If any of the family is there I want to see them too. I will write to the Youngs as soon as I can; as of two minutes from now I must grade about a million papers.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Love, aloha, avec mes amours, and as they say in the Chetto, you are my tall pine,</salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>