<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.33a.13.18">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from T.W. Held to John G. Neihardt,  September 23, 1969</title>
<author>Held, T.W.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.33a.13.18</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from T.W. Held to John G. Neihardt,  September 23, 1969</title>
<date when="1969-09-23">September 23, 1969</date>
<extent>6 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, Nicholas N.</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Held, T.W.</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4140963">Washington (D.C.)</placeName>
<date when="1969-09-23"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.33a.13.18.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>
<note>3 pages not encoded b/c of unclear writing</note>
<fw type="letterhead">DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY 
OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF SUPPORT SERVICES
WASHINGTON, D.C. 20315
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</fw>

<note type="authorial">IN REPLY REFER TO
SPTS-MH
Neihardt, Nicholas N. 
NSN</note>

<opener>
<dateline>23 September 1969
</dateline>
<address>
<addrLine>Mr. John G. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>5835 Vine Street</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska 68505</addrLine>
</address>
<salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>This is in reply to your letter of 9 September 1969 seeking information about the grave of your fater, Nicholas N. Neihardt. Inclosed is a photostatic copy of an application for a Government grave marker which contains pertinent information.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
<signed>T. W. Held</signed>
<note type="authorial">T. W. Held
Chief, Headstone Branch
Memorial Division</note>
<note type="authorial">1 Incl
as</note>
</closer>

</div1>

<div1 type="document">
<fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
<ab>CERTIFICATE OF SEARCH
STATE OF CALIFORNIA, DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH
EVENT                    PERIOD SEARCHED
Death                    From 1930  Through 1939</ab>

<ab>This Is To Certify, that an examination has been made of the Statewide Index in the State Bureau of Vital Statistics Registration covering the event shown on the attached receipt and no reference to this event was found therein.</ab>

<ab>OFFICE OF THE
STATE REGISTAR OF     
VITAL STATISTICS
By: Paul W. <unclear/>
Chief, Cureau of Vital Statistics Registraton
Date September 2, 1969</ab>

<ab>BUREAU OF VITAL STATISTICS REGISTRATION (REV. 1-1-69) FORM VS-1163
27178-450 11-68 5M 2 OSP</ab>

<ab>NAME OF REGISTRANT                 DATE OF EVENT
Nihart or Neihardt, Nicholas Nathan
NAME OF FATHER - NAME OF SPOUSE         TYPE OF EVENT       FEE RECEIVED
            , Alice Culler                  D                 2.00
MAIDEN NAME OF MOTHER                   RECEIPT NUMBER
                                                76295
PLACE OF OCCURRENCE                     DATE OF RECEIPT
Possibly Vallejo                           8/14/69 bg
REMARKS: about 1935                        REQUESTS FOR TWO OR MORE DIFFERENT CERTIFICATES 
                                                ARE RECEIPTED AND MAILED SEPARATELY</ab>
<ab>Mrs. Florence  M. Boring
2836 South 40 Street
Lincoln, Nebraska   68505
STATE OF CALIFORNIA              RECEIPT                          REV. 10-1-68
DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH      DUPLICATE                       FORM VS-1281
Pe</ab>

</div1>

<div1 type="article">

<fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
<fw type="header">Morning World-He</fw>
<note type="authorial">pg. 1, c. 3</note>
<fw type="header">OMAHA, NEBRASKA. NOVEMBER 30, 1908.</fw>
<note>first column is somewhat cutoff</note>
<p><unclear/>s recommendation for a re-<unclear/>he rate and an increase in the <unclear/>t for fourth-class matter "in <unclear/> move an unjust discrimination <unclear/> people."</p>
<fw type="footer">Known in Denison.</fw>
<p><unclear>atch</unclear> to the World-Herald.
<unclear>la..</unclear> Nov. 29.-The news of the <unclear>ed</unclear> Bond at Sioux City, which <unclear/> the World-Herald, was a <unclear>ise</unclear> to many of his Denison <unclear>ed</unclear> Bond was the only son of Bond, of this place, and was <unclear>stside</unclear>, this county, and later of his life in Denison, where manhood. After graduating <unclear>lecated</unclear> in Fonda, Ia., where <unclear>eried</unclear>. He leaves a widow and <unclear>en</unclear>.</p>
<fw type="footer">negie Sends $30,000.</fw>
<p><unclear>a.,</unclear> Nov. 29.-President William <unclear/> of Upper Iowa university to-<unclear/> <unclear>d</unclear> a check from Andrew Car-<unclear/> 30,000 in payment of Mr. Car-<unclear/> <unclear>dge</unclear> to give that amount when <unclear>itional</unclear> endowment of the uni-<unclear/> <unclear>uld</unclear> have been completed.</p>
<fw type="footer">ERTALITY RECORD</fw>
<fw type="footer"><unclear>s,</unclear> George W. Lewis.</fw>
<p><unclear>patch</unclear> to the World-Herald.
<unclear>s,</unclear> S.D., Nov. 29.-Mrs. Goerge one of the oldest and most <unclear>re-</unclear> <unclear>sidents</unclear> of Sioux Falls, was <unclear>d</unclear> in bed, she having been <unclear/> apoplexy during the night. <unclear/> retired she was in as good <unclear/> spirits as usual and the an-<unclear/> <unclear/> of her death came as a great <unclear/>e many friends of the family <unclear>lls.</unclear> Mrs. Lewis and her hus<unclear/> to Sioux Falls in 1878. She <unclear/> any years, been prominently with the work of the local church, and at the time of her vice president of Epiphany <unclear/>uxiliary of the church.</p>
<note type="authorial">Rudolph Kolls.</note>
<p><unclear/>patch to the World-Herald.
Ia., Nov. 29.-Mr. Rudolph of Crawford county's pioneer was found dead in bed this <unclear/> the home of Mr. John Waetye, was rooming. The cause of his due to heart failure. Mr. <unclear/> up and around yesterday and <unclear>g</unclear> in his usual health and his <unclear>th</unclear> was a shock to his friends. <unclear/> man over 70 years of age, a <unclear/>is wife having died a few <unclear/>. He leaves three sons and one besides scores of friends all <unclear/>ford county. Mr. Kolls came ntp from Clinton countp in an <unclear/> and settled on a raw 120 acres <unclear/>enison and by hard work and became a man of considerable <unclear/>.</p>
<fw type="footer">STOCK TAKING OF <unclear>URAL</unclear> RESOURCES</fw>
<p><unclear/>sion About Ready to <unclear/>ate Report of Country's Wealth.
<unclear>ton,</unclear> D.C., Nov. 29.-Tuesday of the national conservative will meet in this city in closed begin the formulation of its <unclear/> President Roosevelt on the state <unclear/>ntry's natural resources. <unclear>ort</unclear> is due January 1. It will <unclear>he</unclear> results of six months of <unclear>ed</unclear> research work and will be <unclear/> upon which the president will <unclear/> special message to congress <unclear/>ding legislation to meet the sit-<unclear/> <unclear>he</unclear> commission will go over the and reports that have been during the six months and a tentative outline of its re-<unclear/> <unclear>eh</unclear> it will sumbit to the joint <unclear/> with the governors of the <unclear>d</unclear> other representatives of the national  organizations, which <unclear>lled</unclear> for next week beginning <unclear/> 8, to assist with advice and <unclear/>. After opinions of the joint <unclear>g</unclear> have been heard, the com-<unclear/> <unclear>ill</unclear> get to work at once on the <unclear>ulation</unclear> of the report.</p>
<p><unclear/> material and informaiton nec-<unclear/> <unclear>ncluding</unclear> the first inventory of <unclear>try's</unclear> natural resources ever in hand now. This material typewritten pile equal to a re-<unclear/> library, but the work was so <gap reason="cutoff"/></p>
<fw type="footer">MARRIAGE OF AN AUTHOR AND ARTIST</fw>
<fw type="footer">John W. Neihardt of Bancroft and Miss Mona Martinsen of New York Married.</fw>
<fw type="footer">Ceremony Performed in Omaha Sunday Afternoon by Rev. T. J. Mackay.</fw>
<p>Here is a partnership in art as well as a nuptial partnership: the wedding of John G. Neihardt of Bancroft and Miss Mona Martinsen of New York. He is a man of letters who, in the past three years, has been making a name for himself in the field of prose, fiction and verse. She is a sculptor well known in the east, but still better known abroad. In the spring of 1907 an important wrok of hers was exhibited in the Paris salon; it was a life figure called "The Maiden."</p>
<p>With Rev. T. J. Mackay officiating, the marriage ceremony was held Sunday afternoon at the apartments of Mr. and Mrs. Keene Abbott, 531 South Twenty-fifth avenue. It was an informal event with no guests present aside from the mother of Mr. Neihardt.</p>
<p>This is the initial visit of the bride to the west. Although she is young in her art she has already had wide recognition. It was of her, some two or three years ago, that F. Edwin Elwell, curator of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, said in an article puclished in the Arena Magazine, that he considered her the most gifted of the younger generation of women sculptors.</p>
<p>Words of such warm praise are, of course, to be considered an honor, but not to the same degree as is the bare fact that for five years she studied under Rodin, the pre-eminent master of France whose statue of Balzac is acknowledged by art critics to be one of the most striking pieces of modern sculpture.</p>
<p>As to Mr. Neihardt, his work in the eastern magazines began to attract wide attention some three years ago. His collection of short stories called "The onesome Trail," received many congratulatory reviews, both in America and in England, but his lyric sequence, "A Bundle of Myrrh." published a year ago, is the work which has done most to bring his name into prominence.</p>
<p>In an essay on Mr. Neihardt's book of poems, published in Putnam's Monthly last June, Gerald Stanley Lee has the following:
"***That first morning when the poems came I did not read them through. I was happy in the middle of the book, and in the middle of the idea that there could be such a book, not to go out doors on the meadow and think about it, think how there realiy was such a man, a latent, big conmporary, a possible classic, a man singing as if he were singing three hundred years ago or a thousand years on from today. After the first few pages I was too glad merely to take him as poetry. He was "news" and there was nothing to do but go out doors with him and look at mount Tom and the sky  and a man like this in it-not under a headstone visited by pilgrims and young ladies, or in a classical dictionary, but walking about this minute, in the town of Bancroft, Neb."</p>
<p>Since then Mr. Neihardt has been placing his verse with the leading periodicals. Last summer, for the Outing Magazine, he went down the Missouri river form the head waters to Sioux City in an open boat. His descriptive articles of that journey are to be a feature of that magazine during the coming year.</p>
<p>A representatice piece of prose fiction by Mr. Neihardt appeared over a year ago in "The Smart Set." The tale a novelette called "The Discarded Fetish," was a character study of uneusual strength, which earned much favorable comment from the reviewers, both in the cast and in the west.</p>
<fw type="footer">WILL ANNOUNCE
FOUR JUDGES TODAY</fw>
<fw type="footer">Governor Sheldon Will End the Scramble for Coveted Places.</fw>
<p><unclear>eral</unclear> days. More than 500 thoroughbred birds were entertd and over $200 in cash premiums were offered besides a number of special prizes given by local merchants.</p>
<p>The little son of Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Nickerson of near Odell fell on a fruit jar and badly cut his face.</p>
<p>Joseph Bates of this city was badly bruised up and suffered a broken collar bone by the earth caving in on a sewer ditch where he was working.</p>
<p>Rev. J. B.  Lewis and Mrs. Sarah Milburn were married Thanksgiving day at the home of the groom's son, Rev. J. W. Lewis officiating. The couple will make their home in West Beatrice.</p>
<fw type="footer">SEEK PLACE FOR BISHOP.</fw>
<fw type="footer">Is Lancaster County Democratic Chairman Who Managed Its</fw>
<fw type="header">Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.</fw>
<p>Lincoln, Neb., Nov. 29.-Lincoln democrats will seek a state position for Attorney H. F. Bishop, county chairman of Lancaster county. Bishop's friends assert that he has made a record as a campaign manager second only to that of Gruenther. With everything against him in Lancaster Bishop put up a winning fight, sacrificing a large chunk of law business to serve his party. Bishop took hold of the local organization several years ago and has patiently and persistentlp outlined plans for county organization. Bishop has served three terms in the city council, being elected each time from a ward overwhelmingly republican.</p>
<fw type="footer">Freeman-McCully Wedding.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch  to the World-Herald.
Kearney, Neb., Nov. 29.-The marriage of Claude L. Freeman, son of a prominent contractor of this city, to Miss Mary McCully, Saturday morning. The Rev. Granville F. Bennett conducted the ring service of the Episcopal church. The rooms were profusely decorated with cut flowers. At noon Mr. and Mrs. Freeman started on an extended wedding tour which will include an indefinite stay in Old Mexico, being accompanied to the train by a large number of friends whose well wishes were merrily expressed in time honored ways. Mr. Freeman has a beautiful home under course of construction in West Kearney, where they will reside upon their return to the city.</p>
<fw type="footer">Kearney News Items.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.
Kearney, Neb., Nov. 27.-Coon, the alleged forger, wanted in many cities and recently brought here from Omaha, appeared in county court yesterday and pleaded not guilty. He waived preliminary examination, was bound over to district court, and went back to jail.</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. E. R. Sizer of Lincoln have been spending Thanksgiving week with C.W. Hoxie and family.</p>
<p>Evangelists Fife and son have opened a series of meetings at the temporary tabernacle recently built by the people of the Christian church.</p>
<p>A new 150-horse power boiler has been placed at the state industrial school.</p>
<fw type="footer">Teachers at Valentine.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.
Valentine, Neb., Nov. 29.-About fifty teacher have been here for the last two days attending meetings of the East Cherry County Teachers association. Forenoon and afternoon sessions were held on Friday and in the evening a banuet wqas given the teachers at Bethel hall. There were sixty present at the banquet, at which L. C. Sparks acted as toastmaster. A fine afternoon session was held Saturday. Miss Lulu Korts, county superintendent, upon whome all responsiblity of the association rested, received credit for the way everything was arranged.</p>
<fw type="footer">Republicans Lay Plans.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.
Lincoln, Neb., Nov. 2<unclear/>-"Let Shallenberger do it all."</p>
<p>This in brief is the policy the republican state officials w<unclear/> adopt. They will give the incoming exective no suggestions whatever. They will make no recommendations to the legislature. </p>
<p>In the matter of appropriations they will ask liberalip, hoping to prepare a basis for a charge of extravagance against the democrats.</p>
<p>Governor Sheldon is preparing data for his message. It will be a review of the last two years.</p>
<fw type="footer">Kearney Odd Fellow Eleciton.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.
Kearney, Neb., Nov. 29-At a meeting of the local Independent Order of Foresters last evening the building committee made fainl report on matters connected with the recent completion of their new $15,000 building just across the street from the new Methodist church. The following officers were elected for the ensuing year: N. G., George N. Smith; V. G., M. N. Troup; secretary, J. A. Larimer; treasurer, E. A. Miller; trustee, F. E. Wilcox.</p>
<fw type="footer">Liberty Beats Bancroft.</fw>
<gap reason="cut off"/>
<fw type="footer">FIFTY MORE THAN OFFICIAL ESTIMATE
Death List of Marianna Mine Disaster Will Probably Reach One Hundred and Thirty-eight.
Work of Recovering Bodies Goes on Slowly Owing to Prevalence of Deadly Gases.</fw>
<p>Pittsburg, Pa., Nov. 29.-Twenty-five bodies, all but two horribly mutilated, and a number dismembered, were today taken from the mine of the Pittsburg-Buffalo Coal company at Marinna, forty miles south of here, where an exlosion occurred yesterday, killing many men and casting into gloom what was until then considered the model mining town of the world.</p>
<p>There is little doubt that the death list will reach at least 138 men. Officials of the company, who ast night stated that no over 125 had been killed, tonight admit that 138 men went down the shaft to work yesterday morning. According to miners and others familiar with the number of men generally employed in the mine, the death list will exceed the company's estimate by at least fifty.</p>
<p>It is possible that the exact number of men killed will never be known. Up to darkness tongiht twenty-five bodies had been brought to the surface in an iron bucket. Arms, legs or heads were missing from some and the trunks of others were burned, bruised and cut.</p>
<p>Two of the men had been suffocated and their bodies were not even scratched. On of these was John Ivoll, a cousin of John H. Jones, president of the Pittsburg-Buffalo Coal company, owners of the mine, who was employed as head timekeeper. Ivill's body was found beneath a coal digging machine and it was apparent that the young man had crawled there in a vain effort to escape the deadly fumes.</p>
<fw type="footer">His Head in Water.</fw>
<p>The body of the other man was found near Ivill. The unfortunate had placed his face in a pool of water, which all miners are advised to do when an explosion occurs, in a desperate attempt to fight off suffocation unti rescued. </p>
<p>This afternoon the coroner of Washington county held a meeting to organize a jury and then adjourned until all of the bodies have been taken from the mine.</p>
<p>Early today a small fire broke out in the mine. The blaze was extinguished before serious damage was done.
Reports have been in circulation all day that a second and more terrific explosion is likely to occur at any moment. The company officials assert this is not true. There is considerable gas in the mine, however. It is estimated that one-fourth of the victims are Americans. The work of rescue is being hurried on as rapidly as possible. At short intervals new men are sent into the mine to relieve others. Owing to the dangerous gases and mass of wreckage, the work is slow and is being carried on with great precaution. Experts form Pennsylvania and Wast Virginia are in charge and are being manterially assisted by J. W. Paul and Clarence Hall of the United States experimental and testing station <unclear>ocated</unclear> in Pittsburg. Notwithstanding the isolation of Marianna thousands of persons found their way there today. Tonight the undertakers are arranging for many funerals tomorrow.</p>
<fw type="footer">COUNCIL OF JEWISH WOMEN</fw>
<p>Cincinnati, O., Nov. 29.-Papers on educational and philanthropic subpects will be red before the ntionl councill HinBBw cational and philanthropic subjects will be read before the natioanl council of Jewish women, which begins its sessions Tuesday in the handsome new temple in Avondale, this city. THis council is one of the largest and strongest women's organizations in the country. The delegates and visitors form New York, Philadelphia, Baltimore and Washington are due Monday, coming in a special car.</p>
<fw type="footer">Husking About Over.</fw>
<p>Special Dispatch to the World-Herald.
Bancroft, Neb., Nov. 29.-Cornhusking in this vicinity is about completed and a number of farmers are shelling and hauling the corn to market.</p>
<fw type="footer">FUNERAL OF DR. BICKNELL.</fw>
<p>The funeral of the late Dr. G. H. Bicknell will be held this morning. The services, which will be strictly private, will be held at the family residence, 2401 Hawthrone avenue. Interment at Prospect Hill cemetery.</p>


</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>