<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 65

LONNIE T. VANDERVEER
521 WEST 64th PLACE
INGLEWOOD, CALIFORNIA 90302

May 16, 1971

Dear Dr. Neihardt, Julius and Mrs. Young: (And Jacguot)
<p>If all you people like each other to the extent that you can spend weeks together in the Black Hills---with a honeymoon, too---I assume it's alright to write one letter for all three.</p>
<p>Thanks! to all of you. To you, Dr. Neihardt, for giving NOla and me the thrill of meeting and talkin with you on the very day we and millions more watched you on the Dick Cavett show. (We saw it on an excellent TV in a motel in Beatrice).</p>
<p>And to you, the Youngs, for being so charming and entertaining! Your interest and trouble in getting all the material to me are deeply appreciated. Now, I feel that I have enough information to hold a semi-intelligent (on my part) conversation with my Nebraska friends.</p>
<p>Let's see---here's what I've received from you:
THE MUSIC OF WHAT HAPPENS, Bess Eileen Day
Program of the "Ceremony Honoring Dr. Neihardt on April 21, '71
Sept. '65 copy of NEBRASKA HISTORY with "Along the Trail" and 
          "Remarks at Bancroft." (Thanks, Doctor, for the autography).
The record, "the wonder of it all."
The SONG OF HUGH GLASS ) These two from my neighbor, Mrs. Winter.
THE SONG OFTHREE FRIENDS)
The LYRIC DEED (Given to Nola by Mrs. Young)
BLACK ELK'S PRAYER (On cardboard and I'll frame this)</p>
<p>That's not much, but it is a start. I'm sending an order to the University Press. Also, writing to Bison Courier for "Homestead Years."</p>
<p>I haven't said much to Nola yet, but I think my '72 trip will be to the Black Hills. And, Julius, I may call on you to help me plan the route. Just a few marks on a map?</p>
<p>Last week, just after we returned from Kansas and Oklahoma, I called Eva Weaver and had a good talk with her. She seemed to be such a nice lady. Nola and I will have to see her in person. She thanked me for calling her and you for telling me about her. She sends her love and best/wishes.</p>
Sincerely, and again---THANKS FOR EVERY THING!
<signed>Lonnie</signed>
Lonnie and Nola Vanderveer
