<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26.52-55_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, March 2, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26.52-55_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-03-02">March 2, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisneau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.52-55_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">52</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>March 2, 1958</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have seen Mr. Chaffee, and next Sunday Bower is going with me to talk with him again. He is a delightful person with a wonderful <unclear>twinkle</unclear> of humor in his face and in his words. He doesn't hear well, and wears an aid, but he has no <unclear>apparent physical difficulty</unclear> as a <unclear>result</unclear> of the stroke. He doesn't use his arm much, but he <unclear>seems</unclear> to get around well. He has less energy than you have, but that's <unclear>true</unclear> of everyone I know. He is making a note of everything he remembers, and will tell me all of it when I go back. I do wish the two of you could get together!</p>
                
                <p>If you still have Mr. Chaffee's letters, please don't destroy them. When you have finished with them I would like to see them if they have reminiscences in them. Anything like that should be saved for permanent record.</p>
                
                <p>Mrs. Skillings is a lovely person. She has a very <unclear>sweet</unclear> face and <unclear>an</unclear> inner poise of manner that the strong, giving people have. Her husband is an invalid, <unclear>confined</unclear> to <unclear>a bed</unclear>, but he is <unclear>alert</unclear> and interested in all sorts of things. He lent me a copy of <hi rend="underline">Sunshine Magazine</hi>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.52-55_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">53</fw>
                
                    that has an article about <unclear>Custer's</unclear> battle. They are all very much interested in you, and <unclear>enjoyed</unclear> the pictures of you that I took over to show them.</p>
                
                <p>There are some minor <unclear>news items</unclear>, but they're interesting: I took the tapes over to the library to listen to them, and as I sat in the audio-visual room, passers-by became quite excited and stopped to ask questions. Martin Schmitt, the Historical Society man, came down to listen and wants to use some of the Jed Smith tape in the <hi rend="caps">T.V.</hi> show I told you about. It's in <del/><add>April</add>, and I have promised to help with it &#8212; but why should I read Jed Smith passages when people can hear you read them? The only problem is that I don't know what <unclear>legal</unclear> complications could result from use of the tapes. Do you know the copyright deal on such things? Can the tape of you reading Jed be used on a program about you on <hi rend="caps">TV</hi>? I suppose tape recordings and <hi rend="caps">TV</hi> programs complicate the copyright laws terribly, and I would appreciate any information you have on the matter.</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Kelly writes that a little town in Montana is <unclear>named</unclear> Neihardt, and he thinks it's for you. I'm writing the <unclear>postmaster</unclear> to try to get the story in writing for the record. Do you know anything about it?</p>
                
                <p>I <unclear>now</unclear> have a complete copy of "Song of the Hoe" &#8212; I copied it out of <hi rend="underline">The Youth's Companion</hi>, and I see why now. Mr. Long was impressed with it. It's a good poem; you
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.52-55_0003"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">54</fw>
                
                    had a <unclear>genius</unclear> for rhythm from the very beginning I shall <unclear>now</unclear> hunt up the "Skating Song."</p>
                
                <p>I'm well along with the second chapter, which is lots of fun to write; it's about your theory of rhetoric and how it grew. I was surprised how clean your taste in speech was when I got the <hi rend="underline">Blade</hi> comments together form the year you edited. Did you ever hear <hi rend="caps">T.R.</hi> speak in person? You wrote about his speaking <unclear>several</unclear> times, but I had the impression your reactions were from reading the speeches and reading about them. You never liked the ornate style, I was happy to see. Reading about you is quite exciting &#8212; you could have gone so many directions and arrived at the top, and all the time, as you have said yourself, the real <unclear>point</unclear> was the <hi rend="underline">living</hi>. More than one person has said to me, "It must be wonderful to write about a man like that!" and it is.</p>
                
                <p>I suspect you're all getting ready for the spring horse shows. I shall be thinking about you, and I will want to see all the blue ribbons in June. Give everyone my love, please, and I'll <unclear>write</unclear> again after we're <unclear/> back to Albany.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Aloha,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I haven't forgotten the General Crook book. It is <unclear>out</unclear> of print and Mr. Schmitt is trying to find you a copy &#8212; for me to send you I <unclear>mean</unclear>.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.52-55_0004"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    2094 Hilyard
                    Eugene, Oregon
                </ab>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">55</fw>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    GIVE
                    RED CROSS
                    FUND
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢
                    LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

