<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0001-8">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Elanita Frye to John G. Neihardt, September 9, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0001-8</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Elanita Frye to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-09-09">September 9, 1959</date>
                    <extent>7 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>7 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">68      Neihardt Collection</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">51</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Sept. 9 &#8212;</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>My dear friend &#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I still have moments of regret that I missed you here at the airport. The day you stopped here, I was in a workshop, but it was nothing I couldn't leave, especially to come out to the airport to see a good friend! Anyway, I'm glad you thought of me; but here is fair warning &#8212; don't try to pass through town again &amp; not contact me! I'll have all the gods on Olympus after you if you do. &#8212;</p>
                
                <p>Today has been a windy, dusty &#8212; challenging day. To some people, the grit &amp; blowing sand is a bother &amp; a menace. But to me, it makes me lean into it, and I think of all the Indian people I've seen protecting themselves against the sand blasts with their shawls &amp; blankets. OF that, I won't trade one day of sand blowing for 3 of Missouri's hot muggy weather.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">52</fw>
                
                <p>Had a delightful excursion with our friend, Miss Bratton, the middle of August when I went with her on a Saturday to the big Gallup Indian Ceremonial. We packed lunches, left <hi rend="underline">early</hi> in the morning, I helped drive her car, and after a colorful parade, we both spent the afternoon in the exhibition hall seeing friends, some of whom it had been years. I saw many former pupils of mine, &amp; now they all have a string of little papooses after them. Miss Bratton &amp; I haven't been able to get a weekend evening together so that I can show her the slides I took at Hilda's place, but we definitely have a Neihardt evening planned. She's quite a woman, that Miss Bratton!</p>
                
                <p>Yes, my friend, our evening around the Kitchen table, is indeed memorable. Hardly a day passes but what I live it again, plus the other days at Hilda's. I <unclear/> onto Cloud 19 every time I
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0003"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">53</fw>
                
                    think about the weekend, or look at my Slides, which incidentally are <hi rend="underline">good</hi>. The one of you, Hilda, Yo-yo &amp; me is my favorite. Would you like a copy of it? &#8212; Robin did a good "shooting" job on it. I wonder if there is any significance in the fact that I have pictures of everyone except Albert. It was not deliberated on any part, I'm sure.</p>
                    
                <p>Have recently read Song of Hugh Glass again. The one line "The miracle of being loved <unclear>at</unclear> all" &#8212; has stayed with me all these years since Hilda quoted it all of 20 years ago. I guess I've had my share of the miracle, but it's still a magic line.</p>
                
                <p>Also, I find my thoughts are altogether different now from former years when I first read Song of the Messiah. The story was not about Navajos, I realize, but I see &amp; feel Navajo in in nonetheless. Some fatal things happen when certain
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0004"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">54</fw>
                
                    Church groups, especially, try to impose their religion on the Navajo. It is a situation I have discussed with certain Navajo people, <del/> and their patience amazes me.</p>
                
                <p>A word about my immediate activities. I have been transferred from the teaching dept. to the guidance dept. &amp; I'm the head "Mogul" in the new girls dormitory which houses 256 girls. There are 11 Indian women for whom I'm responsible also. I'm not too sold on the idea as yet for I do so prefer teaching. the switch was made last summer, after I saw you, when school authorities felt the coming fall High School enrollment would be too low to warrant my <unclear>position</unclear> Since I was low man on the totem pole, I was transferred. Am glad the principal wanted to keep me on the campus, of course. If the enrollment jumps I'll be back in the classroom, but
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0005"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">55</fw>
                    
                    I have my doubts. This new work is more confining than I like, although the chance for advancement is greater. But I like my free time to pursue my interests &amp; that can't be done where I am now. But I guess it will work out to the good. By the end of this week, we'll know what the high school-numbers will be, as the children are coming in now.</p>
                    
                <p>A big step towards educational integration was made here this fall when 300 Navajo pupils entered Alb. public schools. They are living in our new dormitories but are under federal contract with the public schools. Quite an experiment here, altho<sic>although</sic> it's been going on in Gallup-Halbrook, Ariz, and elsewhere the past few years.</p>
                
                <p>Yes, I am impatiently waiting for next spring when you all can come
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26b.51-58_0006"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">56</fw>
                
                    out here. Altho<sic>Although</sic> my little "hogan" won't hold all of us, I'll make arrangements. Gee, I hope you earmark a sizeable portion of your time for the stop here! There are a thousand places to go &amp; things to do. Take your pick.&#8212; This is <hi rend="underline">not</hi> sponsored by the Chamber of Commerce either.</p>
                    
                <p>I owe Hilda a letter, &amp; soon I shall write to her. In the meantime, you might convey whatever you wish of this letter to her. It is still a wonderful thing to me, to find that the years have not altered the good <unclear/> you &amp; Mona <unclear/> so long ago when I was an ignorant kid in college &amp; I came to visit you in Branson. I recounted to Hilda how you once said I <unclear>was</unclear> was like a drink of fresh spring water &amp; I should keep it that way. I'm afraid the water has been muddied all too often by my mistaks, but if the good Lord has seen fit to clear the water, I'm glad.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27b.51-58_0007"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">57</fw>
                
                <p>Goodness, I've written too much, &amp; it's so hard to read. I should use a typewriter, at least the mistakes are legible.&#8212;</p>
                
                <p>Again, dear friend, it's my loss I didn't get to see you for a brief time here. I can give you a number to call at school, during the day should you stop again. <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="caps">C.H</hi></hi>(apel)7-0311-ext.75. When I have a phone <del/> in my own office, I'll send that. I have no phone at the house, but you can get me <unclear>quietly</unclear> at my neighbor, <hi rend="caps">DI</hi>amond 4-1-118,</p>
                
                <p>Hope to hear from you soon &amp; again.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>My love and constant thoughts to all &#8212;</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Elanita &#8212;
                        <unclear>Yanabah</unclear>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>