<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34a.17">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, August 29, 1970</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34a.17</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, August 29, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-08-29">Augst 29, 1970</date>
<extent>1 page</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Bingham, Edward</term>
<term>Pomeroy, Earl</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1970-06-16"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34a.17.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>August 29, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>


<p>I haven't disappeared from the face of the earth--and I should have written at one to say I got back safely, but I returned to a quagmire of work and problems. We have just had a family crisis about the granddaughters, and all the family has been here, and I have had to finish the summer term; that's what happened. I thought about you, though, through all the bustling, and today, when the crowd has dispersed, I can finally write.</p>

<p>It was good to see you, and to see you looking so well. I did worry a bit about the effects of the trip and the cyclone; I hope you weren't flat the next day. That was really a rain; when you give the Black Elk prayer, the Powers don't begrudge, do they? Perhaps that was their way of saying it was a really great day. It was, too. It was wonderful to see so many people there to honor you. I'm terribly sorry Mrs. Vogt has been so ill; I had not seen her since the pageant several years ago, and it is saddening to see the effects of the pain she must have had to endure. I'm glad she could be there to see the results of her efforts.</p>

<p>A great many people are here ask about you, since they know I have seen you. Ed Bingham, the American historican, thinks you are a marvel, and sends his greetings, also Earl Pomeroy sends regards. He read the Jed and Hugh Glass chapters and says the material about the scenery is one of the most interesting and amazing things he has run across. The same thing might really have happened with Jed if you had made the same kind of trip over that country.</p>

<p>I will write another letter about the book when I get my head geared to think about something besides what for dinner for nine people and how to get the beds all changed and the grocery shopping done. I haven't heard yet about the report form the reader. When that is in I'll have to do a final alteration and editing. I'll let you know as soon as I hear from the Press. Love to everybody, and take care. Bower and Stewart and Jingle send love too.</p>

<closer>
<salute></salute>
<signed></signed>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>