<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
104 w 3rd st. 
ans. 5/9/73
Villisca, Iowa
Feb. 18, 1973
33
Mr. John G. Neihardt
Dear Sir,
I do not know where you are living at present; so I am sending this in care of Julius D. Young whom I knew in college. I know he will forward it. 
I have just finished reading your 1881-1901 autobiography and am looking forward to the next portion. In fact I was the first person to check in from our public library. One of my friends, I'm sure, will be the second. She lived in Omaha during her school years and heard you when you spoke at the school she attended.
This was my former home, and I am now in my sixth year of retirement from the high school here. 
In 1911 we moved to Wayne, Nebr. where my father became 

2
editor of "The Nebraska Democrat." 
Your book brought back many memories. Yes, Charlotte White was quite a personality and often 34
dropped in at the office to visit with my father. 
I first heard of you when my freshman English teacher, Mrs. M.A. Phillips, read us "The Song of Hugh Glass." The crowd on a broken leg and his suffering for water impressed me so that after class, I asked permission to stop at a fountain for a drink of water - his thirst rubbed off on me! 
I majored in English, having all my classes under Dr. House. Mary was a special friend. Her first year of teaching was in Mobesly, Mo. (if I have the correct

3
memory) where she lived with your mother. She wrote me 35 she would be home christmas and wanted me to meet her at the station. When we arrived at her home, we knocked. I said to Mrs. House when she came, that I'd like her to meet a friend. We <unclear/> in. Mary had gained weight, and her face was very plump. Mrs. House shook hands with her and said she was glad to meet a friend of Lila's. That was too much for Mary, who gave a "giggle" which her mother recognized. All she could say was "Why, Mary House." 
Pardon me for my reminiscence. Again, let me say how much I enjoyed your new book. 
Sincerely,
Lila M. Gardner 