<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36a.54-59">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Mildred R. Bennett to John G. Neihardt, October 12, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36a.54-59</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mildred R. Bennett to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-10-12">October 12, 1972</date>
                    <extent>5 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>5 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="3">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.54"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">54</fw>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="caps">FOUNDED 1955</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>A Plow</figDesc>
                        <p>WILLA CATHER PIONEER MEMORIAL
                        RED CLOUD.NEBR</p>
                    </figure>
                        <lb/>
                    
                    Willa Cather Pioneer Memorial and Educational Foundation 
                        <lb/>
                    _________________________________________________________
                        <lb/>
                    Non-profit Organization Exempt under Section 501 (c) (3)
                    and Section 170 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1965 
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA</hi> 68970
                        <lb/>
                    
                    <hi rend="caps">BOARD OF GOVERNORS 
                    OFFICERS</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Mildred <hi rend="caps">R.</hi> Bennett
                    President 
                        <lb/>
                    Harry Obitz
                    Executive Vice President
                        <lb/>
                    Josephine Frisbie 
                    Secretary-Treasurer
                    Omaha, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    
                    William Thomas Auld, <hi rend="caps">M.D.</hi> 
                    Nephew of Willa Cather
                    Stockton, California
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">W. K.</hi> Bennett, <hi rend="caps">M. D.</hi> 
                    Coordinator
                        <lb/>
                    Richard Borton
                    Superintendent of Schools
                    Red Cloud, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    Vi Borton
                    Red Cloud, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    Don <hi rend="caps">E.</hi> Connors
                    Instructor in English
                    Downey, California
                        <lb/>
                    Virginia Faulkner
                    Vice President
                    Author and Editor of 
                    University of Nebraska Press 
                    Lincoln, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    Ella Cather Lewis
                    Niece of Willa Cather
                    Long Beach, California
                        <lb/>
                    John March
                    Research Librarian for 
                    Collier's Encyclopaedia, Retired
                    Lawton, Oklahoma
                        <lb/>
                    Miriam Mountford
                    Editor Newsletter
                        <lb/>
                    William Mountford
                    Insurance Consultant 
                    Red Cloud, Nebraska
                        <lb/>
                    Helen Obitz
                    Associate Vice President
                        <lb/>
                    Jennie Rieher
                    Cather descendant
                    and genealogist
                    Red Cloud, Nebraska
                        <lb/>
                    Dr. <hi rend="caps">C.</hi> Bertrand Schultz
                    Vice President
                    Author and Director of 
                    the State Museum
                    University of Nebraska 
                    Lincoln, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    Marian Schultz
                    Membership Chairman
                        <lb/>
                    Margaret Cather Shannon
                    Niece of Willa Cather
                    Denver, Colorado
                        <lb/>
                    Bernice Slote 
                    Vice President
                    Professor of English
                    University of Nebraska 
                    Lincoln, Nebraska 
                        <lb/>
                    Helen Cather Southwick
                    Niece of Willa Cather
                    Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
                        <lb/>
                    Laird <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Wolfe
                    Assistant State Conservationist 
                    with <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> Dept. of Agriculture
                    Lincoln, Nebraska
                        <lb/>
                    Lucia Woods
                    Professional Photographer
                    New York, <hi rend="caps">N. Y.</hi> 
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Oct. 12, 1972</dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>C/o <hi rend="caps">J. D.</hi> Young</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine St.</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebr. 68505</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your book is wonderful. As I told you the <hi rend="caps">WESTERN AMERICAN LITERATURE</hi> editor asked me to review it for the magazine.</p>
                
                <p>My review copy just came a couple of days ago--after I had bought a copy in Lincoln on Saturday <del>a</del><add>o</add>f last week. I am sending you a copy of the review and I hope you will like it. I loved every word of your book.</p>
                
                <p>You have done so much for me and this book will do so much for me and this book will do so much for people who need a better otulook on life. There is something very inspiring about the book, and I hope everyone will read it.</p>
                
                <p>I'm sorry I didn't get to Hastings to hear you, and see you. At such places you are always so surrounded by friends and admi<del>c</del><add>r</add>ers that it is impossible to get a word with you. Better I should come to the house and see you when I can sometime in Lincoln.</p> 
                
                <p>The best in the world for the sale of the book.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Affectionately,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Mildred</signed> 
                    <signed>Mildred R. Bennett</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">HONORARY MEMBERS</hi> 
                        <lb/>
                    Ted Kennedy
                    Realtor
                    Miami Beach, Florida
                        <lb/>
                    Helen Lengfeld 
                    National President United 
                    Voluntary Services
                    San Mateo, California
                        <lb/>
                    Frank O'Rourke
                    Author
                    San Fransico, California
                        <lb/>
                    David <hi rend="caps">E.</hi> Scherman 
                    Author, Photographer and 
                    Senior Editor of <hi rend="caps">LIFE</hi>
                    New York City
                        <lb/>
                    Marcella Van Meter
                    Fremont, Nebraska
                        <lb/>
                    Durward <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Varner
                    President University of 
                    Nebraska 
                    Lincoln, Nebraska 
                </fw>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.55"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">55</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <hi rend="underline">All Is But A Beginning</hi> by John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt(Introduction by Dick Cavett) Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc. New York. $5.95
                </opener>
                
                <p>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt, now past ninety, author of more than twenty books and poet laureate of Nebraska as well as the recipient of many honors, has written the story of his boyhood from the time of his birth to the time of his first school teaching experience and his burning of his first masterpiece, The Divine Enchantment, <unclear>at age</unclear> <add>19.</add></p>
                
                <p>If anyone has the idea that poets are made by growing up in ivory towers, Dr. Neihardt's story will correct that view. Althou<del/><add>g</add>h through the mists of memory he sees everything with compassion, the reader is bound to realize that he grew up amid poverty and disappointment. Aware as he is of the failure of his father to make a good living, he never lets that fact dim the love he feels for his father, and when, after a bitter quarrel with the mother and an absence of several days, the father comes back to the house and does not gain admission, but goes out into the night never to return, it is little John who rushes to the door and calls goodbye and hears the echo of goodbye. Even the <unclear/> separation does not diminish John's love, and he takes great pride in the memory of his father's physical prowess and his knowledge of intellectual things, although he is a man without education.</p> 
                
                <p>The family moves from place to place so rapidly that the small John loses track of the places and the times, but always he has his steadfast mother in the background keeping things together. Moments of sorrow mingle with bursts of joy.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.56"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">56</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">2 Neihardt</fw>
                
                <p>Early he showed a remarkable memory and some of the experiences from five years of age on, he uses later in his <hi rend="underline">Cycle of the West</hi>. Sensitive, alert, he misses nothing of the life around him.</p>
                
                <p>One of the most poignant scenes in the book is his visit back to the old home of his grandparents in Stockton, Kansas. Little is left but a mound where the sod house stood and a caved in place for grandma's cellar where she churned and from which came such r<del/><add>i</add>ch buttermilk. But in his mind he reconstructs the grandfather with his twinkling blue eyes and his skill with the blacksmith's tools. For a little while he dreams back the memories, but something is lost.</p> 
                
                <p>"This time as I pass through the gate, I close it gently and wire it firmly shut, wondering why I should take the trouble. Surely there is nothing on the inside wanting out, and nothing on the outside wanting in. But it seems, somehow, the way you close the door of a quiet room where someone dear is sleeping and greatly needs the rest."</p> 
                
                <p>Such is the tone of his memories as he looks back on his childhood of over eighty-five years ago. Always he has the ability to see beauty in everything, if not humor. Once with his father he comes upon a sunlighted clearing. "And in the center thereof a single wild crab-apple tree was blooming gloriously. I remember how we stood still there for quite a while, just looking. It seemed we were having an adventure somehow."</p> 
                
                <p>The vision of the tree reminds one of the tree that grows in the center of Dr. Neihardt's prayer garden and seems a preview of his ever growing view of the universe.</p>  
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.57"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">57</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">3 Neihardt</fw>
            
                <p>Despite the hardship of his growing years--the years when he can't find a job and has to ride the freights and ask for handouts, he never loses the feeling that something greater is just ahead.</p> 
                
                <p>Until he is twelve, he has intended to be an inventor, but about that time during a grave illness he dreams of flying, faster and faster, even though he wishes to stop. The dream comes three times. Later, he realizes the meaning--that there is more to be done, and part of him is always striving forward, while the rest of him lives the life of a virile young man. He early begins to write, but his first volume actually published is <hi rend="underline">The Divine Enchantment</hi>, based on the Vedanta concept.</p>
                
                <p>He finishes it when he has just become seventeen. After publication and after he has time to think it over, he burns most of the books(although he has a good two hundred dollars invested in them.) Somehow the book does not come up to his standard and he adds it to those other earlier efforts that he has already burned. Only a few copies remain and they come at a premium. Dr. Neihardt knows from the twelfth year on that there is something he has to write, but he knows it is farther on--and must be perfect.</p> 
                
                <p>Fascinating too is his account of beginning school teaching when, as a small man of five feet two inches, he has much bigger boys to deal with, but he has learned some tricks of wrestling and he has not neglected his physical development. He is a mighty man though small. When he throws the biggest boy across his shoulders and keeps him helpless there, the whole school surrenders to him, and most of all the boy he has bested.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.58"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">58</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">4 Neihardt</fw>
                
                <p>Dr. Neihardt has the theory that we see here only part of the cosmic pattern, that we are part of a planned whole, of which we see only a shadow in moments of spiritual enlightenment. His per-sistent optimism in the face of defeat expresses that faith, although he was among those who might have been thought irreverent, he was and is of a most religious and phi<del/><add>l</add>osophic mind.</p>
                
                <p>Willa C<unclear>a</unclear>ther says in <hi rend="underline">Death Comes for the Archbishop</hi> that the archbishop in his old age "sat in the middle of his own consciousness; none of his former states of mind were lost or outgrown. They were all within reach of his hand, and all comprehensible." The same can be said for Dr. Neihardt. He can lead us from an incident at four years to one at sixty without losing the continuity of his thought.</p> 
               
                <p>The book must be read by everyone who needs a viewpoint in today's mass of conflict and disappointment. Little wonder that he has rapport with the young people of our generation. Through his more than ninety years, Dr. Neihardt sees the good of life and expresses what that means: love, given freely with no demand in return; the pride of workmanship; moments of deep spiritual meanings and deep sleep where we touch eternity.</p> 
                
                <p>His admonition is that of the eagle in his Indian friend's dream: <hi rend="underline">Hold fast, hold fast; there is more</hi>. . .   Not only does this express his philosophy, but for all those who love and appreciate Dr. Neihardt, we will be holding fast and hoping he will go on with his inimitable autobiography.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Mildred R. Bennett, President
                    WILLA CATHER PIONEER MEEMORIAL &amp; EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.59"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">MILDRED R. BENNETT</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    329 North Cedar
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA</hi> 68970
                </ab>
                
                <note>
                    Contains review for Western Am. Lit Mag. 
                    To ans&#8212; Norene &amp; Gaki. 
                    ansd M.M.Y&#8212;also letter q
                    act 25&#8212;sent Materials to her&#8212;10-25-72
                </note>
                
                <note>10-13-72</note>
                
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>8 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>US 8¢ OSTEOPATHIC MEDICINE</p> 
                </figure> 
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine><hi rend="caps">C/O J. D.</hi> Young</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine St.</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebr. 68505</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note>ans 11/1/72</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">59</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>