<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.27a.30-32_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Louise Hovde Mortensen to John G. Neihardt, May 15, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.27a.30-32_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Louise Hovde Mortensen to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1959-05-15">May 15, 1959</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.30-32_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        705 Polk Blvd
                        Des Moines,Iowa
                        May 15, 1959
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Last evening I made a little talk to our <hi rend="caps">A.A.U.W.</hi> Creative Writing group on "Authors I Have Met" and I was very proud to have you in my collection and to feel I know you really very well. I made the remark we <add>know</add>no<!--"no" is circled--> authors through their writing often better than we no<sic>know</sic> our everyday acquaintances whom we see often, because in their books the authors let us see their heart and soul. Of course, this is really knowing a person even better than merely seeing them from day to day.</p>
                
                <p>I met Ralph Connor when I was only 5 years old when my parents took us to Lake Louise one summer. He was the first author on my list of "Authors I <del>h</del><add>H</add>ave Met," which sounds a little bit like "Wild Animals I Have Known," which was a book we had in our bookcase when I was a child.</p>
                
                <p>MacKinlay Kantor attended North High in Des Moines when I did and I think I told you I had a recent letter from him saying that he couldn't write even a page for me on how to teach English as he was in the midst of packing for Europe where intends to write a long novel on pioneer Iowa, even longer than <hi rend="caps">BIG A</hi> as he called <hi rend="underline">Andersonville</hi>, I presume. Both he and Henry Felsen, another Des Moines writer (Hot Rod books), happened to have rented the old ballroom third floor of a large mansion which stood on Arlington Avenue where I used to live. However, they lived there when I was out of town in the East in the thirties. And Henry Felsen said he did not know Mac Kantor had lived there when he rented it, and in fact did not know him at all nor has he ever read his books. Not interested, I guess.</p>
                
                <p>I also met Padr<del>i</del><add>a</add>ic Colum in Washington,<hi rend="caps">D.C.</hi> at a little <hi rend="caps">AAUW</hi> poetry reading group in a second-hand bookshop. He told us we reminded him of the old days in Dublin when small literary groups were all so interested in one another's writing and if one of the members had a poem in the Dublin paper one morning, the rest of the group all be talking about it during the day. I had heard Padraic Colum at Smith around 1923 and then heard him again in 1942 and of course I am fond of his work. He told us that his father had been the overseer in charge of an Irish workhouse and as a boy he some of the poor people go out on the road again rather than be confined to the workhouse. I believe that is the origin of "An Old Woman of the Roads". He knew such women personally as a child and felt deeply their need for a home of their own which they were too poor to own. I also heard Margaret Land<del/><add>o</add>n, author of Anna and the King of Siam, in Washington at our clubhouse, Frances Carpenter Huntington, daughter of Frank Carpenter, and other interesting writers. So they did enjoy my talk about "Authors I <del>h</del><add>H</add>ave Met."</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.30-32_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
                
                <p>I see that you will drop in on the Farimont Writers' Conference, and I am sorry that I shall probably not be there. I expect to go to Ripley, West Virginia, to see my daughter this year in June when my mother has her 93rd birthday. My sister will come home at that time, and unless she comes home, I cannot leave mother at her age.</p>
                
                <p>I wouldn't go just to hear <hi rend="caps">P.</hi>Evans Coleman talk on the novel of course, but am very grateful to him that he had you as the main speaker last year, because I did enjoy that conference very much. It was probably the best he will ever have up there, inasmuch as he wants to do too much talking himself and really is not qualified to talk very much about literature. Odd individual. It's too bad really, because many Midwesterners would like to go to a place like that.</p>
                
                <p>I sold a piece on <hi rend="caps">THE OREGON TRAIL</hi> to <hi rend="caps">THE INSTRUCTOR</hi> for the May issue. I studied my material for at least five years before I wrote it, and should have first submitted it to a magazine that pays well, but rather than lose the material, which I am always doing with my projects, I just mailed it to The Inst<del>ur</del><add>ru</add>ctor, which only paid $20.00 for it. But I thought some teachers would be able to benefit by my outline on The Oregon Trail and its relation to children's literature. I suppose you are well acquainted with the lady who wrote "In the Wake of the Prairie Schooner." I think that's the name. It was some time ago that I read it. My favorite is "The R<del>ao</del><add>oa</add>d to Oregon". When I left Glacier Park last summer, I went West to Portland and then home via the <hi rend="caps">U.P.</hi> over the Oregon Trail in a domeliner, which I described in the article. But the Instructor rewrites material, so I probably won'<del/><add>t</add> recognize it when I see it. In the Portland library where I spent an hour or two, I looked up The Oregon Trail in the card catalogue and at the desk they had a fine list of books.Also the Salem State Lib<del>ar</del><add>ra</add>ry had a fine list available for the asking. Have you seen that one?</p>
                
                <p>I am looking forward to the publication of your biography. No doubt I will read the reviews of it, as I subscribe to the <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi> Times Book Review and read it each week. I can learn a good deal for a $4.80 subscription to that each yr.<sic>year</sic> </p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Louise Hovde Mortensen</signed>
                    <signed>Louise MOrtensen</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.27a.30-32_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">32</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    705 PolkBlvd<sic>Polk Blvd</sic>
                    Des Moines 12,Iowa
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    DES MOINES
                    MAY 15
                    230PM
                    1959
                    4 IOWA
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>UNITED.STATES.POSTAGE FOUR 4 CENTS</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Route #7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
