<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.33a.22.23">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Jean Walker to John G. Neihardt, October 2, 1969</title>
<author>Walker, Jean</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.33a.22.23</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Jean Walker to John G. Neihardt, October 2, 1969</title>
<date when="1969-10-02">October 2, 1969</date>
<extent>pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Walker, Jean</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4406282">Rolla (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1969-10-02"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.33a.22.23.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<fw type="letterhead">University of Missouri-Rolla 
<figure type="stamp"><ab>SIGILL UNIVERSITATIS MISSOURIEN MDCCCXXXIX</ab></figure>
DEPARTMENT OF HUMANITIES
G-3 Rolla Building
Rolla, Mo. 65401
Telephone 
314 364-2998</fw>

<opener>
<dateline>October 2, 1969
</dateline>
<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt,</salute>
</opener>

<p>In respone to your inquiry about information for the "introduction" for our publication, I shall give you as much detail as I can. The project is one of compiling brief biographical sketches of Missouri-born or Missouri-related authors; these sketches need to be available for the general use of scholars, public schools, and others who want such information. The project is under the sponsorship of the Missouri Association of Teachers of English (M.A.T.E.), the only organization in Missouri which includes both secondary and college level teachers of English in a sound dialogue and a cooperative spirit; M.A.T.E. is trying to improve teaching methods, materials, and conditions in English. (M.A.T.E. has close connections with the National Council of Teachers of English and with the Missouri State Teachers Association.) Specifically, our committee is called the Literary Landmarks Committee, composed of some ten members of M.A.T.E. form various regions of Missouri; our chairman, Professor Mareta Williams, is a recently retired member of the faculty of Southwest Missouri State College in Springfield, Missouri.</p>

<p>Our project is in an embryonic stage. We are first publishing a special edition of the
<hi rend="underline">Missouri English Bulletin</hi> (the journal of M.A.T.E.), which will be composed of some fifty biographical sketches of Missouri authors. We hope to have this edition off the press by later October for distribution for Missouri Writers Week, a period designated officially by the Governor of Missouri.</p>

<p>M.A.T.E. is financing this first issue of the biographies in an attempt to get the project launched. Members of our committee are, of course, donating our time and efforts to the projects (which is a service and scholarly effort, not a commercialone).</p>

<p>M.A.T.E. hopes to compile many more of these biographies as time goes on and publish them in an easily availabe form. The final form has not yet been established as we are seeking additional financial support from the state of cooperation from the Missouri Historical Society in the ultimate costs of putting our material into final form and making it easily available for public use. The committee plans also to try to collect and preserve other "literary landmarks," such as color slides of Missouri literary scenes and landmarks, and we hope to mark with bronze plaques locations of leterary significance throughout the state.</p>

<fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-Page 2-</fw>
<p>In discussing our first edition, we thought it would be desirable to have a prominent Missouri writer to endorse our project. Perhaps I should say, rather than "to endorse," that he could simply affirm that our project is a worthwhile one and wish us well in our efforts. Such an "endorsement" can be very brief and simple. Its purpose would be to demonstrate that the writer himself is interested in preserving Missouri literary tradition and in any legitimate effort to collect the relevant material of that tradition in a permanent and easily availavle form.</p>

<p>You are therefore free to make any comments you wish. It is, we realize, something of an imposition on your time for us to request such a letter. May I emphasize that such an "endorsement" or salutation may be brief. We as members of M.A.T.E. are convinced that the project is worth our time and efforts. We are simply asking your moral support and enthusiasm.</p>

<p>May I express my appreciation for your interest and cooperation? Our committee is deeply in your debt.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
<signed>Jean Walker</signed>
<note type="authorial">Jean Walker
Associate Professor of English</note>
<note type="authorial">JW/df</note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>