<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.28.14-16">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt, April 14, 1960</title>
<author>Kendrick, M. Slade (Myron Slade)</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.28.14-16</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Kendrick, M. Slade (Myron Slade)</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1960-04-14">April 14, 1960</date>
<extent>3 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>3 hand-written pages</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kazantzákis, Níkos, 1883-1957</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Hawaii</term>
<term>Charlottesville (Va.)</term>
<term>Washington (D.C.)</term>
<term>Chicago (Ill.)</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term type="Neihardt">Easter</term>
<term>Odyssey : a modern sequel</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Kendrick, M. Slade (Myron Slade)</persName>
<placeName>Ithaca (N.Y.)</placeName>
<date when="1960-04-14"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> transcription and encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<note type="curatorial">Neihardt Collection</note>
<note type="curatorial">14</note>

<div2><opener>
<address>
<addrLine>225 Willard Way, Ithaca, N.Y.</addrLine>
</address>
<dateline>April 14, 1960</dateline>
</opener>

<p>Dear John: The soft air of spring is over the land,
and it brings a feeling of life &amp; growth, the sweet
life of spring. The great silence that bound all out-
doors is broken. There are returning birds, &amp; the sap
is rising. How good all the things seem after the
long winter with its cold &amp; continuing snows.
</p>

<p>And no doubt spring is more advance with you,
and the greeting of flowers more frequently to be seen.
I always thrill to such wondrous beauty rising
from the dark earth.</p>

<p>I wrote to you some little time ago asking whether
Oct. 19 would be a suitable date for you, &amp; explaining the
reason for the suggested change. Actually, I believe
that in most years the week beginning Oct 16 (and we
would want you to come then) has more beautiful
colors than the preceding week. We try to plan
our lectures well ahead. Besides I need to get such
matters in order before taking off for Hawaii.
</p>

<p>Have you by any chance found those copies of
your Easter poem? If you could spare <del/> a half
dozen &amp; autograph them, I should love to have that
many. I should then make that many more fans for
you. I never give one except to a person who would
value it.</p>

<p>Always as I write, a feeling for my dear elder
brother <unclear>upheld</unclear> in my heart.</p>

<closer>
<salute>Love you</salute>
<signed>Slade</signed>
</closer></div2>

<div2>
<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">15</note>
<fw>-2-</fw>

<p>I have been doing a little reading in Kazantzaki's
The Odyssey, A Modern Sequel. But I found this,
a mammoth <unclear>work</unclear>  exceedingly difficult to understand, the
general theme was never clear to me, &amp; the metaphors &amp;
other comparisons bewildering <add>And then I get tired of the <unclear/></add> Yet some of it, I think, is
magnificent poetry, or, for example, the four lines on Odysseus
death

<quote>
<lg>
<l>"As a low lantern's flame flicks in its final blaze</l>
<l>then leaps above its shriveled wick and mounts aloft,</l>
<l>burning with light, and roars toward death with dazzling joy</l>
<l>so did his fierce soul leap before <unclear>it</unclear> vanished in air."</l>
</lg>

</quote>
</p>

<p>I have had two trips this spring. On April 9 &amp;
10 I attended a conference in Charlottesville Va. as a 
University representative. On the edge of Washington,
travelling by bus, I saw the Jefferson Memorial, the
stone setting on a <add>water filled</add> ring of cherry blossoms. At
Charlottesville, I was lucky in being taken over the
grounds of the U. of Virginia. <unclear/> an early institution
that is with its white colonial buildings, planned
by Jefferson. And to visit it gives one
the sense of an earlier time, &amp; of the great men
who dominated the founding days of our country.
I saw, too, the ten serpentine walls. I had thought
that there was only one.</p>

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">16</note>
<fw>-3-</fw>

<p>My second and more recent trip was to Chicago where I
attended a national conference on school finance, two days of
solid meetings. We <unclear>met</unclear> in the Loop section, well downtown
near the Board of Trade, so I looked upon tall buildings.</p>

<p>School keeps here, but the pace of things quickens
examinations, theses, etc. My candidate for the doctorate
wrote an excellent theses, &amp; passed an examination with
equal <unclear/> I feel very proud of him. And now I am
busy with a masters theses written by an Ethiopian.
The boy has worked hard, but the language gave him great
difficulty. So I am trying to straighten it out. I have had to
forget all about style, &amp; to be content with grammar &amp; meaning.</p>

<p>Nita continues with her teaching, and likes it. I am
always surprised at the quality of the products that
her class turns out. But she has to ride herd on the boys
to keep them up to the standard. It is so easy for them
to grow <del/> careless.</p>


<p>The wave of spring is dashing high over these hills, leaving
everywhere a  thickening green spray. And how fresh &amp; lovely
the newborn colors glow. Once more we look upon creation
and it is good. I always feel in spring the lift of eternal
things. The grass never forgets, nor do the flowers. The
forsythia hangs in long golden strands down the
wall back of our house. And now <unclear>winter</unclear> departs from our
city, the redbud has opened, the fruit trees are abloom, &amp;
now &amp; then one can see the white spray of dogwood
 breaking on the green wall of a wood.</p>

<p>I trust dear, dear friend that all goes well you are 
often in my thoughts &amp; always in my heart.</p>
<closer>
<salute>Affectionately,</salute>
<signed>Slade</signed>
</closer>

</div2>


</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
