<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
19
(Even if this unburdening really sparks, give no thought to reply-
(ing until your current ms. is safely in print. My intent as an old 
(fan is to egg you on. And if I inadvertently diverted you, neither 
(of us would forgive me. 
Groundhog Day 2/2/73
(No sun -- no shadow) 
Dear John Neihardt: 
For quite some years I'd supposed my chances slim of catching up with you this side of the river. But for half a century I've taken for granted I'd manage somewhere sometime. Mainly becausae you'd given me major experiences that called for face-to-face acknowledgement with a few explanatory footnotes.
Then a little before Christmas, as I recall, suddenly I saw you eying me quizzically from a book ad -- and what a lift! As soon as I could get hold of All Is But a Beginning, I gourmandized eagerly through a first reading. Next I read the book aloud to  my gal friend, Dorothy, in liesurely sessions over breakfast coffee (three shamelessly huge mugs each as we loaf on a living room  loung in our converted cowbarn with a prospect of Indian Mountain across the little valley -- there was a Mohegan village just overe the crest which I see in imagination from a tall pine tree on the crest.)
One of my measuring sticks for creative values is what you did to me with Hugh Glass. In my twenties it hit me as hard as The Hound of the Baskervilles had at twelve and as The Hound of Heaven had in my last year of college. Yet the greatest impacts were still to come. After a few years of teaching, I foiudn myself at Grinnell College in Iowa that, for me, seemed of a piece with your Plains and Mountain West. My mother, aunt, and uncles were born in an Iowas sod house near the Red Cedar where my Covenanter grandfather, a railroad surveyor and contractor, turned homesteader in expecta-tion of a projected rail line that was never put through. 
Well, as you likely know, Grinnell made much of its pioneering tradition as the first college west of the Mississippi. So I was shocked to find the Homer of the Old West had never been heard of on the campus. As one of my propaganda ploys to remedy that deplor-able situation, one evening I rounded up English faculty friends and read them the whole of Hugh Glass at a sitting. Though I'm no great shakes of a reader, it held them spellbound. But waht it did to me was almost too much of a good thing. I don't wear my emotions on my sleeve. However, when I read the last lines and found my-self facing a blank page, it was like what happened to Lightning Bill Jones when the Apaches were after him darkening the sky with a hail of arrows and suddenly he saw the vast chasm of the Grand Canyon yawning in front of Whitey's nose. There was no such thing as stopping -- and nowhere to go. Like Lightning I found myself soaring out over an infinity of empty space. I hadn't forgotten how LIghtning finally hauled in the check-rein and told Whitey There's just nothing for it, Boy, but to turn around a <unclear/> back!" However, when I tried the tactic, all that momentum just had to be converted into physical action to release the unbearable tension. When I'd held onto myself to the utter limits of my endurance, I hurled the book across the room so hard I broke the back of it. 
(over)
1

20
-2-
on the opposite wall..... And no one in the circle seemed to think any the worse of me. They understood! 
Then came that amazing sequal which seemd to open up the fan-tastic vista of Hugh Glass into the kind of panoramic perspective I first saw from the peak of Evans in the Front Range of Color-ado in the company of Paul Sears, the pappa-dady of Ecology (a boyhood friend from Ohio who'd turned up at timberline the nigth before by an outrageous coincidence -- hadn't seen or heard from him in decades -- hand't seen a human being-in two days of climb-ing until Paul with two companions, U. of Nebraska students, appeared from down the trail.)
You may know the story -- at least part of it. yet since I doubt you know it all, perhaps it's worth spelling out. Emerson Hough's Covered Wagon had been made into a movie feature. We had no movie house in town. But on a Saturday night they showed it at the "Opera House". AFter the show I dropped in at the wagon diner for a coffee and sandwhich. There I found myself sititng beside a teen-ager I only knew by sight - a lad who worked in the town garage. owned, as I recall, by his father. He had a grievous stammer which made him self-conscious, but was so steamed up over the movie, he soon opened up quite freely.
Presently he asked me point-blank what I thought of the show. He was so earnest, I said that, good entertainment as it was, it might have been far better -- pointing out that the stand-out scene of shooting whiskey glasses off each other's no ins was an apparent "steal" from a story which multiplied the impact by giving it dramatic meaning and going on from there to build up a tremendous climax. Then I rough-sketched your narrative. When he wanted to know the name of the story, I told him Three Friends -- omitting the Song of for fear of turning him off. But when he talked about looking it up in the library, I had to tell him it was poetry -- adding quickly that it was poetry of a very special type with a unique pattern which made it even easier reading than prose and kept adding an extra wallop you just don't get from prose. 
nate in letter 
It this point he hooked me with a glittering eye and asked the name of the author. I told him, "John Neihardt" -- whereupon he gulpeda hard, then sputtered, "J-J-John Neihardt is my c-c-c-cousin!"
In less than a week my new friend phoned to tell me your mother was visiting his home and would like to talk to me. When I went over on a Friday evening, just meeting her was a major experience in itself. That little nutbrown lady completely captivated me on sight. She must have been about the same age as my own mother. (My "Big Brother" Tom was very close to yours. I'm the "baby" born in '98.) Your mother's unlined face, deep-searching eyes, glowing warmth, inner serenity, and ageless vitality added up to a compelling appearl for which "beauty" is too trite a word. Even you have not described her so far as I'm aware. And I think I understand why. Yet I hope you'll give it a try -- either in the next edition of All Is But a Beginning, or in a sequel.  

21
-3-
When she told me she'd never met anyone before who'd read much, if anything, of your poetry, it knocked the wind out of me. But her straight-from-the-shoulder bid to tell her my frank appraisal as an English teacher put me on my mettle -- though who the hell was I, a young nobody, to attempt such an order to teh mother of the greatest narrative poet of modern times? 
Well, I could only do my damnedest. I was never more grateful that at least I had some background: Virgil; enough beginning Greek to have sampled Homer and Herodotus in the original; Chaucer; and from teh early Elizabethans a rather thorough grounding in English lit up through the two Brownings (Aurora Leigh rates higher in my scale than Robert's character poems) and Masefield. It also helped that I was teaching a little course in verse writ-ting which gave me some extra appreciation of your artful pattern of breaking sentences int eh middle of a line so that one reads in natural breath-groups like prose to avoid sing-song, yet has the magic of rhyme continually ringing in one's ears like bird song as you walk a winding trail through the countryside. I told her how I admired your bold stroke in choosing the form of the classical epic to underscore epic themes of the Old West. here I could set you in context with the best writing I knew in prose: Lewis, Catlin Bonneville, Irving, Parkman. (By the way, I'm betting you also give high rating to Irving's Tour of the Prairies.) Also of course I illustrated the impact of your Songs with such stories as the reading of Hugh Glass to that faculty group. (Sampling to students in lit classes was of a piece.)
It was humbling to have her take my running coomentary so seriously. But I couldn't regret it for she responded  to my eager questions about your background by painting a picture of your early years that was most revealing. It covered quite a bit of what you tell in All Is But a Beginning -- though from a very different angle. Nothing about the valiant role she played. Just waht you endured during those years of grueling poverty -- stress on your lonely isolation as a budding poet in a typically raw barbarian town -- a glimpse of your friendship with the understanding tombstone carver -- nothing that I recall about the schoolteaching adventure -- yet enough on many of your trials and tribulations to appreciate your astonishing feat in presenting the same experiences in the perspective of cosmic humor -- also to understand your motivation in going off to hobnob with teh Indians on the nearby Reservation and why you were drawn into a feeling of spiritual kinship that tended to make up for waht you so sorely missed with your own kind. That struck me as a fascinating parallel with George Borrow's relationship with the Gypsies as he narrates in Lavengro With the Bible in Spain. 
I never knew for certain whether your mother told you the sequal to that first session -- although she was so wonderfully forth-right that I was reasonably certain of it. I must have gotten through fairly well for when I was bowing out, she laid a hand on my arm and told me with some hesitation that there was more she rather felt she should pass on but needed to consider overnight -- and would I come back next day (Sunday) for a further talk? 

22
-4-
What she confided that Sunday afternoon implied a trust so deeply personal that I've never allowed myself to put it on paper. Twice I was sorely tempted. Once I was working up a manuscript I called Writer's Itch on writing know-how and how writers "get that way" from stories, mainly first- and second-hand, gleaned from unprinted sources. For example, MAsefield's account of what he tagged his "most glorious year" of a lifetime when he was working in a Yonkers carpet factory and cutting his baby teeth as both student and writer -- and Seumas MacManus' tale of his beginnings as he outpoured it on all-night walk in Iowa when he was home-sick and alienated by the bleakness of Main Street America where he'd been on lecture tour for months. 
My other temptation came when I was deep in a book project on psychcic experiences. One of my own had parallels with yours -- a "course" of half a dozen sessions on sensory description given me (apparently) by an older cousin in sleep over a stretch of months several years after his passing. Bun was a born storyteller in the Irvin Cobb tradition who'd made his mark as a newspaper feature writer by his mid-twenties when he forgot he was part mortal flesh that required sleep now and hten -- so knocked him self with pneumonia. 
Anyhow I resisted temptation in both cases. But naturally I'm hopign to glory you have reached the poit of realizing waht a major contribution it would be to common understanding of the true facts of life and so-called death to spell your collabora-tion out  with uninhibited drankness. Such understanding is surely the difference between unlimited horizons and the not-so-well padded cell of ordinary blind living. 
Down the generations there have likely been quite a sprinkling of parallell -- and you may know more of them than I do. One is the case of Stephen Crane who perhaps moer than any other American prose writer came closer to the hypnotic involvement you achieve in passages of Hugh Glass and other Songs. You'll recall Garland's account of how young Crane worked in his room for a stretch of weeks where he could observe the process closely -- his clean-cut impression Crane was taking dictation, reeling off pages in a swift steady flow, never hesitating for words, never making even minor corrections -- then how at the end Crane stopped abruptly, gathered his sheaf, telling Garland, "That's all I have to write." Just thanked him for the deskroom and walked out, never to return. 
Your case was of course different. Yours was a genuine collabora-tion with differences of opinion that brought on sweaty battles to see who got his way with the project.... But how did it work out over the long haul? Was there a point where the partner-ship was abandoned to leave you strictly on your own? And how closely were you able to identify your collaborator? Your mother could only tell me he claimed to be a distant relative who'd lived in the days of Jim Bridger. Could you ever verify his flesh-and-blood existence one way or another? 
No need to answer ever if I'm too nosy. (Remember, I don't want you to write anything -- at least beyond a possible note at present. 

23
-5-
Some sweet day if-as-and-whereever I catch up with you, I'll be hoping you may be minded to talk freely. On the other hand, you can count on me to press no embarrassing questions on you.) But my interest is far from idle curiosity I'm familiar enough with deliberately faked "literary" communications from the technically dead, some clever, some clumsy -- also with the same kind of thing that's almost certainly dreamed up by the subconscious. But when I came to discover Patience Worth, the student in me (like the campus scholars, journalists, and others who worked over the volu-minous documents) could see no alternative to accepting them as genuine. 
Then I <unclear/> upon Jap Herron. And here I was onfamiliar ground for I'd made a term-long study of Mark Twain in the Chicago graduate school, so was saturated with the feel of his style and on speaking terms with fortes, limitations, quirks, and problems. There were several good men still writing in the same genre. Yet I couldn't imagine the most gifted of them pulling off a tour de force half as convincing. Matter of fact, after two careful readings, the one difference between Jap and Mark Twain's credited books was that Jap was pure essence of the man which made most of his other books seemwatered down. I could spot no give-away slips or shortcomings such as show up in the most inspired imitations. 
In one sense, however, it was too much of a good thing. As Mark Twain, the "spook", says in the introductory background piece, this is the kind of book he always yearned to write when he was "alive" but couldn't manage. He just couldn't plan ahead, organize, inte-grate -- was strictly dependent on his subconscious to take over for him. In Jap he portrays the interweaving life development stories of individuals and a community as a whole -- does it in half the wordage of most skilled craftsmen, yet with an air of easy, off-hand spontaneity that shows no trace of deliberate condensation and foreshortening. 
Now that's precisely the nature of your feat with All Is But a Beginning -- from one point of view at least. It's the capacity nobody but nobody starts out with or is likely ot achieve in the middle years of a writing career. Few ever do in their mortal span. And those rare individuals only grow into the capacity as the pull up out of the caynons and up through the forested ascents to emerge into the open at timberline. I think of it as the blessed state many of us are permitted to sample in brief interludes to bait us on with the implied promise we have a sporting chance of acquiring it as a normal way of life if and when we've earned us by striving through enough rounds of muscle-building to break out all the way from the cocoon that imprisons us. 
Well, you've done it! Have done it in a single round. So you can tell us the inside story blow-by-blow of how you made it up the mountain. You've made a magnificent start with the revelation of this first volume. And I for one will be figuratively holding my breath till you carry though all the way. 
In signing off, should tell you you are giving me fresh vest and vision for a book project of my own. Have much (mainly in the 

24
<unclear/>
-6-
lighter vein) i'd like to brainstorm with you. But it will keep -- if necessary <unclear/> we meet up in some snug tavern on the other side of the river.... Meanwhile -- 
just keep on soaring!!!
Arthur C. ("Sandy") Kemble 
A. C. Kemble 
Ore Hill 
Lakeville, Conn. 06039
Answered
March 5th, 1973 


