<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.42.6-16">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, January 25, 1964</title>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4c.42.6-16</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
<date when="1964-01-25">January 25, 1964</date>
<extent>10 pages, plus envelope</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>10 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sterling, George, 1869-1926</term>
<term>Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950</term>
<term>Graf</term>
<term>Nelson, Fred</term>
<term>Harman, Neil K.</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term>A Bundle of Myrrh</term>
<term>The Divine Enchantment</term>
<term>Bancroft Blade</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1964-01-25"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName>Eugene (Or.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0001" />

<fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
 
<note type="authorial"> I <hi rend="underline">must</hi> know about Perky. She is a friend and fellow celebrant of the Bocchio mysteries!</note> 
   
   <note type="curatorial">Aly Collection
204-10</note>
<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>  
</fw>
<opener>
<dateline>January 25, '64</dateline>

<salute>Dear Lucile:</salute></opener> <p>You're a perfect gentleman (in the high sense, of course) as well as a scholar; but you're a lovely lady too, and I don't like you some, the way I used to didn't, do I? (Parse that one!)</p>

<p>I've read your letter several times - with satisfaction and gratefulness. You <hi rend="underline">do know</hi>, bless you!</p>

<p>About the Sterling remark concerning "Bundleizing": I do not know the year, and your objection is reasonable. But Sterling did write enthusiastically about the Bundle, saying in effect: "No one has ever expressed the gloom and glory, the Hell and Heaven" of love as you have. <del/> I remember this clearly because I thought, surely no one is a better authority on erotic love than he!! It was almost the <note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<note type="authorial">The Millay editorial is only a paragraph. <hi rend="underline">It's a clipping</hi>.</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0002"/>
<fw type="curatorial">7</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>

man's profession, and it would have been impossible to impress him with less than the real thing! This is cited to show that George was <del/> greatly impressed by the <hi rend="underline">Bundle</hi>. It came out in 1907, 
<hi rend="underline">but</hi> the "New Poetry" outbreak did not come until 1912. So there could have been 
<hi rend="underline">no</hi> "Bundleizing" before that date. <add><note type="authorial">Or <hi rend="underline">was</hi> there?</note></add> Soon thereafter it seemed that a considerable portion of the population had taken to "poetry".</p>

<p>I wish we could locate Sterling's letters to me - those that I sold back East. It's a pity; but I needed money - had to have it. Is there not a way to <del/> run those letters down?

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0003"/>
<fw type="curatorial">8</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

I understood at the time that they were sold "to an institution". Brown University was very active then in collecting poets. Maybe they would know, even if they didn't own <del/><add>them.</add> They must have been microfilmed, I'd suppose.</p>

<p>I've sent the tape. It gives an<del/> accurate account of the Graff brush war. I am sure he did not turn &amp; hasten down the street because of cowardice. No such thing. But he did know about my alleged athletic prowess. The whole town knew. He might well have thought I'd make a fool of him <note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0003"/>
<fw type="curatorial">9</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-<del><unclear>3</unclear></del>4-</fw>

And, indeed, I would have done at least that, because I could have hurt him; and, I believe, I would have done so under the circumstances. He was not magnanimous. Really, Lucile, <hi rend="double underline">I</hi> <hi rend="underline">was</hi>, ten years later when I told him he was right and I was a damned fool.</p>
  
<p>In dealing with Graf's political campaign, I had <hi rend="double underline">no</hi> thought whatever of "politics". <hi rend="underline">I was</hi> <hi rend="double underline">after</hi> <hi rend="underline">Graf</hi>, the <hi rend="underline">man</hi>, in the interest of my <del>f<unclear/></del><add>friend,</add> Fred Nelson, the <hi rend="underline">man</hi>, who wanted to be State Senator the same as Graf did. It <hi rend="underline">was</hi> funny,

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0005"/>
<fw type="curatorial">10</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

Lucile, and should be handled in a way somewhat less than <hi rend="underline">heavy</hi>. <add><note type="authorial">But still not derisively.</note></add> You can <del><unclear>make</unclear></del><add>make</add> a real small-town drama out of it, by golly! The impending clash <del/> with Graff, who had announced his intention to "<del/>trounce" me; the meeting; his insulting remarks about my size; my expression of <del>the <unclear/></del><add>my</add> intention to "go through him like a dose of salts"; the offering of a horse against what have you that I'd <del/><add>win</add> the battle (this across the street). This 

<note type="authorial">(over)</note>
<note type="authorial"><hi rend="double underline">People watching</hi></note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0006"/>
<fw type="curatorial">1<unclear reason="missing" cert="medium">1</unclear></fw>
<fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>

episode <hi rend="underline">is</hi> characteristic of country journalism, in the good old days of "fighting newspapers" before the <hi rend="caps">R. F. D.</hi> came in with the city dailies. So it has historical value too. 
<hi rend="double underline">Make</hi> <hi rend="underline">a story out of it</hi>! It's a damned good yarn, and, in <del/> essence, very funny.</p>

<p>(You make a <hi rend="underline">good point in your defense of <unclear/></hi>. <hi rend="underline">The Divine Enchantment</hi> makes a good story too - but not a funny one.  <hi rend="underline">Tell it</hi> as you would to friends around a fireplace. Don't forget my carrying it with me on the hobo trip. It meant <hi rend="underline">so</hi> much to me.</p>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0007"/>
<fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

<p>I've been writing fast (with bad eye-sight too) and almost missed the page in my enthusiasm.</p>
   
<p>On the tape I explained the wrestling hold I used on my big boys in my country school. (This was the winter of 1898-99). This too is a good story, characteristic of conditions in the one-room country schools. Remember that my <add>former</add> school-mate, a young lady, was put out of the school, &amp; locked out, the year before. She went home <del/> crying and never came back. I took the school for <unclear>$</unclear>30 per month, knowing well what I was <del/><add>up</add> against - big husky<del/> boys, who were really men &amp; only half civilized. I <hi rend="underline">knew</hi> and secretly 
<hi rend="double underline">liked</hi> that breed. The Director of the school board was reluctant to hire me because, as 

<note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0007"/>
<fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>

he insisted, "what them boys needed was to be <hi rend="underline">trashed out</hi>." (He was a big Swede). The boys found they couldn't handle me in wrestling and became admiring pals. But, even so, they would laughingly "gang up" on me in our cob-fights at noon and recess. (We heated the school with <del/>corn cobs). Once, on my birthday, three boys tackled me, and after a big struggle, got me down. I leaped up and said, "no two of you can do that." And one said, "<del>That</del><add>That is</add> why we came three!" Long before school was out the big boys were my friends and would have fought for me, I do believe.</p>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0009"/>
<fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-9-</fw>

<p>I infer that you have not yet <del/><add>read</add> your <hi rend="caps">MS</hi> to which <del>I</del><add>my</add> notes refer. There are further comments on the margins, and even on the backs of pages here and there. Most of the favorable, even rejoicing, comment is on the margins. The notes were prepared <hi rend="underline">for reading with the <hi rend="caps">MS</hi></hi>. Please do read <del><unclear>through</unclear></del> through the <hi rend="caps">MS</hi>.</p>

<p>The <del/> stories I've emphasized are vital and really interesting. They are the prime stuff of biography if conceived as good <del/><hi rend="underline">anecdotes</hi>.</p>

<p>Yes, I <hi rend="underline">was</hi> awfully young, wasn't I,<del/> to be running a newspaper<del/>! It's such a pity that you could not see a complete, <del>unm</del> <hi rend="underline">unmutilated</hi> file of the Blade. There <hi rend="underline">were articles</hi> that <hi rend="underline">did</hi> represent 

<note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0010"/>
<fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-10-</fw>

me at the time, I know. Perhaps a bit callow, but with stuff in them too. - <hi rend="underline">And</hi> those <hi rend="underline">primer pages</hi> with illustrations prepared for little children, that they might know and revere Mr. Graff!! Wow! If I had been he I'd have wanted to kick <del>my</del><add>Neihardt's</add> pants up <del/><add>on</add> the back of <del>my</del><add>his</add> neck!! 
<hi rend="underline">But</hi> it <hi rend="underline">was</hi> funny. My cartoonist was Neil Harman, a budding artist <hi rend="underline">who</hi> clerked in his step-father's hardware store. He had a lot of fun too, but 
<hi rend="underline">I</hi> caught all the hell! (Why do I remember names,<del/> names &amp; details as I do?)</p> 

<p>Love to you, dear Lady, and to Bower - for that matter - to Perky also.</p>

</div1>


<div1 type="envelope">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0011a"/>
<fw type="curatorial">16</fw>

<ab type="return">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>   
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</ab>

<ab type="postmark"><hi rend="caps">AIR MAIL</hi>
COLUMBIA, MO. JAN 27 5-PM 1964</ab>
<figure>
<figDesc>8 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
<p><unclear reason="missing" cert="high">8¢ U.S. AI</unclear>R MAIL</p>
</figure>

<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. Lucile Aly,</addrLine>
<addrLine>1138 22nd Ave., East,</addrLine>
<addrLine>Eugene,</addrLine>
<addrLine>Oregon.</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>

<note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.42.6-16_0011b"/>

<note type="authorial">When you are revising, perhaps it would be well to make me a list of matters you want me to illuminate and I can <hi rend="underline">tape</hi> the answers in detail.
- Jno.</note>

  

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>