<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

Neihardt   
Route 7<hi rend="caps">VIA AIR MAIL</hi>
Columbia, Mo.  <hi rend="caps">CORREO AEREO</hi>
   <hi rend="caps">PAR AVION</hi>

Dr. Lucile Aly,
 1138 22nd Ave., East,
  Eugene, Oregon.



<fw type="curatorial">230-4</fw>

Last Day at the Office. June 7, '65

<hi rend="underline">Dear</hi> Lucile: 

Yes, you <hi rend="underline">are</hi> a part of me, and not a "tiny" one. That was beautifully and truly said, and it means a very great deal to me.
My "live" class in <hi rend="underline">Epic America</hi> ("The Mountain Men") left a happy glow all through my "innards." They actually gave me a big ovation at the end
of the last class

-2-

period. Since then, many have come to me and thanked me for the course This is a surprise to me, because I have been worried over leaving so much out of the <hi rend="underline">one hour</hi>
course. (It should be two-hours, and I've asked for the change when I return in February.)
The doings in Bancroft are, apparently, flourishing. The <hi rend="underline">tree of life</hi> is planted; the brush has been cleared out around the little 

-3-

house, and much grading has been done by bulldozers, I'm told. The highway marker has not yet been placed, but should be soon. It is <hi rend="underline">ready to install</hi> 
&#8212; has been for several months.
The Laureate Tour will cover the state rather thoroughly, I'm told &#8212; both larger and smaller places. It is sponsored by the Governor, the Centennial Commission,
and

-4-
   
the Hist. Society. Stanley Smith is in charge. He will conduct me on the tour, <hi rend="underline">transporting me, arranging everything</hi>. All I'm to do is my lecturing.
Under such circumstances I'm sure I can do a lot of talking and reading.
My "Memorial Library" is developing nicely. About 3/4 of the collection is processed and permanently placed. It will be a lovely place for a friend

-5-

to go for a quiet visit with my ghost!! 
You really ought to see our horses and <hi rend="underline">colts</hi> now. It has become a very distinguished group of fine animals. I have three new colts &#8212; two hackneys,
one American Saddle filly. The latter is superb. There are <hi rend="underline">8</hi> Stonewall <hi rend="underline">King</hi> crosses in her pedigree; so you see she is very much
<hi rend="underline">inbred</hi>. There was 

-6-

a chance that this might work out for good or bad. It is definitely for <hi rend="underline">good</hi>. I'll call the beautiful filly, <hi rend="underline">Mary Madaleva</hi>,
after the great Catholic woman who was especially friendly to me, for some reason or other. (She died three years ago) It was this lady who told me that if I were a Catholic, they would keep me
going steadily all over the country! More later. <hi rend="underline">Love</hi> to you, dear lady, and to Bower &amp; Stewart.

&#8212; <signed>John Neihardt</signed>