<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.9.137.41">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Sigurd Neihardt to Maxine M. Neihardt, October 23, 1932</title>
<author>Neihardt, Sigurd</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&amp;#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.9.137.41</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Sigurd Neihardt to Maxine M. Neihardt, October 23, 1932</title>
<date when="1932-10-23">October 23, 1932</date>
<extent>5 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Sigurd</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5074472">Omaha (Neb.)</placeName>
<date when="1932-10-23"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Maxine M.</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Maxine M.</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2019"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.9.137.41.001" />
<fw type="curatorial"></fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>10-23-'32
5116 Cass SO., 
Omaha Nebraska.
</dateline>
<salute>My sweet girl,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Here I am - all by my lonesome &amp; of course I'm thinking about my dear sweetheart, as usual! You blessed girl, I can't say to the full extenet of my feelings just hwo much I'm missing you! 
Nothing can help me 'til I am once more with you, &amp; satisfied! Dad, Judge Vinsonhaler, &amp; Rev. Plank are all enjoying themselves in a secret manner somewhere in this city! They gave me the Auburn &amp; I've been staying with Mr. Leigh Leslie! Lovely people! They do all they can think of in effort to show me a good time, but Heck! I'm not happy with out the only girl I love! 
Sweetheart, I love you always the same, &amp; I'm so glad </p>

<fw type="curatorial">138</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>

<p>that you do realize it! 
Take care of yoruself, be as happy as possible, &amp; always remember the things I've told you about my sincere feelings regarding yourself!
I know you will, &amp; it makes me so happy &amp; grateful! Hope you have received all of my letters, honey! I have never yet missed a day of writing you either a letter or card! 
I have read your sweet letters over &amp; over again, &amp; still am wishing for another one before time is up in Omaha! 
Please, don't think ('cause I haven't answered your letters systematically) that I disregard anything that is in them; be-cause I don't disregard a single word you write! I just haven't answered in detail the things you've written! C? 
</p>

<fw type="curatorial">139</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>

<p>I haven't gone to a show here yet &amp; don't suppose I will; be-cause if it's a good show I miss you &amp; wish for you so, that it ruins it for me! You dear girl, I am satisfied with having only you for my happiness!
I feel as happy as any human needs to feel - when I can be with you! Excuse the stationary, dear; but it is all that I could find here at Leslie's home! Please! Remember how i love to hear from you, &amp; that your letters play the im-portant part in keeping me happy! See? Sweetheart!! 
I'm so glad that you enjoyed the trip to <unclear/> with Eny! Did she "kiss" you as much as I always have done?? Ha! Ha! Sweet girl, I'll bet - U - she didn't!! 
I'd give anything to kiss you goodnight each night, but gee </p>

<fw type="curatorial">140</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>

<p>We're separated by so many miles! One thousand &amp; four hundred miles to date I've driven in a "round-about" way from my dear girl! Of course this is only about 750 miles from you where I am now! Not so bad, but plenty far at that! 
The Auburn has done very well!  You have by this time heard of the speedin' from Fulton MO. to Manhattan Kansas via K.C. MO.! I will get sufficient rest while here in Omaha to make that mile drive from Lincoln Neb. to Kearney Neb. 
Dad will sleep in the rear seat while I travel along thinking about the vacant seat next to me not having my dear girl in it! 
It's saddening to me, but when I think of being back with you soon - then it relieves the pain a lot! 
(over) </p>

<p>Hope your father's leg is better, &amp; also that Curran will not have to suffer so! 
You know, after a person weakens down to a certain point - they won't suffer so consciously as if not weak! 
I don't know anything more to write about, except that I love you, my sweet girl!! 
I want to be with you so!! </p>
<closer>
<salute>Always the same Endless love,</salute>
<signed>Your Sig.</signed>
<note>
P.S. I have not found any music yet, except a book of modern harmony which is beautiful when used either with classical or popular tunes! S.N. 
P.S. No. 2 
Mrs. Sutton hit it right! Don't you think so??
No. 3
These are the silliest letters, all chock full of adjectives as usual, but you understand! Sig. </note>
<fw type="curatorial">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</fw>
</closer>

</div1>

<div1 type="envelope">
<fw type="curatorial">141</fw>

<ab type="postmark">OMAHA NEBR. OCT 23 6 PM 1932 BURLINGTON STA</ab>

<figure type="stamp"><ab>UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <figure><ab>3CENTS3</ab></figure> </ab></figure>
<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Miss Maxine Melton, </addrLine>
<addrLine>Branson, 
Missouri </addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>