<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
41
March 2nd 43
Darling Alice:
<p>I have written ana torn up letters and more letters to you, fearing to hurt you. So I'll try to do better today, writing <hi rend="underline"> only cons</hi>tructively.</p>
<p>I have a job as assistant copy reader, with "Buxton and SKinner" Printers and Stationery, St. Louis. I earn $18.00 per week.</p>
<p>Daddy has been much sicker than he was when you <sic>wer</sic> here. He has a Bronchitis now with fever and is in bed, but is getting better.</p>
<p>My job can support Daddy and me till he gets one also. Enid is tired of our imposing on her husband, and I don't blame her - so I expect to move into a room closer to work as soon as I can move Daddy. This next week end, I believe: unless a job turns up for Daddy in Lincoln Nebr. which is possible - Now if you decide you <hi rend="underline"> cannot</hi> any longer be forced to <hi rend="underline"> wait</hi> for the Government (and we here <hi rend="underline"> all of us</hi> believe there is <hi rend="underline"> no</hi> reason to believe it will make <hi rend="underline"> any</hi> effort whatever to help Mons Leon to return to the U.S.) then you many have to break away and make a clean start for your<hi rend="underline"> self</hi>. If so Alice I'll do my best to help you get to the nearest big American City where you <hi rend="underline"> can</hi> get <hi rend="underline"> work</hi>. I <hi rend="underline"> cannot</hi> help the Leon Doucers - but I can help Alice Neihardt whenever she decides that it is right for <hi rend="underline"> he</hi>r to start to stand on her own feet again. So, let me Know how much money you need for that, and I'll to borrow</p>
42
<p>it on my job for you. Maybe I could get enough to buy your ticket back to Chicago, where you could join Hilda. Let me Know <hi rend="underline"> every</hi> thing, not just <hi rend="underline"> some</hi> things about your position. <hi rend="underline"> You</hi> must <hi rend="underline"> decide</hi> your own self.</p>
<p>Hilda leaves tonight, unless Albert's money does not come today. I hope to be with her after today's work.</p>
Endless love to <hi rend="underline"> my</hi> baby from her
Mama.
<p>Alice, under no consideration should a man allow you to remain idle, to have to borrow money, and get deeper and deeper into debt - not for <hi rend="underline"> any</hi> reason. I too am sorry for Mr Leon and his grandmother, but <hi rend="underline"> their</hi> family will have to help them, as <hi rend="underline"> your</hi> family must help you, please please use <hi rend="underline"> reason</hi> and make a constructive plan - <hi rend="underline"> any</hi> thing other than get into debt when jobs are so easy for <hi rend="underline"> young</hi> people to get now - or else what?</p>
