<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- page 123 -5- is missing -->

219 Fink Collection 119
June 25, 1940
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Tuesday, June 25.
Lack Haven, Penna.
Dear Enot and Oddie:
<p>I've just finished writing for the day, and a lovely place it is for work - <underline>deep</underline> in green mountains and right on the bank of the Susquehanna River. I've seen about all of the U.S., but there's no more beautiful country than this one.</p>
<p>We're just now getting rested after the 1200 mile drive. I do it without any, conscious strain, but it's very wearing nevertheless, and the impact on the eyes' - especially very sensitive eyes - is considerable.</p>
<p>Happily, I <underline>am</underline> getting on reasonably well with Jed. We've entered the great central desert after crossing the high Sierras, and it's getting to be pretty damned hot! It will take us a solid <underline>month</underline> to cross</p>
(over)
120
-2-
<p>that desert, but we don't know it yet! The pictures are coming very clear again. Hardly seems possible I'm making them up out of my head. Maybe, sometime before I'm too old, I'll see if I can find the route I'm describing. What makes me wonder is the meticulous details that I see, some of which, naturally, I don't describe.</p>
<p>My Grandfather was born 30 miles from here in the year 1802. There are plenty of our family in Centre County - <underline>and</underline> all over the state, for that matter. One relative thinks his name is spelled "Nighthart". I told him it should be "Neidhardt". He said he had the old family Bible withe the family record in it, so I asked him to get it and I'd show him how to spell his name! They were all Neidhardts!!!</p>
121
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>That is a perfectly darling formal you made &amp; sent to Mama. I do hope there'll be some night affairs. Here it is a morning stunt; but, as I remember, I as<unclear/> in the evening at Shippensburg. So Mama may come out shining down there. I hope so. Mighty dear of you two, but just like you.</p>
<p>Ollie, I'll bet you're just all a - trimble with excitement over the big convention! Golly! Wouldn't it be hell if they made a mistake, <underline>for just once</underline> and nominated the wrong guy!! Good God, it's awful to contemplate! But it's hardly like that glowing patriots could fail to choose a great patriot.</p>
122
-4-
<p>to save the nation in her hour of peril - not to mention Civilization, Democracy, Freedom, and Brotherly Love!</p>
<p>Is Rossey nuts, or what? I guesss he's the latter, maybe. But Oh how I do trimble and faunch and froth, a worrying over Democracy and the like! We're all going to vote for our own Dr. George Katt of Branson.</p>
<p>Isn't it wonderful, how the people suddenly discovered Wilkie's presidential qualifications! Another poor boy who made good!</p>
<p>But don't you think it's awful mean of France not to go right on bleeding and dying for England and Civilization? My! My! And don't you think Churchill is an old darling?</p>
<p>But if we only look sharp and catch the 5th columnists and other subersive elements, we'll be all right. Don't you just love words</p>
124
-6-
<p>a few emeralds. I'll see There's a heluva big emerald some place that belongs to me. Maybe it's here. Poor as I am, I'd gladly spend 75<cent/> for a really good one.</p>
<p>We'll be seeing you.</p>
Endless love, 
<underline>Dad</underline>