<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
53a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Mon. p.m.
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad;
<p>Well, Baby Nei had his party Sat. I made him a 4-layer sponge cake &amp; Ol went over &amp; got a huge bunch of ice cream. Hilda &amp; Max bro't Joan &amp; Elaine out Sat. afternoon, &amp; Francis was here. We had Neenie &amp; Sue over too. It was great fun watching him open his gifts. He was so cute &amp; excited! He opened the big red box from Amama first &amp;, it was so cute, he liked it so well that he wanted to play with it &amp; not open any of the other things! Neenie H. gave hima  curved sppon &amp; fork set very lovely, too. We read the telegram from you three dear people &amp; devery one got a big kick out of it. It </p>
2
<p>surely was sweet &amp; to the point. I'm putting it in his book to keep. I told about the coat, legging &amp; helmet set you were making him &amp; everyone tho't it grand. mrs Tacke bro't him a savings bank with money in it &amp; someone or two people shipped in some more, as it now has 50<cent/> in it - no, 60<cent/>, because Dadda slipped in a dime this a.m.! Tackes also gave hime two prs. of anklets. Mother Fink sent an adorable card with 2 pro. hose. Joan &amp; Elaine bro't him an adorable toy to pull along on the floor. Francis donated a darling pink doggie with a blue ribbon around its neck. Ol &amp; I presented Master Fink with a fort, knige &amp; spoon set of sterling silver. We're going to keep it for him when he's a bit older, &amp; perhpas engrave "N" on it.</p>
53b
3
<p>We had a dandy time &amp; missed you during the party several times, wishing you could have been here. We took pictures of the big boy opening pkgs. &amp; othe rhtings, &amp; hope they're good! I wanted pictures of them on his celebration of the "rip old age of 1."</p>
<p>We'll see Amama tomorrow &amp; would love for her to stay to dinner,as Hil &amp; Albert would no doubt be happy to come &amp; get her back to the Hotel. But, as you say, Amama has her own ideas. The things is she won't see Ollie at all if she doesn't stay to dinner &amp; Ol would be disappointed.</p>
<p>We're looking forward to seeing you again &amp;</p>
4
<p>won't it be next week-end? We miss you two when you aren't here!!</p>
<p>Ol picked a bunch of grapes &amp; I made 5 qts (in smaller containers of course) of grape jelly!! It's good too! Wed. I shall can anotehr bushel of tomatoes; canned a bu. last week. We're proud of our produce &amp; canned stuff. It has been only 50 ago this year, but, even at that we've made money on the garden! Next year it'll be even better, no Ol has learned a great deal about various things.</p>
Here's loads o' love,
always,
Ollie, Nei &amp; Eny
<p>See you soon!</p>
<p>I bet it's nice being there alone awhile!!! isn't it?!?</p>
<p>Mom &amp; Dad: <underline>Please</underline> let us know if you can use a little money, won't you?</p>
53c
Tues-.
Dear Mother &amp; Dad -
<p>We are looking forward to seeing you - wish our Car was not <unclear>hors de liecense</unclear> etc., so we could come &amp; get you - IF we can help in any other way let us know - Amama will be with Enid todya - Hope I get to see her -</p>
Love -
<p>4 Nei Says "Hot doo"</p>
Ollie
53d
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO Fink
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI
SAINT LOUIS, MO.12
SEP1
1130AM
1942
BUY DEFENSE SAVINGS BONDS AND STAMPS
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
THOMAS JEFFERSON 1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Dr. &amp; Mrs. J. G. Neihardt
Branson 
<underline>Taney Co.</underline> Missouri