<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
44
Missouri Collection 
HOTEL STATLER BOSTON 
1300 ROOMS, 1300 BATHS <figure/> 
UNDER
SAME MANAGEMENT 
HOTELS STATLER
BUFFALO, CLEVELAND
DETROIT, ST. LOUIS
<FIGURE/> 
HOTEL BUFFALO
BUFFALO
<FIGURE/> 
HOTEL 
PENNSYLVANIA
NEW YORK 
Park Square at Arlington Street 
Tuesday A.M. 
Nov. 13 '28 
Dear Mama:
I arrived here last evening at 7:45 and had a good night's sleep. This morning I took a long walk - through Boston Common, fast old King's Church and the Old. State House to Fanevil Hall. The latter ("Cradle of American liberty") is a market & you can buy cheese there! 
This is surely a beautiful <del/> city. 
I read at Wellesley at 4:15 this afternoon & must <del/> go to a dinner afterwards. Wish I could dodge the dinner. 
I notice that two of my stocks have gone up - one $10 a share & the 
(over) 

45
(2)
other a little more. I think I'll were an order to sell tomorrow. Hope today's market is strongly so that I may cash my profits of yesterday. All my stocks are up a bit, except one & it is a good stock, so I needn't worry. 
I hope Wellesley's crowd will come across as other crowds have done. Can't see why they should not. Perhaps I should have afternoon clothes, but I'll have to wear my new street suit, which is a very good one. 
Statter Hotel has a radio in every room - rather nice. I heard a lot of jazz last night. There seemed to be nothing else on the air. Mama, how I wish I could be down there a week with you! I think we should fear to spend Xmas with you or at least the nearest Saturday

46 
HOTEL STATLER BOSTON 
1300 ROOMS, 1300 BATHS <figure/> 
UNDER
SAME MANAGEMENT 
HOTELS STATLER
BUFFALO, CLEVELAND
DETROIT, ST. LOUIS
<FIGURE/> 
HOTEL BUFFALO
BUFFALO
<FIGURE/> 
HOTEL 
PENNSYLVANIA
NEW YORK 
Park Square at Arlington Street 
(3)
I'll not wake over $100 on this hard long journey, but, my salary goes on, so I'm ahead. 
I came through Washington Philadelphia & New York yesterday. Had no time to stop at Washington. May stop in New York tomorrow & see Lotham of Macmillans. 
Johns wants me to go on at $110 per week. Said they had no change in mind, but didn't want to raise salary now. I think I could have gotten a raise if I had been like other people. 
I do hope you are feeling well, Mama, and that you are reasonably happy. I want to live in Branson 
(over)

47
-4-
again & finish my cycle & several other books-probably prose. The strenuous life in civilization isn't worth what it costs. Your life there is so much better. YOu are near the real things - the only real things. All I regret about your being there so that you must be above. That ought to be changed, & will be. 
Mona has some bully work to exhibit, & I do hope she will get some satisfaction out of the exhibit, I want it to make her happier. 
Endless love, Mama. 
John 

48
Later. Wonderful reception at Wellesley. Also had successful <unclear/> with Macmillans - Brett, the president: Nelson, head of education department; <unclear/>, head of editorial dept. am to see Taulsersely in in Chicago soon Special plan to push school editions. 
-Jno 
NOTICE 
Letters mailed in hotel envelopes, if not delivered, are sent to the Dead Letter Office unless the writer gives a return address. 
If not delivered in days, return to 
Neihardt
Post-Dispatch
St. Louis.
(2)
HOTEL STATLER BOSTON 
1300 ROOMS, 13 BATHS 
SAINT LOUIS NOV15 330PM 1928 
AIRMAIL <FIGURE/> SAVES 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 2CENTS2
Mrs. Alice Neihardt
Branson,
Missouri 
(Taney Co.) (over) 

