<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
243 -<strike>244</strike> Fink Collection 40
December 24, 1940
BRANSON
DEC25
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
MO.
(St. Louis Co.)
41
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Night Before Xmas
and All Through
the House, 1940
Dear Ones:
<p>Two more lovely letter from you! We're through building a gorgeous Nativity <sic>spectaclle</sic> in the front room for Joan, and she si upstairs singing her head off, hoping to God Xmas will hurry! She's a dear - such a satisfactory companion - and she is really unfolding fast in the free atmosphere here. No puppy dog sisters to fuss her, and no bad Dickie boys to immitate!! She swears very soberly, with big serious eyes, that she <underline>never never</underline> will act like a bad boy again. "Why <underline>did</underline> I go up there where that boy is, anway?!!" (I know well what you meant, Enat. Kids can be so godawful when they get that way; but Joan is naturally a lady, and old 'Laine is a dollish too, but she's a puppy dog yet.)</p>
(over)
42
-2-
<p>I'm really interested in the progress of the table made of ancestral walnut. It's nearly if not quite impossible to make a <underline>long</underline> joint perfect with a small hand plane; but if you've done your best with patience, you have collaborated with divinity, and something of holiness clings to the result. There <underline>is</underline> a way that I have in ming now by which you could have compelled the joint to fit. It's a trick, and I wish I'd been there to pass it on to you. <underline>Is</underline> the seam already glued?</p>
<p>the legs will be ready here to be taken up when we come. Surely you can have the job <strike/> ready for attaching them. How are you going to fasten the legs?</p>
<p>Enot, you may count on a jade-crystal-white sapphire ring. It's all planned. You'll see Max's, which I did to replace the ring made over a year ago - unsuccessfully</p>
<note>text underneath is in margins of letter</note>
<p>It may well be the joint is better than you say.</p>
43
-3-
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>I dont' want to stop with your ivory ring, either.</p>
<p>Anyway, I'm more fascinated by crystals as material. Harder by far to work, &amp; proportionately more beautiful. I've begun old Hiddy's bracelet to go with her earrings. In the back of my head a plan is growing for some sturdy piece of jewellry for Ollie.</p>
<p>Yes, it's too damned bad about Xmas and all the sentimental twaddle it entails, not to mention the fact that it is a colossal commercial racket. As a source of mystery for kids, it's all to the good, or <underline>can</underline> be.</p>
<p>The essential Christ story is profoundly symbolic of a truth central in human experience - hardly flattering to so crude a world; but it</p>
44
-4-
<p>is little related to the Xmas celebration. I always have had to fight melancholic wrath at this season. I've downed it pretty well this time. Heluva a wonder how people suddenly bubble with love <strike>for the</strike> <underline>in December!</underline> Yeah! Peace on earth, good will to men! Of course, war is the <underline>other</underline> guy's fault, always; just as all damned human meanness is! In a pig's rumble seat!</p>
<p>Well, it's all in <underline>The Song of The Messiah</underline> - what I really mean here. <underline>And how</underline> it <underline>is</underline> there for those who look to find it! The beauty and the terror and the pity of it - <underline>and the cleansing</underline> too.</p>
<p>We're fingered your packages, but refused to open till morning. No fair peeking, by God!</p>
Love always
Dad.
45
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>P.S.
Next Day, Noon
18 pound boy born to Joseph and Mary last night. Mother and child doing well. Joe passing cigars around all over the place, as tho' he really done it himself; and everybody knows it was the Holy Ghost! Snicker, snicker, snickers.</p>
<p>Hurrah for warm slippers, crochetted of love &amp; wool! And hurrah for a beautiful writing set to wear when I'm dressed up &amp; going places! Awfully dear of <sic>you'ns</sic>!</p>
<p>Say, Ollie here's how to make that joint <underline>absolutely</underline> perfect. No snide about it either. I've done this often, &amp; it works. Maybe you've thought of it already. Anyway, do</p>
(over)
46
<p>it Thus:
Run along deep in the joint, wherever imperfect, with a sharp blade. Then make thin slices of walnut, wet these with glue, &amp; the slit also, &amp; drive the slices in, keeping the <underline>grain</underline> of the slices running as nearly horizontal as possible. Fill all carefully. Let dry, till thoroughly set. Then with sharp blade trim off the protruding slices &amp; sand paper the joint &amp; surrounding wood carefully. If <underline>any</underline> places are thus left unfilled, do it again until it's all perfect. No use in leaving an imperfect joint. Your satisfaction is the great thing.</p>
Love
Dad


