<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
46
40 Piper Collection July 26, 1923
BRANSON JUL 26 11 PM M.O. UNITED STATES POSTAGE <figure/> 2CENTS2 
#255 <unclear/> 
Miss Mildred Piper 
1921 West 7th Street
Soo City
Iowa 

47
July 20, 1923
My Dear little girl; 
If you could know how many times I think of you; it might be some compen-sation for my tardy letter writing has been so hard this summer. For weeks I have not been well, Have been to "blue hole" but once this summer, but Mona has been going, little alice to and they can hardly get her out. She tells Daddy "No sir I swim" and back she wades. I was so glad for your letter weeks ago and I hope you are having a pleasant vacation. So glad to know you have bot the home and how pretty it must be all <unclear/>. 
I hope you will get into Soo City to teach. They have been having a great time here for teachers this summer the school is much better unclear the new <unclear/> and wages are better but teacher have so much to do I did not want you to have so much work, but oh! I did want you here. Mary House of Wayne was elected to the Primary at $10. I board here for $20, she is a dear little girl but I did so wish it were you to be here.  

48
y yard has been so beautiful this summer and I have a lovely garden. 
Mother has gone to Lincoln I hardly expect her back again. With there she can go out in their car. Here she could not get around. 
The weather has been so hot here. John is gone again and I am doing the milking, we are making cheese too, we make a 2lb cheese every other day. And we have 5 of them now. I don't need to can peaches this year I have so many left I think of you every time I open a can. How you did help. And I wish you were her this Summer. Peaches are not so plentiful this year melons too are scarce, they had to give up for the tobacco craze. Every one is raining tobacco this year. Lots of plums and apples I have such lots of ripe tomatoes. Must can this week get Mrs. Garner always asks for you and so do the Balls. I have not been out there this summer. Think I shall go before school begins. Remember me to your father and mother all the boys and your own dear self I am so glad for the sweet photo of yourself lovingly Alice Neihardt
<unclear/> 