<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
279 Fink Colleciton 124
Neihardt 
Branson Mo.
BRANSON
MAY12
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O. F. Fink.
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
Mo. St. Louis County
125
Mother's Day
1941
Darling Enid and Ollie
<p>Your dear telegram was such a happy surprise for me - Many thanks dear children for your thoughtfulness.</p>
<p>A dear letter came from Alice in which she mentions your gift of plants which are yet to come. I am thrilled at the prospect and will do justice to them whatever they may be. I Know of no gift quite as wonderful as a new shrub or plant or tree to add to ones homegarden. It makes such beauty each year and affords so many pleasant memories as well for ones old age</p>
126
2
<p>thanks a htousand times!</p>
<p>Daddy is working on your new ring Enid. He got a <sic>finepiece</sic> of rosequartz on the way home from St Louis for that purpose.</p>
<p>Hilda and Max want to go to the Branson Alumni banquet - I do hope Alice gets a formal here in time for Hilda to wear. This is rather a dull place for a yound woman's vacation - but I am <underline>so</underline> glad Hilda cared to come Home and be with us. She will get a good rest anyway and a happy though quiet time.</p>
<p>Our cannas <sic>ar</sic> 8 inches tall - We've had 4 tea roses so far and there are hundreds</p>
125
3
<p>of blooms on the red ramber, the Paul scarlet and Van Fleet. Also our second Wisteria is blooming, the mockarange is so sweetly fragrant and the Hollyhocks are already budded!</p>
<p>Lots and lots of fruit this year. Our plum and cherry are loaded as well as the Mulberry with health, green fruit. Our nasturtiums are up and strong looking as well as our poppies. These have to be thinned.</p>
<p>Miss Brehwer the Dean of Women who has built the new houses on Dr Mitchels place called here yesterday and we had a wonderful visit</p>
126
4
<p>with her - She is a fine and interesting lady and we will enjoy her a lot form now on.</p>
<p>Hilda and Max made tea for us and she was so interested in all the things Daddy has made etc. She wants very much to write a novel of student life in a small college - and talked in a very intelligent way about it to Daddy.</p>
<p>I am so very happy over the way I am getting Daddy's bust and wish you and Ollie could see it. I am getting down to the <underline>skin</underline> now and I know it is good - Better late than never! I'll send you a pic</p>
127
5
<p>time of it if you wish to love it.</p>
<p>Our Radio is playing so beautifully at last again - all it needed was one new tube!</p>
<p>We got a Post today and read Lindberghs wonderful talk - Oh how fearlessly he tells the truth and how we do admire and respect him!</p>
<p>So long, dear children, and continue to be good and fine and loveing you'll never regret the sacrifices you must make! Endless love to my girlie and her wee one and to</p>
128
<p>my dear good Ollie - son</p>
from your devoted
Mama - Mother
<p>Monday:
Today the two fine shrubs came, and Daddy adn I are seeking them  in water with you "tablet" added - </p>
<p>We decided to plant the two shrubs in the deep soil in front, South of the big pear tree which is visible from the front gate. This is in the Sune and in deep soil as well and will add a lot to the beauty of the grounds. I am <underline>so</underline> very happy over them!</p>
your grateful
Mama - Mother.


