<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
26 Thompson Collection 64
Tuesday
June 10th 1942
Darling Alice:
<p>I am so grateful that Mons. George sees you right. I always thought of you as a dancing doll - <underline>That is</underline> your role - and the fact that your leader wants you to be the doll in the Debussay number shows me that he sees you right. You <underline>will</underline> succeed as a doll - and I wouldn't be surprised at <underline>any</underline> <sic>ammount</sic> of success you might achieve as such. Of course we pray for you - every breath is a prayer for you my baby girl!</p>
<p>You  are right in feeling happy and <underline>very</underline> fortunate too. The shorts are down in Branson but will be sent you from there at once. We are expecting Amama this week end, and will drive down then. She says she longs for the quiet there - and thinks Daddy and I can do her more good than any one else now. Is that not wonderful? It makes <underline>me very</underline> happy. She speaks of having one "torturing obsession" and I can well guess at what that might be - and am eager to help her over it. Is it not fine that our Home can do her some <underline>real</underline> good? She is strong physically and will not mind the stairs she says. She will have the back room with the porch.</p>
<p>I have finished Nei's little portrait</p>
65
2
<p><unclear/> - It <underline>is dear</underline>!</p>
<p>Am making Hilda a lovely blue and white dress now. Wish I could make you one too. The Harrisons are <underline>so</underline> interested in what you are doing! We gave Sue the stump baby (that was <underline>yours</underline>!) for a graduation present - and I have <strike>yours</strike> a new one for you ready to paint. She's crazy about it! --</p>
<p>Alice, could you maybe find out the address of the "<underline>Original Art Co</underline>" in <underline>Chicago</underline> for me? I think the stump baby is the sort of piece they might buy.</p>
<p>Ollie and Enid are so very dear and good to us and we have been most happy with them. Nei would be terribly thrilled if he knew he had <underline>your</underline> name! Gaki takes him down to the wee lily pool in the yard here under the Willow tree, and he splashes his little feet in the water and shouts with glee, just like a big boy going swimming! Yesterday he said his girst real word it was Enid's first word too = "Light" Is this not remarkable? He sort of drawls it out - and leave off the t - but says it very plainly.</p>
<p>Your letters are very interesting, and I often read them 3 or 4 times. I see no</p>
66
3
<p>reason why you could not start paying Madame Cassan as you said, $10 at a time. She wrote me that she feared this Summer would be a most difficult one for her as she had to have a "serious operation" right after recital. This was said in confidence so dont' mention it please. I should think $25 per month would be a good way too. - That might be a bit easier for you, and would be the equivalent of a pupil for her, not? Alice you mention paying a lawyer in your last, and I cannot understand that - Am I asking about something I should not, when I inquire about your having to pay a lawyer? What for? I wonder. Oh how I wish I had some money <underline>now</underline>. How I'd love to help you to be free from debt! I want daddy to get a good position yet so that he can pay Hilda back, and you too for your training.</p>
<p>It is so wonderful though that you can begin to earn already. It makes me so very very happy. "Dites Madame Carson bien des.</p>
67
4
<p><unclear/>"! How sweet of her to take such a helpful interest in all of you girls. Please tell me Alice if you are still thinking of getting together with Ruth Pryor - or has your connection with Mon. George changed this?</p>
<p>Ollie thinks Phil Baker may be an important man in the Show World, he seems to have heard of him in the Radio World. It is nice Mrs Baker called you. Mrs Stoker is very sweet but yet "a phantom Xmas Tree!"</p>
<p>I am so glad you hair is henna tint - you have the skin that goes with it. <underline>Do tell</underline> me if you are Keeping your eyebrows black and if you are having curls or bangs down on your forehead or not.</p>
<p>We here are all well; Hilda is progressing <underline>very</underline> rapidly with her Piano playing. Sig is really teaching her now, and she is really working. This is most important for her at her present stage of growth. A <underline>real</underline> singer msut be master of some instrument. In three months she should play her own accompaniments, if she continues as she now is doing. This is far mroe important <sic>fo</sic> her now.</p>
68
5
<p>than going to Chicago - <underline>After</underline> she is a good Pianist <underline>then</underline> she <underline>should</underline> go, but not before. This is the way I see it, and I know I'm right. Maxie promised me she'd quit working the last of June. The little girls need a mother's care all day - and it makes me simply sick to see how they run wild. No mother has the right to put her children over on <underline>any</underline>one else.- I go in only on Hilda's lesson days now. Joan started a letter to you with my help but I do not Know if anyone will help her get it off to you. Poor little girl - she is so much nicer when she is with Nanny!-</p>
<p>Enid and Ollie are going in to have dinner with the folks on Bartmer tonight, and Gaki and Nanny are taking care of the sweetest baby boy that ever was!</p>
<p>Alicia Nye is a good name - May she be happy and famous - and never quit loving her devoted.</p>
Mama.