<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
205A-205B Fink Collection 85
ANDREW JACKSON
HOTEL 
ROCK HILL, S.C.
ROCK HILL
MAR 1
6 PM
1940 
S.C.
Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
86
I.W. COYLE, LESSEE &amp; MGR.             MODERN                           FIREPROOF
ANDREW JACKSON HOTEL
ROCK HILL, S.C.
Friday Noon, March 1, '40.
Dear Enot Peanut:
<p>It was bully to find a letter from you here!</p>
<p>Naturally I'm tickled to hear of Oddie's portrait of Gaki. I'll bet he makes a good one. Yes, I too believe he could do things in that line. He's that sort.</p>
<p>If I can't pick up some rougth amethyst for those earrings, I knwo how to make them of stones that I already have. May set small deep-colored ones in larger and <unclear/> - colored stones.</p>
<p>On the way home we'll spend a day where they mine ruby &amp; sapphire (along with commercial corundum for abrasice purposes). I may get a chunk to cut - or some smaller chunks. I'm getting good with</p>
87
<p>stone cutting, adn am growing more eager for fine stuff to work on. It's a good thing I've had to work on rock crystal first. So many little &amp; very vital things to learn about difficulties and dangers to the work.</p>
<p>Spring here - grass a rich emerald green. We love western Virginia, but not this section of S. Carolina, which is <underline>much</underline> lower and monotonous in landscape. Virginia is very lovely. Southerners up there (and down here too) are folksy &amp; kindly - like to talk.</p>
Endless love to you adn old Oddie,
Dad.
88
I.W. COYLE, LESSEE &amp; MGR.             MODERN                           FIREPROOF
ANDREW JACKSON HOTEL
ROCK HILL, S.C.
Friday Noon, March 1, '40.
Dear Old lady Alice:
<p>Mama sent me your recent letter, and I'm very happy over what you tell about your progress adn what Madame thinks about it. I've had the utmost faith in you right along, and am not surprised. <underline>I do believe in you.</underline></p>
<p>Mama said she would send you money, so I'll not enclose an, as I'l planned to do.</p>
<p>We found Virginia a charming country. It would be a lovely place to live - right altitude in the west and very beautiful. Also, near to important points of the East.</p>
<p>We say the old Hiddenite mine which has lain idle 15 years.</p>
(over)
89
<p>Emeralds were found there too - one weighing 2 (1/2) oz!! It's in Smithsonian Institute. On the way home we'll spend a day in the ruby and sapphire country. May get a piece to cut - who knows?</p>
Endless love, precious Alice!
Dad