<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Branson, Mo. 
57
Omaha Pub. Lib November, 1938 
My dear Mr and Mrs Hohn:
Last night I read your work on my husband and I want to extend my most sincere thanks and appreciation to you. 
It might be called a coin-cidence, but I believe it was more than that, that just prior to my husband latest visit to Nebraska with Sigurd I had felt the strong urge to begin a biographical sketch of him in order to facilitate the efforts of his future bio-

2
pher, unknown as yet to me. 58
Now that I have read your bulletin - I am eager to assist you, and so I am sending you what I have so far put down, and it will explain itself. I want you to use any or all of it just as you wish - and then kindly return it to me. You see that I am approaching "Nei-hardt" in a different way. You can- not over emphasize the importance of the so called fever dream when he was twelve. I am continuing to get data down - and so will conti-nue sending it to you if you wish, anyway the Nebraska part.- 
Please put in some 

3
59
where that our last baby, "Alice" was named for John's mother, in appre-ciation of her faithful love for her son and his family. She adored her son and chose to follow him to Mo. when we left Nebraska, rather than to remain there alone, or to go to either one of her daughters. She lived beside us in a charming home of her own till her death, and we feel that she is still with us. The climax of her life undoubtedly was her presence at the erection of the monument to Neihardt in Wayne, and her unveiling of his painting in the Omaha Public Library. Her satisfaction is that "The Poet's Song shall live for her long, dumb, aching years of prose."- You have 

4
60
<unclear/> Sigurd for something about me, and I hope you do not misinterpret his silence. He has not known just what you wanted to know, thinking you meant data about Mona Martinsen as well. But now that we have your bulletin in which I feel you say plenty as it stands, it will be easy for him to answer, and I know he will. If you should want any thing from our girls - they will be glad to give you their angles as well: Mrs Enid Fink, 9716 Hawthorne Ave. Overland, St. Louis County, Mo. 
Miss Hilda Neihardt, Consulate of Switzerland. 
Ambassador Bldg. 
St. Louis, 
Mo. 

5
61
and Miss Alice Neihardt, 5540 Gates Ave, St Louis, Mo., these are our children's addresses, and all would be thrilled to hear from you. .
Personally I think you hit the nail on the head when you said that John's dedication of the Messiah is the finest tribute I could have dream ed of receiving - and little or nothing else need be said about me. 
Hoping I am helping you in your great work, I am 
most sincerely yours 
Mona Neihardt. 

62
P.S. I have just read this to my husband, and he says it is good and wants me to repeat that what I say of his mother is very impor-tant and should go in. 
S. N. 
Anna Lu. Sailor Bay 
gone readings - Brocke & epoches 
Davis. 
Square Dance 
S. S. in neighbor's house. Old man <unclear/> - <unclear/> daughter, Weekly prayer meeting. 
<unclear/> Jully at Mills this north - New Mill old man Higglemaster Daid in Mill. 
Went anyways <unclear/> Wagon load E of Stories. Women charges Jens edes play - Fox and Grove, Pullewen the <unclear/> 