<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
33
[Journey 24, 1931]
Sat. morning
Dearest Enid.-
Your note and order reached one yesterday & dear girl I did so wish for a little letter, just "heres your money," is not very loving altho you meant all right, I know of course it is only a duty to Daddy and must be rather irksome, but dear girl you are one 
course all you children - when I came home they gave me the loveliest big bunch of roses - thea yesterday I was in bed most of the day. but this morning I feel much better and think I will plan now to leave here the 30th of Jan. for <unclear/> Lulu's - That will be a week from last night at Midnight. I usually get your letters Friday morning. I have wondered so much how you are getting on with your budget plan 

34
the dearest girls I know and I get real homesick for you - I have been sick Enid dear the last week and some times I wonder if I should risk going to Auntie Lulu's 
It just seems as tho Everything shoudl come at once. May Enter-tained for me last Wednesday and I got out of bed to go then Thursday Evening I was entertained at a six o clock dinner by the Poetry Club <del/> at the college I felt a little better but was in bed the most of the afternoon - they came for me and that brot me back It was awfully hard to act as tho I was well and yet could not tlel them I was sick. The dinner passed all right Everything lovely and they were all so nice to me, asked "so many questions about. Daddy and Mama and of 

35
2
tell one about the P.T. a play. I had a letter from Mrs. Sweeney this week she had written it just before the play. had a letter too from Mrs. Garner a few days ago. Glad you have a horse. Do you ride much?. Are you planning on going North with daddy - I hope so. Write Enid and tell me a lot of things I will write to Mama many thanks garlic all for the order tell Daddy and mama thanks too. 
love to you my dearest big granddaughter from Grandma. 

36
GRINNELL JAN 24 1230PM 1931 IOWA 
a soon in de Daddy 
Miss Enid G. Neihardt
Branson
Mo. 
1234 West St
Grinnell 
Iowa. 