<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
24 Neihardt Collection 
July 3 
111
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON JUL 5 7-AM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Dr John G. Neihardt 
5544 Pershing Ave 
301 Ilene Apts. 
St. Louis, 
Mo. 

July 3rd 36
My own Darling
112
You can't know how thrilling hta tsounds about your writing Jed Smith on wheels with me to enjoy you, your writing and the nice little place ot take care of when not resting. <del>not</del> If we coudl just see the children settled happily you and I would have little trouble being happy together yet we coudl not htink of being without any me of our four darling children - so complex is Life - John do you know I have thought so much of that first baby we lost who looked so much like you and I've had the distinct feeling that we should have been thinking of him more constructively and loving him Oh so much 

2
113
because of the accident that stop ped his growth in this world. Oh God what a terrible thing that was - and how can I ever make it right? Of course I cannot. But i feel I shoudl not try to forget but rather feel and think of him as an enti-ly that <del>will</del> has developed in spite of the handicap I placed upon him - so unintention ally. Please tell me what you think about this. 
Darling, don't you think we should really try hard to sell here, and then we will have means with which to meet all the changes that are likely to come our way be fore long. You remember the medium telling me there would suddenly be 2 daughters who would get married? 

3
114
one right after the other? Well I feel like we are approach ing that time in a year or so - Then we would have only Alice who would fit in either with you and me or with one of her sisters - Now that you speak of the far West calling you I think we should keep your house on wheels in mind and get rid of this place first so that we do not feel (or I do not feel) that weight and responsibility towards the place. What do you think? Darling I believe we can sell if we go after it - In the mean while I am 

4
115
getting better but Oh! My & wol=len foot - which improves al-most imperceptibly and to walk is not thinkable at all. I have to keep that foot up or it aches and fills up like an old sausage - turn ing ed and blue. However eating as well as I do even though I cannot use my legs they must of necessity grow stronger, not? I have no power in them at all they might be tooth picks for all I'm concerned. It makes me so restless - I can - not sleep properly I am awake hours and hours and cannot feel peaceful no matter how hard I try. - There now I've been a selfish baby once again - 

5
116
Please understand - 
Darling send us an other rain, we need it! but Oh how wonderful the last me was! 
Darling another hting on my mind or is it in my heart? is this: When Hilda goes to Lincoln this Fall can the not take Harp lessons? She sings about her work just as I used ot do only much much more perfectly and so much sweet ness in it you would love to hear it. She longs for some thing of she sort but says that will never be just us she feared her teeth would never be 

6
117 
straightened. She said she Mamma just think! I'd never be bored if I could accom pany my self on the Harp! It would take a relative by short time to learn the Harp. and if Hilda were to be single she could with her languages sing songs from various countries and make a real hit - and if she mar-ries she will have so much so enrich her Home life.- Please think about this darling along with any thinking you may have the time to do in my direction. Tell me what you think? 
Loads of Love from Mona. 