<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
253 Fink Collection 35
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo
BRANSON
JAN14
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs O. F Fink
9917 Emerson
Overland,
St Louis 
Mo.
<gap = "cutoff"/>
36
Tuesday
Darling Girlie:
<p>We were wishing for news from you when your dear letter came telling us about things - you can never tell us too much about yourself.</p>
<p>You must have the same weather as we down here. It has been Spring and we have even let the furnace go out at night! Now it is cloudy and raining a bit.</p>
<p>We cannot sell as many books as Daddy thought, so will not have as much cash as we hoped but we will have about $300 anyway. If we could just sell this soon! and buy up nearer you! There is a big town springing up around Waynesville because of an army camp. If we could buy a farm near there it might be sensible - and not far from St Louis. Eventually we simply <underline>must</underline> all live together on one producing place each family in its own house, yet p<unclear/></p>
37
<p>ing our interests in one Neihardt Fink camp. Just think how wonderful to visit each other and do things together - yet have our own privacy! Some how we must beat this crazy scheme that makes slaves of our men to <underline>no</underline> purpose but playing into the greedy hands of Pulitzers and Baldwins and the like!</p>
<p>You are experiencing the blessings of life as they <underline>should</underline> be Enid darling and I am so happy and grateful!</p>
<p>I cannot send things to Overland without extra charges so I am brining plenty of bedding so that we can put a pair of blankets under us - Your mattress, the hard one is the Kind Daddy and I like best and I Know we will be warm and comfy on it in your Sun room. We love to sleep in the cold upstairs here - and you can Keep the Sun room closed off and unheated most of the time as far as <underline>we</underline> are concerned. Also please do not give us your dresser - as we need only one drawer in <underline>your</underline> place, and about 3 hangers in yours and Ollies clothes closet for all we will bring. Enid please tell me if I left my rose dress in your closet?</p>
<p>The bust is swell, Daddy finished the difficult part of Jed this morning.</p>
Endless love
Mama.Mother
