<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
8
<figure/> 
CONRAD H. MANN, CHAIRMAN OF BOARD
SAMUEL J. WHITMORE, EXECUTIVE VICE PRES. 
BARNEY L. ALLIS, PRESIDENT & GENL MGR
8
Hotel Muchlebach 
BALTIMORE AVENUE 
AND TWELFTH STREET 
Kansas City, Mo. 
Monday Noon 
Oct. 10, 1938 
Precious Mona: 
I arrived at 10 P.M. Rather dull job, riding that train, and it was "air-conditioned," which made it worse. There was a dear little girl of Joan's age in front of me, and her Mama couldn't make her go to sleep, so the little girl and I flirted across the back of the seat. She even held my hand! 
I've gotten in touch with the secretary of the Pres. at the University, and I'm free to give whatever I please, thank heaven! Maybe I shall not have to talk about "Contemporary Poetry" after all!! I've wired Mueller in K.C. Kansas. the President Hotel is in K.C. Mo., only 3 blocks from the Melbrock. 
<del/> 

    <figure/> 
    CONRAD H. MANN, CHAIRMAN OF BOARD
    SAMUEL J. WHITMORE, EXECUTIVE VICE PRES. 
    BARNEY L. ALLIS, PRESIDENT & GENL MGR
  9
    Hotel Muchlebach 
    BALTIMORE AVENUE 
    AND TWELFTH STREET 
    Kansas City, Mo. 
-2-
There are several conventions here, and the hotels are jammed. They tried to put me into a swell corner of artiment at $6.50, but when I <unclear/>, they remembered just one room without both on 7th floor. It's nice, and ^anyway I'm so clean that everybody says, "Where are those violets?" When I pass, you see, I had a bath once. 
I've been out after pawn shops. Pitiful stuff! Not <del/> to be compared with St. Louis Golly, they tried to sell me a "ruby' "bigger thana  grain of corn, and two "sapphires" (genuine) that would have been worth $500 each, if only!! 

    <figure/> 
    CONRAD H. MANN, CHAIRMAN OF BOARD
    SAMUEL J. WHITMORE, EXECUTIVE VICE PRES. 
    BARNEY L. ALLIS, PRESIDENT & GENL MGR
   10
    Hotel Muchlebach 
    BALTIMORE AVENUE 
    AND TWELFTH STREET 
    Kansas City, Mo. 
-3-
It occurred to me last night that I neglected to qualify my enthusiasm for the author of "Out of Africa". There are several generalyzations I noticed, in skimming, that will not bear examination, altho' there is a valuable suggestion in each. The author is not remarkable for intellect, which, after all, is not of greatest importance; but for the warm richness and fine temper of her personality.. I sewed this, she is a veritable ruby of a person. 
I came to the musklebach, rather than the President, because I thought you might need to wire me about some letter. 

    <figure/> 
    CONRAD H. MANN, CHAIRMAN OF BOARD
    SAMUEL J. WHITMORE, EXECUTIVE VICE PRES. 
    BARNEY L. ALLIS, PRESIDENT & GENL MGR
  11
    Hotel Muchlebach 
    BALTIMORE AVENUE 
    AND TWELFTH STREET 
    Kansas City, Mo.
-4-
I worry about 'Laime and her appetite. Do cox the child to take a little nourishment the pretty little girl in front of me was for from being a match for Joan. 
Nothing to say, really, but that I love you all, and that is not news. 
Jno. 
Dad. 
Don't fight, girls!  