<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
116 Fink Collection 90
Tuesday
March 5, 1940
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>First I want to explain about the $5.00 <sic>checque</sic> being returned. We <underline>were</underline> overdrawn and Mr Eiserman told Max when she went in to deposit more money (which was right after Daddy's first appearance in Virginia) that they had made a charge for covering that $5.00 <sic>checque</sic> to Alice of 25 cents - so we thought everything was O.K. - But it seems that little "snip" (as Max calls him) King was officious and very business like and muddled it all up. Now tomorrow Max will show them what you sent</p>
91
2
<p>us - and I trust that will teach the young man a lesson about butting in! We don't Know how the overdraft happened - but I Know it will not happen again. I enclose the $5.00 for Ollie here with - and thanks a lot for helping out. Please do not fear <underline>this</underline> <sic>checque</sic> is bad, there are funds there now for sure - and please do not hesitate to tell us the truth about any and all situations - <underline>ever</underline>!</p>
<p>Endi I'm so grateful for your interest in my figure - I think your idea a good one - but <underline>I</underline> am <underline>not</underline> pushing this at all. Sparky and the Junior League are doing it. I'm going to make the model as soon as I have my present pottery piece</p>
92
3
<p>finished - and it is almost ready to cast now. It is truly a beautiful thing - It is a decorative piece or a fruit-bowl. You children are going to have a copy of it for your Home - and I am so glad you are at last determined to <underline>buy</underline>. Enid <underline>Home</underline> is the sweetest thing a person can posess - and it does not matter <underline>where</underline> it is. Some people always want to be somewhere else - and some people want to beautify <underline>one</underline> spot for always. You have a man who is satisfied to be wherever <underline>you</underline> make home - It is all in your hands therefore.  I believe you could not have a</p>
93
4
<p>sweeter place than the one you are now in - <underline>any</underline> where. And remember that you have my promise of a fountain figure for your pool, providing I am able to please Ollie and you, and providing I am still young when you need it!</p>
<p>I had a small garden spot ploughed this afternoon, and all our trash carried off - I have planted a lot of flower seeds outdoors as well as in.</p>
<p>I am so pleased over your Knitting - Max now is crocheting. She washed yesterday and I hung the clothes out as it was cold. Today I ironed. Am going to</p>
94
5
<p><unclear/> a nightgown for Max who has been sleeping in a white shirt of <strike>Dad</strike> the girls and her <strike/> sport-pants for want of a nightgown! and next a pair of Pajamas for each Wub. I got enough white outing flannel to do these things yesterday. The day before I made a pair of curtains for our door between the front room and the dining room. I used that lovely piece of cretonne you got at Parnell's for me when you were here, for the front room side and blue and white cretonne for the dining room side - The effect is simply lovely! Then I covered Grandmas' big old arm chair with the same blue cretonne, it looks good enough to eat! I am so interested in</p>
95
6
<p>every thing you tell me about your home, so please always tell me every little thing.</p>
<p>Please tell Alice to write and thank aunt Lu for the quilt; Do you like it? She asked me if I wanted her to send it and I said I was delighted to have it for <underline>Alice</underline> as <underline>she</underline> was closest of all our children to her Grandmother. I am <underline>so</underline> glad she has done it and mean while tell <strike>her</strike> Alice to use it where it looks pretty in your Home - unless you'd rather not.</p>
<p>Marie, who is not at Rolla is supposed to send you the baby basket that was bought</p>
96
7
<p>for you, the first little Stranger at the Gate. Since then, Sigurd, Hilda, Alice, have used it, and then Joan, Elaine, and Paul - so you see there have been <strike>8</strike> 7 in all who have used it. Paul is so very large that already he has outgrown it. <underline>You</underline> will, I hope use it for your whole family no matter how many - and then have it to hand down to your grandchildren!! Things that we <underline>love</underline> are almost human and they outline many generations because of that love!</p>
<p>I had a ride to Ozark and back with Mrs. Dawes the other morning. She is <underline>so</underline> fine!</p>
<p>Tomorrow morning we'll plant peas. I am going to try to raise Holly</p>
97
8
<p>hocks in the house. transplanting them after they have 4 leaves - I sent for a very special Kind that are new to me. We'll see! Nearly all our Canna bulbs rotted in our cellar. I'm <underline>so</underline> disgusted. Next time I'll Keep them in a dark closet.</p>
Loads of Love to you both dear children from
Mama
Mother
<p>I'm looking for a letter from Alice!!</p>