<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
95
Hope you are well! 
I must say that I am healthy as can be! 
Love, Sig. 
July 24th '32, 
North Platte Neb. 
12:45 P.M. 
Sunday! 
My sweet girl,
When we arrived in Alliance the mail was all in favor of me - & from my dear girl! I was so happy & felt so fine after that letter! 
I am more & more convinced of what a fine girl you are, sweetheart! 
Looking forward to being with you again is a great great pleasure, & is also the source of my happiness! I am anxious to tell you of all the experiences & happenings on this trip! At present I am in a lovely little tourist cabin-just thru with a bachelor meal & must clean up dishes etc. 
Nothing to do all afternoon, so I can take my time to this letter! 
In the morning I am ex-pecting to receive letters 

of introduction to influence men in this city from Dad's friends in Omaha! Hope they have "cooked up" something that will in the near future be of value to getting me back into aviation, & in this beautiful North Platte Valley country!
Can't tell - it may be the beginning of something! By the way - I played beautifully at Chadron Normal school & on a 10'-Steinway concert grand! No radio broadcasts are possible, as Kearney neb. is our last stunt - & already arranged! I have been thinking of you all of the time - you dear girl! Certainly you are the sweetest person to think about! To be with you is the best tho'! 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER

96
-2-
It won't be long 'til we will again be together! I've had some terrible spells of sadness over it all, but I feel much better when I think of how true & honest you are with me! 
I know that the love we have for eachother makes it a sure thing, & that distance doesn't have any effect on us as far as forgetting eachother is concerned! We can't do that sweetheart, becuase our tho'ts are the same! I was just wondering last nite what you would think if you knew "we" were lost in the sand hills,- roads goin' every direction & of course we didn't follow the right one! Several times at nite while driving along & looking

at the big dipper (& the moon) I would wonder as to whether or not my sweetheart should just happen to be looking at it too! 
Ha! Couldn't see 'ya anyway if you were lookin' at the moon, could I? I bet-U-not! The reason I ahve been gasing at the sky instead of the surrounding country is because I knew that if you were outside-it woudl be the only place we could both look & be seeing the "same" things! Well so much for that! Yee! I've a bright chile, eh? 
I believe we'll arrive in Branson Thurs. evening! I love you, you blessed girl, & never in the world could I do anything but care more & more for you!! You know it's true sweetheart! 
Always I love you,
Your Sig. 
P.S. Glad you have enjoyed the conference! 
I'll be seein' you by Friday I think son. 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 

97
SPECIAL DELIVERY! 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> FRANKLIN 1CEN
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 
