<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
46
Missouri collection
Tuesday Feb 26 <unclear/>.
Dear Ones:-
Had a nice trip up from Los Angeles. Saw the ocean for 100 miles. Got here 2 hours late - at midnight. The folks weren't expecting me until Monday so I took a street car within two blocks of the house & found the place without difficulty they were all snoozing, but I roused them out. They are all very sweet <unclear/> enid, & it feels nearly homelike to me Last evening I went to dinner at Jordan's. Swell home & John wants mrs. J. is a society queen sort of woman very gracious, of course. after dinner they took me out to hear Yvette Gurlbert. Yvette is a <unclear/> cady with a so-so voice & a fetching manner.

47
-2-
She can scarcely speak English intelligibly. It is april here & things are green yesterday uncle Eph got a taxi to take us for a 50 mile drive up into the Santa Cruz range. Had a fine time. Wasn't it fine of him? Grandma & Aunt Minnie went along such a country: It's Cooked like Maxfield Parrish in many places I was so glad to get your letters yesterday. Also, the package, which I have not yet opened. What a party that you must have devilish winter, while I am in mid-april. I hope you will wake the best possible use of Lawrence. 

48
-3
You must remember that it's hard to write intelligent letters when one is <del/> sort of "up in the air" as I am, naturally I feel uneasy not unhappy, at all; but just uneasy. I'll be glad when I'm through here. I don't care for visiting & I don't care much for public stunts. It's neither here nor there except as advertising nothing counts but being with one's own & working steadily in one direction. I read at the Little Theatre (Stanford) at 7:30 <unclear/>, & left the English club tomorrow night Hope my throat won't fail us. It hasn't been right since Lawrence.  

49
-4-
And yet, it may be <unclear/> fire of hope. I've been using a <unclear/> & a rose spray-
Tell the Wubs Papa thinks much about them & loves them. Take care of yourselves.
Lovingly,
Jno 