<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
31
41 Piper Collection:
Box 255 
Branson 
mo 
BRANSON OCT29 11-PM 1928 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 2CENTS2
Miss Mildred Piper 
Wayne State Normal 
Wayne 
Nebraska 

32 
Branson Mo. 
Oct 28 - 1927
My Dear girl- 
I need not apologize to you for my neglect of your letters is no new thing. - But I can say I'm sorry and ashamed,-When your letters with its good news of the new building came I was overjoyed and that it is to be Neihardt Hall just fills me full-your invitation to me to be there iwth you is surely very tempting - and if I went on any invitation it should be yours But coming in the coldest of Nebr. weather and in lieu of the fact that I am not so young any more and not as strong as I might wish I were - will have to just say thank you dear for the kind invitation-In a letter a few days ago from <unclear/> 

33
-said he thot he would be there at the Dedication-I do hope he can-then I want you to be real nice to him-you maybe don't know how much you are to all of us-
Dear girl there comes a time in us our lives when if given time we plan a little on the disposition of our little belongings-you know dear, none of my possessions are worth much but the books of John's that he has given to me as they were published-and these because I prize them. I am going to give to you in dire time.- knowing they could fall in no friendlier hands. Than yours, they are all autographed - and I shall write on a card to be placed in one <del/> my name to make sure to all who maybe concerned the authenticity 

34
2
of the gift.- 
I do hope you will have your little car next summer and will plan a trip there the Ozarks with my home the objective.- 
I had a lot of company last summer - my children were all home. - Grace came the 31st of May and stayed three weeks - John drove down from St. Louis her third week and we all had a nice visit - they they left Hilda and Alice who stayed until John returned the first of August-or rather Mona and Enid and Sigurd drove here and John went to the Penn. State University Pennsylvania, for a week of lectures 12 in six day 80 minutes each - at the end of the time he came on here and spent the rest of his vacation with the family - then they all returned taking the little girls 

35
<unclear/> them - they had been gone three days when Lulu and Donald <unclear/>, drove in and surprised me they were here one week and when Lulu had been gone two days Miss Tregs came for a couple days The 10th of July my Bro. from Lincoln and his wife came for a week and later his manual training teacher and family came for just one day. - now I am expecting Mona's mother - She I hope will be here some time - so you see dear girl I have been busy and very tired part of the time. - my yard has been so beautiful this summer - is really the show place of Branson - How I do love my little home - you can guess it tho by the way I stick to it and stay here alone much to the disgust of 

36
of all the children - Lulu was so sure she was going to take me bag and baggage when she returned but I said no. - Lulu has a boy, her oldest, in the Minnesota Un: Entered this fall we are terribly set up. He is a very bright boy, the younger is in his second year high and is doing so well, Enid graduates this year from the Kirkwood High School, and is carrying a stenography course at the same time.-Sigurd is making grad in school and is doing wonderfully in music. How I wish Sigurd could go with Daddy when he goes to Wayne, He played for good things in St. Louis, is accompanying a fine St. Louis Soprana for her Entertainments Hilda is Daddy's girl-has his 

37
<unclear/> of mind - reads all the time and school is so easy for her alive has been in school but one year-reads "regular books" and writes the dearest letters to me, school is easy for her to.-I wish you could see Enid and Sigurd, now I meant to write Alice & Hilda swim.-Alice dives into water deep enough for John and swims out under water.-Hilda is a little fish too and it is lots of fun watching them - Mona is sculping - Has a group of five - John; Enid, Sigurd, Alice & Hilda ready. to Exhibit for the St Louis art Guild I have not seen them, Mona made a bust of Alice for me last christmas the dearest little thing, I had such a good time with the little girls last Summer they both cried when they had to go back and are already planning for next summer, now. dear I could "go on for Ever" but you no doubt have been hired before now - So will close with loads of love to you dear Miss Pipes - Alice M. Neihardt 
