<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
98
53 Piper Collection 
BRANSON SEP12 4-PM 1932 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1CENT1 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1CENT1 UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 1CENT1
Miss Mildred Piper 
Wayne State Normal 
Wayne Nebr. 

99
Wish you could see my Pool & Rock garden I am most awfully "proud of them, except the pool I did the rest myself and I helped on the pool - In the pool I have Lilli's and water Hyacinths water poppies parrots Leather and coon Tail - the <del/> blooms are lowly - I started with 8 gold fish but now, as Alice says the pool is busy with baby's fish, in the garden across the End's and the hack is my garden very colorful a number of different kinds of flowers the front and running down into the water is sudan a regular rock creeper back of the pool I have Carmas lessons a big as my head back of them are blue morning glories - wonderful i wish you could see them and that I coudl see you loads of lvoe dear girl - form Alice M. Neihardt

My Dear Girl - 
The vacation is gone and you have not been here, when I recieved your letter, saying you might come down for a short time, I look and hope but no Miss Piper and no letter - I was and am disappointed - now an other long year full of duties that will keep you before you can <unclear/> think about, and I may not be here, Do you know <unclear/> which I will be the coming winter makes one feel as tho they were right on the <unclear/> and but little time to bank on, well be that as it 
do you hear from Miss Fish? 

100
may - If we do meet again or if we don't you wil always know how I have loved you, there are so many think I want to tell you but they will all be about us and you know that I know little else.
I enjoy so much to hear the folks tell, when they come from Wayne, all about all you dear people and especially about you which they never tell enough, John says Miss Piper looks just the same, but I would like to see for my self. 
Every body is busy around here, John is writing "The Messiah" The fourth Epic, Mona is finishing a bust of John, the little girls, I say little girls Hilda is tall as her mother and Alice almost as tall as Grandma which is nothing to speak of, well I said the little girls are so thru school again <unclear/> Sigurd or Enid have anything permanent yet - Enid wants to go to School and work her way. She woudl make a dandy secretary, writes a good, business letter and ^in short and and typing is <del/> very good.-
There is nothing to tell about myself only that I am busy all the time - Have a rug in the ames all the time, and when I am not busy at something else I work on it I 