<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
J4b.19a.1
Thompson Collection enc. with Mona letter pn
August 3, 1943
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland, Mo.
Mon. p.m.
Dearest Alice:
<p>Many congratulations from us to you on your 22<hi rend="underline">nd</hi> year, and may you have sixty-leven-hundred more, if you can use them, is our wish for you! There is no doubt other people besides you could use you that much! That experience (or, <hi rend="underline">those</hi> experiences, rather!) in Mexico certainly did things for you - not that you weren't A-I before, you understand!</p>
<p>Also, we want to hear mroe about that future possible life in Mexico! The more I think about the whole thing from as many angles as I'm acquainted with in the more excited I get! I've never heard of such a ro-</p>
2
<p>mantic happening as yours, kid and I say you won't read a <hi rend="underline">story</hi>, as far-fetched in almost any romantic novel as this true-story of your own! Boy, <hi rend="underline">would</hi> I grab it!! Ha!</p>
<p>Well, we'll see! It's all your <sic>binness</sic> anyway, isn't it? I told Mom - maybe she'd get to go to Mexico yet to bring another grandchild sometime!!</p>
<p>Little Mona C. isn't here yet, but we expect her the end of the week, if not before then. if it's a boy we'll call it Norman Michael. How do you like that?</p>
<p>Albert was over yesterday to see us. We all had a dandy time chatting. He obviously misses his Hilda. He thinks he'll be an uncle and we tell him he'll be an</p>
J4b.19a.2
3
<p>aunt!!</p>
<p>Hilda, it was dear and <sic>tho'tful</sic> of you to say "sweet somethings" about mty hair. I like it this way too - very much! It's nice &amp; cool too, for a hospital. Will write you soon. Ollie was delighted over his lovely shirt. He's writing you tonite. Would have sooner, only he is a bit upset - like about the new-arrival to be! Wait till you have one. It's a touchy <sic>binness</sic> form beginning to end!!</p>
<p>Keep on a-bathin' in the waves Alice, and Hilda &amp; try to make us feel good too! ha! Boy, it's warm today.</p>
<p>Lots of love to our birthday gal, and lots of love to you, Hilda.</p>
always,
Enid Ollie &amp; Nei
<p><hi rend="underline">P.S.</hi>
Alice, the ankle socks aren't much, but they mean a lot of love from us. Mom put them in with her lovely blouse for you. Hope you can use the socks a bit!!</p>
Love, Enid