<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
46 Sigurd Neihardt Collection
19
Overland, MO.,
Jan. 25, '43
Dear Max &amp; Sig: 
<p>I was very glad for your good letter, Max, and my failure to answer sooner means nothing at all - except, perhaps, that I've been laid up. The good letters from Sig, too, cheered us. It is so good to know that you are in a good job for the duration and that your <hi rend="underline">hands are safe</hi>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">And</hi> the dear letters from the precious young ladies, which we answered!</p>
<p>We do miss them, bless theri hearts!</p>
<p>The Lincoln possibility dangles, &amp; must</p>
-2-
<p>continue to do so, altho' Dr. Wimberly of the University is an the job, evidently working for a state-wide movement to put me in, sooner or later, as Supt. of the State Hist. Society. It's a very big affair, surely. It may work out. In the meanwhile I'm trying everything I can think of - even writing to Dr. Henry S. Canby, Secy of the Institute, in the hope that he may know of a vacany in some magazine or publishing hosue editorial staff.</p>
20
-3-
<p>Sorry you couldn't see Latham; but you will, no doubt, when he returns. They could really do something this year, if they'd really try. I hope they may. I tried to get away from them, and Latham wrote. A sad-ish letter. I could get a publisher easily. but maybe they mean business. The Book-of-the-Month Club or the Literary Guild could change the face of the world for <hi rend="underline">me</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">us</hi>. Lathan swears he will work on them.</p>
-4-
<p>Altho this year is a life-climax for me in ways that matter most in the long run, nevertheless I'm at my lowest ebb in a wordly way. It's quite ridiculous, and while I'm <delete/> troubled, naturally, deep down I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> and am amused. But -</p>
<p>Perhaps you <hi rend="underline">may</hi> be able to get some engagements back there. It's so good of you to try. Maybe the militarization of universities &amp; colleges has not wholly wiped out possibilities.</p>
<p>Love to each of you and all four.</p>
Dad.
<p>The enclosed belongs in your files.</p>