<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Going to Hannibal & look around at different Mark Twain attractions there! S.M. 
Oh! Sho! Excuse mistakes please! SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL 
IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT
WASHINGTON AVE. 
WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT 
A REAL HOTEL 
FOR EVERYONE 
64
<FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. 
HOTEL MARQUETTE 
18TH & WASHINGTON
ST. LOUIS, MO. 
HOTEL ST. CHARLES 
ST. CHARLES, MO. 
ST. CHARLES, MO. Feb. 14th 1932
Dear Maxine,
I'm sittin' here & waiting for Miss Wilhoit to bring me my mail, also Dad's! She promised to do so, but sure has been taking her sweet time about it! 
Mail is important & should be given prompt attention! Oh it is certainly a luxury to ride in this lovely care. It has hydraulic brakes, also hydraulic shock absorbers. There is a lever under the dash (foot operated) for operating the Bijur automatic chassis

JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
I never forget bad things about a place where I once lived! When I drove in to town - it all came back to me! You know how I feel, - hard school days disagreeable in every way & other things too! 
By the way, old dear - I managed to save your gear shift knob! I took it off but don't know where I put it! We must have the same one on this "Auburn Beauty" you know! Ha! It would be too hard to find the balck knob which "auby" has on its shift lever! WEll! So much for all that! Just this minute rec'd your letter, was wonderful to hear 

65
SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL 
IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE. WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT 
A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
<FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. 
HOTEL MARQUETTE 18TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. 
HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
-2-
ST. CHARLES, MO. 193
pressure lubrication! This car is simply full of features which help to make it long - lived! Just imagine, you never have to have this outfit greased, just merely push the lever with your left foot every 500 miles! It feels like riding on a big block of rubber, my dear, no rattles at all! Sorest-ful! 
Such a "Harrison trip" as we'll do next time, eh? 
I am still feeling a little bit ill, but will be O.K. 

SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL 
IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE. WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT 
A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
    <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE 18TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. 
    HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
    -3-
    ST. CHARLES, MO. 193
by time for the playing at Lindenwood College tonite! I'm not quite over the sickspell I had when I left home! This is certainly an ancient town (as you've no doubt hear), the buildings are <unclear/> the oldest style & looks I've ever seen! The old Missouri river is plenty cold looking! Dad said "how about a swim"! I didn't act very anxious to take him up on that! I'm so glad I'm away from St. Louis! I get a gigantic pain when I think of SD. Louis county as a "(w)hole"! 

67
SOUTHEAST MISSOURI'S MOST BEAUTIFUL HOTEL 
IN THE HEART OF THE GREAT WASHINGTON AVE. WHOLESALE & RETAIL DISTRICT 
A REAL HOTEL FOR EVERYONE 
    <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> <FIGURE/> 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE CAPE GIRARDEAU, MO. 
    HOTEL MARQUETTE 18TH & WASHINGTON ST. LOUIS, MO. 
    HOTEL ST. CHARLES ST. CHARLES, MO. 
    -4-
    ST. CHARLES, MO. 193
from you! 
I didn't want you to take my letter as an insulation of anything, in regard to your mother's "watch" over you, or anything of that sort! C? 
I understand you in what you wrote, & am glad you "see the point" anyway! Gotta get cleaned up for another program soon, so I'll close this! 
Wish you as you know! Thanks for wishin' me lucky I do want to play well this time! I feel more 
(over) 

like something now! It was nice of you to get that letter off so promptly! Your letters are the next best thing to seeing you!
Be nice in school now! or "I.J" will get "ferocious"! Ha! Ha! at hime (sez "M.M.") I just can't imagine ever getting this beautiful car home, it doesn't seem natural to drive such a swell car! 
With Love to you, 
as always, 
Sigurd. 
P.S. 
Also "affection" in any desired amount 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER 
With whipped cream on! 
yum, yum!! 
I'm feelin' Gil. 

68 
<figure/> 
HOTEL ST. CHARLES
ST. CHARLES, MO. 
ST. CHARLES, MO FEB 15 930 AM 1932 
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 