<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.3.46-49">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Alice Culler Neihardt, December 30, 1922</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.3.46-49</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Alice Culler Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1922-12-30">December 30, 1922</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Lulu</term>
                    <term>House, Julius T. (Julius Temple)</term>
                    <term>House, Flora M.</term>
                    <term>Brittains</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1922-12-30"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.46-49"/>
                <note type="curatorial">46</note>
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Dec 30 22
                    </dateline> 
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mama:-</salute>
                    
                </opener>
                
                <p>That was most interesting about the clairvoyant and I'm glad you weren't. Did you
                tell us everything she said? If not write it down before you forget. The fact that she knew so much that we know as true makes the rest more than merely interesting.
                I expect Lulu to win. If I were with her awhile, I could tell her how to get the
                most out of herself. She must practice systematic self-suggestion &amp; become
                certain of doing what she plans. There must be no doubt. The best time to do this is
                when she is falling asleep. This is not new thought, &amp; there's nothing spooky about it or sentimental. It's merely discipline for the subconscious mind. I know what it does. The fact that I have driven straight for one marks for many years without any hesitancy. Proves that the system works.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.46-49"/>
                <note type="curatorial">47</note>
                <note type="authorial">-2-</note>
                
                <p>But the nature of the assertion made when falling asleep must never be personal.
                    Emphasize the work always, regarding yourself as something to be thrown away for
                    the task. That is somehow the secret of realizing dreams-to learn how to throw
                    yourself away on something you want to do. Lulu has been away form me so long
                    that she will probably have some difficulty in thinking of me as intensely impersonal in my work, passionately unselfish. Before I won out no one could be expected to see that my sacrifice of anything or anyone, <del/> even my own <del/> momentary offenses and the respect I might have won in lesser ways, was to be seen ultimately as impersonal &amp; in the highest sense <del/> unselfish. In 1913 I began a twenty-year job with no reason to feel sure that</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.46-49"/>
                <note type="curatorial">48</note>
                <note type="authorial">-3-</note>
                
                <p>The public would give me either honor or money for my pairs, because it was regarded impossible to write epics now, much less to get anyone to read them. I hope this doesn't sound priggish or preachy. To me it's only brass tacks.</p> 
                <p>I know Lulu can win. I'm sending a book to her. No one has written we about it before, but I remember now that I forwarded to send it when I was there.</p> 
                <p>We had an 18 hour rain with thunder &amp; lightning an the 27th &amp; 28th, and now we're having another thunder storm. It didn't get cold even tho' the wind got into the north.</p> 
                <p>Your wood is saved a big heap of lechary &amp; ash for the fireplace. I'll order some kitchen wood for you too.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.46-49"/>
                <note type="curatorial">49</note>
                
                <closer>
                    <salute>Lots of love to all</salute>
                    <signed>Jno</signed>
                </closer> 
                <postscript><p>Dr. House urges that you go to Wayne. Says all the women you know
                    were eagerly cooking for you &amp; even had a reception planned. Also he says be
                    &amp; Mrs. H. Want you. Don't worry about Mrs. Brittains stones. She is a sour selfish old woman-always was sour. 
                Jno.</p></postscript> 
                
            </div1>
            

        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>