<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.3.43-45">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Alice Culler Neihardt, December 19, 1922</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.3.43-45</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Alice Culler Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1922-12-19">December 19, 1922</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt-Ballinger, Grace</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Donald</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Jesus Christ</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Minneapolis (Minn.)</term>
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Springfield (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Northfield (Minn.)</term>
                    <term>Nebraska</term>
                    <term>Cincinnati (Ohio)</term>
                    <term>Chicago (Ill.)</term>
                    <term>Kansas City (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>New York</term>
                    <term>Washington</term>
                    <term>Omaha (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1922-12-19"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.43-45"/>
                <note type="curatorial">43</note>
                <note type="curatorial">1922 [1922]</note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Wednesday Noon. Dec. 19. 
                    </dateline> 
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mamma:-</salute>
                    
                </opener>
                
                <p>We received three letters from you today, all from Minneapolis and one of them was intended for Grace. I've sent it on to her. We were tickled to hear from you, and to know that you are safe up there. You must lose no chance to have a good time. If the ten dollars you sent for deposit is not enough for your needs- and make them fairly liberal-let me know, and I can deposit 15 more at any time. Or more, if you want it. It's a shame you missed Wayne. Mona and I are both put out about it. You should have gone by all means, but I understand how one feels on the road when the money is steadily leaking.</p> 
                <p>Hurrah! Branson has the North skinned to a frazzle. No snow here, no really cold weather, no storm of any kind. We got the tail end of your cold wave, but the very lowest it reached was fifteen above zero, and that for only a few hours. We had a couple of days that people here call cold; but you know, it's not real cold. An old hill billy was telling me how terrible it was up at Springfield. He had been there-, probably for the first time in years-nd he had a whopping tale to tell. He said you couldn't stand it out on the street. "Well", he said, "you can tell just how cold it was; the thermometer showed fifteen above". It's warm - rather springy, here today. The grass is green $$$ yet.</p> 
                <p>I do hope Donald can get to Northfield for the evening of Feb. 2. I'd surely love to see him. My stunt is at Carleton College.</p> 
                <p>Things are looking ripping for my trip. I'll have at least ten pledges in Nebraska in a string-maybe 14; then I'll have Bethany College, Carleton, Cincinnati, Chicago, K.C. Art Institute. In May I have three at $100 There three 100 each, cycle Cincinnati</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.43-45"/>
                <note type="curatorial">44</note>
                
                <p>each and more coming. Long is just beginning to work on the May trip. I've just hear that K.C. Institute wants me for the 16th instead of the 23rd. So I've wired to accept Chicago High School Teachers Club for the 10th (the date they wanted) so that I can double back and get home a week earlier without going to New York or Washington. Damn the East. It stinks, and I don't want to go East. West is the only direction for living. Of course, I'd have a big time down there, but I odn't want a big time anywhere. We rejoiced more than you know because you got into the limelight that way at Omaha. It was all perfectly bully. You should have accepted some choice invitations to dine and lunch. That would hav ehelped my affairs. When people know you, they feel eager to be of use. Next time you must accept some choice ones and ditch the others.</p> 
                <p>No doubt you met nearly all the money in Omaha. And money represents the only usable power in certain directions. One doesn't need so much money oneself if one has friends who have lots of it and who will use their influence where directed.</p> 
                <p>Hurrah for the boys and their radio! How fine that they were able to set it up! Bully! No, the station here is not for broadcasting. Have been making fine progress with the "Wars". The chickens make no trouble whatever - none. Why think about them?</p> 
                <p>Lots of love to every one of you there. Your Omaha letter was probably sent to Grace! If so, we'll get it in time. Long did not send enough papers - only one of each. We have not seen the later articles you mention.</p> 
                <closer><signed>Jno </signed></closer>
                <postscript><p>Thursday. warm &amp; sunny today with a gentle breeze form the gulf.
                    Teh wubs &amp; mona are going to write. Sig has already. the ten is deposited. That gives you $35, doens't it?</p></postscript> 
            </div1>
                
                <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.3.43-45"/>
                <note type="curatorial">45</note>
                
                <p>Here is the "piece" Hilda spoke at the church the other $$$$. night. She had toe have something, and it seems that first $$$$ rate poets have written almost nothing about Christmas-everything by awful dubs and always on the Santa Claus stuff, never on the Christ spirit. Of course, Christmas is a Jew lie grafted on a Pagan superstition and utilized for $$$ profit by the merchants. But I thought it woudl be fun to kid the pious Christ-killers of the church, so I wrote this thing for Hilda. No one knows who wrote it. We said it was "anonymous".</p> 
                <l>The Meaning of Christmas</l>
                <l>This holiest of all the nights-</l>
                <l>I wonder what it means:</l> 
                <l>It's surely more than candlelights</l>
                <l>On tinselled evergreens!</l> 
                <l>It's more than toys that make it dear,</l> 
                <l>And eating pleasant things;</l>
                <l>For if you listen right, you'll hear</l> 
                <l>A murmuring of wings.</l>
                <l>My grandma says it's more than fun</l> 
                <l>And hanging up your stocking ;</l>
                <l>It's knowing any needy one</l>
                <l>Might be the savior knocking:</l>
                <l>It's helping those who feel the rod</l> 
                <l>of grief and heavy labors.</l>
                <l>I guess it's being nice to God</l> 
                <l>By loving all your neighbors!</l> 
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>