<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
71 Neihardt Collection
103
[October 19, 1939]
Hotel Rickman
JOHN EHRMAN
MANAGER
Kalamazoo, Mich.
One Block From Union Station
FIRE PROOF
Thursday A.M.
Dear Girl:
<p>We stayed at a cabin camp 9 miles out, and came here this morning. The affair, as you know, is this evening. Had a fine rest in the country - and seriously needed it, having lost much sleep.</p>
<p>The two days at St. Mary's College were wonderful. It is a large, exquistely built &amp; appointed college. Beauty in every detail, and the spirit of Sister Madeleva fills the huge place. There are 450 young women of university age - and are they being <underline>really</underline> educated!! It's something to be truly happy about.</p>
(over)
104
-2-
<p>Sig, as you know, was not scheduled for that affair; but Sister Madeleva (president) arranged for a meeting of all the girls in the vast parlor after lunch yesterday when I was through. They sat on chairs &amp; all over the floor. Sig was tired &amp; felt a bit bum, but after the first piece he got awake, &amp; did a good job. I'm proud of him - and of all the others in different ways, Hiddy, Enot, Alice, you, old Maxie and the babies. You're a dear lot!</p>
<p>I seemed to get over unusually well - 4 affairs two on Poetic Values, one The Messiah, and one an evening with a select group of faculty members from Notre Dame University <underline>and</underline> St. Mary's.</p>
105
Hotel Rickman
JOHN EHRMAN
MANAGER
Kalamazoo, Mich.
One Block From Union Station
FIRE PROOF
-3-
<p>The sisters (some of them dear, <underline>dear</underline> old ladies) were angelic with me., And Sister Madeleva! I don't know how old she may be. She <underline>seems</underline> ageless - intensely warm and human, simple - hearted strong and infinitely kind! Her poetry (well known and published by Macmillan) is exquisite truly. She radiates a quiet power all the time.</p>
<p>At the end of my 4 affairs, when we were leaving, she said: "It seems to us you just came home to us. It has</p>
(over)
106
-4-
<p>been a rare spiritual experience for us for which we cannot pay. Perhaps our prayers will help to pay."</p>
<p>Sig has told Max, I think, that she wants to give our program to a Catholic College at Salt Lake <underline>for a X-mas present</underline>! Pay for it herself!</p>
<p>I've long felt as a result of the few Catholic <unclear/> I've visited, that they truly have what's worth while. They seem to take me in naturally. We talked at meals with two wise old fathers - educated &amp; cultivated to their finger tips, and do they have the right view of the social problem!!</p>
<p>I'd be glad if Max would mail that book, "In the Footsteps of St. Francis", to Sister Madeleva, St. Mary's College, <underline>Holy Cross</underline>,</p>
(over)
107
Hotel Rickman
JOHN EHRMAN
MANAGER
Kalamazoo, Mich.
One Block From Union Station
FIRE PROOF
-5-
<p><underline>Indiana</underline>. She worships St Francis &amp; has a huge collection on him. When I mentioned the fine quality of "The Steps etc" she was much interested, and I want her to have the book.</p>
<p>I've thought a lot about you two old, old ladies working hard there - you in beautifying the house and Max in pushing our business. You're good girls.</p>
<p>Love to you and to the Wubs &amp; Max. Gaki wants to kiss Jaine. Grandan wants to</p>
(over)
108
<p>pet Mrs. Brown.</p>
Jno
Dad.
<p>Yes, I think you should plan to be in St. Louis while I'm at Knox. I'm not sure I'll return that way. It might be cheaper to cut across Iowa. But I'll see.</p>
Jno.

XJ