<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
2
47
1938
Neihardt Collection 
Branson, Sunday after Breakfast
[July 24, 1938]
Dearest Girl: 
I'm not quite awake yet, but I want to write you. 
Something pleasant happened yesterday. It has been very dry here for a good while. (Roark is just rocks) Yesterday at 11 a.m. I went into the pasture and asked for a little thunder and a little lightning, just to show that they were with us yet. At 5:30 P.M. blue-black-clouds come upx There were a few brilliant flashes of lightning and thunder rolled in the West. Then there began a gentle, sweet rain, and it kept on late into the night - no wind, no more thunder. Since we don't know much, there may be everything or nothing in this. But if it is true, it is no more amazing than the abysmal meanness of poor human beings - or the goodness of the relative few. In the <del/> midst of so much that is idiotic, I prefer, and incline, to believe. If such things are not true, then there is nothing at allx
I'm not used to ^being <del/> here yet. but will be soon. Ollie & Enid will look today for a place to camp, & they'll probably stay out a week. 

3
I don't feel at all sure that Bovard will make any sort of protest. For his sake, at least, I wish he couldx As I think the matter over quietly, it seems more preposterous than at first. They have made so many obvious blinders at the P-D during the past year. It is as though an organization had gone insane. There were even better business ways in which to consider the matter of a book page. I wonder if they really know nothing at all about their public. It wouldn't surprise me if I should, get a good break somehow, but I don't bank on it. In a rich world that starves millions upon millions & murders women & children with air bombs, there can be no more reasonable pattern than in a madmen's mind. If I'm helped, it won't be this world I'll have to thank. 
The place is beautiful. The grass grew so well during the rain, that the draught had not yet hurt it too much. It's surprising to hear old Joan practice on the piano. She almost makes up real pieces! 
Endless love to you and the Girls. 
Jno 
D.R 