<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
320 Fink Collection 20
pm. <strike>Feb. 1</strike>, Jan 31 1942
Saturday 
morning
Darling Hilda:
<p>You made me so happy with your dear letter. You have such a wonderful feeling for Alice and that makes me <underline>terribly</underline> proud and grateful. So many sisters do not appreciate each other - and having always wished for such companionship I Know how foolish it is to have a dear understanding sister and not enjoy her!</p>
<p>You and Alice both help and are helped by your loving understanding - and that does make me</p>
21
<p><undelrine>so</undelrine> happy.</p>
<p>I wish you could find a way to impress on Alice the need we here feel for more communication with her. it is honestly a <underline>need</underline> on my part. I feel a sort of panic every once in a while that unfits me for my duties - such a little effort on her part would do away with this state of affairs for me.</p>
<p>Tell me darling about your ball at the <unclear>Coronado</unclear> - I Know you were radiantly beautiful! I have never been to such swell affairs because when I was a girl my</p>
22
<p>Mother Kept me at home while she went to things with the boys, considering me too young and that my time would come - then when I was old enough we had lost all our worldly goods. I almost Know <underline>no</underline> Operas and I never heard the great Singers such as Caruso - even Daddy in the "out of the way" open spaces has heard more of the great singers of our day than I have! Is this not strange? So please always tell me about Such things - I can enjoy them now through you - And am so glad and grateful you are seeing and hearing them. I never was to a swell dance! I do not</p>
23
<p>say these things to complain, but so that you may better <underline>Know me</underline>. One does need communication with someone who can understand, and someone who cares. So please forgive my <sic>remeniscing</sic> on paper - It relieves me a lot to do so!! Also it seems so wonderful to be able to do so with one's very own daughter!</p>
<p>The babies are awake upstairs now so I will get them to dress and give them their breakfast. Tell Alice I am wearing her sweater <underline>all</underline> the time, and love it!</p>
Always your devoted
Mutti
<p>P.S. Don't forget I do want those drapes!</p>