<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.12.27.35">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, April 21, 1936</title>
<author>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</author>
<principal>Gossin Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.12.27.35</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, April 21, 1936</title>
<date when="1936-04-21">April 21, 1936</date>
<extent>pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1936-04-06"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4407066">St. Louis (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2020"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="envelope">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.12.27.35.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">68 Fink Collection 
27</fw>
<note type="curatorial">Neihardt Branson Mo. </note>

<ab type="postmark">BRANSON APR 21 3-PM 1936 MO.</ab>

<ab type="return">
<address>
<addrLine>Miss Enid Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>209 Ilene Apts.</addrLine>
<addrLine>5544 Pershing Ave</addrLine>
<addrLine>St Louis, Mo.</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
</div1>

<div1 type="letter">
<fw type="curatorial"></fw>
<opener>
<dateline>
</dateline>
<salute>(I always destroy your letters that have any thing "private" in them dear!) - 
Dearest Enid: </salute>
</opener>


<fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
<p>
Your dinner must have been grand and dandy as well as pretty to look at. I do hope you are not using wine too freely. Does Daddy drink Beer very much? Please tell me! 
Miss Conn was a great help to me and she is very genuine in her appreciation of the bust. She believes I will "capture" many things that portraits as a rule do not do - This is the way she puts it. 
I hired Mrs Spurlock and together we had a lovely</p>

<fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
<p>time. She likes our country! 
Yesterday Miss Bennet had us out to her place for supper and then we all went to the "Tale of two Cities" - We had a fine time. This evening I'm looking for Miss Stratte to stay all night and Alice is going to have Margaret Swain for supper and to listen to Nelson Eddy. Enid we laughed until we almost cried <del>of</del> over Big Business the first itme we played it - Alice, Helen, Richard Greer and myself - I told the</p>

<fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
<p>kids they must look out and not make me laugh any harder, or else my teeth would drop down - and then did we all laugh all the harder!! - 
There is a bad dry wind blowing every thing to pieces out of doors and I feel so anxious for rain. Our cis-tern is actually dry - 
I use city water with lye as I used to do in Nebras-ka. We need rain! I do wish Daddy would send us some - Tell him! 
Enid I have our new lawn mower - and
</p>

<fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
<p>it is a beauty. Our place looks so neat - but every thing is at a stand still because of lack of rain. I sent Max, and Aunt Lu a box of pansy violets today. Yesterday one ot Judge V. and to you - Hope you received them O.K. I wrote Mr Beyheiuer thanking him for those gorgeous pansy plants I never received anything that gave me more joy! They are planted under our Rose arbour. It will be wonderful to see them bloom! 
Enid I have our cook - stove pushed straight back as I always wanted it and it just fits in! Also </p>

<fw type="curatorial">32</fw>
<p> 
the stove pipe goes straight into the flue from the side and I need but one elbow instead of 3 as I had to have before - It makes such a difference in the way it draws - and changes the look of the kitchen so much for the better. 
Yes I received some snaps of the Three - they are so sweet. It would be wonderful if htey could spend a week end with you. Maybe they could do that once when I am up there - if that every hap - pens - really! I am so</p>

<fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
<p>busy trying to renovate - Every thing is so run down - I need to varnish the whole house and every thing in it, really - But if I do one thing at a time I can get it all done I know - but when I see it all together I feel lost. I'll have the woodwork in the down stairs to enamel first I expect to begin with the dining room and next the bath room. Then I will varnish the dining room furniture. Then Ill enamel the front room and Daddy's and last I must paint the wood work upstairs. All this before I can get</p>

<fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
<p>to the floors. I think I can make them swell with varnish - and just forget about Oak floors. They mean too much ex-pense. 
Yes I think you knit beautifully - I love that wash rag dear, many thanks. Your suit is a dear and you'll look sweeter than that sweet picture in yours I know. 
I am wondering about that Yellow Stone Park letter I forwarded to you - what did it say? Ask, Daddy to be sure and send those books for Dr Mitchel</p>

<fw type="curatorial">35</fw>
<p>nright soon, will you not? Also "the Last Puritan", Please 
This must be all for to day - Do write soon - </p>

<closer>
<salute><del>Loades</del> Loads of love always </salute>
<signed>Mama. </signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>