<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
260 Fink Collection 55
Jan. 28, 1941
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F. Fink 
BRANSON 
JAN29
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
St. Louis County, Mo.
56
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIAHRDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Jan 38th 41
Dearest of Children"
<p>Your good letters make us feel how good it is to be so fortunate as to have such dear fine, loving children - Indeed you do make us <underline>very</underline> happy. Thanks for all you say.</p>
<p>Daddy is definitely better, although his Knee and leg hurt very much by spells. I had Dr Mitchel come yesterday and he diagnoses the case as an injury (<underline>not</underline> a cold) to the siatic nerve caused by</p>
57
2
<p>twisting his back. You see he did not do so with the mattress nor any other heavy article. He was all through getting things into the car - but decided to put some nice green <underline>medium</underline> sized logs we had left, into the truck part of the car, thinking we all would enjoy unsing them in your lovely fireplace. Daddy was conscious of the lid of the car trunk adn in order to avoid it he made a queer sort of motion that resulted in the twist to his back. It was an accident pure and simple and dead nothing to do with <underline>heavy</underline> lifting nor with catching a muscular cold it seems. Dr Mitchel said he would probably get better fast, although if this had been rhematism</p>
58
3
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIAHRDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>which it was <strike>Jan 20 '41</strike> <underline>not</underline>, it might take a long time. So we feel very hopeful, but we cannot tell you anything more definite than this. Ollie, I <underline>meant</underline> it when I said Daddy <underline>crawled</underline> on all 4s - he could not walk a step not even with <underline>any sort</underline> of help. We don't understand why it did not hurt him to crawl! yesterday and today, however, he cannot do that either, so he is confided to the big couch in the front room, although he has been able to get on to the tall chamber pot right besides the couch. He has not had the slightest bit of fever, and the ironing has once again</p>
59
4
<p>proven to be the <underline>best</underline> thing to ease the spells of pain which are voilent although we have had other things too. His sleep has been broken but last night he had a capsule from Dr M. that really made him sleep hard and long. Now he is getting the proper medecine and will aslo take the capsules for sleep every night.</p>
<p>I have had no hard work Enid darling - just keeping things done at the proper time, is not hard. Nursing Daddy is really a joy to me and a satisfaction - although I'd rather I could have the pain for him as well. He is <sic>to</sic> good and sweet. He says he really feels fine most of the time and is getting a rest! But he does nto dare move much, or the</p>
60
5
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIAHRDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
<p>siatic nerve starts raising "Hell" once more.</p>
<p>We have green wood logs and small dry wood for the furnace now. It makes it easy for me, as I have the logs on the back porch now - and do not have to go to the coal farm at all.</p>
<p>Clay Cantwell is sick with the Flu, very much so, poor Kid. The neighbors are all so nice to us. Mr Miser has helped with the car, and Frankie has done errands and brings the mail up at night unless the Special Del. makes it unnecessary. Continue to be <underline>very</underline> careful Enid.</p>
61
6
<p>darling - "<underline>an ounce</underline> of prevention is worth a pound of cure" is a motto that was upper most in my mind during the months I carried you, darling - and it worked O.K., I had steps then too, at the back porch, remember them?! But I had to work and carry a lot of things up and down them - and you <underline>do not</underline>, ,so you have no need to worry, nor do I for you. I Know you <underline>are</underline> being careful.</p>
<p>I am so sorry Mrs Harrison has worries for her sister; please give her my love. It seems the Junior Chamber of Comerce is requesting $5.00 from every business owner here - so maybe I'll still have some sculpture -luck! I am lucky in so many ways!</p>
<p>Daddy is snoozing while I write this!</p>
Endless
60
5
love to you both from
Mama - Mother and Dad.