<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.11.119.122">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, March 27th, 1935</title>
<author>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.11.119.122</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, March 27th, 1935</title>
<date when="1935-03-27">March 27, 135</date>
<extent>3 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1935-03-22"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2020"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.11.119.122.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">119</fw>
<note type="curatorial">Fink Collection 32</note>

<opener>
<dateline>March 27th 35
</dateline>
<salute>Dearest Enid:</salute>
</opener>

<p>Your good letter to Daddy and me was a joy and I am so glad you wrote it. 
Of course you want to be in the country - and I hope you will be West - but Oh don't be in a hurry to get married - you should try to put that out of your mind as it will hap pen soon enough any way! 
It seems my chances are fine once more with Mr Good's bust. Mr Leonard who 
gave me the order was here form Kansas City - and be talked Mr Good into reconsidering the propo-sition. So Mr. Good told Mr Leonard, if he pro-mised to box the bust <del>it</del> when done, and not show it to anyone till after his death he woudl consent to hav eit done and have Mr Nei-hardt take the necessary pictures when he returns from his next little trip - so that is how it stands now! Is this not most </p>

<fw type="curatorial">120</fw>
<p>unusual? Maybe the good God is working for my work too?! This makes food for thought 
Enid dear you should see my stump baby in its latest stage! i am sending it to Amama tomorrow or the day after, by insured Express - I surely know that my Mommie will do all that is possible for me, and you know how much "it" means to me! Please tell Amamma to tell me jsut how it impresses her and also you and Ottocar. - We have several of the books on your last list and will send them as soon as Daddy gets through with them. Did you get the ones we sent? There must have been 5 or six sent at different times, you do not mention receiving any, I mean Amamma 
How about the Artists League? 
Enid why don't you find out how to get into the "Daughters of the American Revolution I don't think it woudl cost much - and you would need </p>

<fw type="curatorial">121</fw>
<p>a different set of people - you know you are eligible, as are all the Neihardts. ^Anna Lu belongs. Ask Amama about it. 
Sig and Maxine are mvoing into their little home - How I would like to buy it for them! Only $350.00 in the price! They are renting it and Sigurd with the help of Bill Macmullen did all the cleaning and placing of the furniture and even the making of the cutest curt-ains you ever saw! It was a surprise for Max! 
We are having a real cold wave after enchanting Spain weather - our pearties were which 
P.S. Daddy says: to look for any of his own works, First Editions. "The Bundle of Myrrh" is now veyr high priced. It is a small grey blue book witha  gold crescent Moon on it you might find one as it was my popular in New York City. Any other "first" also of his....
He says he does not care about owning firsts any more so he used to do!
N. </p>

<fw type="curatorial">122</fw>
<p>ooms from tip to too - I do hope they will not freeze!! Alice took old carpets and gummy socks and papers and covered her little garden with them - the rows were all up so slick and so straight we have a lovely new pool about twice as wide as the one you know, and if any one wants to give me anything ever, I do hope it will be water lillies, hardy ones! We have about 16 fan sails now - they are so pretty! 
Kitty fell into a big container of motor oil in Dad's word shop - and poor kitty was "all spoiled"!
Alice has some new pets - but I'll let her tell you of them herself!
I am so pleased with what your "Manager Man" seems to think of you - I'll say you have the making of an A number one girl he is finding it out, so that is O.K. - If you wanted to do so, you could get into MacMillains! Hope you will see Mr Lathane soon. </p>

<closer>
<salute>Loads of Love to my own sweet sweet good Girlie </salute>
<signed>from 
Mama. (over) </signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>