<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
69
Branson, Mo.
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your sweet letter was so welcome. You may count on me between now and "then" to come to you if you need me. By "then" I mean the date we have to go to California on. You are now about seven months along are you not? It would be funny if "it" turned out to be <underline>my</underline> special Baby instead of "John" or "Neihardt" or "Olliver"! We here think he should be Olliver after his Daddy! In anycase we love him or her already, and are eager to have the privilege of Knowing him! Bless his heart!</p>
<p>Enid darling I am trying to make a beautiful copy of the Lullaby - and hope I can succeed.</p>
<p>It will be very beautiful to upholster the wicker set in brown, that always wears so well.</p>
<p>Hilda and Albert were so dear and we loved to have them surprise us here! We are very happy over the Kind of man Hilda has chosen. He will prove to be a very fine addition to the Neihardt "clan"! He has the quiet strength that Hilda needs and I'm sure she is in the Keeping of a good, true and intelligent man. I hope they will enjoy their engagement time, and will not get married till next Spring when all of us, including you, can be here at a quiet little Garden Wedding. I am so sorry that you, Ollie, are having to stand the extra strain of noisy workmen at the Post, and that you have so much to do at Home in the way of painting etc. but I Know how good you are to do things for Enid - and only wish I might be assisting you somehow! Do please write us if but a few words. I wand very much to Know how you liked the picture of John's bust, and was so glad that you Enid really and truly liked it. Yes do frame the picture as you said. I like to hang on your wall that way!</p>
<p>I am so glad and grateful you</p>
70
<p><unclear/> Keeping well and happy.</p>
<p>The children will love to be at your Home to a Buffet supper - That will be in honor of Hilda's engagement, not?</p>
<p>I am so sorry I could not be at Alice's recital, but we cannot have many of the things we most deeply <underline>want</underline> in this World. In fact we are fortunate if we are able to bring up our children without too much heartache, and then can see them started the way <underline>they want</underline> to go. Daddy and I both are grateful for having had that privilege!</p>
<p>Daddy is working on the fasteners of his lovely present for you! The Baby will think its Mama specially lovely with this on! and in the meanwhile dear girlie mine - continue to be very careful -</p>
Always devotedly loving you
Mama
Mother.
71
BRANSON. 
JUN12
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs. O.F Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
St. Louis County