<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
148 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 77
May 23rd 43
Chicago
4920, S. Blackstone
<p>Please write to Alice: Donato Guerra 14.
Dept. 16.
Mexico, D.F.</p>
<p>Daddy was happy, over your letter Maxie - He'll write soon.</p>
Dearest Children:
<p>Thank you <hi rend="underline">so very</hi> much for remembering me on Mother's Day - Indeed your doing so has given me a wonderful feeling of love and grattitude that comes as a great blessing when one's hair has turned grey and ones usefulness is no longer a thing depended upon. Many thanks also for your last card, Maxie dear. I think you are <hi rend="underline">so right</hi> in looking for a place in Bayside. Please keep me further informed on thought wishes and plans for they mean very much to me.</p>
<p>Mrs Seymour is so marvelous to Hilda who is still staying there and all of us. She said she wanted very much to meet me because of the <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> things <hi rend="underline">you</hi>. Maxie had said to her about me! This I was <hi rend="underline">no end glad</hi> for Amama to hear - as Amama has felt that you and I were not a close as <hi rend="underline">I always</hi> believed we were. So you see you did a very Kind and good thing for me, when you spoke well of me there. And I Know too that you spoke the truth, for as</p>
78
<p>I look back on our lives together, I Know that my feelings, and therefore actions towards you to your face, as well as behind your back, have always been those of a mother, never, no not in any instance there of an "in law." If I have failed, it has been as a mother may fail who truly loves her child, and may assume uncalled for "experience." - Enid wants me to be with her at her next Confinement, which is to take place the end of July, so I will go to her the 20th (about) of July and remain for at least 2 weeks after the blessed baby arrives. I'll have entire are of our darling "Nei Fink" as he <unclear/> himself - You Know that makes me recall my having had the privilege of Keeping our Joanie for you, Maxie! I feel that Amama may go to Hot Springs, Ark. at the time that I go to Enid as she is really in need of such treatment - and Ottocar will hasten to make that possible, after that she is planning to return with me and remain with us in Chicago.</p>
79
<p>I am not certain however, because Amama gets the desire to go someplace else every once in a while. - Anyway she knows she is overcome with us, and I want her to have the feeling that with us is <hi rend="underline">one</hi> place where she <hi rend="underline">can</hi> stay as long as she wishes to do so.-</p>
<p>What about your raise in salary Sigurd and is the outlook for South America dim now, or is it still probable? I don't Know anything about the roofing business - but I am always <hi rend="underline">afraid</hi> of such ventures.</p>
<p>Daddy is not getting a big salary but has the chance of a raise soon, however we think a bird in the hand is worth 10 in the bush - and we don't forget to be grateful for that one! His eyes are bothering him a lot now too, and you Know how unhappy he can feel, and how he makes <hi rend="underline">me feel</hi> with him.</p>
<p>But I trust soon he will have better results with the occulist, then he has been having.</p>
<p>There was a "bite" from our M.D. for our Branson House and we are waiting</p>
80
<p>to hear again soon. There have been terrible floods down there, as well as in many other parts of the U.S. Hollister caught it extra hard it seems.</p>
<p>Are you having any news from Branson? - I am still hoping that after the War is over - The Neihardt Program etc will be putting on "Entertainments travelling by Airplane to distant parts of the Anglo-American world. - Why not?</p>
<p>Hilda is having the proper teaching that you and I feel she needed when in St Louis. She has also found that her <hi rend="underline">voice production</hi> training was good - and that while she has much to learn she has <hi rend="underline">no bad</hi> habits caused by wrong training to <hi rend="underline">un</hi>do. You'll be glad to hear this. She said yesterday - <hi rend="underline">Oh how</hi> Sig and I could make a hit together!....She had a <hi rend="underline">very</hi> fine concert <sic>piannist</sic> for her accompaniment who has played in New York City and other important places, and has wonderful write ups as Pianist <hi rend="underline">and</hi> violinist: a young woman. - I'll hear you Tuesday <unclear/> - <unclear/> to the Bootfelltons' Home <unclear/>. I can <unclear/> wait.</p>
Endless love to you precious <unclear/>

