<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
230 Fink Collection 25
BRANSON.
SEP13
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Mo.
(St. Louis Co.)
26
Sta-Sold Baking &amp; Cutlery
Std.
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE 
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
First Frost, 1940
Dear Sir:
<p>We greatly regret the omission of holes from our latest consignment of doughnuts, and are shipping you a gross at once under separate cover, all our holes are elastic, and you will have no trouble in getting a snug fit.</p>
<p>We are greatly interested in your project for producing flying soldiers on the self-propulsion plan, and should be happy to cooperate with you in getting these under production. Unforunately, we are not at present properly equipped to produce the soldiers themselves, but our engineers advise us to the effect that an enormous number of arse replacements would be required in case of war, and our facilities for manufacturing doughbut holes should prove invaluable. Also our supply of material is unlimited. Properly surrounded with a resolute soldier, one of our elastic non-skid, non-blowout holes should withstand the most</p>
27
<p>violent outbursts of patriotic fervor and democratic enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Before beginning production, however, we shall have to know if these are to be clean-shaven, or if you prefer Van Dykes with goatees, or only the usual perpheral fringe? Our engineers favor the clean shave as offering less obstruction to the bean - gust.</p>
<p>If you were proposing a self-propelled flying <underline>horse</underline>, I'd say that Mr. Roosevelt would be a good model for the posterior orifice.</p>
<p>Yours for bigger and better <sic>binness</sic>, free enterprise, individual intiative, the American way of life, University Democracy, and Liberty.</p>
Sta-Sold Pastry &amp; Cutlery, Inc.
per Dad Gaki Pres.
George Katt, Secy.
<figure><p>A Great <sic>Binness</sic> Man</p></figure>
<p>Our founder Mr. Gaki, who is still our President at the ripe old mental age of seven,</p>
