<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
142
Mon. Nite 10 min. til 9:00 I'll be with you in concentrated tho't til 9:05 Love, Sig 
Oct. 24th, '32,
5116 Cass, 
Omaha Nebraska. 
My sweetheart, 
I'm just back from the funeral, & am so lonesome for you! I love you, & am to the place now where I cna't be happy! I must see you soon, or else I don't know what! I love you so!!! I believe you have or shoudl have rec'd my letter from Ashland Nebr. stating that I had to favor the Leslies by making 
(over) 
-2-
it possible for them to attend the funeral of an old friend of theirs! 
I was in a miserable state of mind - missing you, sweetheart, & having to (of all conceivable things) attend a funeral on top of the way I was feeling anyway - was most awful! I do believe that you love me! I should, & also feel safe in doing so! 
What hurts, my dear girl, is that as soon as I get home I'll have to get ready 

-3-
to go away on another trip! Being that I am a year & a month or so form being independent, I just have to contribute my help to Dad! 
Seems awful, but things will change! 
I feel that you love me & care to stick with me, & that is a huge help-I'll shout! 
This trip after I see you will be only a few days, but the way I feel now, & having missed ^you for so long a time - I can hardly feel like I will be in the mood to go! 
Sweetheart, please remember at all times that I love you as I do no one else & you are my ideal of sweetness & sincerity! With all the love in the world fo rmy sweet girl, I'll say goodnight! 
Bless your heart!! 
Please be sure that I hear from you again soon, at the next place! 
P.S. I can hardly wait to see you! 
Sig. 
P.S. May get a job here yet! Can't say for sure now! 
JOHN G. NEIHARDT 

-2-
Just another note - It is 9:00 straight up now, & I am thinking of my sweetheart, & of what she may be doing! 
Seems to me that I can see you sitting in a rocking chair near a standing lamp & you too are thinking & wondering if I am in tho't with you at the same time! 
Love Always;
My heart aches for you dear, 
Sig. 
143

144
OMAHA, NEBR. OCT 25 3 PM 1932 BURLINGTON STA. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson,
Missouri. 