<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
54a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
March 25, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>Today I have something to say that we've been wishing, praying, and working for for two months now. Yes, the re-entry permits for George and his Grandmother have arrived. Thanking the Great Spirit is all I can feel is right, for we are certainly fortunate and happy about it. We do not know just when we'll leave for Mexico: this coming Tuesday at the earliest. It is necessary to have all our baggage checked through and our passport photos taken, as well as passports arranged,</p>
(2)
<p>and all this takes several days. Once in Mexico we must get acclimatized and must wait a few days till our agent there lines up our dates for us again. You can write me here again, just in case we're not gone yet, and if we are, letter will be returned <hi rend="underline">or</hi> forwarded.</p>
<p>I have a few dollars now, so as to be safe in Mexico till we begin earning again.</p>
<p>There is not lots more to say now about us, except that we have been rehearsing and practicing and performing some too, which is all very much to the Good! Perhaps we shall dance again tomorrow night at the Victory Club. That is, if the orchestra can be gotten.</p>
54b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>If you don't say anything about how you're feeling Daddy, but Mama tells me you've been very ill - better now, however. How does the osteopathy help you? Oh, Daddy, <hi rend="underline">do</hi> be careful, won't you. I certainly hope this letter finds you felling much better.</p>
<p>Your new home sounds truly lovely. It must be fine to be in your home again. So Nebraska doesn't look as likely as Kansas City? The latter would be grand, and <hi rend="underline">of course</hi> Richard's Mother would be <hi rend="underline">thrilled</hi> to have you in her home. It would be very lovely</p>
(4)
<p>all around, I should think, for as long as you wanted it so. I hope it will not be long till I can aid you a bit.</p>
<p>Heard from Hilda today - such a happy, "up", strong letter that I was thrilled to get it. I shall write her our news too.</p>
<p>Pray for us as I do always for you - <hi rend="underline">inside</hi> and out. And know how very very much I love and admire and cherish you.</p>
My dearest ones,
Your Alice
<p>I finished three Friends yesterday - How <hi rend="underline">much</hi> I got out of it this time God! What Beauty and Truth and Greatness</p>
54c
Alicia Nye
After Five Days Return To
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS

LAREDO
MAR 26
11 PM
1943
TEXAS

Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
4252 McPherson
St. Louis Mo
c/o Mr. Schmidt