<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
244 Fink Collection 47
? 1940 
Xmas Day
Booking Agent
BRANSON
MISSOURI
Dearest Children:
<p>You certainly were too wonderful to us for Xmas - My, my, my! How many lovely things! Enid you bit just the spots that would make me think most of you throughout the year - (as though I needed to be reminded!) You Knew my cold feet - and that I have never owned such cozy, lovely footwarmers! The ship has only the fault of being <underline>too</underline> extrovagantly swell - but it will be worn just the same by your most appreciative old Mama. So many thanks to both of you dear, wonderful children! The boy of Xmas goodies has already been handed to our guests who happened in on Sunday - and</p>
48
<p>the long box is still reposing in the ice box and I think I Know that it contians my very favorite candy - which I will be most selfish with, Daddy and I having one after every dinner - and no more! So many thanks again! I just bought some lovely outing flannel to make a warm mighty for my self and the footwarmers match it beautifully - I am so thrilled to look forward to the next cold spell and realize how cozy and comfy I shall be thanks to your warm heart and able fingers! Again so many many thanks to you Ollie dear as well as to Enid - You both are very realblessing when I think of you two together, and that is very often. Now that <unclear>Monatisa</unclear></p>
49
<p>in on her way, (or maybe John Neihardt too) my prayers for you have changed to a different motive, but they could not be mroe fervent than they already are for the continuance of the greatest, fullest blessing this Life can give, what you already <sic>passess</sic> in holding each other so dear.</p>
<p>Joanie is completely happy. She has opened her packages, has stood entranced and silent before the Xmas Tree adn the holy scene beneath it, and now is playing with the one git she begged Santa to bring her - Blocks - she is build</p>
50
<p>ing and building on the carpet at the foot of her Tree. Bless her! You would be so pleased with her these days. She is a darling little grown-up. So gentle and timid it hurts to think of what life might hold to harm her - but I trust she too may find a good and loving man - and be safe.</p>
<p>She will write to you and when she does you must Know that she is doing it <underline>herself</underline>.</p>
Love to you two, and thanks once more for your devoted
Mama.Mother.
