<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection October 16, 1938
29
105
WRITTEN FROM ONE OF THE 
STRATTON THE HOTELS 
<FIGURE/> 
Neihardt, Branson, Mo. 
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink, 
9716 Hawthorne, 
Overland, Mo. 
(St. Louis County) 
WA 43 N21 

30
HOTEL STRATTON 
<FIGURE/> 
WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
Sunday, Oct. 16, '38
Dear Enot and Ollie: 
I want to write you, as you see, altho' I haven't much of importance to say, except to repeat waht you know - that you are dear to me. 
Had a swell time at the U. of K. C. and before the Walter League - also at Peru. Audiences are darling with me, and they make me happy, although they do take something out of me by the bucketful. 
Old Sig plays exquisitely, and I'm glowingly proud of his contribution. Audiences come over to him in a lovely way. We have a bully time together - never the slightest function. He seems to have become somebody else - and a very fine somebody - once he has 

31
HOTEL STRATTON
<FIGURE/> 
WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
-2-
been succeeding in boosting his Dad. Also, the success in playing helps immensely. He's really very effective in booking, and will make a pilling next season. Even now - six months late - he lands them. You see, he behaves. 
Everything is fine with all of us. And such bright stars. in that pool! They will not be darkened again, I know. When I think of the dear people around me - all fine - I'm astonished at my good fortune. You two are aroudn me, of course, as much as those in our house; and Hiddy and Alice too. 
Golly, what a little nation of dear ones! 

32
HOTEL STRATTON 
<FIGURE/> 
WAYNE, NEBRASKA 
-3-
Sig has seeral good engagements in November, others scattered through December, and then a heavy schedule in February. He has booked several already for next summer and fall - 3 to 5 day engagements at good money. In March he'll hit the coast, via S. W., and come back through N. W. This for the '39-'40 season. He knows how to get the money. 
Ollie, are there any rumors of a raise for you? a d - good medium told me you'd get a raise. Any chance to get an executive job in your department? I hope so. Enot, dear, dear Girl, I think of you a lot. 
With love always, 
Dad. 

33
<figure/> 
