<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI>



<text>
20a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
January 27, 1943.
Dear Daddy and Mama, and Everyone Else,
<p>Here we are in Laredo, awaiting the arrival of George's papers, which have been delayed and are to come here soon. We shall have to wait here till things are straightened out. <hi rend="underline">Such</hi> a Spanish atmosphere! As I write this, we are sitting on our veranda basking in a warm, tropical sunshine and feeling very much as the lazy Latins do. It is <hi rend="underline">so</hi> good to relax thusly - just to <hi rend="underline">exist</hi> in this lovely weather, amid these strange fascinating people. This morning</p>
(2)
<p>we went walking, after a late breakfast, down to the bridge, where we secured our first glimpse of Mexixo across the Rio Grande. A kind gentleman with an accent even picked orgtanes for us from one of the several overladen trees in a nearby square.</p>
<p>Oh! What tangerines and oranges are here! Shall try a Mexican dinner today.</p>
<p>Now to continue our life story from St. Louis. We left, as you know, at 10:15 A.M. Sunday - after a perfectly grand sendoff by our dear ones. Had a nice, uneventful trip except for meeting with interesting travelers until we reached Dallas. Monday evening at 5:00.</p>
20b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>The All-American Bus had been very comfortable - and a part at least of our meals were furnished - so we were all in all, quite well taken care of. Arriving in Dallas, we set about cleaning ourselves up - and felt much better for it. At 6:00 we saw to our baggage <unclear/> and change of tickets to a different bus line, the Bowen, on which we were to continue to Lorado. Madame Perdu, Sylvia, Doris, and I went to a nearby restaurant where we ate hurridely in order to be at the Union Station at 6:30. As it happened, the bus had to be repaired, and we did not leave till 7:30. To begin with, the bus was quite cold and we were forced to invent</p>
(4)
<p>ingeniuous methods of keeping ourselves warm. Sylvia and I talked French together until the cold became almost intolerably intense for a "ordinary sitting posture "sin uno serape", at which time we fairly wrapped ourselves about each other in order to keep warm. We were informed, some distance from Dallas, that we might wait for the next bus, which would be warmer, and was to be along in several hours time. We, however, with all but two passengers were game to stay with the original bus - and did. The cold was so intense that we had to remain at each rest stop for at least twenty minutes in order to warm ourselves. This went on for several hundred miles, over which we drove with no little difficutly, for it was snowing hard, and the road was a thick mat of freezing</p>
20c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>snow and frozen ice. At last we came to a full stop in front of a little road station, for the battery had run down. Our driver was very confenial (He reminded us all of Gary Cooper), with the same nice way - and humorous attitude in spit of difficulties) He, Harry Hardy by name, succeeded in waking the proprietor of said store, who built a fire therein, and allowed us all to enter and warm ourselves, while arrangements were being made for the second bus to pick us up. We ahd lots of fun together in the predicament - total strangers at first, then friends within a few hours. The relief bus arrived at last - but with a</p>
(6)
<p>faulty fuel pump. of all <unclear/> This coincidence, of both <unblear/> going flooey woudl happen only once in a thousand years, said the driver (just as the cold weather was entirely unseasonable), but we were there when it did - and the experience was a thoroughly unusal one. We boarded the new bus and rode along in a very amusing fashion. First the bus was propelled up a hil by the motor (or most of the way, coasting part of the way) and then it was allowed to coast downhill, for the motor had killed. The joking driver again would, with great difficulty, start the motor and we would again travel uphill. Thusly, we arrived in Habson, Texas, around 6 A.M. Had breakfast there and talked and waited about a little</p>
20d
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>gas brazier. At last we boarded a schoolbus and rode on it (unheated) into Austin. It was <hi rend="underline">very</hi> cold - <hi rend="underline">extremely</hi> unseasonable for this country, as our genial Texan comrades told us. <foreign>Pent - etre, c'est la guerre - n'est epas? Comme toutes les choses marvaises!</foreign> But we passed the time most happily - joking, and, Doris and I, reading Daddy's Collected Poems. In Austin, capital and truly lovely city of Texas, with a large university and gold capital bldg., we boarded a comfortably warm bus bound for San Antonio (San Anton here). Slept most of way - but awoke to see railway stop called "Hilda" - shortly before San Anton. The latter we found to be a characteristically up and coming clean Western City, with a decid</p>
(8)
<p>edly Mexican touch as to archietecture, palm trees, adn large squares with pigeons and orange trees and foutaines therein - but all <hi rend="underline">so</hi> clean. Left at once for Laredo, on a car-bus (large bus was overcrowded) and arrived there about 6:00 o'clock - a little previous. We talked to several interesting Mexicans and Americans on that trip - one nice Mexican woman (a Spec - leanign toward <hi rend="underline">Spanish</hi> rather than Indian), who sang many songs of her country and otherwise, in plain words, sang high praise of old Mexico. Upon our arrival here we secured rooms and called Senor Valencia, agent from Mexico City. He came to see us - and proved very charmign. It seems we are already being announced at the "Folies Barsgere" - so we are all on our</p>
20e
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>toes waiting to fly across that border. Senor Valencia wanted us to leave here with him - but we must await the papers. We shall be only more thrilled when we <hi rend="underline">do</hi> go. Oh! what tales we hear of Mexico - and we can already feel its atmosphere here.</p>
<p>This morning was glorious - and so is this afternoon. Wish all of you dear people were here. You'd love it - and how grand it would be for all of us to see Mexico together. We shall.</p>
<p>Please write me <hi rend="underline">not</hi> until I give further notice of where we shall be. As usual, we are having</p>
(10)
<p>excitement, and a bit of uncertainty for the time being - but all will soon be settled and I shall give you our address.</p>
<p>I just see some Mexican children coming home from school - so it must be around 4:00 o'clock.</p>
<p>Senor Valencia is very eager for us - and so are we eager to be in Mexico City. Are to appear at best spot there. I <hi rend="underlien">shall</hi> apprecitate a costume Mama. The clothes will be <hi rend="underline">so</hi> lovely. Have not our suitcases yet.</p>
<p>Muchas Amour!
Adios!</p>
Loads of Love to all of you - Hilda, Albert, Eny Ollie, Amama, Nei, Everyone.
<p>Much Spanish spoken here! Am learning a bit already.</p>
</text>
</TEI>