<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- letter is incomplete - missing pages -->
139a
1419 North Dearborn
July 21, 1942
Dear Daddy, Mama, Amama,
<p>I was so happy to receive your lovely letter, Mama. Please everyone, <underline>do</underline> write me.</p>
<p>The weather is again coolish and lovely here. Sunday we went to the beach (Eddie, Sylvia, and !) and swam and sunned sevral hours. Then we returned home and devoured a very delicous meal (pork chops, mashed potatoes, gravy, peas adn carrots, tomato salad, etc.) At 8:00 o'clock we dressed to up a bit and, boarding a bus on Michigan, rode ( in the course of several <sic>transfre</sic>) through lovely Grand Park</p>
(2)
<p>to the open concert hall. <unclear/> setting was one of those unusually perfect ones in all respects - the new moon sailing in a calm though puffy cloud - strewn sky, a soft breeze blowing, green grass (with blankets full of families scattered here and there), adn then the truly lovely, white, four-tiered shell against wwhich the orchestra was placed. (Pews of green seats are placed before the stage, but these do not accomodate all of Chicago's music lovers) <sic>Jerze</sic> Bojanowski and his orchestra were the performers that evening together with four soloists.</p>
139b
(3)
<p>I know you would greatly have enjoyed the program - Beethovens 5th, Strauss waltzes, Smetana's "The Modau," selections from Paghacci, etc. This is only another example fo Chicago's wonderful appreciation of music. Some day, you must live in Chiacgo - or at least, visit it.</p>
<p>We have been practicing at Gladys Hights Studio afternoons 3:00 to 5:00. It was terrifically hot last week, but this week it is much cooler, and better for working.</p>
<p>Today we practiced lifts onn the beach, That is, we <underline>began</underline> by practicing lifts</p>
(4)
<p>at about 1:00 o'clock. After that we wrestled and played at <unclear>Jiujitsu</unclear> on the sand until we were exhausted and covered head to foot with wet sand (We had already been in the water - so were nice and wet!) Really, it is amazing what one can do with just a little knowledge of Jiujitsu, and it's really great sport. To make our afternoon one of unforgettable excitement, the watrr of Lake Michigan were, and became gradually more and more, turbulent. Waves (swells) as high as a garage hurled themselves land ward, and broke into</p>
139c
(5)
<p>white capped waves just a few feet from shore. Of course, this was new to me - utterly new and intensely exciting. We went out as far as allowed, beyond the rope, adn there rode the huge swells. As often as we <underline>rode</underline> one successfully, we were absolutely <underline>engulfed</underline> and swirled head over heels by another. I've <underline>never</underline> had more fun. God! I love that wild furiz - and I know now I'd love the open ocean. Some day we'll have a yacht and sail</p>
(6)
<p>to South America! <unclear/> write you not, I can feel the swell, then the intense strength, then hear th lion-like roar of the mountains of crystal water. And what <underline>colors</underline> that lake does create for itself. Every day the scheme is a different one - gray,  fading into the sky on dully days, light blue, green, and deep blue (almost purple) on brighter days.</p>
<p>Last night, after dinner, Doris and I went out into the cloudy moon</p>
139d
(7)
<p>light <strike>night</strike>, climbed the fence across Outer Lake Shore Drive, and proceeded to the beach. (You need have no fear, for there <underline>were</underline> others nearby) We spread our blanket on the sand and lay down awhile watching the fleecy clouds above us attempt to squeeze out a few drops of rain. They did not succeed in any degree, so we removed our slacks and waded into the slightly swelling, cool water, adn then out - out - out into</p>
(8)
<logo>The Drake
<strike>The Drake CHICAGO</strike></logo>
<p>the immensity of that great, powerful, mystical body. The fog was rather thick farther out on the lake, making the goshtliness of everything more marked than ever. As we walked out farther and farther, hand in hand, there was a strangeness about the world - and it was almost as if we were being lured out there - farther, farther,</p>
139e
(9)
<p><unclear/> nothing remained but cool, dark water, and fog over all, shutting out even the faint cold glimmer of the maiden moon. As we looked about the lake and also at one another in wonderment (and not without a strange heart-pang) we both caught the faint, almost ghost-like gleam of a blue speck of light, somewhere in the distance. It seemed to disappear entirely at times - then it</p>
(10)
<p>would reappear with greater intensity. Both Doris and I saw it yet we still are not certain whether it was real or imagined. At the time, the mood was such as to make anything seem plausible. We might have seen King Aruther being borne away on his large - yes, it was like that - like going out never to return. Queer, <unclear/>. Yes, all the more so for me, for I am never</p>

