<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
331 - <strike>332</strike> Fink Collection 100
B
<underline>Branson</underline>, Mo.
BRANSON
JUL10
3 -PM
1942
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mrs. Hilda Petri
5833 Bartmer Ave.,
St. Louis, Mo.
<underline>over</underline>
<p>Can you send me a nice bunch of folders?</p>
101
Title: A LOVELY LETTER
By
Dr. Neihardt
Friday Morning
Precious Hiddy:
<p>Yes indeed, do put the ring on sale in that shop at the price you mention. It will actually be a better bargain (at that price) than any I've seen in the window. I do hope it will sell, and so clear a little of my debt to you. Perhaps it will.</p>
<p>I haven't heard from Kemper yet, and it may well be that they are trying to arrange. I'll not be surprised either way. I'd far rather be in an all-boy school than in a co-educational institution. I had a "conference" (important sounding word) with the English progs. at Kemper, and the problems they brought up covince me that I could do needed work there. Several of the younger instructors were <underline>so</underline> fresh from "courses", if you know what I mean - and you do.</p>
(over
<p><underline>Much</underline> more on the other side! This is only the first  base!</p>)
102
<p>Our <sic>drouth</sic> was broken by a happy rain last night. (This has almost literary flavor.)</p>
<p>Hiddy I think a great deal of your plans &amp; your fine progress. Every night I think again about you and Albert before I go to bed. - And about Sig &amp; Max, the Wubs, Ollie, Enot &amp; Nei. You are a precious lot, and we are prrofoundly grateful for you.</p>
<p>Yesterday Richard Crowder and I had a bully time swimming in our crystal Roark pool. It was breast-deep on me. I wish we could play there together!</p>
<p>Peaches are plentiful at 75 cents per bu, &amp; will be cheaper. A neighbor hauls them from Nashville, Arkansas, where Mama &amp;\ I once spent a night. It is 12 miles from the diamond mine. The neighbor wants me to make the trip with him. I may.</p>
<p>We are very happy together.</p>
With endless love for you, the Pioneer, Sig, max &amp; the Wubs,
Dad.
<p>I <underline>told</underline> you there was a lot more on this side! ain't you glad you turned over</p>