<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
36a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
February 15, 1943.
<hi rend="underline"> Febrero</hi>
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>You cannot know how much your letters mean to me, for your belief in my <hi rend="underline"> capacity</hi> for Good is something that I can never completely fail. And to think that you should feel it necessary to send me money, especially when you are in a tight spot yourselves, and after I have <hi rend="underline"> taken</hi> so much already! I can only say that I appreciate you with all the strength of my heart and soul - and that Something well some of these days allow me to show</p>
(2)
<p>it. You actually make me feel <hi rend="underline"> very</hi> small and silly for <hi rend="underline"> ever</hi> being weak - or perplexed; <hi rend="underline"> And</hi> - you give me new strength. Don't <hi rend="underline"> worry</hi> one bit, please. We <hi rend="underline"> are</hi> eating and sleeping exreptionally well - in fact we're terribly healthy! This has been a vacation for us which will help us when we begin working hard again! As it is, we rehearse daily, but <hi rend="underline"> rest</hi> the remainder of the day, sleep long hours, and eat delicious food at a friendly restaurant here, the Red Parrot Cafe. We have made many good friends there. First of all, the waiters</p>
36b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL 
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>Mexican of course, are exceptionally nice to us. They serve us a breakfast-lunch combination (We always arise late) fit for a king, for 35<cent/>. This consists of our favorite cereal smothered in delicious bananas and <hi rend="underline"> country</hi> cream, <hi rend="underline"> two</hi> eggs, whole wheat toast and jelly, <hi rend="underline"> and</hi> coffee! And, furthermore, to make a report such as this more enjoyable, our waiters take special interest in doing little favors for us, and show real artistry in their service. As an illustration of this, we went as away</p>
(4)
<p>last Saturday morning for our usual petit-dejeuner, and upon approaching our table, saw that someone had designed a little surprise for us. Two of our recently - cultivated friends from local radio station KPAB, who sat next to our table, jumped up at once and ceremoniously helped us be seated. There on the table, at each of our places was set the usual cereal bowl - but marvelously glorified! In it we discovered, after removing the artistically created little covering of wax paper held at the top by toothpicks, a lovely baked apple with a prune set there, and all around</p>
36c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>this castle-ish affair swam slices of bananas in a moat of super-deluxe cream! The radio-men were quick to disown all thanks for this adorable surprise, for they explained that Jose, one of our favorite waiters, has done at all of his own accord! You see, he knew we were to perform that evening - and did it as a special gesture is honor of the occasion! Nice people - these Mexican gracious and charming. I have no trouble borrowing money, for we all do this at different times - and as soon as possible I shall pay it back. Have no worry on your</p>
(6)
<p>minds for me! With all these warm fresh air and sunshine, these "Huacondde" salads, and this rest I am healthy as it is possible to be - and my comrades likewise. But oh! how good it will be to work again and be free of any money problems - <hi rend="underline"> and see</hi> Mexico. Believe me - at least as strongly - yes more strongly even, I want and intend to do what I promised for you. Each will make the other possible.</p>
<p>It is lovely and warm here today as nearly everyday it is. We have eaten breakfast-lunch ("brunch," as we say) and have done a little listening to the radio too. The latter was. this morning, for a very</p>
36d
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>special reason. You see, we have become good friends of the two KPAB announcers here. ON one occasion we spent (allofand) an evening at the studio after hrs. (10 o'clock) listening to "Sherbereade" and other classical music; on another, they took us home form our K. of C. Performance. Now, to get back to my story, we listened at 11:45 A.M. today to a program of poetry read with a background of music. Doris had mentioned your lyrics to him, the other night, so this morning, with my permission, he read "The Sound My Spirit Calls You" besides a poem Sylvia's sister once wrote. He really did your lyric</p>
(8)
<p>quite well - lyrically, and with a definite sense of building to a climax - and as a background he played "Traiimaei" - an orchestral rendition. Tomorrow he wants to do antoehr, and I feel it is good to have acquanted another with your lyrics - who will indoubtedly acquaint other with same. Sylvia and Doris did not know this one and they got "ducky bumps" listening - they loved it! Daddy, I have finished Jed after allowing myself time in reading ti to absorb and enjoy at least a small part of the beauty and truth therein. I am reading <hi rend="underline"> Hugh Glass</hi> again now and am thoroughly entranced. When I have read all of "Collec</p>
36e
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>ted Poems" again, I shall read <hi rend="underline"> The Messiah</hi> and <hi rend="underline"> Jed</hi> "encore". Oh! Daddy! If I could only express to you what your works <hi rend="underline"> do</hi> for me - how they <hi rend="underline"> overwhelm</hi> the entranced reader. That is the best I <hi rend="underline"> can</hi> describe it. And such a wealth of kinds and depth of feelings and truths. "But Oh! the boon of singing on the way!" How well I <hi rend="underline"> think</hi> I understand that. When one has Hope and <hi rend="underline"> Lift</hi> inside, and <hi rend="underline"> Light</hi>, Life is Beautiful - and it is only flashes of darkness that make one realize. This may sound like mere parrot-talking - but I know now a bit of what it means</p>
(10)
<p>"Hope is virtue and Doubt is Sin" - I know form my experience that this must be true - for I cannot be myself when I forget or lose the capacity for Hope. And usually I <hi rend="underline"> do</hi> believe.</p>
<p>The other day George received a letter form his Landlady saying that our birth certificates had arrived there, and that she had not iced on one of them the name "Alice Neihardt". Looking farther, she saw that her father was <hi rend="underline"> John G. Neihardt</hi>. The letter went on with a bullying enthusiasm, telling how she had been a teacher in Wisconsin and that "The Song of Hugh Glass" was the <hi rend="underline"> only</hi> poetry those Wisconsin tow-heads would listen to! Isn't that nice? Just another</p>
36f
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>of your countless fans, but I knew you'd like to hear of another one!</p>
<p>Here it is <hi rend="underline"> so</hi> like a golden summer day. Beautiful - and unbelievable.</p>
<p>Daddy, we were actually given new hope by what you say of Senator Truman's answering you. So it has <hi rend="underline"> already</hi> been seen by the State Dept! That means they are writing New York - for entrance data (from France_ and will soon have settled the matter. Oh! how grateful we are to you for having contacted Truman - and how we pray all will be in order for our "Mexico voyage."</p>
(12)
<p>We can only pray now and wait and work.</p>
<p>had nice affair Saturday at Knights of Columbus Valentine Ball. We performed in a <hi rend="underline"> huge</hi> gym. The stage was too far away form the ring of tables - so we performed on the floor itself. Had native orchestra (<hi rend="underline"> all</hi> of the Compean family) which did better than most under such conditions. We were well received and it looks as if other affairs will result from this one. Do hope so.</p>
<p>I had several wonderful dreams the other night. One however seems especially unusual</p>
36g
(13)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>to me. It seems I was wading in a great body of water, near shore, when the tide, or big breakers came in and dashed me back closer to shore. then, this same water changed directions and foamed back <hi rend="underline"> out</hi> to sea, bearing me with it - and I could do nothing, in spite of all my frantic attempts, but go with the flood. Terrifying was the speed I felt - and I was so alone. All at once this was no longer true, for you, Daddy, appeared from behind a wave next</p>
(14)
<p>to me, and grabbed my arm, and said all would be well. Thusly, we were borne swiftly and more swiftly upon the great current until it narrowed into a large river. So great was our speed that we could not clutch at any of the many little posts or docks that appeared alongside us, for fear of being dashed or pulled to bits. From then on the dream is vague - but I believe we landed at last on a calm beach where there was some kind of a camp. As dreams often do, this one changed or segway into antoher - but</p>
36h
(15)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS  
<p>still the original one was uppermost in my mind after I awoke. I believe it has meaning, which should show you better than I can say in waking hours how much you and your work mean to me.</p>
<p>Sunday I walked over to Nuevo Laredo, Mexico. Sent some cards and walked around a bit. How alive was the town - bustlingly so - and in sharp contrast to Laredo Texas of a Sunday! All down the street I heard comments (mostly nice ones from what I could make out.) "Bonita Senorita da <hi rend="underline"> da</hi> da da <hi rend="underline"> da</hi> da" etc. The above explains the queer</p>
(16)
<p>inflection and sing -some rendition of Mexican speech - but oh! how pleasing! They have <hi rend="underline"> such</hi> life, these "manipana" Latins - when they <hi rend="underline"> want</hi> to have it! We met our student friends (who sang for us several wks. ago) on their way home from Chicago, the other day while shopping in the dime store. <hi rend="underline"> Nice</hi> boys, and enthusiastic too. Wanted us to come with them to Mexico City right then and there! When we <hi rend="underline"> do</hi> go - we are to make sure we call them up, too.</p>
<p>I <hi rend="underline"> must</hi> close this long dispatch. Oh! Mama, thanks <hi rend="underline"> so</hi> for your work on costume - I am looking forward <hi rend="underline"> eagerly</hi> to receiving it, believe me.</p>
36i
(17)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>So Amama has left. It is good she does feel well enough to travel alone now - thanks to your and Hilda's wonderful care (if a bit indirectly so). I am terribly sorry I could not help you <hi rend="underline"> now</hi> to go to Branson. That must be one reason why I suddenly felt so downed one day last week - Thursday to be exact. Amama's leaving and my being unable to do a bit makes that impossible at present - and why it is so I cannot know. I can only believe and trust that all will soon be Light and somehow I no longer feel downed - I feel something in the very <hi rend="underline"> air</hi> that is good - and</p>
(18)
<p>I <hi rend="underline"> know</hi> it will allow me to help those I love most, soon.</p>
<p>Daddy, I'm so glad you're better and that you have the fine job  on hand. It sounds very fine indeed. Mama - please know I <hi rend="underline"> shall</hi> do as I promised whenever I can. Oh! dear ones - how <hi rend="underline"> fine</hi> you are - and how I <hi rend="underline"> know</hi> that all will be Good for you.</p>
<p>Give my love to Eny and Ollie and Nei in great gobs - for I love them muchly. Tell Eny that jelly of hers has been gratefully and jestfully consumed - and even yet we are enjoying the last ounce of it!</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alice
36j
Alicia Nye
After Fice Days Return to
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS

LAREDO
FEB 16
9 PM
1943
TEXAS

Mr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
St. Louis County