<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
34 Thompson Collection 11
Jan 8th 
[1943]
Dearest Alice:
<p>On this Daddy's dear 62nd birthday we are awaiting Ollie's return from work for a fish dinner and aftewards a marvelous cake and jello and coffee celebration to which Amama and Hilda and Albert will elnd their dear presence. Baby Nei has been "bustering" around all day and has connected to go to sleep to make the dinner and evening easier for his dear Mama - and every one else. We are so grateful to you for the lovely gift you were so good to send in the form of 5 "bucks". Today I sent you the</p>
<p>two Ozark Babies, I <unclear/> - and I trust they will not arrive too late for your purpose. Please to not give them <hi rend="underline">from me</hi>, for I am giving them to <hi rend="underline">you</hi>, and you may give them from your own weet self - and I am so grateful you want to give them to your good friends.</p>
<p>There is no immediate good news in the way of a job - but Daddy's being taken into the American Institute of Arts and Letters, means that in spite of the low and debauched take of our society at large, there still exists a group of men who know true literary and artistic merit, and for whomthe highest</p>
12
<p>ideals of what constitutes real achievement in the arts are <hi rend="underline">really</hi> in power to day as they have always been. They cannot be <hi rend="underline">bought</hi>. Daddy had <hi rend="underline">no</hi> pull or influence - The Cycle completed and given to the World is the whole reason for his being asked to honor the Institute by being voted into it.</p>
<p>I did not know that such an institute existed, although in France the Academie Francaise is a similar society. The MacMillan Co is delighted - and will use this in its publicity, which will undoubtedly mean that the complete Cycle will be <hi rend="underline">pushed</hi> instead of just allowed ot make it own way.</p>
<p>I Keep expecting my dream of the Neihardt Program to materialize some day. Sigurd is learning every thing about the delicate instruments of airplanes - and some day you children will be cercling the Earth giving Neihardt Programs, of the <hi rend="underline">best</hi> in Literature, the <hi rend="underline">best</hi> in Music, and the best in Dancing. Hilda gave Daddy and me</p>
13
<p>tickets to the Russian Ballet. I loved Alicia Markova, and also <hi rend="underline">Eglevsky</hi> is the finest <hi rend="underline">man</hi> dancer I have ever seen. I Knew all the steps from you - and the "turns" on one pointe with the other foot place beside the oppostie leg (understand what I mean!?) were marvelous - I counted 11 turns and they were done with seemingly <hi rend="underline">no</hi> impetus or effort an Eglevsky's part! I think Barovino is far too big and fat - she must be oldish - but she <hi rend="underline">was</hi> fine nevertheless.__</p>
Endless love to my Alice
from her devoted
Mama



