<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
137 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 59
Aug 19? 26? 1940
Monday A.M.
Dearest Sig and Maxie!
<p>it was good to hear from you over the Phone but my ears are out of <sic>commition</sic> because of creek - floating lately and I hear even worse than usual so I fear I missed a lot you were saying. <underline>Too bad!</underline></p>
<p>I did geet that you were worried about us maybe needing money - and your concern makes us feel warm about the heart - Bless you both dear children.</p>
<p>I believe we will get the Loan - which is</p>
60
2
<p>only barely big enough to see us through till Feb first. By "us" I mean Daddy, my self and <underline>our baby</underline>, Alice. It will take car of the note Daddy had to become responsible for during our joint business as well.</p>
<p>In that time, I mean between now and Feb. 1st Daddy will have found some "<sic>binness</sic>" connection, as you have alone Sigurd - and then we <underline>all</underline> can breathe more freely. Then too Jed Smith will be done as well as my head of its dear writer!</p>
61
3
<p>After that, We both will be young again and free to face new conditions, whatever those may be!</p>
<p>As you Know, we can do nothing different until Jed <underline>is</underline> completed, adn since we have not yet sold, we are now planning to remain here till something from the outside happens to us. <underline>I</underline> think judging from a number of things, that you had best find a small place for your own immediate family in which Alice and Hilda do not</p>
62
4
<p>figure. <underline>If</underline> then there should be a nook for Alice to sleep you would be to the good by having her with you. But do not burden yourselves with a place bigger or better than <underline>you</underline> yourselves, i.e. You and the Wubs, really need.</p>
<p>After all that is what you Maxie <underline>really</underline> wish for and have a <underline>right</underline> to have, if there is any <underline>right</underline> left in this crazy world. The fact that you have had to live with us, does not mean you have to continue to include "in laws" in your life. "I am <sic>agin</sic> it"!</p>
63
5
<p>I don't Know yet, what Hilda <underline>really</underline> wants to do, whether she prefers to take a room just for herself, or whether she really wants to go in with you, or whether she prefers to remain in her present Apartment having Alice with her to do the work and Keep her from being lonesome.</p>
<p><underline>If</underline> she <underline>does</underline> want Alice with her, I am for it, but we cannot pay half of the expenses at the Apt, and also pay Madame, even if we get the Loan. We are figuring that $10 to 15 <underline>will</underline></p>
64
6
<p>take care of Alice <underline>some</underline> where, besides paying Madame and toe shoes and carfare.</p>
<p>Maxie you can find a dear little modern place for less than you think if you do not set your standard as high as Hilda sets hers, and after all that is your first duty <underline>as I see it</underline>. Home is too prescious a thing to you and yoru very own to flounder in deep waters now in order to include in laws in your scheme. Go on foot around St John's, Vinita Park etc and see what you can find that will take care</p>
65
7
<p>of your family, then you will be gaining ground. There are plenty of <strike/> nice families living on what Sigurd now earns for you You <underline>could</underline> get along wtih just <underline>one</underline> bedroom yet awhile since your babies are so young. If <underline>I</underline> were <underline>you</underline>. I'd save money now, even if you could not get settled till later than you have been planning and then when you <underline>do</underline> get the Wubs you will be in your <underline>own little</underline> place. It does not matter whether the family next door be a summer</p>
66
8
<p>workman. Your Piano, and your privacy will be what matters most to <underline>you</underline> to Sigurd and to the Wubs. What you make with getting lectures for Daddy will be well paid for, adn will be the start of a Savings account, that will make it possible to move into better surroundings later.</p>
<p>This is just expressing to you what has been worrying your
devoted and loving</p>
Mom.