<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.10.5.10">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Alice C. Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, October 2nd, 1933</title>
<author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.10.5.10</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice C. Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, October 2nd, 1933</title>
<date when="1933-10-02">October 2nd, 1933</date>
<extent>6 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1933-10-02"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2019"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2019"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.10.5.10.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">5</fw>
<note type="curatorial">10 Fink Collection </note>

<opener>
<dateline>Monday, Oct 2nd "1933
</dateline>
<salute>My own two dear, dear Ones! </salute>
</opener>

<p>You have been gone a longtime it seems I wonder just how cold you have been? I hope not serious-ly so. 
On account of P.TA convention everything in Branson is upset. No school for Alice on Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday! She is delighted - we had Maxine and Patty here to dinner yesterday noon. so both Sigurd and Alice had a nice time. I have the carpets back in the house and another washing done. Am baking for the first time since you left. </p>

<fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
<p>I paid the dry goods and grocery hill which was $9.80 for the last week you were home. The Light bill you handed me^to pay John dear, was Grandmas' (=$1.75) ours was $2.35, and the water was $3.50. I paid both; then I sent Hilda $7.50 flus Special Del. stamp and money order. Mr Eiserman had taken the $4.65 C.O. D. out of the $25.00 he was supposed to put back in the Savings Account, and so I told him to give me the remaining $20.35, which will more than run us and pay up what may come in in the way of bills - I know of none save the Tele-phone. I already told you that I depicted the $50.00 (in my name)</p>

<fw type="curatorial">7</fw>
<p>the Bank, and think I'll not leave to draw on it at all before you get back, when I can return it to you and you can put it in the Postel Savings with the rest of the money you may have. Mr Eiser-man say sit takes so much of his time to take out or put back small ammounts, 3 hours he said, everytime!! 
Bol Thornbill asked for books to sell during convention. I told him I would bet him have some, but he is to return to me what he does not sell as I am responsible to you. He agreed to this. So I sent down all the worst looking trash from the back </p>

<fw type="curatorial">8</fw>
<p>the room. (Not any of there you are still to review) There were 87 in all. 
Hilda called up by phone right soon after you left up there - She said she was not home sick. So we did not get here this weekend. We are planning to go after her Friday noon. I can hardly wait ot see her again. Sunday Sig. is supposed to play over the Radio in Springfield. I do hope things will work out for him The little Ford idles like a big expensive car and it is the sweetest car I ever was in. I am hanging on to your money for all our sakes - Please dont think I am spending any more than necessary. I am not going to paint anything </p>

<fw type="curatorial">9</fw>
<p>ther because this is not good drying weather. I had Mr Powel test my eyes for glasses - and that is out of the question now - He wants $8.50 for close ups to say nothing of what he woudl take for "byvocals". 
So I am going to find a pair at the dime store for close up work. The ones I have are just fine for general use. 
Loads of love to you two - always I am thinking of you and Hidla and wishing you the best possible -</p>
<closer>
<salute>Your Girl -</salute>
<signed> Mamma.</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
<div1 type="envelope">
<fw type="curatorial">Fink Collection </fw>
<fw type="curatorial">10</fw>

<ab type="postmark">BRANSON OCT 2 4-PM 1933 MO.</ab>

<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Mr John G. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>Miss Enid Neihardt </addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
<fw>Gen. Del. Custer.</fw>
<fw>S. Dak!</fw>
<fw>OCT 4 1933</fw>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>