<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- french language starting at 58bb page 4 -->
58aa
Donato Guerro 12
Devartmento 16
Abril 9, 1943.
Mexico City.
Dear Daddy and mama,
<p>It has been several days now since I wrote you, so naturally I have much to say. This is so like another world, this Mexico - and a very, very wonderful one too. In fact, the beauty and scope of interest hire are <hi>so</hi> great that one is actually <hi>dazed</hi> at first - it is too much to comprehend all at once. Oh! I do so want you to know this Land of Enchantment.</p>
<p>The weather, first of all, is as near ideal as one can imagine. It is neither hot nor cold at any time - but bracing deliciously cool and invigorating. Although the elevation causes quite a bit of difficulty in breathing when one exercises strenuously, still, it is in the main part very beneficial to one's entire circulatory system (I am told). If feeling is any indication of wellbeing, we are certainly healthy people.</p>
<p>Where did I leave you? (It must have been with news of our first day in Mexico D. 7, so I shall continue from there. As you know, we arrived here on Monday, and spent a most exciting day at Bellas Artes, and in visiting our new apt., as well as Sansborn's Restaurant where all types of people swanky Americans, distinguished looking. Germans, French, and Spanish, and what have you come</p>
(2)
<p>to dine. This is a very charming restaurant founded by a Texan Pharmacist who came with the intention of establishing only a drug store, and, finding that food was often the cause of various disorders of his patients, decided to start a restaurant too. Besides this, Sanborn's now includes a large silvery and curio shop, expensive but really fine. The interior of the cast itself is quite the most beautiful. I've yet seen. made all in Spanish style architecture (balconies, etc.) it has a skylight of colored glass (high - very high up) which sheds a glow over the entire, large floor. The waitresses are all dressed in one type Mexican costume, and the food itself is both Mexican and American. Even Madame Perdu approves of its coffee. You see, here in Mexico we have cafe con leche (with milk), much more frequently than con cremo, and the coffee itself is so highly concentrated that a ratio of 1 cafe to 3 leche is generally required! I personally like it as such. Me gusto mucho!</p>
<p>Tuesday morning, the 6th we arose at 10:00, ate breakfast in the restaurant adjoining our hotel lobby, wrote letters, and went out walking. We went to Sanborn's for lunch (or dinner), then hurried black to the hotel to pack. moved into our lovely new apartment around 4:00, and unpacked, raving a bit about the general aspect of our little mansion as we worked. We have never had anything as nice anywhere - and we have this for 70 pesos apiece per month with gas, electricity, and telephone. That is, roughly, $14 per month. Our food we</p>
58bb
(3)
<p>get extremely reasonably at the Native Market (Mercado de San Juan), which is only seven or eight blocks away, and we can buy nearer if we so choose. <hi>Everything</hi> is furnished linens, lovely dishes and all. George, Doris and I went shopping at this Mercado de San Juan, in order to stock our new abode with a few needed groceries. My! How strange, quaint, and intensely interesting was that place. Everything from "soup to nuts" was being sold in a long line of <unclear>canopeed</unclear> stands. "Es muy bueno, Senorita. Es dulce" Each time I stopped to examine a new kind of fruit, etc., something like this greeted my ears. The sellers were most <sic>accomodating</sic>, trying to sell us absolutely everything they had to offer - and if we had possess enough pesos to do so, I'm sure we would have brought everything. Fresh shrimp, oysters, etc., too, Daddy - and really fine. I bought a new kind of fruit, the money, which looks like a kind of longish melon with gray skin, and has an orange pulp <sic>ressembling</sic> in looks and taste a baked sweet potatoe - muy delicioso (tres delicieux Doris bought some mangoes which look like smooth yellow pears and have a delicious orange meat inside those smoothie skins Madame Perdu cooks, like a true French chef-ess, and we do the cleaning up both at the table and after!) We have our privacy, too, in our own rooms, or our living room and sallea manjer, so no</p>
(4)
<p>ones toes are trampled on. In truth <unclear/> are quite a family. Over Madame Perdu nous parlons toujours en francais, et nus avons vrainent appris beaucoup a cause de ca. Maintain c'est tres facile a comprendre toutce - qu'elle dit, et nous <unclear/> trouvons pas difficile a parlerl grand la conversation n'est pas trop extraordinaire Maintenaut, aussi, parce que nous sommes au Mexique, nous avons une honne apportunite a apprendre l'Espagnol, et vous pouvez etra bien sur que japprendrai <unclear/> possible de cette joke langue. Ella ressemble beaucoup al francais mais la promouciation n'est pas de tout la meme chose. Je sais bien que j'ai fait beaucoup de fauz pas dans cette lettre, mais je venz vous ecrire en francais parce que je pense beaucoup dans cette langua, et parce que je venx apprendre plus comane ca. Voulez - vous une repondre un pen en francais, Mama? Je serais tres contente a causer avec vous dans la langue que je pourais appris de vous depuis longtemps, chere Manean.</p>
<p>Wednesday morning we arose,</p>
58cc
(5)
<p>breakfasted in our apartment, and dressed suitably for going shopping. All of us left together then the three of us "senoritas" went shopping alone. This turned out to be more of a window - shopping expedition than an actual buying - spree, for we were so intrigued and, it must be admitted, perplexed over the difference in stores here, that we had more fun than accomplishment. We walked through a kind of arcade peppered with little stands selling everything in the way of clothing, refreshments, and novelties - and for such a price as the buyer was clever enough to dictate. We were enthralled by all we saw, and must have looked like the rankest of "turista" suckers. We bought little, but stopped long enough in our scampering about enough in our scampering about to enjoy "fresas con crema" (strawberries with a mildly sour thick cream and sugar) - "muy muy deliciosas." Upon leaving the stands, we visited one of the three large department stores, which are situated on the square near a beautiful and ancient cathedral in the heart of Mexico City "en el corazon de Mexico" (Pronounced with "ch" sound, as in German). By 2:00 we <unclear/> ready for lunch, so went to a</p>
(6)
<p>restaurant which we found near "Biedermaider's" (a cosmopolitan city, you can see). Thence w walked to San Juan, and took a bus seven blocks (siete quadras, to the Folies Bergere Theatro. Had a short rehearsal on stage, and found our rigor increased but wind a bit hard-hit. When we become acclimatized all this will change. After rehearsal, we returned home. Madame and I went to the market, and we had "un bon diner - d3es cotelettes de veau, des pommes de terres, des tomates, etcetera. Did this and that after dinner and, at last, retired at 1:00 or so.</p>
<p>Thursday we managed to awaken at 10:00, take showers dress, eat breakfast, etc. Oh! I've forgotten to tell you something about yesterday (I mean Wednesday!) When we returned from shopping (Madame Perdu and I), I was presented with a note which had been placed under our door. It was from, guess who? Max. He said he was having a very hard time to get in touch with me, but at last had managed. You see, I'd sent him a card saying we were to arrive several days earlier</p>
58dd
(7)
<p>than we actually did, and that we were to stay at the Regis Hotel. Then we were detained in N. Laredo a few days, and besides, decided to stay at Hotel Coliseo- cheaper, Mexican-owned, and <hi>very</hi> fine in all respects. As I've found out later from Max, he happened to see a friend who worked at the Post office and had seen a card I sent much later from Coliso's, to correct my former card. The friend remembered that the Hotel I mentioned on that card began with a "C," and, by means of elimination, Max had finally found that we'd been at Coliseo's. They in turn gave him our address at the apartment. So you can see, he took a great deal of trouble in finding me. To continue with my "narrative," on the note was Max's telephone number at the Hotel where he was staying, and also the message that he could call for me any time after 7 P.M. I telephoned him at once, and we had a nice conversation. The others suggested having him over "pourile cafe," so that was just what happened. At 8:15 Max arrived, looking fine, tanned, and handsome - and truly</p>
(8)
<p>"gentille". Madame Perdu was thrilled at his French, and we all were thrilled by his intensely interesting stories of Mexico and ranch life. It seems that the country where his and his brother's Rancho San to Takia (80 miles from here) is situated is yet very wild. It is 12,000 ft. in elevation, and is plainsy with surrounding mountains. The two of them have, starting from adobe, thatched-croofed, huts, established a fine house with all modern improvements (the only ones in that part of the country, Max added modestly - as he is inately), all types of other ranch structures, and, with the enlisted aid of quite a number of "peones", put many acres of land into cultivation. He has fine horses too. As for neighbors, however, those are a bit on the untamed unsocial side (not all of course) for they sometimes steal horses, or even commit outright murder to gain such or similar properly. Max says they must at all times carry a gun. "People say 'It must be marvelous to live such a peaceful life on your own rancho.' If they only <hi>knew</hi> that every minute of our lives there is filled with excitement! Our day begins at 7:00, when we detail our peones to their</p>
58ee
(9)
<p>various tasks for the day, and <unclear/> not end till, after riding or walking all day from one group to another seeing that work is being done right (if not actually doing it ourselves), for lack of knowledge on the part of our peones), we return for supper, after which we sink exhausted into our beds. Then, there is other excitement too - shooting, or making good damages done but <unclear/> of our escaped horses, or one of a million other possibilities." But that is not all he told. Above this I remember what he described of the millions of flowers that blossom there certain times of the year, the beauties of the surrounding snow-capped mountains, the miles of perfect horse-country. Villa Guerrea, near where Rancho Santo Tobiasi's located, is a nice little village, where even occasional dances and other social gatherings are held. Of course, Max and his brother, are looked up to by everyone there, and hold quite a position for several reasons. We were enthralled for several hours by these stories, which we encouraged Max to tell us, and later had Max to tell us, and later had coffee and sweet pastries (cafe y pan dulce) about 11:30, he left - leaving a fine</p>
(10)
<p>impression in the minds of all. Really, I <hi>know</hi> if you knew Max you would heartily agree, for he is truly fine. I say this from a purely unbiased, unpremeditated standpoint, for it is a true joy to find such a spirit as this in a world where such is not too terribly common.</p>
<p>To continue with Thursday, w spent that day in such a flurry of activity that I yet cannot really grasp all of what I saw and felt. It was a joy form beginning to end - of that I am certain. Max called for me at 1:30, and we boarded a bus bound for Capultepee Park "El Bosque de Cahpultepec:. Driving along several miles of an indescribably lovely Boulevard - El Paseo de la Reforma, we passed many lovely homes (You would jump up and down with glee at the styles in architecture, the unbelievably brilliant, boganvilla (a brilliant red-purple climbing flower) and flowering trees, theatres and Night Clubs. Then cam "the Angel," a huge gold angel set high above the highway, and guarding the entrance to Chapultepec. Other monuments too, and beyond these, visible from quite a distance, "the Castle" home of Maximiliano and Larlota. We got out of the bus at the entrance to the park, and</p>
58ff
(11)
<p>continued on foot along one of the beautiful footpaths, which leads beneath huge trees of every species, to the road climbing to the Castle. Passing the guards of the fate, we wound our way uphill on the little sidewalk to the foot of the long staircase. Continued up these till, we came at last to the castle where Maximiliano had actually lived. We went first of all to the railing to see the excellent view of all the city. That is a sight I cannot hope to describe - but I <hi>can</hi> say I was truly overcome and undeniably <hi>enchanted</hi> by what we saw. Max painted out everything to me and we chatted of many things. Later we got glimpses of the rooms of the castle - furnished so gorgeously, and so well preserved for posterity. Last of all we walked around the railing, taking in a last bit of the beauty of that view - the shining buildings of all types and sizes, the beautiful paseos, avenidas, calles, and beyond and above all this, the majesty and serenity of high mountains - no snow - capped ones, such as Popocatepetes and <unclear/> were visible, however, for it was too foggy. After descending the stairs, we went walking along a lovely path, then had "<unclear>repcesnas</unclear>" at a little outdoor restaurant, where we talked and generally enjoyed ourselves. With</p>
(12)
<p>a bit of effort we forced ourselves to return to our bus. While waiting for it, Max asked if I'd care to go to the opera "Barber for Seville" with him at 9:00 that evening. Of course I was delighted, and readily consented. We boarded our bus (1st class, for the 2nd class are usually overcrowded) and rode near the apt. Took a take there (one may ride quite a distance for one peso) bound for the Folies Bergere, where we were to rehearse at 4:30. I was early, but the others soon arrived and we quickly set about dressing. Max of course, left me at the door. We worked on new numbers during rehearsal (which Valencia watched), and did much more than on the previous day. By 6:30 we were home, and a dinner built around steak was soon neatly prepared - and eaten. Then we cleaned up the dishes as usual. Afterwards we dressed - they to go to a movie, I to go to the Opera with Max. A little before mine he came, and we drove in his nice car to the Palacio del Bellas Artes. The night was a glorious array of stars and velvet sky - immense and brilliant, as we hurried from our parked car into the marble-walled, splendid Palacio. We were not at all late, although it was nine o' clock already. Once the opera began, however, all went like clockwork. I had never seen</p>
58gg
(13)
<p>this opera - nor had Max, so we were particularly pleased by it as well as the actual performances of the artistas. It was a fine production all around and we enjoyed ourselves tremendously. Max does not pretend - he enjoys because he enjoys - not because it is "the thing to do" - so we got along beautifully. He understood all of the opera because he speaks Italian fluently, as well as English French, Swiss German, and, after two years in Mexico, Spanish. One would never know this until one discovered such, for he is too unassuming to blow his horn. In spite of this, there is a <hi>definite</hi> and unmistakeable <hi>drive</hi> in him - and a standard in all he says and does. Hence, he is <hi>stimulating</hi> to be with - and a gentleman to the finger typos. The "artistas" in the opera were most convincing in voice and acting - and were all entirely new names - even to Max. We sat in the balcony in <hi>perfect</hi> seats - and the whole thing was thrilling. Between acts, the huge curtain, made entirely of small pieces of painted glass arranged into a picture of Papo and Ixtace, was lowered, for examination by the audience. During outermission we walked up and down outside in the corridor talking of the opera. When it was over, we happily de-</p>
(14)
<p>scended and went out into the night air to our car. "Oh! you must cover your mouth like that" joked Max "The night air will harm you" as he pointed out a well-dressed couple who had planted their handkerchiefs firmly and concentrically before their mouths, as they hurried to the shelter of their closed auto. As we drove along the Paseo, Max said "Do you wish to go straight home or are you in favor of a detour?" I admitted I preferred the litter, so detour we did "There is a night club here which belongs to a Swiss band leader who was stranded in Mexico. I've never been there, but I hear it's <hi>very</hi> nice. Would you like to go there?" So we went to the "Casanova." It was truly charming - three rooms, each furnished differently, but all with adorable, large candles, which, later in the evening served from time to time as the only light. In the largest room was the dance floor, with one wall made of mirrors, and in a small one near it we found our little table. Max insisted on my "<hi>trying</hi> to eat something" with him, and besides, we drank ginger ale. You see, we are both terrible drunkards! Then we danced and</p>
58hh
(15)
<p>danced - and danced. Max is an excellent dancer - especially of rumbas, tangos, and waltzes, (jazz as well.) So we had one grand time together. "You must tell me when you want to go," he said. "When do <hi>you</hi> want to?" I asked. "I <hi>don't</hi> want to, for as far as I'm concerned, I'm having such a perfect time I am perfectly satisfied to stay here. But when you say, we'll go." As Max was going to take us to see the Pyramids the next day, we decided at last that we should leave a little before 3:00. Drove home, and I retired after a day almost too beautiful to be real.</p>
<p>Friday, we arose before 10:00, dressed in slacks, and awaited the arrival of Max. He had intended to take us in a friend's <unclear>camione</unclear> (station wagon), but the latter had not been returned form the garage at time promised, so we took a taxi. Then began another day, entirely different in every respect to any yet spent - a day of joy - pure joy. We climbed the Pyramid of the Sun, built by ancient Aztecs 2000 years ago. An immense structure, built in terraces, this has an altar of sacrifice on its summits, where</p>
(16)
<p>many thousands of bones haven't excavated What a thrill to look out over that landscape - and to feel the atmosphere of an ancient day. We had quite a time climbing it, and coming down as well for it, and coming down as well for it is extremely steep. At the base we took pictures, as we had on the ascent and the summit. Max caught a burro and we all took turns riding it. Bought a jade pin and a nice black stone carved for a ring. Tried to get pure uncarved jade without success - but I shall find it. The native children who sold us these spoke several words of English a surpresing amount snice it was all collected form passing "<unclear/>". We went then to see the temple of the Feathered Serpent Quetzllcoatl, God of the Aztecs - the principal one. I am enclosing pictures which will explain better than a thousand words. This temple is built with a huge arena, in the middle of which is a "muy grande" high, stage. Theories are many concerning the original use of these and it is interesting to imagine. You would love this, Daddy - or rather, you will, when you see it. After those several hours of great interest concentrated on such wonders, we were - very hung up! So Max took us in our taxi to a fas-</p>
58ii
(17)
<p>-cinating restaurant situated in a cave (gruta). It was cool there, and we could look up to the beautiful warm daylight above - for it was very summery that day. We had a complete dinner - and I do mean complete: crema de tomate, tortilla con jamon (<hi>omelette</hi> {not regular tortillas} with ham), cabrito (kid), potatoe salda (ensalada de papas, tomates y lechuga, pan y mantiquilla, and then helado (ice cream), and cafe. We also had cidreal, a kind of apple cider drink -- muy delicioso. Going outside the restaurant, we saw parrots (lorita) of extraordinarily lovely plumage - green, blue, yellow, red, orange, who sat in the trees and looked sleepy or <unclear/> a bit. Then we went walking to an outdoor theatre nearby where native dances, etc. are sometimes shown. Took pictures all around. I even climbed a huge vase and hung onto a cactus while Max took a picture. About 4:00 we drove back again over the fifty Kilo. of plains and mountains on the way we passed many burros loaded with hay pottery, or what not, peones driving herds of goats and cows, beautiful horses ridden by costumed charros; etc. We also</p>
(18)
<p>repassed la Cathedrale de Virgin de Guadalupe. Max told us the very beautiful legend connected with this. It is said that long ago a certain "ignorant" young Indian was walking <hi rend="strike-through">past a</hi> along a little ridge when he heard the voice of the Virgin Mary calling him, and saying that she wanted a church built at that spot. The Indian went hurriedly to the Archbishop and fearfully related his story, but the Bishop would not believe him. "Why; You are only an ignorant Indian.," he said "Why would the Virgin tell you to have a church built?" So the Indian returned over the same path he had come on, and was stopped in the same spot by the voice of the Holy Mary, requesting the same thing. The Indian told her that the Archbishop would not believe him. "Open your scrape" said the Voice. With that, the Virgin caused the scrape to be filled with roses, though they were nowhere to be found in that country. "Now go to the Archbishop," she said "Rud he will believe you" Of course, this time he was believed and a lovely Cathedra was built on that Holy Place. The 18th of December is the day this is supposed to have happened and that day in you the most important church festival in all Mexico. Indians</p>
58jj
(19)
<p>come for miles on foat to visit this place - and see the scrape with the image of Holy mary and the roses painted on it. Some even say she will answer questions by a nod of the head, or will move her eyes. Mexico is filled with such Legends for these are a truly romantic people. Returning home seemed almost a pity after such a marvelous day - but the latter was actually not yet over. At George's suggestion, Max stayed to supper - and an excellent one a la Madame Perdu. We ate and talked till 9:00. Max had put off business from 7:00 till then so he could stay. Also, he had to arise early to return home the next morning. While here, he had attended to business as well as pleasure, but he had to get back to pay his peones. Otherwise they would not continue working. Max left us with a final invitation to visit him at his ranch whenever we have a vacation - and I am certainly looking forward to that. However <hi>much</hi> is to be accomplished first. We thanked him profusely for all he'd done - and he visited it'd been a great pleasure for him. "Somehow I think we'll come" I said "Oh! You <hi>have</hi> to." said Max. So has <sic>inded</sic> this contact for several weeks to come. When he returns, we</p>
(20)
<p>shall be deep in dancing - and he shall come to see us.</p>
<p>Saturday morning we arose at 9:00, with the knocking of George's fist on our door. Dressed and breakfasted, and were ready about half an hour before our host for the day, Valencia, arrived. He greeted us heartily and we went gaily downstairs and out into the warm, yet invigorating morning air to his fine five seater-coupe. Madame Perdu did not go with us this time - she went shopping "seulo." We drove first to Chauttepec Park, where we took a boat and rowed all over the little lagoons which wound in and out about little islands, etc. There were patos (ducks) geese, and fish in the water, and many birds in the tall trees. We took turns rowing - then drifted, sang and talked. Valencia taught us some Spanish words - and we sang Mexican songs. My two favorites "Jalisco" and "Lac Teria de las Flora" especially. Dont' know the words but Valencia is going to get them for us so we'll "learn the songs". We were getting a bit hungry when we caught sight of a sign on the shore of our lagoon "Fresas con crema" "Let's have some," said our host, and we did. My! How deliciously fresh they were - and served to us in our boat. We even had half a second helping a piece. At 1:00 or so, Valencia</p>
58kk
(21)
<p>suggested out of the clear blue sky that we go to Kochomilco - the Floating Gardens - or a Mexican Venice, such as the Italians will never see. The drive of 20 miles was most beautiful, though the mountains immediately surrounding Mexico City are quite barren - not forested like those within easy driving distance from here. Arriving in the twon of Xochomilco (Prounounced <hi>so</hi>-cho-mil-co) we saw the Native Market, when someone was giving a political speech - and then left the town itself for the Floating Gardens. Arriving there, we had our pick of a mat of real, woven flowers. Valencia chose "Elamor," which means "Is the Love," although first had Sylvia snap my picture in "Alicia". We boarded out little gondola and were paddled away into the canal by a little boy who manned our boat from the rear. Then, in an instant we were surrounded by boats offering us corsages of fresh smelling, artistically-arranged blossoms such as would be most difficult to imagine in the States. Such delicacy - such color - such heaven by fragrance I have never before witnessed in a corsage. We screamed</p>
(22)
<p>with uncontrollable delight at the <unclear/> of each corsage each one more lovely than the preceding. My eyes fell at once, however, on a little piece of heaven - dark purple pansies framing a red, red rose, a sunlit yellow one, and a white gardenia with green leaves and frothy Baby's Breath adding the contrast and softness desired. This I soon fastened securely in my hair, as did Sylvia and Doris those of their choice. A huge bouquet of earthy and dewy smelling violets was bought, also, by our almost unbelievably - generous and most charming host, Senor Valencia. Then we moved on over the cool water passing fields of carnations the size of a large arrange - or grapefruit, and several other boats filled for the most part with Mexican families having lunch or singing and playing. Coming to another boat filled with flowers, we were almost sorry to have bought our first corsage - but our host insisted on buying these too - and for guess how much - ? 8<cent/> apiece American money - guarente centavos por quatro! Imagine such artistry in Chicago or St Louis - and it price! We were so <unclear/> that we could hardly tell whether to laugh or cry - I cannot explain that feeling one of utter happiness, inspired by the</p>
58ll
(23)
<p>beauty and romanticism of everything about us. To make things more so, a little boat with musicians caught onto ours and rode alongside as it placed my favorite Mexican tunes. Then, another boat took pictures of us, which I shall send you and towed along behind our still they were ready. The little fellow who paddled our boat had the slight mishap of falling in the water but clambered out quite easily. So, returning laden with flowers to our spot of embarkment, we jumped out - still in the Dream of Beauty we had entered. We walked over a little bridge and entered the Restaurant, which is built on eh water's edge. There we were treated to a delicious dinner served apin in four courses - Sopa de apio, delicious Dish, Pollos fritos, ensalado, helados de frasas, y cafe. My, how good that day was. We danced too with Valencia to a Mexican orchestra - and forced ourselves to leave about 6;00, with the promise that we'd come back next Saturday. Imagine! Our host insisted "It is a great pleasure for me." Madame Perdu awaited us eagerly when we returned but our thoughts were still in that Heaven we'd been privileged to enter for a day - and we saw or heard little else than what our hearts remembered. After resting for awhile,</p>
(24)
<p>for we were mentally as well as physically tired, we got up and dressed for dinner. Went out for this since up marketing had been accomplished that day. We walked downtown, on the beautiful Alameda (Avenida) past Bellas Artes. Sanborn's was overcrowded, so we ate in a Mexican Restaurant nearly Service was fine - and food very good too George left us at 9:00 to go to the theatre for a consultation, and we walked home (the four left of us), stopping in nearly every shop to view the lovely blouses, silver, blankets, etc. of Mexican handicraft. We spent most of the evening writing letters, playing chess etc., and by 2:30 I was in bed breakfast, and spent day in doing tasks.</p>
<p>Please write me at once, please, for it takes long for a letter to arrive here. How are you all getting along - and how is everything? I hope you are all very happy and well. Will you let Eny and Ollie read this if they wish. I shall write them too - but not in such terrific detail.</p>
<p>Oh! Life is so full - so Different, <hi>so</hi> beautiful - and I am so grateful.</p>
Loads of Love,
<margin><hi>(See page 2 &amp; 3)</hi></margin>
Your Alice
58mm
(25)
<p>Later:
    We shall have two shows to do each night at the Folies Bergere - at 7:30 and 10:30, and two at the Patio at 1:30 and 3:00. We open the 24th at the Folies Bergere and the 28th at the Patio. At the theatre we shall have thirty show girls and twelve line girls as background. A really large production, as you can see. I shall write you all about rehearsals, then our actual openings, etc. when they take place. We shall do two numbers in each show. So we shall lead a very busy life, as you can see.</p>
<p>I am enclosing, or rather, sending under separate cover, more pictures of our visitings with a few notes on to backs. You will keep all with the rest of the scrapbook, n'est-ce pas Mama? I am <hi>very</hi> happy you are doing this - and so much better than I could ever do.</p>
<p>I shall look for the little gems, see a <unclear/> the paper, etc. There are many lovely fire opals for sale, but as yet I've seen no garnets. I shall, however.</p>
<p>Oh! dear ones - I love and think of you so so often.</p>
Loads of Love,
Your Alice