<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
126 Finn Collection 91
AFTER FIVE DAYS RETURN TO
Neihardt
Branson Mo
BRANSON
MAY 21
3 --PM
1939
M.O.
Mrs. O.F.Fink
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, 
Mo
St Louis
County
92
Sunday
AM.
<p>So sorry we cannot take your sweet black Kitty unless something happens to our yellow <unclear>george</unclear>!</p>
Enid Darling:
<p>Your good letter was so welcome. You have everything about your little Home that we have. Cherries and garden stuff and flowers - but she fact remains that you and your dear Man are so far away - that you cannot come to this Home as often as I want you. There is nothing to it all if we must be so separate after lving as closely united as we have done.</p>
<p>Yesterday a mammoth storm came along and broke down our wonderful shade tree over Daddy's cement seat. He had connected the electric wires so that we night fulfill our Dream of long ago and eat breakfast there of a morning - but all the year it has been too cold, or both cold and wet to enjoy of are early morning how I have the very strange feeling that that "act of the Gods" was symbolical of our life here and that Daddy's yearning for the West is about to culminate in our going to California.</p>
<p>After all Home is not Home if you children cannot be there - and I feel the roots</p>
93
<p>of me pulling loose _ It hurts of course - but every radical change does that, even one for the better.</p>
<p>Mr Good is successful, to say the least, and I with you and Ollie might come while it is still here_ I'd like for you to see it. I am expecting Leonards very soon - and when I get the $50.00 owing me I'll turn them over to Dad who needs them worse than Hilda does right now.</p>
<p>I have the best thing in clay of Dad. I am making it down behind the barn, a splendid place to work. Wish you could see it <underline>now</underline> or <underline>soon</underline>.</p>
<p>It is pouring once more and everything is very beautiful _ but cannot be enjoyed fully as it is too cold and wet.</p>
<p>I am glad you have our girlies out ever weekend _ Please feel me there with you in heart and spirit</p>
Loving you devotedly
Your Mom_Mother