<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.49.51">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Alice Culler Neihardt. December 1928</title>
<author>Neihardt, John G.</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.49.51</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, December 1928</title>
<date when="1928-12">December 1928</date>
<extent>3 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4407066">St. Louis (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1928-12"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>


</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.49.51.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">49</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<fw type="letterhead">Missouri Collection 49 
<figure/> DAILY SUNDAY 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
PUBLISHED BY THE PULITZER PUBLISHING CO. 
ST. LOUIS, MO. </fw>
<opener>
<dateline>December 1928 Tuesday.
</dateline>
<salute>Dear Mamma: </salute>
</opener>

<p>I'm awfully sorry you were sick Thanks-giving Day - just when you should have been eating goose with us, but I'm awfully glad yourecovered so quickly. I haven't any doubt that C.S. helped a whole lot. You must be careful-and not expose yourself. Do you wrap up when you go out doors to do some little thing? Be sure to do what you would insist upon having anyone else do. 
I'll surely send you a bunch of books for Christmas presents. Will take a bunch home tonight and have them packed. it is the best possible way to give presents. 
You mustn't let any cost of keeping up the radio rob you of that pleasure. When it gets out of fix, have it fixed and write me what it cost. I'm glad there was nothing much wrong with it this time. No doubt you'll have a tube or two to buy one of these times. If so, don't let that fuss you. 
$$$ Buy them and go ahead, letting me know the cost. 
By the way, how about coal? You must be in debt for it, aren't you? Send me the bill. Better get enough to last you awhile, <del/> all at once. 
Yes, my investments on the Stock Exchange begin to look pretty good. I'm already pretty much a winner, and the outlook is bully. I have 9 stocks now, all (over) </p>

<fw type="curatorial">50</fw>

<p>with excellent backing and prospects. Some of them are going to be sensational climbers, but all are good. Pennsylvania, I believe, will reach 100 sometime early in next year. I'll hold with that in view. 
Here is my <del/> list, so that you may watch the market:
75 Pennsylvania bought at 68.
100 Middle States Cil. bought at average price of 6
50 Tennessee Copper and Chemical, bought at av. price of 17 1/2
40 Mahoney, bought at 20. 
35 Phillips Petroleum, bot at 49
25 Atlantic Refining, bot at 56
30 Kelly Springfield, common, bought at 22. 
25 National Power and Light, bot at 44. 
30 Mother Lode Coalition (copper) bot at 3 (This I am buying today) 
I have made several sales at good profits, and this represents my new list, not what I have been doing. I made 110 % on $550 in less than two weeks - and other profits nearly as good. This is recent. I've been making profits off end on ever since I started nearly a year ago. My credit balance now is between 5 and 6 thousand. I haven't my monthly balance sheet yet. 
Don't be fooled when the papers say that "the market" has declined. There isn't any market; there are only individual stocks and groups of stocks. My stocks generally rise when the high priced gambling stocks have a smash. <del/> I buy value, determined by earning power, and in the long pull I can't fail to profit most satisfactorily. 
Don't be worried over occasional drops in price all these will rise.</p>

<fw type="curatorial">51</fw>
<fw type="letterhead"><figure/> DAILY SUNDAY 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
PUBLISHED BY THE PULITZER PUBLISHING CO. 
ST. LOUIS, MO.</fw>
<fw type="authorial">(3)</fw>
<p>I am sincerely glad that I have all of you and am able to treat you all pretty decently. It is a pleasure that I feel pretty steadily now, though sometimes when I'm off feed or perhaps more than ordinarily sick of "litrachoor" I can't see so well. But I am, deep down, delighted to be able to do this and to have you all to do it for. 
Mrs. B. is certainly a fine person. We want to do something for her Christmas, and Mona and I think we know what would probably give her pleasure. 
Mama, I am wondering if it would not be better for you and all ofus if you would consent to come up here for your birthday and stay only as long as you want to. You could take in some good shows, and you could go back when you felt that way. It would be more crowded for you here, of course, but wouldn't it be all right for a few weeks? Our time there would be so short and the trip so strenuous. We'd not get used to being there at all, and winter is no time anyway. Don't you want to have a change and go to some symphony concerts, recitals and shows? I think that would be fine, and Mona favors it very much. We are more than ordinarily happy here now, and you would be too, I think. </p>
<closer>
<salute>Endless love,</salute>
<signed>Jno. </signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>