<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.54.60">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, September 6th, 1929</title>
<author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.54.60</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, September 6th, 1929</title>
<date when="1929-09-06">September 6th 1929</date>
<extent>7 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1929-09-06"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4393739">Kirkwood (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="envelope">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.54.60.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">54</fw>
<note type="curatorial">54
Fink Collection
4</note>

<figure type="stamp"><ab>BRANSON SEP 6 1-PM 1929 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE</ab></figure>
<figure type="stamp"><ab>2CENTS2</ab></figure>

<ab>
<address>
<addrLine>Miss Enid Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>507 North Clay Ave</addrLine>
<addrLine>Kirkwood
Mo. </addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
</div1>

<div1 type="letter">
<opener>
<dateline>Friday Morning 
</dateline>
<fw type="curatorial">55</fw>
<salute>My Dear Enid;</salute>
</opener>

<p>We are having a long rain
It began three days ago and has been raining off on Ever since and this morn-ing the whole sky is
one big gray sheet of rain-I got up at half past five and carried in some wood filled the wood box
and the oven-I'm afraid the Moores will have a bad time to Move, altho it may be <del>a</del> dry by
Sunday - I have invited them to sleep at my house Sat. night. had expected to have only Mr &amp; Mrs. Macumber but the Dr. went on ahead so I asked Mrs. Moore and Ardella, - I'll get breakfast for them - they expect to start with the lost load Sunday morning Early yesterday was Mrs Macumbers birth-day And Grace came home and stayed over night with them and </p>

<fw type="curatorial">55</fw>
<p><unclear/> back last Evening-She has been looking for a letter from you School began here as it did Every Where else I guess - and those who are in a position to know say we will have the best school this year Branson has ever known,-Here is hoping-I'm so glad you are out for a business Diploma-Book keeping will make you an all around more useful secretary - I am so glad Dear Enid Girl I am so anxious about your success-Don't overlook little things it is the little things it is the little things that one sees without being told that count for an invaluable secretary and the dignity you carry with you will make your position dignified Look out fo rhte shiny eyes and soft words of your Employer or any man for that matter-Men are foosl about a pretty girl and sometimes I want </p>

<fw type="authorial">2</fw>
<fw type="curatorial">57</fw>

<p>to call your face your damnation sweet and pretty as it is - these are not words of an ugly cross old grandma but warnings against what has not only been my Experience and many more that have come into my life by other people Experiences.-So please think seriously of all I have written-It is not in Spleen I have written - It is not in Spleen I have written - It is not in Spleen I have written it but knowing the fitfalls I want to guard you because I love you Enid dear.-Now I never will preach to you again - I could say no more anyway if this does no good more would not either Any way you can feel sure that I shall never go to sleep at night or wake in the monring without a prayer for you - I spent a most un-happy time for too days and nights after you all drove away.-Even yet as I write about it a big hard <unclear/> comes </p>

<fw type="curatorial">58</fw>
<p>my throat and then goes splash in the pit of my stomache, But I said on Sunday morning look here Grand-ma <del>you</del> you are not the whole cheese. Just look around see all the things you could be doing and you standing here sobbing - I go tto work made the house in order, got my C.S. lesson wrote a couple letters,-Then on Monday I wen tot work at my chairs got them ready to enamel blue, but did not stop there - I sand papered the table - washed the little red rocker sand papered it and then you should have seen me with that brush and Enamel - you would be surpised to see how pretty the things look - you know I only had three chairs that I could fix up.-Well mrs. Macumber had one almost like mine and she offered it to me, So I have the table and four chairs-which will be all I will ordinarily need.-And then Enid you know the shape my dishes are </p>

<fw type="authorial">3</fw>
<fw type="curatorial">59</fw>
<p><unclear/> - just one <unclear/> <del>a</del> with a handle thru of my plates cracked and but thru pie plates left.-now I am not enumerating things with any relfection on you-I don't believe you broke one dish all Summer which is a mighty good record.-But I am saying this to make me feel justified for the thing I have done.-If you look in the Sears Roebuck Catalog on the top of the page 897 you will see the yellow stone glaze with big poppys all over them - well I have ordered the 22 piece set for $4.18 and I think they will just set off my blue dining room suit-Well I did not stop there I got a can of forest green Fix all and added black enough to make a beatuiful bronzy green and painted the red chair that was the Judges. Then I took the black enamel and gave your great grandfathers chair a coat and it is just beautiful-I am discoloring the cords and tassels this morning </p>

<fw type="authorial">60</fw>
<p><unclear/> will dye them orange, I think wheth re orange Tassels and the oriental cushion. the chair will look distinguished-but the End is not yet - I got a can of french gray Fixall and added some green making a very delicate shade of green in the gray and put it on the old squeaky Chair in the corner by the book case-and I put the plain green on the leather seat - say I feel like a million dollars now next I want ot mend my old lace curtains, wash the blue over drapes clean the windows-Then I'm going in the Mama's rug with a Vengence, - Dear Enid please don't say I thank you for letting me stay with you this Summer-Dear girl I thank you for wanting to stay - as I thot of it after you were all gone I thot of so many things I should have said, but I seemed dazed I will write to Sigurd next - love my little girls and be patient with my Alice be thotful of Mama and Daddy, and make the most of your chance now, very lovingly I am </p>
<closer>
<salute>Grandma Neihardt</salute>
<signed></signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>