<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
337 Fink Collection 140
Box 167
Branson, Mo.
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
(St. Louis Co.)
141
4.88     8
3.---
----
7.88
1
-----
8.88

75
69
---
6
8
---
14
82'
----

35
10
5
16
3
69
----

39
27
---
12
8
---
4

1419 N Dearborn St. 
Chicago
142
Here
This Morning, 1942.
Dear Ollie, Enot &amp; Nei:
<p>We were, as always, glad for your letters and news of your doings. I've made a search for the books, Enat, and found two only - and those, I'm afraid, you don't want.I'll continue the search, but I'm doubtful.</p>
<p>I'm sending the Culver reply &amp; a letter on his plan to write a study of Gaki &amp; his doings. You may stick them in a letter. The U. of Neb. letter was very friendly and went into detial about reduced enrollments &amp; drastic cuts in <unclear>appropriations</unclear>. I sent it to Hilda, &amp; can't remember getting it back. I think the military school is the best bet, since enrollments increase in such schools. I believe Culver is sincere &amp; might well offer me a job if a vacancy occurs.</p>
<p>Kemper seems not to have decided yet, and it may be</p>
143
<p>that something may come from there. They certainly believe in Gaki there and at Culver Home I'd love either! It is a month now since Kemper wrote me.</p>
<p>The rain I told you about <underline>did</underline> arrive - <underline>one</underline> day late, but it began heavy preparations on time! We had had 3 weeks of burning golden weather. Golly, how glad the grass &amp; gardens are! It's just like the weather they are said to have in Heaven now.</p>
<p>Doc is resting up after his long hard job of keeping as quiet &amp; cool as possible. He is <underline>such</underline> a restful person!</p>
<p>How's old Nei doing? I think &amp; think <underline>so</underline> very often about him. The dear, precious, excessively lovely, illuminated little cuss! Gaki wants to hug him write now, Hot do! <underline>Such</underline> a <underline>good boy</underline>! How is the wooden spoon holding out?</p>
Endless love to each and all.
Dad Gaki