<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.12.16.25">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, April 6, 1936</title>
<author>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</author>
<principal>Gossin Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.12.16.25</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, April 6, 1936</title>
<date when="1936-04-06">April 6, 1936</date>
<extent>pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1936-04-06"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4407066">St. Louis (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2020"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="envelope">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.12.16.25.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">67 Fink Collection 16</fw>
<note type="curatorial">Neihardt Branson Mo. </note>

<ab type="postmark">BRANSON APR 6 3-PM 1935 M.O. </ab>

<ab type="return">
<address>
<addrLine>Miss Enid Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>209 Ilene Apts.</addrLine>
<addrLine>5544 Pershing Ave</addrLine>
<addrLine>Saint Louis 
Mo.</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
</div1>

<div1 type="letter">
<fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
<opener>
<dateline>Monday AM 
April 6th 36
</dateline>
<salute>Darling Enid:</salute>
</opener>

<p>I have been want-ing to have a real talk with you - and so I'll do the next best thing. 
I have your big pic-ture in the front room where you smile at me as I sit in Grandma's big chair by the radio - and Daddy's big pic-ture is up on the wall beside the entrance to the dining room, so I can see you both! I have re arranged the front room, placing the Piano where it looks its best because I'm expecting Mr Webb soon with a customer.</p>
<fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
<p>Sig needs money as usual and if I can settle his debts here for him with the Piano sale I'll be so glad - then his salary will better cover his present needs. 
It is so cold here now I'm sick over our frozen blooms to say nothing of the fruit that is killed. But our little orchard is safe as it has not yet begining to bloom. 
I wish I could share my vision of Mother Earth with you right now, I can see her so perfectly, just the way I want to model her and place her against</p>

<fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
<p>our lovely hills surrounded by flowering fruit trees in the Spring and ever greens in Winter. I mean I want an inner half circle of low growing evergreens about the sculpture - and the fruit trees of our orchard will do the rest to make a perfect back ground. You remember the pic ture of you and Sig kneeling on either side of Grandma Cul ler? Well I'm going ot use that in part in my compo sition. You both will be looking up at Mother Earth in that way. I could say more but I'm afraid I'll only spoil what I am try</p>

<fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
<p>ing to tell about. You will have to wait till I can model it all.- 
I like the swap you sent me, it looks so natural dear- such a neat, trim little lady! 
I am very happy over your dancing - I know you will be good when you have had proper instruction. Indeed it is a matter of knowing not just making it up, of course. 
I am having curried rice for dinner today have you tried that? 
Alice is learning to bake bread now that she can bake my good cakes, icing 
</p>

<fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
<p>and all. 
I'm anxious for all of you girls to be able to bake bread. One Home made break baking is just what we need for the entire week and does it make good toast! Also it is a de-cided saving, I can prove that even with flour at 95 cents for 24 pounds - Miss Bennet spent the night with us and slept well and warm enough she said, which is hard for her to do. 
There is a Mother Cardinal trying to decide on a nice location for her babies. I do hope she will find one that the cat does not discover!</p>

<fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
<p> 
I'm not using your coat pattern dear, as what I wanted was a straight coat with <del>lose</del> open long sleeves, I wanted to make it of black crepe un-lived, and trim it with a few large red buttons; if I did this I'd have soemthing that would go well with that black dress of mine trimmed in red which Daddy got me recently, you remember? It may be I'll not need it at all though. So I've not yet decided to get the goods - It is so cold now and it will pro-bably turn very warm soon Then I can wear the rose ensemble you gave me. It</p>

<fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
<p>fits me exactly, and I'm in love with it! I wish I had some Bird houses on our place! Have you ever noticed any at your shops? 
Every body else in Branson lost most of them last winter! Ours look so dear and pretty! I gave old man <unclear/> 2 dozene the other day! Some day I'd like to have a natural looking swimming pool in our yard, with the Niobe Weeping Willow reflected in its depths - It would be per-fect! Maybe some day Bran son will buy this place</p>

<fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
<p>from you children as a <del/> public park, who knows? - I am so glad you like to be in St. Louis, as that is not so far away from Home, and yet it is a good center of culture. 
Yes we get Major Bowes Sunday evenings at 7. But our Radio is not in good condition. I am going to have Mr Fowler look it over shortly. Our Floor is not near as bad as it was, since I moved the Piano, loose on the Radio, I think Tell me about your self and your friends, and do</p>

<fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
<p>not trust your moods too much, dear girlie of mine! I hope you will soon tell me you have met the Church people at some gathering - and also that you have gone to see Mrs Lippman. She does not deserve to be neglected, neither does Mrs Holsen. 
Lippmans live on Alexander Drive. </p>

<closer>
<salute>Loads of Love to my own and only Enid girlie from her old</salute>
<signed>Mama.</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>