<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
75 Neihardt Collection 119
JOLIET
OCT 24
200 PM
1939
ILL.
Mrs. Mona Neihardt
Branson,
Missouri
(Taney County)
FRED J. WALSH, PRES.
FRANK DOYLE,
MANAGING DIRECTOR
224 ROOMS
175 WITH BATH
HOTEL LOUIS JOLIET
JOLIET, ILLINOIS
120
FRED J. WALSH, PRES.
FRANK DOYLE,
MANAGING DIRECTOR
224 ROOMS
175 WITH BATH
HOTEL LOUIS JOLIET
JOLIET, ILLINOIS
Tuesday Morning
Oct. 24, '39
Dear Girl:
<p>We drove over here from Ada, Ohio, between 4 P.M. and midnight, passing through Goshen at 7 P.M. Kreider had gone - a day early - and was evidently in much better condition than would have seemed likely when we left Sunday. His recovery was surely remarkable.</p>
<p>The alleged University at Ada (a Methodist institution) was like a gloomy cellar after the white light at St. Mary's. It was astonishingly obvious. They have a small &amp; weak college of Arts, &amp; are strong on Science, Engineering, Business Administration etc. I've been in few places mroe materalistic. It was almost funny, I felt. In the afternoon, I had a group for an hour, and often the head of the English Dept. quit talking</p>
121
FRED J. WALSH, PRES.
FRANK DOYLE,
MANAGING DIRECTOR
224 ROOMS
175 WITH BATH
HOTEL LOUIS JOLIET
JOLIET, ILLINOIS
-2-
<p>about his Uncle who was a cavalryman in the Civil War (15 minutes of this by way of introducing me!), I pitched into them on the subject of poetic (human) values. The Prof. <underline>did</underline> say they needed more of that and hope I'd come back. But I have no faith in that. A student <underline>did</underline> come to me afterward and say "Thank God for someone who believes in more than three dimensions!" He may have been insincere, but I hope not.</p>
<p>No wonder I felt as I did about Methodism in my boyhood! Without mysticism there is no religion; and so, most alleged religion is only a sort of organized ingorance and <underline>meanness</underline>. It's a pitiful world - beyond tears to express.</p>
<p>From here it is only 51 miles to DeKalb. We'll run over this evening. Then from noon tomorrow we'll</p>
122
FRED J. WALSH, PRES.
FRANK DOYLE,
MANAGING DIRECTOR
224 ROOMS
175 WITH BATH
HOTEL LOUIS JOLIET
JOLIET, ILLINOIS
-3-
<p>drive 339 miles to Evansville. A sister across the Ohio in Kentucky wants me at their institution while we're at Evansville, and I think we'll appear there Friday. She wrote her Master's Thesis on my work. One of those with whom I talked at the Nat. Council of Teachers of English. Sig asked $50 by wire, but will take what they can pay. I expect $50.</p>
<p>Mona, naturally I'd love to be with you at Knox, if you don't feel you should be with the girls in St. Louis. I can't decide for you, and I want you to do what you really want to do. There is no arrangement to board me there, and I'd think we <underline>could</underline> get a kitchenette. I'm going to let <underline>you</underline> do the planning; and what you plan will be right. You seemed so eager to be</p>
(over)
123
<note>number sequence correlates to miles to Evansville</note>
51
21
22
7
16
8
26
81
46
10
<underline>51</underline>
339
<p>with the girls, that I don't want to influence you.</p>
<p>I'm happy to know that your Joanie came out so well. I'll bet it's a dear thing. Pet the old lady for Grandan, and kiss 'Laine for Gaki.</p>
<p>I'm amazed at all you've done there - even tho' I know few details of it. And Max's letter-factory output flabbergasts her Dad with admiration! If she only had a nice new rubber nose, she'd be almost all right - pretty fair, anyway!</p>
love always,
Jno.
<p>You might see the girls &amp; find out whether or not you want to run up to Galesburg.</p>
<p>Don't feel unhappy about what I wrote regarding Hiddy; but certainly to regard that trait as a virtue is pathetic and dangerous. She <underline>should</underline> love Amama and feel tender toward her. I feel so.</p>