<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
15 Thompson Collection 49
[March 6, 1943]
Saturday P.M.
Precious Alice:
<p>We rec'd your letters and a postcard this morning.</p>
<p>Don't let yourself feel bad about us. We're all right and are going to be much all righter very soon. I'm not at all discouraged. A group in Lincoln is working on Gov. Griswold of Nebraska for me - a sort of "bring N. back to Neb" Movement. The idea is a state job for me until Sheldon retires - or at least <hi rend="underline"> a state job</hi> - They  may will succeed. There are other chances too.</p>
<p>Don't feel bad because you can't <hi rend="underline"> help</hi> now. There are no finer people than you are. Things will break for <hi rend="underline"> you</hi> too - <hi rend="underline"> soon</hi>. I do hope you 4 stick together, going either to Mexico City or to some other engagements. I moan, if this is possible; and why not?</p>
<p>I've written Truman still another - and a heluva lot hotter letter. One reached him Monday of this week. This last letter will reach him next Monday, Mach 8. I <hi rend="underline"> do</hi> hope you can <hi rend="underline"> still</hi> make Mexico City.</p>
(over)
50
-2-
<p>I'm getting really well, &amp; will be doing things by Monday. Was pretty sick with flu-bronchial attack; but came through finely. Mama &amp; I will move to our own little place on Sunday, March 14th; and maybe Amama will return. She is very lonely &amp; eager to be with us.</p>
<p>There's a chance for an <unclear>instructorship</unclear> at Washington U on April 1st.</p>
<p>Mama is a brick! Ran out &amp; got that job, by gosh, while I was down. Reading copy to a proof-reader! Wasn't that pretty wonderful?</p>
<p>Keep high-hearted <hi rend="underline"> somehow</hi>. You can! Nothing is going to defeat you!</p>
<p>We do love you, and admire you too, Precious Girl.</p>
Dad
<p>I sold my shotgun to the government for $30.35. Cost me less than $10 long ago. This pays interest due on April 13th. Isn't that bully?</p>
Dad
<p where="margins">Rec'd the stamps you sent &amp; used them on Truman.</p>
