<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Bancroft Nebr. Oct 23-38
Dear Mary: - 
I am not writing this myself on accent of my eyes - they have caused me trouble for some times, so asked a friend to answer you. 
The happenings we know of the home, all seem too personal to mention, <unclear/>. 
This week we had a very happy experience we will tell you about we were personally surprised to spend an evening with John Neihardt and his son Sigurd, who is a wonder ful pianist. In words of 
45
Omaha Pub Lib 
The young fry - I fell for Sigurd. he left here when seen. He resembles his father in features <unclear/> his pretty light moving hair, he is normal height - around 508 - He seemed as pleased to be with us as his father who was very happy meeting old friends here. 
Several of the old friends were evicted in by Mr Mrs. Burke to spend the evening. This was sauce of teh conversation that took place. He was on his May home from Wayne Normal, where he had 

been for two days - during tha ttime he spoke 7 hours interspersed by Sigurds playing the piano. Sigurd played a number of classics with such grace and easy. All so perfect, he carries no music met him. A party here said to Mr Neihardt - how grand to have your son traveling with you, He said 'not as father and son, I have no <unclear/> about me, we are companions as man to man. They pay the greatest respect to <unclear/> <del>each</del>
46
wish of the other
This being <unclear/> season the subject of yours came up we found that is one of his hobbies, guns-another is Jewels, that has been taken up the lost three years - He jokingly referred to his son's hobby - perfumes - He is so interested in Jewels. he has a New York jeweler sued him guns to study, we all had a <unclear/> to go under his test. his testing instruments are glass and file which he carries in his packet 

The Neihardt are now living in Brasow, after many years in St. Louis, more quiet for them in old home. Mona is again doing <unclear/> work, just now finished figure of Sigurd's baby girl, this is called first step, the pace is one fast in the air, Mr. had just helped her cash the veiled mother studying behind the child for protection, this will be placed in their garden when completed Sigurd has two little girls and lives near father. 
47
Sigurd has given up his work - giving his father tiem as the advance agent, Booking for his father, who is now giving much time to lecturing, they will make a complete town of the West next years. Have been planning to go to Omaha to consult <unclear/> regarding my eyes and hope to host some relief. 
Some one in Wayne asked about he as sent master, he could not recall that. 
Your friend Mrs. <unclear/> Ward
J.G. 