<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
280-281 Fink Collection 130
May 26
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
131
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
Monday, May 26, '41
Dear Enot and Oddie:
<p>I've had no news to share, but I've thought of you often. My news even now concerns jewelry. I've just finished a rose-quartz-whtie-sapphire set of three pieces that will give the baby something to rubber at when it's sucking &amp; something to grab after, and pull off, maybe, if the breaks are right: The ring worked out all right, but unforeseen flows in the material make the job less than satisfactory to me. Rose quartz of gem quality is very rare in sizable pieces. The three-piece set is of gem quality.</p>
<p><underline>And</underline> I have made up two stones for Stick pines - five stones on brilliant-cut golden citrime. One is for Oddie, if he'll promise to wear it as a habit. Maybe he'd prefer the carved emerald jade set for a pin, since jade has</p>
132
<p>An overtone of meaning for him. But I had nothing to do with the jade piece.</p>
<p>It's funny writing to two people at once. You get all mixed up. Anyway this is to both and each.</p>
<p>I'll bet your place is beautiful, with the roses &amp; things doing their stuff. Ours is too. Do the hedge twigs seem happy &amp; posperous for the most part?</p>
<p>I'm sending a folder. Thought you'd like to see how it worked out. The photo is rotten, but why have another taken? Mama's bust is the real picture. And surely it is a masterly job. We're all happy about it, &amp; all who have seen it have been really impressed.</p>
<p>I hope the Wub is being good to its Mama. And here's love for all Three of You.</p>
Dad.
133
<underline>JOHN G. NEIHARDT</underline>
<p>For further information, see "Who's 
Who in America," International
Who's Who," Columbia Encyclopedia,
Webster's unabridged Dictionary,
Everybody's Encyclopedia, etc - - -</p>
<p>Neihardt is writing a national epic style. He has spent many years upon it, and his time has been well spent. He is leaving us a legacy of heroic and inspiring literature."
-Cleveland Plaindealer.</p>
<p>"A tremendous piece of work, splendidly done." - The New York Sun.</p>
<p>"Let us fervently pray that these Songs may take rank with, if not prededence over, Scott and Tennyson in our schools." -The yale Review.</p>
<p>"This cycle of poems of the heroic period of American hisotry that Mr. Neihardt is creating on epic lines, is one of the profoundly notable and one of the few original things in the development of American poetry." -Wm. Stanley Braithwaite in teh Boston Transcript.</p>
<p>"It is a pleasure to find a poet able to make himself heard and able to interpret his own poetry inteh melodious and rhythmical fashion in which Mr. Neihardt did his. Its dramatic quality came home to us with increased power." - Dora V. Smith, Prof. of Education UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA.</p>
<p>"During and after his reading before the Fine Arts Society of Texas at Dallas intense enthusiasm prevailed; surprise and admiration as much for his natural genius and originality as for his sculptured artistry. He is the American Homer, the spirit of the West." -Pope Collier, President FINE ARTS SOCIETY OF TEXAS, Dallas, Texas.</p>
<p>"Mr. Neihardt made a profound impression at CARELTON COLLEGE, both as an interpreter of his own poetry and as an educator. In fact, we liked him so much that we tried to induce him to stay." -Dr. J. E. Boodin, Professor of Philosophy, CARELTON COLLEGE, Northfield, Minn.</p>
<p>"The attendance at Mr. Neihardt's lectures here at the University increased with each succeeding lecture. I think this is one of the best compliments that a student body could pay to any lecturer." - MUNICIPAL UNIVERSITY OF OMAHA.</p>
<p>"His appearance in Columbia was in every sense a literary event in the History of the University." - UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI.</p>
<p>"Mr. Neihardt instructed and entertained his audience. They were delighted with him." - Prof. Charles K. Moschter, LEHIGH UNIVERSITY, Bethlehem, Pa.</p>


