<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Fink Collection 
72
154
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON JUL10 3-PM 1936 MO. 
<FIGURE/> 
Miss Enid Neihardt 
5544 Pershing Ave. 
Ilene Apartments. 
301
St. Louis 
Mo. 

155
July 9
Thursday-
Enid Darling:
"I'm all for it" dear, dear girlie of mine. But a certain statement in your letter makes me feel the need to say this: No one at all fair can blame my leadership for your early love affairs - as you know in your own heart that all the King's horses and all the King's men coudl not have saved you those expe riences - that you did what you did knowingly - although not realizing fully the results. I know that Daddy must re-member how might after night I worried over your having to be here in Branson with <unclear/> -

156
fit friends - He has not for gotten how many times I said to him "Oh John I am heartsick over Enid just "not thing" here getting older and with no companion but D-and young people must have some pleasure - we cannot deny her that "Act the time Daddy seemed in a queer con-dition himself - of course he was full of the work he had to do - and nothing I could say seemed to call forth any action - Grandma too was mixed up in this and the many falsified talks that 

3
157 
went on over in her house that I never did wholly know about - all I know was that Daddy was over at Grandma's again - I don't want to recall those times they were too wrong all around - Where I was to blame, was in trusting you and D-. I ad-mit I was a fool - but I talked many times to him and to you appedling to his honor. Daddy then had all the power to kick him out that he had later. Only he believed I was against him 

4
158 
whereas I was just teh same "go between" that I have always been, trying to see everybody's side - which is a mistake of mine, for that way you suffer for all parties and not one party understands you - and I'm afraid you do no good, although your heart is O.K. I am very happy that you have decided to be led by Daddy - but you must again be fair, and remember that you have written me many letters in many moods - and that only lately have you come out firmly with any 

159
definited point of view. 
Darling my blessings are upon you whereever you may go, whatever you may do - and I will always love you witha  love tha tis just yours - you have been and are my very dear, good, love ly daughter and I am very grateful to you for what you are doing for Daddy and for the "much" that you have done for me. 
It will be fine to see you if you <del>de</del> decide to come home - and it will be O.K. 

160
if you decide it best that you do not come home. I under-stand the aversion you must feel for Branson - I would have, if I were you - Indeed that is the way I feel about Bancroft, Nebraska. 
It is so pleasant here in the front room. We have Sig's old fan going, and a new one Virginia brought. and any way this house was always cool in the Summer! 
Loads of Love to Daddy and she same to you my girlie
As always 
Mamma. 