<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
336 Fink Collection 135
July 21, 1942

Neihardt 
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON JUL22 3 -PM 1942 M.O.
UNITED STATES POSTAGE 3 CENTS 3
Mrs Albert Petri
Mrs Sigurd Neihardt
5833 Bartmer
St. Louis, 
Mo.
136
Branson 
July 21st
Dearest Hilda:
<p>Your letter telling of entertaining the dear parents was so welcome adn I am sure they as well as you yourself feel much happier because of the effort you went to to give pleasure. That is always worthwhile.</p>
<p>Maxie tells of the great heat and your head being affected - so please darling be very very careful and keep out of the direct rays</p>
2.
<p>of the Sun, as you might now <underline>more</underline> easily be hurt in that way than before the first attack.</p>
<p>I hope you are a great deal better now.</p>
<p>We here have been very comfortable, even in the heat becuase we sit out under our Lady - Tree and there is always a delightful breeze.</p>
<p>Amama feels a lot better and I am hoping she will want to remain through August at <underline>least</underline></p>
137
3
<p>after which she will probably be wanting to go back East once mroe. I dread the thought of any more travel alone for her - but she has made up her mind to do that till she drops in her path - and she does not want to be told what to do, does nto want to be loved and cared for by me anyway at the last - so I can do nothing about it but continue to make her as happy as possible while</p>
4
<p>she <underline>is</underline> here.</p>
<p>You should do as you see fit about your ring - I consider it yours.</p>
<p>Please tell Albert we do not expect him to make so expensive a trip down here now. We Know how good and dear you both are and that you'd <underline>like</underline> to come.</p>
<p>My bust of Daddy really is a fine thing now, and we have a lot of my small pieces cast. I hope to have them rea-</p>
138
5
<p>dy to sell for Xmas up in St Louis, and around here. I hope to have the whole <sic>ammount</sic> we owe on the house this year by September as Daddy has $100 from her lectures and we can save $5.00 per weeK here out of the 15 Amama is paying. Swell! We had a wonderful, much needed rain last night. We sleep in the house but strtch out in the hammock every evening till later under the stars. It is so</p>
6
<p>lovely. Today it is cool!</p>
<p>Daddy has broken his glasses again, too bad! It makes it bad for him but luckily he can see with mine so we give each other my pair, back and forth all day!! I am writing now without glasses, but I think you will be able to read my letter anyway, not? Please write me a detailed letter all about the little things of every</p>
139
<p>Day doings - even to how many holes you have <unclear>damed</unclear> etc!</p>
Devotedly loving you, my precious, one and only Hilda- 
I am always your
Mutti.
<p>I have written Alice about her shoes. M.</p>