<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
<del>11,12,13,14</del> 11
<unclear/> TAYLOR <unclear/> 
<figure/> THE SOUTHERN 
PAULENE SCHAFER. 
<UNCLEAR/> 
<figure/>
H.C. Paulsen@pager. Rates $1.50 to $3.00 European 
El Reno, Okla., May 18/1922
Dear Ones:- 
Well, I'm here after an all day's dirty ride up from Dallas, nearly 300 miles. Got a noon with faith at 4 o'clock & had a good hat soak, so I feel ready for the affair taught Got only 5 hrs. in bed last night-to bed at midnight up at five. 
Schafflemayer will send the dope from the Dallas news about my stunt there I have another article in my pocket up stairs. Gotoff finely down there & made bully friends of the right sort. Went to Two painters' studies - among the best in their field 

12
<unclear/> TAYLOR <unclear/> 
<figure/> THE SOUTHERN 
PAULENE SCHAFER. 
<UNCLEAR/> 
<figure/>
H.C. Paulsen@pager. Rates $1.50 to $3.00 European 
El Reno, Okla., /192
-2-
in America. Reaugh paints prairies & cattle - stunning Eisenlohr paints landscapes & they are wonders! Both came out to my reading & were enthusiastic. They both said: "You know my prairies!" There's lots of artistic ability in Dallas, & some big things will surely develop there. It seems I may be back there next fall or winter, they spoke of it-many did
I'm here alone now, but Thompson will arrive at 6:35. It's six now
The Schoffemayers are dear people. Poor Schoff <unclear/> is the same 

13
<unclear/> TAYLOR <unclear/> 
<figure/> THE SOUTHERN 
PAULENE SCHAFER. 
<UNCLEAR/> 
<figure/>
H.C. Paulsen@pager. Rates $1.50 to $3.00 European 
El Reno, Okla., /192
-3-
hopelessly scattered man of many gifts, & Mrs. S. still uses him as her baby. He'll <del/> never land, & his ambition to do something big is pathetic. He seemed to cling to me for encouragement. I told him that he must mistrust his facility & his many gifts; that he spent his power though a <unclear/>, & he should get a nozzle! He told me in glee that when he sits down to <del/> write, the stuff just pours out as from an <unclear/> supply! I said: "Schoff, I hate to write, 'its' so damned hard to do & comes so slowly!" he was flabbergasted.

14
<unclear/> TAYLOR <unclear/> 
<figure/> THE SOUTHERN 
PAULENE SCHAFER. 
<UNCLEAR/> 
<figure/>
H.C. Paulsen@pager. Rates $1.50 to $3.00 European 
El Reno, Okla., /192
-4- 
They may come up next summer. I told them to spend a vacation year at Branson & I'd hypnotize Schofflenmayer & make him do whatever is in him. 
They have a pretty brick one-story house. Very nice 
Lots of love to all of you. Kisses for all the wubs. I'll be home Monday. I think may not have quite as much as I hoped, but it will be near $100 anyway - which is good. 
Jno 