<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
71a
1355 No. Dearborn
June 16, 1942
Our 
Bokemian
Basement
<strike>The 
Palmetto</strike>
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
Dear Daddy, Mama, Eny, Ollie, 
Nei at 9917
and - Hilda, Albert, Sig, Max, Joan, and Elaine at 5833,
<p>Hello Everyone! Here we are, back in our city of excitiment and good - happenings, Chicago. It is queer how short a time it seems since we left here for Detroit although in fact it was a good three weeks. We were lucky in being able to locate ourselves so quickly, and so near our former Dearborn address - within one block of it. How Bohemian we are! Our apt. is a "front basement" abode, which of course is completely redecorated and suffers from none</p>
(2)
<p>of the typical cellar-dankness worthy of a tragic opera. Quite on the contrary, we find our little home both comfortable and attractive, with its large living room containing an Murphy roll-away, a studio couch, davenport and chair (overstuffed) set, fireplace with mantle, and picture of General MacArthur (thrown in for good measure), its roomy and ultra modernly equipped kitchen, and its combination bath and dressing room. We are now completely unpacked, our abode has been straightened up, adn we have tucked a good breakfast safely away in our tummies.</p>
<p>I will go back in memory several days (my-</p>
71b
(3)
The 
Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>what an effort!) for your benefit, as well as mine. Last week we spend mainly in rehearsing - working on our new reperitoire. Meanwhile, George's Mother, Mrs Carson, did much work on our costumes - adding tarlatan underskirts, etc., and George bought new wardrobe trunksm a baggage rack, and repairs on his Plymouth (a good littler puller it is, too!). As I've already explained in a recent letter to Hilda, we did not work <underline>nearly</underline> as long in Detroit as George had intended that we should. The knee-trouble, A.G.</p>
(4)
<p>V.A> trougble, and most of the incompetency of our agent in arranging for dates in apple-pie order, kept us from earning what we expected. However, we did accomplish a great deal we couldn't have under any circumstances, while holding down a job. So, all in all - it is O.K. We just have to hold out a few more days here till we receive definite news of an engagement. I shall hold this letter till this afternoon - when George will call and tell us what has happened since yesterday.</p>
<p>While in Chicago, we shall rehearse, get costume fittings for our new repertourer (have several auditions, and</p>
71c
(5)
The 
Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>generally collect ouselves. Anything good requires a bit of holding out - and a good measure of <sic>gril</sic> - yes?</p>
<p>We received a letter from Madame Cassan per Snippy, the day (yesterday) we left Detroit. Madame is in the hospital, as you told me she would be, and is getting along nicely, although she is very nervous and can't reveice visitors at present. She is happy for us, Snippy reports. I wrote madame I could begin paying her soon - and that I <underline>shall</underline> do.</p>
<p>The lawyer affair is nothing of great importance. I meant not to mention it at</p>
(6)
<p>all, but simply forgot. You see, I still owe that dentist something. He cut my lip very noticeably, as you know, and I was told by everyone I shouldn't even pay him. taking my time to pay seems only right to me - and I told this lawyer who represents the dentist that I thought so. I must pay a certain amount by June 23 (only $9 more) and everything will be O.K. If I can't do this till a bit later, I shall simply tell him so - for they both have a <underline>damn</underline> lot of nerve to approach me for payment after inflicting an injury (especially since it concerns my looks) upon me! That's the way</p>
71d
(7)
The
Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>I think. Don't worry one bit about this. It is all settled now - and it is purely my affair. Besides, I resent the attitude heartily - although it changed with my explanation!</p>
<p>Owing to the several large expenses I had in Detroit, my money went quicker than it otherwise would have - but we'll soon be earning again, so I can begin paying dividends, as an investment should!</p>
<p>To continue with our life, we left our Palmetto apt. yesterday morning at 9:00, at which time George called for us. The morning was glorious - <unclear/></p>
(8)
<p>sky, golden sunshine, <unclear/> fresh air - and our <unclear/> sand, scarcely less audibley than the birds, as we sprang out into this slendor. After breakfast as guests of Mrs. Carson, we arranged our bags and baggage and climbed into our limousine. There were tears in the Madame's eyes as she kissed us all good bye, for she is as fond a mother as our dear mama! Our trip was a lovely one - we drove along at 40 miles an hr., enjoying the "<unclear/> and pastoral" loveliness all about us - and the thrill of being a <unclear/>. We managed to stop awhile at a roadside</p>
71e
(9)
The
Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>table to devour sandwiches and cherries and feel the coolness of a country breeze blowing through our be-curled hair. We sand and talked of many things until a flat tire stopped our train of chatter for some ten minutes, and then we resumed it again. The whell on the spare tire was off-center, we soon discovered, so in the next town we spent a happy hour indulging in such childhood joys as skipping rope and playing hopscotch till the amiable garagemen there had succeeded in <unclear>enter</unclear> changing wheels and tires. For this service George paid the huge sum of twenty-five cents - and besides, Sylvia</p>
(10)
<p>and I won a Mound a penny gumball machine. Chicago we reached at 8:00, half an hr. earlier than was expected, and we at once set about finding an apt. Our good luck brought us here - and George as usual acted as porter.</p>
<p>After a bite to eat in our favorite corner drug store, we three "escapadoes" (or something else romantic) went to see George and his Grandmother to discuss certain matters. The dear, French cherubic Grandmother met us with kisses, smiles, and a torrent of endearing French phrases as we entered her charming little high-ceiling apt. The latter is located within one of the brownstone houses in the 800 (828) glk. of Dearborn, just five blks. away from us, and this will be George's home while</p>
71f
(11)
The
Palmetto
John R at Hancock
Detroit, Mich.
<p>he is here in Chicago. About 10:00 we left the Grandmother's for our new apt., and guess whom we met? Eddie, Sylvia's brother who is here in quest of radio work. We were overjoyed to see him, of course, especially  since we'd been trying to get in touch with him and couldn't. He took us out for a sundae before our bedtime - for he too lives very near here, and hadn't far to go home.</p>
<p>This morning we arose at 10:00, shopped, adn ate breakfast. Eddie came around noon and we all went to the beach (Oak St.) for lunch and a sunbath. (sandwiches and other such things). Eddie also came for dinner, after George had come to tell us what's up. We are to go to Jacksonville</p>
(12)
<p>Florida after our Milwaukee engagement, if it comes out. Tomorrow we'll know about that.</p>
<p>We rehease and have costume fittings tomorrow. Our agent will be at rehearsal. Will tell other developments later.</p>
<p>Hil thanks <underline>so</underline> much for letter rec'd today. Thank Albert for me too. Tell everyone else to <underline>write</underline> whenever tney can.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice
<p>Package will follow me here by forwarding.</p>