<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
37a
September 28, 1940
Saturday
Dear Mom &amp; Dad;
<p>I'm taKing time off to get thsi written. At present I am sitting out bacK in one of the chairs in the sunshine while the Wubs stay in the sand box. I taKe them out for an hour every morning &amp; late afternoon. I can't get them to go out alone and I guess its just as well.</p>
<p>Yes we are planning a birthday dinner. Eny, will come in and Mitcheal will be here. Sig wont' be off that evening. He gets Friday evenings off-</p>
<p>I can't get time to go to a dime store for the coat pattern but Joan doesn't need it until much later. It is perfectly swell for you to maKe it often the Denver trip.</p>
<p>Dad - I enclose a letter from Davison at Boulder.</p>
<p>We are now worKing the liver our of NebrasKa. If we could just get mroe there. Business certainly is slow and will probably be worse until after election.</p>
<p>Its been cold here too out warmer the last day or two.</p>
<p>Mom - I'm so gald you are at last maKing clothes for yourself. I feel since you will have plenty of opportunity to wear the coat you are maKing.</p>
<p>Alice is spoiling me by doing dishes all the time. I am most grateful to her for the many things she does for me. I tell her its liKe <strike/> having a maid. Bless her heart she is one swell girl.</p>
2
<p>Mom - I have neglected to say this but Sig has no time to worK up the Naila waltz. This can be done later but at present he feels that the time he does have must be devoted to Keeping up the numbers he has and all spare time he spends on the Mozart <strike/> concerts. I am sorry but it is all he can do at present. If he can get the concerts worKed up sometime this year he might have a chance to play with the symphony. At any rate it seeems to us that that plan is better for the present. If he wants to play for Madam he can play what he already has. Is it necessary that he have the Naila expesically for her?</p>
<p>He has to worK nearly all day at the store on inventory but he gets paid time adn a half for overtime which we are very grateful for.</p>
<p>Of course we realize that <unclear/> people "exposing oneself" is vitally necessary. But that is easier said than done at present. But the time will come when this will be somewhat easier. Sig must get at least another month of practice.</p>
<p>You asKed in your letter if Sig was better off worKing for Western then for the Aviation outfit. Definitely he is. Curtis Wright is only paying $20 per weeK on assembly lines. However there is the chance that Sig might get a job higher up in the plant. It remains to be seen. Its so hard <strike/> to find out about these things when mornings he needs for practice &amp; the evenings he is at home he &amp; Hilda practice together. So time is the bug-a-boo with us. The weeKs have flown here and there aren't enough hours in the day to suit any of us.</p>
37b
3
<p>Had Mom Waisy came up. I hope she is well.</p>
<p>I'd love to see the place. I <strike/> personally would hate to see it sold. I Know we all feel pretty much that way but I hardly Know what to say. Time only can show us what must be done. Things will worK out O.K. I'm sure.</p>
<p>Theres a great deal of puzzlement in life <strike>but</strike> and unless one Keeps a definite goal the scheme grows muddled and the sight of the goal fades. Sometimes I get tired and feel that things are muddled up pretty much and wonder if they will ever grow light. Then I remember the things we have talKed about at home - about the upset condition of the world and affairs of people all about us and I can see that, given enough time, with faith, things usually came to a head. Then new strength comes. Perhaps that is as near prayer as I'll ever get. But to approach it at all is something I'm grateful for. That strength has to come from somewhere.</p>
<p>I want Alice to mail this for me so will close for now.</p>
<p>Don't forget us in the pasture Dad - we need all the help we can get in many ways.</p>
<p>We are very happy in this little place. Surprising how well we get along. The girls are so swell.</p>
Always loads of love,
Max &amp; Wubs.
<p>P.S. Dad, I englose a letter from Davison at Boulder. You will need it on your trip. The contract blanKs are upstairs in the reddish letter foling case.</p>
over
<p>you might put this letter with the <strike>blanKs</strike> contracts of Boulder &amp; Denver so that it will <strike>not</strike> not be misplaced.</p>
Love,
Max.