<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
56v
1425 N. Dearborn
Chicago, Ill.
May 12, 1942.
<p>Please, Mama, send my white and blue lastex (new from Hilda) bathing suit.)</p>
Dear Daddy and Mama, and Everyone else there,
<p>I was <underline>so</underline> happy to get your dear encouraging letter, Daddy. How I am praying that you will soon be given peace of mind (Good gosh - how you of all people deserve it!) by the acceptance of that marvelous position you speak of. It would certainly be fitting too, that you should return in honor to Nebraska - with practical assiss</p>
(2)
<p>tance included! I know Mama would <underline>love</underline> the cultural atmosphere there as well as everything else. If it is good, it will come - that must be true. That would be <underline>marvelous</underline> for Ollie too - and could he grow a garden <underline>there</underline>!</p>
<p>We entertained our partner - director, George Leon, and his charming chubby, dear French grandmother this evening. We had a grapefruit juice, meatloafs, potatoes, stuffed and baked</p>
56w
(3)
<p>au gratin) lime fruit jello, your home baked bread, Mama, peas, coffee, devil's food cake (which they brought), and butterschotch pudding for dinner. Then we spent the remainder of our evening till now talking about dancing and all points of the "theatre world". George and his Grandmother (iwith whome he stays here) speak French fluently. Wish you were here, Mama! You'd love Mrs. Leon.</p>
(4)
<p>We are rehearsing several hours daily. According to George, we are improving, and hope like --- to have our numbers in shape by Monday, when we are as now planned, to open in <underline>Detroit</underline>. Friday is music dress rehearsal, and the Coutness plus several agents are coming to watch. Pray for us! We are to leave Sunday for Detroit so we can be fresh for our</p>
56x
(5)
<p>opening Monday. We really feel we need more rehearsing, since the original girls has 6 wks. rehearsing, whil we will have had only <underline>2</underline> wks. These dances take a lot of oomph and artistry plus precision. We'll see how all goes this week. Details are being atteded to now plus regular rehearsing - costumes, correct make-up, etc. We now knwo 3 complete numbers - 2 fairly well, 1 shakily.</p>
(6)
<p><underline>Please</underline> pray for us, <unclear/> it is what <underline>we</underline> make of these dances that will pick them over. Specialties are like that.</p>
<p>We haven't registered for sugar, and can't till June. Can you possibily still get out a card for me - on shoes too. I've heard, besides the sugar rationing card. Please <underline>can</underline> you send me some sugar, as we must pay back some we've had to borrow from George. I hope you don't mind too much all this asking. I'm forced to do till we</p>
56y
(7)
<p>get started earning. All depends on our success now - and we must hand on till we can earn.</p>
<p>As for money, I do need a few dollars now to tide me over to Detroit till we earn. I have around $4 left - must pay that much for this week's rent here. Carfare and very few more groceries are all we'll spend money for the rest of this week. How I hope I'm not pressing you too terribly now. I do greatly dislike "milking" you, but you realize that it will</p>
<margin>Mama, you are such a <underline>dear</underline> to send <unclear/> bread. It means <underline>more</underline> than you can <unclear/>.</margin>
(8)
<p>be only a short while till I'll be earning, and this help from you <underline>now</underline> means everything. Words are so inadequate to tell what I feel in gratitude to all of you, in every way. Maybe you can consider me an investment, n'est-ce pas?</p>
<p>Hilda, your letter was a great thrill for me. You don't know how happy it makes me feel to know you miss me! Yes, you <underline>must</underline> sing - and you will. Albert is almost an unbelievable person, and I love him <underline>too</underline>! You tell him so - because I have a perfect right to say such a thing about him now!</p>
<p>More later, We saw carnation contented for Mon. at 9:00.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice