<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.12.1">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Hilda Neihardt to Mona Martinsen Neihardt, 1936</title>
<author>Neihardt, Hilda</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.12.1.2</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Hilda Neihardt to Mona Martinsen Neihardt, 1936</title>
<date when="1936">1936</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
<term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
<term>Neihardt, Maxine</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Hilda</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1936"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Martinsen Mona</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2020"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>


</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.12.1.2.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">1</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>Tuesday afternoon
1936
</dateline>
<salute>Dearest Mama:</salute>
</opener>

<p>You cannot well know what your letters mean to me: they are truly inspiring. I am grateful and if my saying what I know <del/> he true makes you happy, I regret I have not expressed myself before. But here is how it is: each day I know more about my-self, more about what I really do think and feel. You understand, do you not? I am young, but no longer so very young as I was. Be that - watco? 
I was so glad fo rhte letters you sent me from Enid and Max. but I do not understand waht Enid meant when she said Daddy sent me $5 extra teh must be mistaken, for I did not get 3 extra. 
I'll have to see about my teeth I sent for a few thing I need right now; namely, shall, hat, gloves, pajamas, stockings. I'll have time to get my teeth fixed during the time between the end of the spring term and the beginning of the summer term. I'll have the time, if I have the money and it is possible to do the job. 
Do you really want Betty to come to Branson this summer? She said there's nothing she'd rather do, and that she'll just think and think about it from now on. She had such a good time last summer. 
I have to study quite a bit today I prepare <unclear/> </p>

<fw type="authorial">2</fw>
<p><unclear/> I have to give for N.N.C.A. tomorrow evening. I have charge of the program for our quest groups. This group in the one on Interpreting Religion. I am studying nervoisu <unclear/>, and I'm going, although of course only superficially, compare them and the Christian religion. We hit last time upon the idea that perhaps we are wrong when we think of ours as the only one. 
Nearly everyone is dissatisfied with President Anderson. The general opinion, as near as I can see
of both students &amp; teachers is that he has stepped into shoes far too big for him. They say, however that it would be hard for anyone to take Dr. Conn. 
I hear regularly from Lacke. He sent me a <unclear/> he made. It's a swell jot. I like him letter than anyone I know - always have. I believe I told you that at Xmas time, did I not. </p>

<closer>
<salute>Now I need to start studying for that talk, so I'll close, with across and mountains of love,</salute>
<signed>Hilda</signed>
<note>Give my love to Alice. She's a swell girl, &amp; I think of her a lot. I must write her soon. <figure/></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>