<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
374 Fink Collection 81
[May 27, 1973]

<unclear/>, 4920 S. Blackstone, 
Chicago

25 CHICAGO
MAY 28
230 PM
1943
ILL.

Mrs. O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
St. Louis County
Mo.
82
Chicago, Ill. 
May 27th 43
Dearest Children:
<p>Your dear letter, Enid, and then the wonderful birthday card and the exquisite, beautiful pair of hose make me feel very much in your debt - Many thanks - and please believe that I am especially grateful to you for remembering that I probably needed <hi rend="underline">just</hi> what you chose for me. <hi rend="underline">So</hi> many thanks!</p>
<p>Amama gave me a lovely dress up hat, and a pair of hose - as well as a marvelous, singing hot water Kettle. Otti sent $5.00 for me so I'll get a dress-up pair of shoes with that - Daddy wants me to get myself a nice dress - so I feel terribly well treated. Joanie</p>
83
<p>wrote me a sweet "Happy Birthday" letter and Hilda and Albert gave me $3.00 to spend for <hi rend="underline">just</hi> what I want. So I feel I am terribly spoiled!</p>
<p>Amama had a wonderful cake ordered - which Hilda attended to getting with Happy birthday, Moria, upon it. We had Seymours over and lights, and strawberries and all to make a great festive occasion. On the evening of the 25th, we had an invitation to the Bookfellows, dinner at the Sherman Hotel, and Songs by Hilda Neihardt Petri. You would have been pleased with our Hilda who sang beautifully - Dear girlie! She certainly has improved greatly - and her voice was specially lovely in a "Lullaby" that I know you would have been pleased to hear - So sweet and soft the whole</p>
84
<p>thing!</p>
<p>Amama has gone downtown today alone - She is going to go to the Bank - then to a Movie, and afterwards to meet with one of Dicks' Xwives. She went last Sunday to Ottocars' Xwife in Evanstone - and feels that "<hi rend="underline">I</hi> never see the <hi rend="underline">other</hi> side because I am unable to understand anything but <hi rend="underline">my</hi> side!!" I suppose by saying this, she feels she can understand my having told her I did not care to be drawn in to <hi rend="underline">knowing</hi> any of Ottocar's former wives, as I felt to be friendly with them would be <hi rend="underline">disloyal</hi> to Ottocar and Gwynne - So that is that! Funny, not?</p>
<p>She has already started to Kiss Mr Seymour - and I don't Know who else she'll start to slobber over - disgusting!</p>
85
<p>Daddy has been having trouble with his eyes - but to make a long story short, I believe Friday he will have good glasses. He has received a <hi rend="underline">real</hi> offer from the Kansas City University for 3 months, from September to December - So he may make a change. I'm all ready to go to Kansas City although I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> like Chicago -</p>
<p>The Branson deal has finally fallen through.</p>
<p>I think you are wonderful to have such a good garden in spite of all this rain. Almost everyone is having trouble to get things planted.</p>
Loads of love to my best of little families - and count on your Mom for July 20th!
Devotedly Mom