<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- on page 12; not completely transcribed !-->
30a
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
February 5, 1943.
Dear Mama,
<p>Here in our little hotel room, each occupied in his own little method of amusement, sit the members of our little troupe! We have had quite a busy day; rehearsing and all, and are now relaxing a bit. Therefore, I am taking this opportunity to write the account of our little automobile accident of nearly three months ago, which you, dear Mutter, requested of me!</p>
<p>It was on the morning of November the 9th</p>
(2)
<p>that we were driving along the highway somewhere outside Savannah, Georgia. We had driven thusly all night, but had just stopped fifteen minutes previously at a little trucker's cafe in order to have our breakfasts. Therefore, we felt well fortified enough to continue for the few hours necessary to reach Newport News, Virginia where we were to fulfill our next engagement. How happy we were that morning! I shall never forget the beauty we seemed to <hi rend="underline">feel</hi> as strongly as to <hi rend="underline">see</hi> that morning of mornings. Maybe there</p>
30b
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>was a presentiment of the <hi rend="underline">nearness</hi> to the other world which we were so soon to experience. Who knows! Anyway, one thing is certain - there was a goodly amount of beauty abroad at the hour and in that picturesque country. All the little draws, as we drove along, were bulging with white, ghostly fog, trees laden with Spanish moss assumed queer shapes in their garments of mist, and just above the horizon rose the sun, a ball of burnished orange. We were unusually peaceful, happy yes, even inspired, that</p>
(4)
<p>morning, and were finding joy in talking of the beauty all around us - when something like a nightmare took place. What I now remember, as was what I remembered immediately after the accident is not a clear, ordered description of what actually took place. No, it is rather like a surrealistic painting - a queer conglomeration of pictures and feelings - each of which is clear in itself, but which is strangely dreamlike in its entirety. The severve of horizontaly wooden slats, the feeling of sudden terror, the impact of collision, the crazy zig-zagging of the heavy</p>
30c
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>Buick in which we rode then nothingness! How easily could we have stayed in that darkness or have come out on the other side of it! Why we awoke here I do not know. The next thing I knew Sylvia was shaking me by the arm saying "Get out, Alice!" "I can't," said I, "I'm pinned in." Actually, the dashboard was caved in so that it practically sat on my lap, and George, at the wheel, was pressed in between the latter and the seat in almost unbelievable fashion. When I got a chance to see Syl</p>
(6)
<p>via - my hair fairly stood on end, for her head was covered with blood from top to chin. I got out and crumpled down on the grass (Vaguely, I remember all this) beside the wreck. Soon someone came  to me, picked me up and asked if I was already. I really though I was fine now, for after that first glimpse of my bloody fist with the white, severed tendons protruding from a gaping wound, I forgot my injury almost completely. As we were told afterward by our friends and co-troupers, we were piled at once into our producer's wife's</p>
30d
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>car and driver eighty miles an hour to the next town, little Ridgeland, So. Car. That ride I scarcely remember - only George's puzzled expression as he muttered dreamily and self-accusingly "But I was driving!", Sylvia's bloody, dazed countenance, and Doris' bunged - upface with the large goose - egg on right temple. We arrived quickly at the hospital, and were led like willing lambs into the small, pleasantly - un hospitalish operating room. There George was laid face up on the white table while his appalling deep, sunken, gash just above the left eye was sewn up. The other victims I could see, and hear, too in various places if the room</p>
(8)
<p>while their less-serious <unclear/> were attended to. When at last the doctor came to me (I was sitting on a chair witnessing all this "rehabilitation" - meanwhile thinking suddenly how lucky I was not to have been injured!) he took my hand, examined it carefully and said "Hmm, Looks as if you have the worst cut of all!" I was actually very surprised to hear this, for the nerves had been severed along with the tendon in my hand, and thus I was unable to feel much pain <unclear/> sulfaccilimide (sp?) was put on the wound, and then all of us were sent to bed. There we remained several hours in a state of dopiness due to shock. When at last the doctor came to see us he presented me with another problem. I could have my hand repaired there, but only at the risk of being forced later to repeat the same operation, for tying tendons is a delicate job - one requiring a specialist. There</p>
30e
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>fore a specialist in Savannah was suggested. I thought it just as well to have the job done at once - for I do hate being a burden and a bother but both Connie (Mrs. Taylor) and George insisted that I go on to Richmond with the rest of the invalids for treatment in the Johnston Willie Hospital there. So it was done! We were dressed around 1:00 o’clock, booked our taxi shortly thereafter, and rode to the train which was to leave at 2:45, Richmond-bound. <hi rend="underline">What</hi> a sight we were! Still stunned, our eyes had that other-wordly stare, and otherwise we closely resembled a troupe of wounded soldiers returning from the front! Our clothes were blood-soaked, and our general appearance confirmed the solider idea most convincingly. In fact, once on the train, that is exactly</p>
(10)
<p>what we were told by the hordes of solider-boys riding with us. How marvelously sympathetic they were! Everything within reason was done for our comfort - and we even forgot the increasing pain we were begin to realize, not that the stunned feeling was going. All that afternoon - and all that weary night we rode. There sate Sylvia opposite me, her entire skull covered with a white bandage, in true Pocahontas-style on her forehead!): across from me, George, still a bit weakened by the terrific blow he had received on his head, and next to me, Doris, with eyes that were rapidly turning black and blue. The other girls were with us too, one with a cut nose, and the other with a cut on the nape of her nick. Morning came at last, and we found ourselves in Richmond. There we got out of the train and hurried to a certain hotel in which we were to find rooms. No rooms could be hand, we were informed, for a Medical Convention was in town - and all hotels were filled to overflowing. Doctors, doctors, every</p>
30f
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>where, but non even looked at us! We sat in that hotel lobby several hours, then breakfasted and went at once to the hospital, where, mercifully, we were attended to almost immediately. Dr. Daniels, who attended to me, came to remove the blood-soaked bandage, and as he did so, I shuddered with the sudden, willing pain I felt. It was as if all my nerves were <unclear/> and all centered there in that hand! So the "twilight sleep" was injected into my arm, and I slept peacefully till the nurse woke me. When I came to again, there was a splint on my arm from tips of fingers to elbow, and I could feel almost nothing for numbness. Thence, I was wheeled upstairs on a white table and placed in a comfortable, high bed next to a gentille,</p>
(12)
<p>suffering Southern <hi rend="underline">lady</hi>. The next four days I spent quite happily - if boringly, for everyone was extremely sweet and sympathetic.. George, who was not released with the others in our troupe, who left after being attended to that first day, came upstairs to visit in each day. He was in quite a condition himself but was eager to be out of that hospital. In Several days he was released, and even attempted performing, but I was kept four whole days! Whats thrill when I was finally released - almost as much as the first day several from the show came to visit me, bringing gifts of candy and books. Dear Buddy and Jean - and Connie, who were simply dear to us in our trouble. I was out walking in the hall when they came (my first days up) - I fairly tore them apart with joy - and they beamed at me <hi rend="underline">so</hi> compassionately! Of course, I</p>
30g
(13)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>was most eager to hear about the show. They told me everything was fine, except that several of the girls had fainted, and that George had been requested by the manager to be kept off the stage for fear he would collapse thereon! So - all <hi rend="underline">was</hi> exciting if not easy!</p>
<p>It was only later that we heard what those others - our friends and co-troupers had gone through in Newport News, where they had driven to carry on the show without us. Upon arriving in Newport News, they went to the theatre there and heard from the manager that "There has been an accident with the rest of the troupe. We don't know how many are <hi rend="underline">dead</hi> yet. Oh! this happens every day." So, this happy picture well</p>
(14)
<p>in mind, our co. troupers put on fine shows - and prayed between them that we were not killed. I heard from Ty Tyson that he and Buddy prayed especially that Bobbie, of the musicians, and "Ozark" would be O.K. When they heard details of our injuries Buddy said "Ozark would have to be the one with the worst hurt!" No - I do not feel that way about it - but it was sweet of them to say that, anyway. I was also told that after the accident I was the only one who did not get hysterical (outside of George, of course for he is always calm in an emergency). Sounds like bragging I suppose - but I assure you I know only vaguely that I was hurt, for the other's injuries attracted my attention,</p>
30h
(15)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>and I simply forgot myself. No <hi rend="underline">bragging</hi> about it!</p>
<p>To go back to Richmond, our troupe opened there on Wednesday the 11th. The dancers being injured, their work was cut down to a minimum of exertion - which was, believe me, all they could take care of under the circumstances. The Jungle Dace was completely removed - and the Russian also, until the last four days, when George managed to dance again. The opening musical comedy number was cut down to a one minute affair, and the <unclear/> or Dance was done minus one sailor! That <unclear>wasteen</unclear> doubtedly one of the hardest weeks I ever spent, for I was "broken up" emotionally</p>
(16)
<p>perhaps even more than physically. I was terribly moody all that week. Tried to act gay at the theatre; ran errands for everyone, and did my barres in spite of my hand. Jeannie would see me getting ready to practice and would approve of it with one reservation "No hop-hop Ozark. It would cause the blood to rush to your hand, and goodness knows, life's hard enough with <hi rend="underline">two</hi> good hands!" One day, however, I was so shaken up that I could not keep from crying long enough to venture out front to see "my favorite show" once more. I was suddenly afraid my injury might never completely disappear - but <hi rend="underline">more</hi> than this, I simply wanted to be performing, and something was keeping me from it! Never have a felt so completely "downed" - and so near ready to give up everything. Yes, it all seems a trife silly now, but at the moment it was real - terribly, <hi rend="underline">unalterably </hi>real. Giving up is <hi rend="underline">so</hi></p>
60i
(17) 
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>hard sometimes - and I was having a rather pointed experience in this respect. On that certain day, and at that certain time, Buddy happened to bring an apple to "Ozark". He saw I was crying, though I tried to hid it, and was really <hi rend="underline">dear</hi> to me. "What's the matter Ozark?" he said "<hi rend="underline">You</hi> can't do this! Look what I brought you!" Then I began to feel a bit like a baby, so I quit crying and accepted his concern and his gift oa they were meant. he then left me and went upstairs to get dressed for the next show. A while later I tidied up a bit and was walking out the dressing room entrance onto backstage, when Jeannie's voice floated down from her room two flights upstairs</p>
(18)
<p>"Ozark! Come up and see me. I went quite unsuspectingly and was greeted cheerfully as always by all our co-troupers within their various little coney-holes. When I arrived at Jean's, she was charming as always, in her crisp pert, yet sympathetic Scotch manner. Then, quite out of the blue sky she said "Do you know just <hi rend="underline">what</hi> has happened in your hand? I think when we known about things, we are not afraid of them." I said I thought I did, for I believed all would be well. Disregarding these assurances, Jean proceeded to tell me just what I could expect from my hand and how long it would take to be perfect again. She told me similar cases - and how they had recovered completely use - by exercising patience and correct treatment of the injury. Then she said "You know, I picked out "Green Light" for you. I thought it</p>
30j
(19)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, HOTEL
<p>would help you as it did me when I was laid-up with a sprained back and had to watch Buddy go away alone for a week's engagement. Dear People! It takes something like my experience to make one realize how <hi rend="underline">good</hi> some people are - how much they will do and care for a friend. And, in my experience, I’ve found this to be especially true in the <hi rend="underline">theatre</hi>.</p>
<p>That weary week passed at last, and soon we were on our way (by train again) for Savannah. In Savannah I performed with my splint swinging out "big as life" - and was <hi rend="underline">thrilled</hi> to be dancing again - with <hi rend="underline">any</hi> sort of  handicap. It was there in Savannah, <hi rend="underline">with</hi> the splint, and a numb, occasionally aching hand that I spent the long, trying night with Gibbie. We slept at the</p>
(20)
<p>theatre the last night, and left on the bus (We three girls) for Dothan, Alabama, the next morning.</p>
<p>That first week after the accident was no worse (Richmond) than the three days that followed in Savannah - so far as hysteries and strain were concerned. Everyone being in a state of physical and emotional upset, (and those <hi rend="underline">not</hi> in the accident were so effected by us that they were likewise a bit unbalanced) the troupe was almost torn asunder <hi rend="underline">backstage</hi>. We girls had squabbles (We made <unclear/> most profusely afterward!). Connie fainted backstage, Gibbie fainted after <hi rend="underline">each</hi> performance, one of the hand boys thrust his hand through a window, George strained his back picking up fainting people - and our producer had a regular 12:00 o'clock to 3 A.M. disagreement with his wife, who certainly could not be blamed for circumstances.</p>
<p>Not till we reached Birmingham</p>
(over <hi rend="underline">and</hi> above)
(19)
<p>from 20 - was the show put back on its feet - and all again ran smoothly. Bandages were off (except mine) - but splint was removed) and <unclear/> were likewise done away with or hidden, at least!</p>
(over <hi rend="underline">and</hi> above)


