<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
192
9917 Emerson,
At Eny's &amp; Ollie's 
8:04 P.M. Friday
Dec. 29, 1939.
(1.)
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We received your recent letter. Hope you have my last letter which I sent to Branson by this time.</p>
<p>Max called us this evening, as she was feeling sort of lonely with you and Sig away and both babies in bed! It was swell to hear her voice. She told us about your leaving Amarillo the 26th or 27th after the snowstorm. We all hope you're having a nice time now and that pure not too cold while travelling. We have snow 9 inches deep now and the roads are ice &amp; snow covered except on <unclear/> <unclear>thoroughfares</unclear>. Last winter</p>
(2)
<p>we experienced no snow so deep as this. Its been snowing off and on now for a week. We had a lovely white Christmas, consequently, however, Francis was out and we had a wonderful time Christmas Ece we sang carols adn made merry in various ways - popped corn, danced, had some wine, cookies &amp; candy. We had a roaring fire in the fireplace, too! Christams day we had a waffle breakfast and then went in to the tree. We had a marvelous duck dinner about 1:00 and then laughed and had a grand time. Howard and John stopped by for a short while about 4:00 for me. Howard</p>
(3)
<p>gave me some really lovely costume jewlery - a necklace - and John gave me a very pretty compact. According to my feeling fo reach of them, I sent them both the same kind of 5<cent/> Christmas card! They're both nice fellows, but nothing of that sort is of the least interest to me. I even become vastly bored during the first half hour of a date. Howard means well I suppose but he is a horribly conceited, rather overbearing, extremely dull sort of person - no sense of real variety - only a disguisting cyniscism. John is a German and consequently knows how to have</p>
(4)
<p>an impersonal sort of good time - you know what I mean. He doesn't take himself too seriously and therefore is really much more intelligent than Howard, who thinks he's a whip. I'm going out New Years Eve with Howard, and, thank heaven, two other couples. Maybe we'll have a good time - since it'll be a bunch. We're going to Club Caprice - a very ritzy place. Here's a surprise - we're ging formal! Hil wanted to get me a formal and wrap  for the occasion which whe could use herself sometime in the future. Therefore, she bought the lovelist prettiest dress and long velvet evening coat</p>
193
(5)
<p>you could imagine at <unclear>Kline's</unclear>. Even some of the customers stared at me in admiration and said "doesn't she look lovely in that?" The formal is made like a ballet costume - those in "Les Sylphides" The bodice is pink satin brocaded with gold at the top adn is tight fitting, sleeveless with strapes only. It comes down to a point in front giving a marvelous length of line and slenderizing effect. The skirt is of pink silk covered with pink net, and is quite full. Really, it is so lovely and just my type. I can wear it in the Spring to, I'm sure the wrap is lovely soft black velvet. It is beautifully fitted and long, and has</p>
(6)
<p>a hood attached to it! I'm going to wear Hil's gold slippers and carry her gold evening bag! it was about $24 altogthere. That's a lot but after all I know one of us is going to need evening apparel now and then Hil insisted on doing it. That's enough of clothes &amp; dates, however I'm sick of writing about them, so you much be so about hearing of them!</p>
<p>We girls have been practicing daily at the studio this week but we've had no classes. This morning Snippy gave us a class of her own freewill. Then we dressed and all of us went in Snippy's car to Madame's home for lunch! We had such</p>
(7)
<p>a lovely time! Their home is so sweet - it's still their old one and pretty, not extremely large, but really very "homey". We had lovely sandwiches, fruit salad, choice of coffee, milk, cocacola, or orange crush, cole slaw, potatoe chips, cookies, and lovely ice cream, and nuts of all kindsfor lunch, served buffet style adn extremely prettily fixed. After lunch we played with the kittens, heared Cesar Franck's Symphony in D Minor which was simply too beautiful for words, as well as numerous other musical mas</p>
(8)
<p>sterpieces - all on Madame's records. Besides that, we talked and looked at Madame/s art books a whole volume of Rodin's works and those of Malvena Hoffman etc. About 4:30 we left with difficulty! Each of us had a wonderful time. Madame said that her husband is going to put a felt pad on the bottom of the Ozark Baby so she can't break it! Does she already have it then, or is it on its way still, as you say in your letter? Tomorrow Miriam <unclear/> a "graduate" of our ballet Russe corps de ballet<unclear/> She's here because of a hurt foot! Sh'll rejoin the co. when she recovers sufficiently. By the way, Hil gave me tickets to Ballet Russe for Christmas. I'm so thrilled. <strike>Loads of Love</strike> (see next sheet -9)</p>
194
(9)
<p>I have some more to say, so I'll use another sheet of paper! Ollie and Eny have decided that $1.50 per wk. is right for you to pay them for extra expenses that I'll cause. Therefore, Ollie is taking $12 out of the $30 as payment for two months. The rest he is going to deposit in the bank for me and draw out enough for me as I need it. If I use $2.50 per wk. as Hilda was giving me from the money you sent before, I can sace there from enough for toe shoes hose, extras, etc. beside the actual $1.05 minimum for carfare each week. I'll no lunch costs for Eny puts up my lunch for me. From</p>
(10)
<p>the $30 therefor, I've kept $5 out for 2 wks., and Ollie will deposit the remaining $8 in the bank for me. At that rate I'll not need anymore money for 5 more weeks, and Ollie &amp; Eny not for 8 wks. see? I'll save all I can out of the $2.50 &amp; if I should find it is too much, I'll tell you. However, I'm sure it won't be with teo shoes, etc. to buy. Is this O.K. with you? Please know that I do appreciate all you're doing for me tremendously, especially since I know you're doing in a rather tight spot just at present.</p>
<p>It was wonderful what the medium said. I'm <underline>so</underline> glad I know in my heart that she is right about</p>
(11)
<p>everything, too. Fine if Ollie does get those raises!</p>
<p>Eny says to say she'll write you soon!</p>
<p>It's grand being out here. I love it really. The ride in isn't bad either. I've visited Hil several times already, once I stayed over night, as I went to a dance and didn't get back till late.</p>
<p>It'll be nice when classes start again, although vacation is lots of fun and <underline>we</underline> have been practicing.</p>
<p>Went to <unclear>Lennox Pats keller</unclear> for lunch and then to Loew's Wed. with John Baker. We saw David Niven in "Raffles" - very good. Had nice time. See the picture if you</p>
(12)
<p>can it's very entertaining - about an "amateur crackssman" as he calls himself - a sort of modern English light fingered Robin Hood.</p>
<p>Please write when you can again.</p>
Loads of Love
your grateful Alice
<note>text below is in pencil, possibly done by a different person</note>
<p><unclear>Twitty's Niersey Tey
areaed
Dallas Inus Herald.</unclear></p>