<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
39a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
Jan. 19, 1940
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo.
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>We appreciated greatly the sweet letters sent Special Delivery on our 3rd anniversary. Ol was just getting ready to leave for work when they came Tues. A.M. Thanks a lot for your kind thoughtfulness.</p>
<p>Hil came out for dinner in the evening brought soem Cook's Imperial rhine wine and  Ol brought some part, so we had several toasts before dinner. I had the new tablecloth that I finished recently; and that with the silverware, and out siler platter &amp; two silver bowls we set a pretty lovely table! Hil said she'd looked forward all that day to coming out. We had to wait till about 8:00 o'clock to eat tho', as Al is always so late getting home. Usually, Ol &amp; I just eat dinner &amp; let her eat when she gets back. We retired soon after dinner.</p>
<p>It was 14<degree/> below last nite here, but today pm it's gone up to 9<degree/> above. Coldest known here for years. I hope the sun stays up there - or we might be going to see the end sooner then we'd all planned!!</p>
<p>Dad, why dont' you bring Mom along when you come by in March? I tho't she was going to be writh you on trips from now on. I think it's the right thing. Why shouldn't she? It's about time that Mom got a few of those</p>
2
<p>lecture trips with you, don't you think? I see no reason, &amp; I'm sure Max would agree, why Mom shouldn't go with you.</p>
<p>this is Ol's day off &amp; we're enjoying being alone together, as we always do. We'd like to go off somewhere in the woods wherewe could always be alone. It seems as tho' we've only been married three days only. I only hope our marriage isn't one of those beautiful things that is <underline>too nearly perfect</underline>; for perfect things just don't last in many cases!</p>
<p>It was <underline>so</underline> cold last nite, that we all just went to bed to get warm. Houses here don't coutn on 14<degree/> below! It did little good to fire up greatly.</p>
<p>Al is speaking at her honorary society meeting tonite, &amp; is staying all nite with Hilda. We would have gone, but it's just <underline>too</underline> cold to go anywhere.</p>
<p>I unravelled an old green sweater of mine &amp; am going to make Alice a pair of mittens if she gets me a recipe fo rsuch. I'm making a <unclear>tam</unclear> now just for fun.  Have been making a chair set for our green chair in brown &amp; orange to brighten it up a bit. It's really handsome.</p>
<p>Alice has about $4.00 left now, perhaps a bit more; but goodness knows she hasn't spent much. I've sent her complete lunch each day and she has had only carfare &amp; occasionally she had to buy something. She had to buy a pair of shoes, $1.<underline>99</underline>; a pair of gloves, 29<cent/>, a slip, 88<cent/> just the other day. So, of course, that cuts down her money a bit. As you requested,</p>
39b
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>we took $12.<underline>00</underline> of the $30.<underline>00</underline> you sent to cover Al's keep for Jan. &amp; Feb. But Alice evidently had expected her money $18.<underline>00</underline> to cover 6 wks. from when you sent it. Even at that, it's not spending much since then as she has about 4.<underline>00</underline> left. Just thought I'd tell you as Alice might not mention it. She'll write you with regard to this.</p>
<p>We stayed in bed till noon today, as we were warmer in bed in the earlier part of the day than we would have been if we were up. Al got up &amp; fixed her lunch to take, got her breakfast &amp; left at about 9:30.</p>
<p>We have all our plants in the l.r. &amp; d.r. now to keep them from freezing. Have two lovely Easter lilies, 3 geraniums, a fern, a pineapple, an avacado (which is truly lovely) and two other plants similar to Mother in law's <unclear>Torgue</unclear>.</p>
<p>We're anxious to see you two. Hope it won't be too long till we do. We haven't seen you for ages, it seems.</p>
<p>Write us soon again. We love to hear from you.</p>
When something other than 14<degree/> below weather happens, we'll write more
Loads of love, 
Enid &amp; Ollie





