<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
149
Almost from last nite in a cabin camp! It was a "brave to" case of staying in a camp! S.N. 
Wednesday noon 
10-25-'32. 
Lincoln, Neb. 
My sweet girl I am sorry that I had not paid enough attention to the schedule to know it by mem.! Lincoln was not on the mailing list! I'm so sorry, 'cause I did expect to re-ceive mail here! How are you, darlin'? I am so lonesome that I do not know what to do! 
Been all upset along with it! I'm getting well tho'-I think! Dad & I are in 

150
-2-
a tailoring shop, having our suits pressed for this evening's occasion! 
This is the town, whose state capitol bldg. is the greatest in the U.S. you shoudl see it - a gorgeous piece of architecture! You know how we both admire the white R. bridge? Well, anyway this structure would no dobut impress you as much as it has me! 
Had a very nice visit with Leslies, they are so kind! 

151
-3-
you can see from this trip for ex-ample that I do not in the least way - care to have any girl but you! I love you & am perfectly satisfied & you know it! I don't consider it a "duty" either!! I just love you as highly as love could possibly be! C? It will always be this way with me & you can depend on it! 
Don't think that I feel the way I say just because I don't happen to

152
-4-
meet enough "other" girls! 
Because I meet hundreds of girls whom I could go with as much & to as great an extent as I wanted to! This means nothing to me, sweetheart!! I love you, & positively have no desire to love any girl but the one I have at present! 
Take my word for it, because my love for you is so deep in my soul that nothing but death could stop it! I must close, & will hear from you at Kearney after the 

153
-5-
All-nite drive! C? Have been thinking about you always! I believe that things will begin to brighten up in a business way soon! 
They must!! 
Always I love you, 
your Sig. 

154
After 10 days, return to 
LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. 
LINCOLN OCT 26 230 PM 1932 NEBR. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Miss Maxine Melton, 
Branson, Missouri. 
BRANSON, MO. OCT 27 1932 PARCEL 
Taney County. 