<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
193 Fink Collection 71
BLAIR
OCT 15
7 PM
1940
NEBR.
<stamp>UNITED STATES POSTAGE
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mrs. O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo St Louis County
72
<underline>Tuesday</underline>
Enid Darling:
<p>On the way from Wayne we went through Bancroft, and it is the very first time that I have seen the house where you were born since we left it for Mo. I have had something happen to me that made me <underline>want</underline> to see it. An inward change that has taken away the bitterness I had felt up until recently - Any way I am pleasantly surprised at my self! We drove up from the direction of the old "Park", remember? We passed teh spot where you and Sig had seen the cow have a calf! Passed Vogts and the little "old man's house"</p>
73
<p>where Daddy wrote Three Friends, and the ploughed land where you used to go bare foot; drove around the corner where you used to "watch th cars go by!" I stepped out and touched the little front porch Daddy made which you used to sweep off!! The place is going to pieces but it is <underline>very dear</underline> and lovely to me. The elms are enormous, the blue grass is thick and matted down - The grapes Daddy planted are very thick-vining and I am quite sure have never been trimmed in all these 29 years since we left! The old backhouse is so covered with the vines we planted that one can barely see it, but I <underline>did</underline>. The ground is so rich and I'd just love to go to work and fix it up and Daddy and I live there again for a while!!</p>
74
<p>It would be nice to save it, for after all you were born there, Hilda was born there - and there Daddy wrote Hugh Glass, The Poet's Town, Ghostly Brother, 800 Rubels as well as the sequence of the "Stranger at the Gate". The place could be bought for much less than we got for it when we sold, and a very good living could be made since the land is marvelously fetile and one could raise chickens and sell eggs. There has been a fine crop of corn etc near here - We are now at Blair, Daddy is resting in bed and I wanted to get this off to you and Ollife. Maybe Hilda too would be interested. - The vines on the house itself, the Wistaria as well as the Prairie-queen rose has been cut down. The old <unclear>cisterer</unclear> is filled up with rubbish! The cave is still there.</p>
75
<p>Daddy and I saw all this and then drove on as we did not want to see <sic>peopl</sic>. Grand ma's old place is in better shape - and her apple tree is covered with red apples. Her peonies are all there. I wanted Daddy to dig one up but he though so many people would find out we had been there and be hurt. So we drove away.</p>
<p>Enclosed leaves are from our grapes!!</p>
Loads and loads of love
from your devoted 
Mama.
<p>P.S. Miss Piper though you had a baby boy, and that we had moved up to St Louis. God Speed!!</p>
Mother Mama.
<p>Read our letters at Southwood!</p>