<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
49
January 24, 1941
At Home - Sat. noon
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:
<p>We were so sorry to hear of Dad's lumbago and all. We <sic>tho't</sic> of calling you up by phone and then remembered that you didn't have a telephone any more. We were looking for you yesterday until we got the card, Mom. Today we are still looking for you regardless, as we hope the lumbago isn't as bad as you think it is. It's a shame Dad had to carry those things into the car! As I mentioned to Ol, things like that are for these big brush apes and not for men who have any brains! Know what I mean? We were so tickled that you had intended to arrive here when Ol was home, as it would be so nice. Well, perhpaps you'll be coming today! We have some fried chicken for dinner as a very special celebration. Whenever Ol and I want to celebrate something we have chicken--it's our idea of something to eat. I called Max yesterday and told her about your not coming for a few days, and of course they were so sorry to hear it.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Ol got the basement all cleaned up again--almost nasty nice, it is,-- awaiting your comin'. He has the desk down there and everything. I know Dad will feel at home down there and will be able to write easily, for it'll be very quiet--no noise but you and me, Mom, during the day! We have the sunroom fixed too. It really looks nice and cozy. In fact, I had never dreamed it could look so nice as a bedroom!</p>
<p>Dad, Ol got one of those things not so terribly long ago from lifting--or I should say, digging in the yard. So he sympathizes with you whole-heartedly. They surely aren't funny. I ironed his back too, Mom. That seems to be the best thing. Vaprub is good too-- we found it helps to soothe it.</p>
<p>We enclose a couple of old letters which we were going to mail to you before we heard you were coming right away. You might care to read <sic>'em</sic> anyhow.</p>
<p>Here's hoping you are getting okay quickly, Dad, and we are <sic>a-waitin'</sic> with joy to seeing you both soon.</p>
Loads of love, always,
Ollie &amp; Enot