<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
61a
<note>Thrilled about news of Eny, Ollie and Nei - and his new sister - to-be. What of Sig and Max - and Joanie and Elaine?</note>
Donato Guerra 14
Departamento
Meuco D. 7
May 15, 1943

Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>I am still marvelously happy and thrilled over the news you dear letter brought me. I want to go to some beautiful place to pray and give thanks to God and the Great Spirit for all the Good he has blessed us with. Just what do you do Daddy, and does it please you to do it? Esquire! Hurrah! It certainly sounds like a position which will be both interesting and remunerative. You will probably be better appreciated there than be better appreciated there than you were even on the Post. I want to hear all about your new life and how you like living in Chicago. Have you driven around Lakeshore Drive lately? How is old Lake Michigan these days? By this time Mama, you and Amama must be in Chicago too, so I am writing you there, as well as Daddy. So you are <hi rend="underline">all</hi> there together - you Daddy and Mama, Amama and my Hilda. How grateful I am to know <unclear/> How <hi rend="underline">right</hi> and <hi rend="underline">Good</hi> it all is. Everyone here is extremely thrilled for with you - and me. God Great Spirit keep you happy and strong, and time to bless you, my dearest ones</p>
(2)
<p>You cannot know, and I cannot tell how trilled and grateful and happy I am. Are you all going to get an apartment together? Tell me all about it, oh! please - for I do so want to know what each of you does each minute of the day. More than ever - the same constant love and appreciation for all you are - and are to me, fills my heart and soul, and inspires me in <hi rend="underline">my</hi> life. Always know that.</p>
<p>You must have been very busy, Mama and I do understand. Now however if you have more time <hi rend="underline">will</hi> you write me more often? Thanks so for waning through my tangle of Francais. yes, I shall. I am learning Spanish to some extent and shall continue I am learning several Mexican songs too. There are many <hi rend="underline">very</hi> beautiful ones - some gay songs sad - but all with a Soul. Yes, this country itself has a Soul. Business methods are different - life in general strange to us. No strangers - but I love many more aspects of Mexico than I dislike. Someday <hi rend="underline">you</hi> shall visit here too wait and see. And I shall show you all around. You cannot know how I've wished for you dear ones to appreciate with me the Beauty I've been seeing - the quaintness, the adventure - the newness, the <hi rend="underline">Romance</hi></p>
61b
(3)
<p>of this land. As yet we have not seen Mexico ourselves - not <unclear>Aryonlco</unclear> on the seacost nor Guadelajora nor Cuernauaro, nor Taxco, nor the wildness of the Interior. All that I have <hi rend="underline">great</hi> desire to see - oh we must.</p>
<p>As things look now, we may have Mexico soon unless we decide it is better for the act to decide it is better for the act to stay here longer. There is certainly no lack of work for us for we have many offers, but George thinks it might be better to return, after termination of our "Folies Bergere" contract, to Chicago, via dates in Texas, etc. Our agent there wants to send us to New York soon, and also the money here is not very good for George since agents fees, etc. are doubled (Chicagoan plus Meucan. We shall see what turns up. Now we are doing two shows at the <unclear/> and one at the Club Bremen each night. That brings us extra money and is really quite an easy routine. Tomorrow we are to dance a matinee at each a two mover tres, the Alameda and the Bucared then a matinee and two evening two performano at the Folies Bergere, and finally, two shows at the Bremen</p>
(4)
<p>So we have, you may count <unclear/> performances ahead of us tomorrow. The Almeda is one of the two best theatres here. I described it you in a previous letter, n'est <unclear/></p>
<p>I believe I told you about our performance at Chaputtepee, and also of Max's last visit, didn't I? I had a lovely evening with Max Sunday then went to a movie with him and his brother Monday afternoon. Monday evening he and Heinz came to see us at the Bremen, and drove Sylvia and me home. We had one grand time. The next day, both returned to the ranch, where they want us all to come for a vacation, if we can. If we close the 22<hi rend="underline">nd</hi> we shall visit Max several days before returning to Laredo. Mama, I want you to listen closely to me and believe and trust me, as I know you will. I had no idea of what you mentioned, and had it even <hi rend="underline">occurred</hi> to me I would not have mentioned anything. I just wanted to help <hi rend="underline">my</hi> Hilda if I could - for I long to do just any little thing I can in face of what she's done for me. With certain contacts certain ends <hi rend="underline">can</hi> be accomplished in show business. Do you understand? Of course, you <hi rend="underline">are</hi> right - I would not, under</p>
61c
(5)
<p><hi rend="underline">any</hi> circumstances do anything to hurt our Albert whom I love as a brother, and whom I admire beyond words. However, I do <hi rend="underline">not</hi> think you are right in your judgement of Hilda in this matter. I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> Hilda - perhaps even better in some ways than you, my Mama! She loves <hi rend="underline">Albert</hi> - and only he - for she told me all about that - and I know just how far her other "attraction" went. Albert, not M, was meant for Hilda - and she <hi rend="underline">knows</hi> it - his qualities are dear to him, and no other match would or could be as perfect in all respects. No I shall not encourage Hilda to come here - but I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> know that even that could not change me Hilda.</p>
<p>I have something more to tell you, that I must tell you because you are what you are to me - and because I am a puppy-dog as ever, and need to tell those I love my <unlcear/> feelings. Please do not make more of what I say than is actually true - just hear what I tell you and believe in me enough to understand that I tell you this only because</p>
(6)
<p>I want to be close to you - as because I know you understand me, Daddy and Mama, as no one else could - and believe in my belief in Good. Here is what I have to say, purely and simply I have met, or re-met someone whom I know I can never forget - and who will always, come what may, be a part of me. No, that is not drama, nor talk, nor infatuation, for I am no, as I once was, terribly unworldly. One cannot stay so when in contact with many different kinds of people; and what I have learned I can honestly say, is almost entirely beneficial. In this business, especially, one lesson to recognize real values in a human being, and to separate the beast from the <hi rend="underline">enduring Spirit</hi>. You must have guessed a ready about whom I speak - yes, it is Max. Furthermore, I am certain that this "condition" <hi rend="underline">is</hi> mutual for he has told me so, and there is Something Else that tells me, when we are together, and <hi rend="underline">now</hi>, when we are apart. I could go into all the usual symptoms, which he has, in his strong, fine yet <hi rend="underline">dear</hi> ways, confessed to me as I to myself, but this would only</p>
61d
(7)
<p>bore you and make you chuckle. I shall only say that I am for the first time in my life really terribly fond of someone. It is not only his charm - no, not at all, for he is perhaps the most modest, honest, straightforward, unstudied personality I've been privileged to know (under like circumstances). It is his Spirit - Oh! I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> you would both love him - I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> you will say yourself how <hi rend="underline">unfair</hi> of you ever to have judged such a Person without <hi rend="underline">even having met him</hi>! That's unlike you - and I know you would and shall, agree with me. Perhaps you will say Max is choosing me as "second fiddle to Hilda, but I do not believe such is true. Yes, Hilda and I are alike - we have the same tastes, the same feelings, and somewhat the same desires - now more than ever. But I know there is much more of an attraction than this. We have so many of the same ideas, the same attitudes, the same likes. Max and I How long have I searched in people (consciously <hi rend="underline">or</hi> unconsciously)</p>
(8)
<p>for what I now see and hear and know is a part of Max. When we go out together, we do not need to speak - for what beams from his beautiful <hi rend="underline">good, fine</hi> eyes is all I ask and he seems to be satisfied by mine. At other times, we are gay and talkative, still others more intellectual - and always we seem to fit into each others world. Oh how rare is that? How rare - how beautiful, how magical is such a thing! Now that I know Max, others are non-existent. My admirers (for we naturally have those au theatre) are no longer interesting in the same light and a sweet-sadness has crept over all of Life. Max writes "I am back on the ranch, or rather, partly back because most of my ownself is still in Mexico, watching a certain girl dancing at the Follies, rushing meals between shows and dancing again. And I am almost afraid that this one-tenth of myself which has to keep the ranch going escapes to fly back to Mexico and leaves here a heart-and-brainless body." He is so sweet, yet never <hi rend="underline">pitiful</hi> - always strong. How I admire <hi rend="underline">strength</hi></p>
61e
(9)
<p>in a <hi rend="underline">Man</hi>. No weakness in Max that he has certainly proved in more ways than one on his ranch, where he has been and is being practically a pioneer <hi rend="underline">successfully</hi> too. Now you are wondering just what I mean by telling you all this - these "inmost secrets of a girl's love life" things that should never see the light of day, or break upon the shares of another's consciousness. But, good or bad, I cannot be conventionally prim and proper. Yes - especially not to you!</p>
<p>You who above all will and can understand Believe me - I am just being honest with you of all People in this world, - and perhaps, too, I cannot help sharing the joy, the little pangs of sorrow that I now know for the first time, <hi rend="underline">really</hi> with you. I shall see Max again the 21st or 22nd. Have no fear. I am <hi rend="underline">still</hi> and shall still continue to be a dancer for some time to come and whatever else life holds for me will keep provided it is real. Am I know right in this? Such I have heard many times,</p>
(10)
<p>but somehow I know it is <unclear/> now. Whatever comes I shall always be grateful, intensely grateful for Beauty Max has brought into my Life - and I shall one day be free to show it. No, it is not serious at present - just a hint of a Heaven shining through the eyes of someone. I have told you only because I want always to be hear you - and because I know you will understand. Do as you like with this letter. Oh! yes, George and his Grandmother  both approve heartily of Max - and both guessed our little secret, though we thought we were very subtle.</p>
<p>I have other news for you, concerning the act itself. Doris has caused really lots of unnecessary trouble, among us, as you already know. Outside of her moods (which are <hi rend="underline">not</hi> actually normal), she seems unable to cooperate in the actual <hi rend="underline">dancing</hi>. She makes the same mistakes over and over in spite of correcting from <hi rend="underline">George</hi>, our director, and even <hi rend="underline">tries</hi> in various little ways to do steps differently form us. This ruins all thought of unison - which is terribly important, even for the <hi rend="underline">mood</hi> which she says she is following! Our Chicago agent
 has</p>
61f
(11)
<p>asked George several times to get rid of her for this reason and also because she is too big for him. SHe is in love with George too, which further complicates matters. Therefore, George has already given Doris her notice, effective upon our entrance into the States. We plan to work awhle as a trio, then come to Chicago to procure another gal before we leave for New York. George has many new numbers in mind which we must create once in the U.S. Again. Probably this will all turn out for the best, though we all feel terribly sorry for Doris. All her own making this mess, too. Sad, but maybe it will be good for her in the long run. What do you think? Keep this a definite secret between you <hi rend="underline">two</hi> - all I have told you in this letter. To make our little drama even more complete; I have just found out for sure (They have confided in me as I in them) that George and Sylvia are quite in love. I cannot help seeing the possibilities in our life-stories for a fine bit of narrative. Don't you think that is true? This shall make <hi rend="underline">no</hi> difference in our plans. In fact, in order not to show</p>
(12)
<p>favoritism, George is almost heading backwards. He is planning several new roles for me - and I am very grateful. We can go on <hi rend="underline">much</hi> farther now, without certain irritations which are killing. Do you see?</p>
<p>We are getting marvelous <unclear/> city both form Folies Bergere and the Bremen. That will be marvelous for us in the States. Now at last you shall see us really dance - maybe we'll have a return engagement sometime at Colosimos. Hold your thumbs for us.</p>
<p>How is Hilda these days? If you wish to show her this you may - do as you like for I do not want to keep anything from my Hilda. I just don't want to <hi rend="underline">broadcast</hi> it.</p>
<p>Give my love to Amama. Tell her I'll find out about <unclear/> here if she still wishes to know. The Regis is perhaps one of the best. - La Reforma the swankiest, Coliseo's the most reasonable in regard to its conveniences and general standard. Tell my Hilda to write me <hi rend="underline">all</hi> about herself. And will <hi rend="underline">you</hi> please write me right away - if only a few lines, dearests,</p>
As always I am,
Your adoring, Alice