<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
214- Fink Collection 76
215-
216-
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON.
MAY29
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
<p>Had store meeting 'til quite late last <sic>nite</sic>. Same thing up for Mon. <sic>nite</sic>. We're doing a nice business at the "5907" store and the men are all swell fellows to work with.</p>
Love
Sig.
<p><underline>P.S.</underline> Saturdays I am due at store 10:30 a.m. - then thru 'til 10:00 at least, that <sic>nite</sic>. Bigger chance to make extra commissions when having long hours you know.</p>
77
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
<underline>Wed. Noon</underline>
Dear Oddie and Enot:
<p>I'm returning the ten herewith and you know I'm grateful. Macmillians sent me $300, and I feel it was good of them to do so. They're eager for the complete Cycle &amp; seem determined to make the most of the opportunity which the finsihing of the work offers.</p>
<p>Another good letter, Oddie, and  I agree with you in your view of Sig's outlooko. You gave good advice.</p>
<p>Our money problem since Sep 1938 has not been a simple matter. So many items, each having its own special justification cannot be known to one outside the scheme, &amp; <underline>fixed</underline> changes have been heavy enough in themselves. Sig did a really sincere job in looking &amp; I give him full credit. He <underline>did</underline> sell a great many engagements, surely.</p>
78
<p>I'll be so glad when he can get hold &amp; feel right. He does want to do so, &amp; will.</p>
<p>You've both been so good, and Mama &amp; I do thank you.</p>
<p>I'm not very letter-writey, but I love you both</p>
Dad.
79
Wednesday.
Dearest Kids:
<p>I'm sorry not to have written sooner but I guess its my confounded laziness. Forgive me. You've been so good to Sig and we're all so grateful.</p>
<p>I do hope Sig gets a fill in job with Baldwin. Of course Western Auto is what he wants but if he cannot go to work there until July 1 then it would be fine for him to be able to fill in the 30 days that will alpse between now and then.</p>
<p>I think it's simply awful that he can't practice and that he and Hilda can't practice together in the apartment. O f course I really don't see why we couldn't see that that would be the way most apartments are. Too bad, and I don't know how to solve the problem but everything depends on what works out for him there. I'm so glad he can get a job at western beginning July 1.</p>
<p>it's lovely here now, still cool but pleasant. the roses are blooming in profusion and they are so beautiful. I never tire of looking at them. Wish you could see them. I wish I could see your roses. Dad had to spray ours to kill the little green worms that were very bad this year. I thin kyou told him what is use didn't you.</p>
<p>Perhaps after Sig gets a job I can come up for a few days but it would be impossible, of course, unless he could. Mom is looking forward to seeing you in June. I don't know just how long she will be there but no doubt she has told you.</p>
<p>Here are my thanks again, and again for taking such good care of my man. It is so darn good of you and so like your generous selves. No doubt he will have this Baldwin thing worked out by this week end and can get a small room in town and use Hilda's place to phone from if needs be. And that won;t be much more expensive than carfare, or rather he can add something to teh amount it takes for carfare and get a pretty decent room.</p>
<p>Mom looks so pretty in her pink dress she has not yet tried on the green but I'm sure it will be just as pretty. The pink fits beautifully, I dont' see how you did it.</p>
<p>Gobes of love to you and two from Macie and the wubs.</p>
80
Dear Aunt Eny &amp; Uncle Oddie:
<p>We have preey red roses. Elaine and I cathc pollywogs with the strainer and we have daisies with the strainer and wild roses in the pasture adn we often eat our dinners there.</p>
Love to you,
JOAN

