<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 
61
Duncan M. Dinsonhaler
FIRST NATIONAL BANK BUILDING
OMAHA 
Friday, Dec. 5th. 24. 
My dear Mrs. Neihardt:
Buffalo, N. Y. 
You most welcome and interesting letter was forwarded to me is <unclear/> when I had gone to enjoy & <unclear/> of walls & talks with John and it was so interesting and worth while that I could not resist shining it with John. I had a most delightful two weeks, only <unclear/> by the flu, which kept John housed a few days, and on Thanksgiving afternoon took Hilda & Mrs. N. in now for a few days both however won <unclear/> where I left on Dec. as Fortunately all <unclear/> will and in van home for Tuesday, and as it was children's day, it paid me big <Unclear/> to look into their shining eyes and happy faces. I know they had all they could eat, and enough for a feast was left. As to details, theyw ill come to you from those who call mom properly <unclear/> there: it is my hope that I may to spend to enjoy many <unclear/> such dinners. We went to you as the opening <unclear/> & all admitted that 

62
Duncan M. Dinsonhaler
FIRST NATIONAL BANK BUILDING 
OMAHA 
You were not with us, I am so glad you are having a winter in "The Malling Crowd." and it will make you all the more appreciation of the just and brother's of the Hills where you return to B. nevertheless the city has its interests and we can also find <unclear/> then, altho the <unclear/> Homes has position genius in creating the grotesque, and it find its highest expression moderate <unclear/> eaters. however you instinctively turned to the hours of never failing delight-The Library and Laws going to <unclear/> grab that while you have access to it. that you grab from it. M.E. Durhams "Higher Albania" and I am sure you will rad if with delight and profit if that pleases you you can follow it up with Maude Wilder Lanes book on Albania, also mark <unclear/>
I hope you have all old fashioned writer and that you have the privilege of seeing Niagara in ice, You'll never forget it. 
With all good wishes, I remain. 
Sincerely,
<unclear/> 