<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
37 Neihardt Collection 
187 
AFTER 5 DAYS, RETURN TO 
BRANSON JUL22 3-PM 1936 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
Neihardt Branson. 
<del>SPRINGFIELD</del>, MO. 
Dr. John G. Neihardt
301 Ilene Apartments 
5544 Pershing Ave 
St. Louis
Mo 

[544 Pershing Ave ST LOUIS, MO]
Wednesday 
[July 22, 1936]
188
Darling 
The drum with Black Elk on the young moon and the golden Star over head, as well as your emblem with Eagle's feather, Star and bison hide, are on the wall facing me in bed. I have my head at the South and so face the North all night and most of the morning I fully believe our Branson rains & came from Black Elk's Thunder Beings through you - Because they did not fit in with Radio fore-casts, not exactly anyway - especial-ly not the first time. Now we are having cool weather, and it seems that the rain was not as soaking & one as I thought - we need more very badly - so please do what you can for us. I know you could turn this into an oasis if you thought yourself into the mood; why not? I have re read the Messiah and it gets greater and more comprehensible to me every time. It never can her popular, because common folks cannot 

189
ever get in the proper mood nor have they the desire to do so as yet - but htere iwll be more and more of us, as tragic happenings increase, don't you think so? It will be grand to sit next with you and to have you unfold more of your plans to me - Oh how I am with you in your ideas about writing Jed Smith! I really believe you have needed to rest in your crea-tive work for a span - so maybe my illness has not done you any real harm. I know it has done me great good, for first of all it has been the way to make me see you really want me - Before I did feel that if I could just drop out now in some decent way it woudl be just as well or better for you and the children. 
I am so glad too, that you want to hang on to some place, as you say "for safety" - why can that place not be this? I spoke to Mrs Wilson and she said she woudl think it over. She seemed to feel it a very serious responsibility - but said $5.00 was ample pay. I think she will do it. So glad you are coming! Amama shoudl be with you. Loads of Love as always - 
Mona. 