<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
212 Fink Collection 59
May 18th 40
Dearest Boy:
<p>Thanks for your letter for which we were eagerly waiting. It has seemed a long time since you left - but we here think of your going as the <sic>advance-gward</sic> en route to a better life.</p>
<p>That house does not appeal to me at all - it would be like exchanging a real Home for a candy box. Dad and I like old places better, where the utilities are there as a matter of need of course - but where the emphasis is put on real living comforts. Maybe a residence in St. Louis is the thing that would serve best? If you do find a paying job in</p>
60
<p>St. Louis, so that you can work at your own and Hilda's Music for a time, I think that would be far better than running off to the coast. New York is a sort of Hell-hole and the Government is getting ready to have new in land factories soon, so you might <underline>waste</underline> yoru efforts by not <underline>waiting</underline> for further developments in armaments production plans. However it is <underline>your</underline> life.</p>
<p>Daddy has been fixing our electric switches and it is swell how they all work now. When we turn on the drive way lights my heart says "<underline>Sig</underline> made them lovely for our Home!" There is no news</p>
61
Sig
<p>from MacMillans' as yet - nor any other letters.</p>
<p>I am anxious to hear from you seeing our girls - and about the Piano, etc.</p>
<p>Daddy is feeling some what better but not right as yet. We are having a wonderful rain today - and our Paul Scarlet rose is blooming. I finished mowing again just before the rain got hard.</p>
<p>Maxie and the Wubs are swell.</p>
<p>I washed our car yesterday again. Our good <unclear>luch</unclear> blue-bird! I do love this car better than any we have</p>
62
<p>ever had.</p>
<p>I Know you are going to feel "schoner wie neu" very soon. I cannot help wishing you'll land some thing in St. Louis.</p>
<p>Love to Enid and to Ollie-</p>
<p>To you always cudless love and prayers for your success  - and the hope that you may find it <underline>with</underline> Music!</p>
Always your devoted
Mama.