<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
102 Fink Collection 2
Neihardt Branson Mo. 
BRANSON OCT22 3-PM 1938
M.O. 
Mrs. O.F. Fink 
9716 Hawthorne Ave 
Overland, Mo. 
St Louis County 

3
Dearest Enid and Ollie - 
I came pretty near running up to St Louis today - be-cause a Mr Janecka here ad did Dad if he wanted ot run up with him - and Daddy told him that I mgith want to. but it turned out that he did not go after all - no I have been sort of on needles and pins -  - Arm enclosing the result of that. <del>Consolidated</del> Associated Pressman's interview when Daddy was on the P.D. - remem ber his interview Enid? Daddy just happened to be looking through the 

4 
2 
Springfield Paper yesterday - and here it was! I think it is one of the very best hit-ting the important things right in the middle - don't you? Good picture too-but Gee! you should see my bust now! I'd rather have died than missed <unclear/> it, that is sure. - 
The two Neihardts had a most thrilling good time at Warrensburg The whole thing very successful and pleasants. They have a week's engage-ment for this ^next Sumer there. Daddy to lecture, and Sig to do something in connection iwth the teacher of Music 

3
5
there such as a two Piano concert. Daddy liked the President and his family very much and all were so interested to hear about all of us especially all the other children - They seemed to thrill at the thought of Dad's son being connected up with him as he was - The whole thing was just fine. Now they are planning for Kansas City a week from Monday after which they may go to Peru and Wayne Nebraska. They made enough in Warrensburg to pay for all Dad's ex-penses^in this business Sigs trips and his suit. So I feel it looks most promising. The great difficulty is not getting lectures, but getting them for this year 

4
6
Sig has quite a few for next year already You'd be tickled to see how systematic Sig is, and what pains he takes with his letters - but it is by personal contact that he lands them! He may go to Il-linois before very long, in which case he may drop me up with you and the girls! I am so delighted Ollies and your Mother is visiting you, "<unclear/>" soon now - I know you will love each other, for a very dear man is the hint between you. - I wrote you just a day before receiving your letter, so I have not much more to tell you. Tomor-row Joanie will be "wise and three." 

5
7
<unclear/> Daddy is baking a wonderful cake at this minute - and your lovely gift and Aunt Hilda's are going to furnish a big birthday for our Joanie She knows every face - I never saw such a child for recognizing snaps ^and platos - but when ever she sees the one of you at 3 and Sig at 2, (like the one you took last time you were home), she says Joanie for you, and Baby Laine for Sig! 
Much much love to my two dear children 
from 
Mamma - Mother. 