<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 54
<figure/> DAILY SUNDAY 
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT 
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH 
PUBLISHED BY THE PULITZER PUBLISHING CO. 
ST. LOUIS, MO. 
Dec. 28, '28.
Dear Mamma:
The little jar came through in good shape, and it was more than welcome: Many thanks. Don't send any more, as much as I'd like to have it. If discovered it would make trouble. Just the same, I'm glad you did it once:
I sent the manuscript of STRAWS IN THE WIND to Macmillans yesterday, and I think it will appear in the spring. It is surely worth publishing. I was surprised at the stuff in it. I think you'll enjoy reading it. 
It's the best of news that you are reasonably happy and contented. Lots of women wouldn't be, and you should hear <del>here</del> how we talk of you here. You seem to have discovered the real secret, and that it is a big accomplishment.
I saw my medium the other day, and she told me an earful. The same thing all of them tell, of course; but with this addition: that I'll be called away from here in February - to New York! After she had talked quite awhile she suddenly said "The New York World". The^n she asked what that meant, adding that she supposed it meant that New York was really the world now, and I'd be called there. She said she heard my guide tell her this, and he said I'd been a fool in under-rating myself. The peculiar thing is that I don't in the least believe 

55
the N.Y. World will want me, and I don't w^ant it either. It doesn't even seem inviting, and I have no hankering to go to New York. She said "I'm not telling you what you ought to do; I'm telling you what you will do". She said that in the new job, at first, I'd feel that I'd gambled my last cent, but that I'd win and be glad I took the plunge. Also, she saw greater and greater success. 
Keep yourself in good shape, Mamma. There are many years for you yet if you only think so. Don't let the notion get fixed in your mind that you necessarily have few years. That's not so. It's only your body that's getting older, and your mind is what matters most. Don't let that change. I judge that it isn't changing. I wnat ot have you see some of the moves that are coming yet in the Big Game as it concerns myself. You'll enjoy that. And you will see, too. 
Endless love,
Jno. 
if we should have to move East, you won't stay down there unless you insist on doing so for awhile. The medium said I'd go on ahead and the family stay here the better part of the year. You could come up here - if this should happen to work out. I'm not at all convinced of any of this. But it seems curious, anyway. 