<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
61a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
February 11, 1940
Sun. Evening 
9917 Emerson
Overland
Dearest Folks:-
<p>It was swell to receive your letter, Mom. We are always happy to hear from you all, as it does seem too bad we cannot see each other oftener.</p>
<p>You probably have heard by now that Alice has been down with the qrippe (not flu). She got caught at Hilda's &amp; the doc advised her to stay there in bed till she was better. It so happened that she could without incoveniencing, for Margaret was gone a week. However, she's back here to day - Hilda came out with her &amp; stayed to dinner with us then went home early to bed. Hil is looking very well now, considering that she has been having the qrippe herself. She's all right now tho', &amp; is seeming to feel quite happy &amp; peppy. Al has missed a week of dancing &amp; I'm going to try to make her stay home two or three days more till she gets over this</p>
2
<p>attack of grippe. Her eyes look so much more like hers now, so I believe she's okay. Hil had Dr. Jennings for her.</p>
<p>Ol &amp; I have been having colds ourselves - I gues I've told you.</p>
<p>Our furnance had to be cleaned out the other day. This "below" weather caused it to get sooted up so that it was gassing! Had to let the fire go out one day to fix it. So I went to spend the day with Mrs. Harrison, &amp; it was just as well Alice could be in a warm room at Clubs. Mrs. H. had a waffle lunch. Helped her hand clothes in her basement in the A.M. &amp; then after lunch we sewed. She's going to teach me to knit; isn't that swell? I want to make a baby set out of that wool you sent! I want to have Mrs. Harrison over here for lunch very soon. She's really a very dear person &amp; is so fine for a neighbor, to say nothing of her rating as a landlady. MRs. H.'s sister is swell too. We three get together &amp; have great times. So, I hope I'll have</p>
61b
3
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>some cute baby things to show you when you're up this way again.</p>
<p>I think, Mom, it's nice you're looking forward to planting flowers too! There's nothing quite like getting one's hands in the spring soil is there. Ol &amp; I are looking forward to our gardening. We're going to have the front lined with masturtiums (along front porch) and a pansy bed on east side; also a bed of lilies-of-the-valley on same side. Then, we want to have our roses way to the back looking down hill. Also we want a lot of daises &amp; marigolds between back yard &amp; orchard &amp; garden. We'll have a large canna bed or two from those you gave us, some dahlias, etc. We have two large peony plants too. We want to have a garden with string beans, tomatoes, onions, broccoli &amp; chard in it. We have a few <sic>holyhacks</sic> by the garage. Oh boy, what we couldn't do to this place if we only had it bought! We are</p>
4
<p>seriously thinking of buying this place, and so anything we do to it will be to our advantage later, we hope.</p>
<p>Incidentally, Mom, when you send the baby clothes you want me to have, would you send me those walnut knitting needles I let you have once? I don't care about the others, <strike>but</strike> I do want to hold on to the walnut ones, as Great Grandma gave them to me. I'd appreciate that a lot as I may do some knitting one of these days requiring that size needle. Thanks a lot. Of course, there's no hurry at all; but I just wanted to mention the needles, as I really think a lot of them. Just think how much Great Grandma must have done on them?</p>
<p>It sounds as though you use coal down there too - sooty curtains, etc.! I wash my kitchen ones nearly every week!</p>
<p>Alice did receive the $10.00, and I suppose she meant to write sooner, but you know Alice about writing</p>
61c
5
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>letters! She <underline>certainly should</underline> have acknowledged &amp; thanked you &amp; Dad for being so kind as to send her it so promptly. I have been doing a number of things to Alice since she's been here (!) but haven't gotten to the point of letter-writing as yet. I do hope she doesn't consider me hard; but I do insist on her doing things neatly - such as hanging up her clothes &amp; putting away her various things that she uses. I just casually ask her &amp; she's always swell about it, too. She says she doesn't mind my telling her. She'll write a long letter tomorrow when she's lying aroung recuperating. At least I'll ask her to. I know she's meant to write before, &amp; I tho't she had, really.</p>
<p>Dad, we're so happy about your progress on Jed. Do I get to type it? Why don't we hear from you occasionally?</p>
<p>Ol is reading Spengler. Dad, there is a notation on the 2<underline>nd</underline> vol., which</p>
6
<p>we had which says Geo. Ward has Vol #1. Ol wishes he could read it, too. He enjoys the book.</p>
<p>When do we see you in March, Dad &amp; Sig? I wish you would write us.</p>
<p>Hil wants me to come down one of these Saturdays to have lunch &amp; go to a show. Isn't that nice of her?</p>
<p>"Gone with the Wind" is going strong here - on 2nd week. Alice saw it. Ol &amp; I are going to wait till it comes to the Esguire theatre near here one of these days. It's the new one the size of the Fox ub the county.. Harrisons want to go, so we might go with them. It would be fun. We want at least I do, to read the book first. Alice said the play is really interesting and worth while. It takes about 4 hrs. to see it.</p>
<p>Ol &amp; I are listening to the Ford hours &amp; wondering if you all are hearing it too. Do you listen to</p>
61d
7
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>Orson Welles' playhouse. It's very good usually. We're hearing its beginning now.</p>
<p>Ol made some swell rolls today. I'm going to bake soon - just as soon as I get to Overland for some bread pans. I like to use real bread pans for bread - it gets nicer, I think. But those rolls Ol made were great - so fine, light &amp; silky! We all enjoyed them so. Have a pan full left for tomorrow's dinner!</p>
<p>This letter was pretty empty I fear; but there isn't a great deal to say - you know how it is!</p>
<p>Let's hope spring is early this year! That would be grand.</p>
<p>Mom, Mrs. H. asked about you &amp; said she wished she could have had a chance to see you more.</p>
8
<p>Mom, that's interesting about the sea nymph bowl. I'd like one myself! I do hope you get it placed with Carnes. You probably will make something out of this. Here's hoping you are successful. It would be so nice for you, even if it didn't make a lot of money. It's so nice to have something for a paying hobby. But, who knows it might prove more than that! Here's hoping. We're holding thumbs up here for you! Yes, it'd be swell if you &amp; Dad went down there, wouldn't it?</p>
<p>So long till later.</p>
Loads of love, 
Enid Enat.

