<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
[July 19, 1936]
Neihardt Collection 
36-no envelope 
Sunday. 
183
My own Darling
My thoughts are once more with you - and I am so grateful St Louis is having a cool spell - I wonder if Amama is with you and when she will come here, exactly. There is a room on the East reserved for her where it will be most cool at night. Virginia is off duty now and I asked her to stay on a few days as the girls' friend, which she is now doing. Wednes-day she goes to Springfield and next Sat. or Sun. she is driving by here to take Alice to Ozark Beach with her sister and another girl friend for a 

184
few day's vacation - Isn't that nice? I feel less worried about Hilda and Lache because they have not been out quite so much lately due to his family's places. If you were here, they woudl want ot be with you, and that woudl help - but with me sick here there is nothing to make them happy here, so they go away. 
Mr Deerberry has done a wonderful job in the garden - and I think the <unclear/> will survive - although there are no Summer flowers. Our pink radiance rose is put-ting forth bloom, and the interest that Alice always used to have with me in the garden has returned since the heavy work there has been done, and 

185 
this makes me so happy. If we get a real rain I'll have Mr D. clipp our hedge, but it would be foolish to do so now, because the higher the hedge is the more it keeps out dust, which rises in huge clouds every time a car orchard is now alive. Alice rolled me out in the wheelbarrow last evening and there was a little cloud burst and we got soaked! It was such fun!! This morn-ing at 6 AM. I washed my self and started the little coffee percolator going right beside my bed on a little table where the folks bud placed every thing I needed. It seemed so wonderful to be able to do things my self! Now in a few hours I'll bathe all over in this same way and put on a clean night gown for the day - and then Alice will carry me into the front room which Hilda will love cla-med up so nicely. She is at present doing some cooking with the range before it gets too hot. - I meant to say that Mr Deer berry worked 28 hours at 25 cents an hour in the garden - $7.00, Hilda paid him, and 

186
left Yandel's for next week, I believe Alice is having 2 cavities filled, for which we should pay - and I must get that mothers remade forsably upstairs. Amama will doubtless stay at Malone's for a week at least. Am so eager to see her, and so glad she will not have to rush away. Many thanks to you dearest! Oceans of love - 
Always your old girl
Mona. 
Please tell Enid that Hilda wants a white lining in the quilt - She is so pleased - but I'll not let her see the quilt sop at all - and she has no idea what "Double Wedding Ring" means! She is only now waking up to such things. 
M. 