<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
49
Missouri Collection 
<del>48,49,50</del>
Nov. 23,'21
Dear Mama:-
You would think naturally, that I'd have a good deal of news to tell; but as a matter of fact, the life here is quite empty, and I'll be damned if I can think of a single thing about the week in S.F. that is worth telling. Howard took me out to see Shaw's play, "The Doctor's Dilemma", the other night, and it was a <unclear/> play 
-2- 
I've later dinners & lunches & gobbled to no effect with many people of local importance, some of national reputation But nothing worth saying was said on either side. 
I've recorded not to take the book to Portland, as the weather is stormy & the sea dangerous. Train casts by <unclear/>. Think of it, $29.60 from S. F. to Portland, and a nights ride from there to Walla Walla. Think I'll yet <unclear/> with about $250. I have one place (miserable) 

50
-3-
about which <unclear/> knows nothing, & I'm going to keep it all - $100. It has not played up to me as he should seek out no advertising matter, & the n.m. schools & colleges are consequently, hard put to boost the affair at the present moment I have $100 in my pocket, Have taken in $250, I sent home $30. So I've actually spent $120 thus far, tho I've kept a tight hand on my pocket. I still have the following:
Walla Walla - $75 
Lewiston - $75 or $50
Pullman 75 or $50
Moscow nothing 
Muscoula 100
Lincoln 75 or 100 
Kearney (possibly) 75 or 100 
Counting the Convest figure, & not condemning Kearney, I shall yet take in $350. Add 100 in <del/> packet - $450. Expense home, 125 (maybe $150). then I must 

51
-4-
pay 20% commission on $500 to <unclear/>- $100. This is figuring high on expenses & corn on income. & should get home until $250 clear - for 7 weeks of nonsense & waste? 
It's nothing surprising. I knew it would be so. In Feb-march, I'll make more in a week than now in seven weeks. But I'll not go east of Chicago. I refuse Damned of I'll waste much time. 
-5- 
We dont' need it. If I can get enough to retain our house a bit & give you a little stoke, I'll be satisfied. 
Well, this is about all, I can think of. Don't worry aobut me in any ay. I'll be allright. 
Lots & lots of love, 
Jno. 
I know now, better than ever, that we are all very very lucky. 
Times have been wanting & telephoning to get me to visit them. I dodged beautifully! Don't want to visit them. 