<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.11b.86.95">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, September 8th 1935</title>
<author>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.11b.86.95</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Mona Martinsen Neihardt to Enid Neihardt, September 8th 1935</title>
<date when="1935-09-08">September 8th, 1935</date>
<extent>9 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term>Neihardt, Hilda</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Private Worlds</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt Mona Martinsen</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1935-09-08"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5780993">Salt Lake City (Utah)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2020"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2020"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.11b.86.95.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">86</fw>
<note type="curatorial">Fink Collection 
64.</note>

<opener>
<dateline>Sunday 
[Sept 8, 1935]
</dateline>
<salute>Darling Enid:</salute>
</opener>

<p>You have been doing up all the little things that needed to be done - and that means you are being a dear good little woman as usual - and that is so worth while. Thanks so much for send-ing the white flower plant. I'll surely do all you say and all i can do to help it live. Some-how or other I have little faith in any northern plant doing well down here - The Bull berries are gone - the Buffalo grass has disappeared as well as the carti</p>

<fw type="curatorial">87</fw>
<fw type="authorial">2</fw>

<p>The Prairie Queen rose seems dead also. This is not cold enough and not cruel enough a climate for such things it would seem. - 
It looks as though I were going ot have a wonder-ful Fall for flowers - The zinnias are full of buds. and everyhting, even the roses have "picked up." and now we got a much need-ed rain on top of the manure which I spread about lately. 
Enid dear, I have the </p>

<fw type="curatorial">88</fw>
<fw type="authorial">3</fw>
<p>finest Permanent you ever saw, and so has Alice. The Olsen Beauty shop is the real thing - such splendid equip-ment. 
We saw "Private Worlds" and liked it - but it was only fairly interesting - not really deep. - The rest of the show was so poor that I wished myself at home a num-ber of times! I simply am getting worse about hating Jazz etc. I have also got-</p>


<fw type="curatorial">89</fw>
<fw type="authorial">4</fw>
<p>ten very good reasons for my feelings out of a book in Occultism which I have been sopping up lately like a dry sponge does water! It speaks of forms and shapes created by music which are very real and powerful - for good as well as back - and Jazz is certainly bad. and most undesirably in its creative power - so beware - and don't expose yourself to its influence unduly dearest </p>

<fw type="curatorial">90</fw>
<fw type="authorial">5</fw>
<p>of girlies mine! Your old motehr is not so wrong on this point, and if you turn on the radio just to keep from facing thoughts you are doing yourself untold harm to say the very least. Better think even unhappy thoughts, than dispel these with such a damming influences as Jazz (or drink!) 
Today, Sunday, Hilda cooked a dandy dinner, I baked an apple pie, </p>

<fw type="curatorial">91</fw>
<fw type="authorial">6</fw>
<p>Sig bought some ice cream to put on it - All was wonderful and we wished you and Daddy might be with us. I know my dad - dy and Grandma were with us! 
Enid dear you will read my letters to Daddy a swell as this one to you and I have little new to say. 
Mrs Spurlock was so pleased. Please look in General </p>

<fw type="curatorial">92</fw>
<fw type="authorial">7</fw>
<p>
Delivery Salt Lake City as there might be some mail there for you by mis-take. 
No, I will not change Daddy's bust - I may not even cast it till after you come back, and I can be sure it is the best I can do!-
I have a lot doen for Hilda and there is more to be done - but she will </p>

<fw type="curatorial">93</fw>
<fw type="authorial">8</fw>
<p>be in fine shape - After next Friday I'll be able to think for myself again. 
Things look fair for Sigurd in Harrison etc. That is the best one can expect. 
Maxine is well but Oh, how can she carry so big a burden much longer?! 
Alice loves school, and she looks so pretty with her Permanent in back, and </p>

<fw type="curatorial">94</fw>
<fw type="authorial">9</fw>
<p>her hair drawn straight back from her face. 
Frankie is dandy help as usual. I called on Miss Bennet and Mrs Denton. Nothing else to tell - excepting that I think of you so very very often and am so glad you are where you are - </p>


<closer>
<salute>Loads of Love</salute>
<signed>from Mama.</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
<div1 type="envelope">
<fw type="curatorial">95</fw>
<p>I sent the Macmillans Booklets and Sheets - and am saving the Papers with Daddy's reviews as you asked:</p>

<fw>Neihardt
Branson, Mo.</fw>

<ab type="postmark">BRANSON SEP 9 3-PM 1935 MO.</ab>

<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Miss Enid Neihardt </addrLine>
<addrLine>c/o Mr Charles W. Kelly </addrLine>
<addrLine>473 First Ave.</addrLine>
<addrLine>Salt Lake City 
Utah.</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>