<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
297 Fink Collection 31
Neihardt
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
AUG10
3-PM
1941
M.O.
Mr &amp; Mrs O.F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
St Louis County
Mo.
32
Saturday
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Your good letter and the package came today, both were so welcome. Indeed Daddy and I are most grateful for the chance to be with you for a long enough visit to really help you Enid during the period just before and after our darling brand new baby arrival. I am therefore eager to hear what Dr Finley and you decide about the probable date of its advent - also I am anxious to Know what hospital if any you decide upon. I am ready to do</p>
2
<p><underline>any</underline> thing to help, and so is "Gaki". he is a marvelous assistant. Needless to say it is a wonderful help to us as well to be allowed to stay with you. We are definitely not going to California thsi Fall. Daddy received a telegram from Mitchel to that effect. I think Mitchel has gotten out of <underline>his</underline> end of it very glibly offering no fair excuse - but it is evident that written contracts are made to bind the <underline>other</underline> fellow never oneself! So now Daddy having depended on Mitchel has <underline>had</underline> to wait until it is too late for anything else in the lecture field.</p>
33
3
<p>our <sic>coffeetable</sic> piece cast.</p>
<p>John says it is very beautiful - and strangely light looking for a thing so heavy. We have made the first cast in concrete, but we think it would be wise to learn to make rubber molds, and then produce quite a number in plaster or else ew could have them in pottery, which would put us in debt to begin with, and this we do not like. Do you think we could sell such a piece for about $3-5.00 to people who really love beautiful things? That would</p>
4
<p>be in plaster, enamel painted. It could not be as beautiful as pottery - but it would be lovely, and could be produced cheaply.</p>
<p>Thanks so much for the chair decorations. I have placed them on the big brown chair where they are perfect. I have not yet decided on the curtains but will do so shortly. They are lovely. Maxie has been <underline>really</underline> sick - a sort of Flu and I have been very glad to be so strong and well able to do every thing necessary. She is now very nearly normal again. We are having her company today Aileen Heirs, the young</p>
34
5
<p>woman who works at Baldwins'. She drove from Kansas City this AM, arriving here before noon. She has to leave for St. Louis tomorrow morning. We are glad to have her.-</p>
<p>It is going to be lovely to see you again. Please allow us to sleep in our own bed upstairs in the <sic>attick</sic>, will you not?</p>
<p>We'd like to sleep out on our cots if it should be hot, and play we are camping!</p>
<p>Please let us Know when you would most</p>
6
<p>want us to come, and we will plan accordingly.</p>
Loads of Love always
from
Mama
Mother
<p>P.S. It seems the War Scare is terrible on the coast, and it is Knocking on all sorts of business so that may explain Mitchels "flunking".</p>