<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
94a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo. 
April 4, 1941
Dear Folks:-
<p>Thanks for the card, Max. And, Mom &amp; Dad, we hope to hear a word or so from you tomorrow!</p>
<p>Ol &amp; I've been having a grand time today! He's been cutting wood, transplanting stuff, namely the small rose of shaion tree, &amp; working on various other things. Just fixed the little boudair chair up, &amp; we're going to use it in the bedroom, where it really belongs, now since we have two new chairs &amp; a settee!! Max, I'm delighted over having the chest of drawers! I had it in mind it belonged to you. I can surely use it for the nursery! I'm going to enjoy fixing up the sunroom as such! I've been <unclear/> past few days, getting all the baby stuff, that wasn't done up, fixed. Max, you know the three wool blankets Marie used &amp; passed on to me at your request? They're going to be great to use. I just washed them out in Lux flakes &amp; got them pulled into shape &amp; all fluffy! Just wanted to mention to you that when I received them they had holes in them (the two pink &amp; white ones!) and so I darned them up as well as I could with pink yarn. I guess they've been used a lot, haven't they? I'm thankful to have them to <strike>you</strike> use for our bunny! I've been wanting to tell you, Max, how lovely the baby things in the box are that you did up! I won't have to touch those things. It'll be so much fun to place things in the chest after we've painted it &amp; all!</p>
2
<p>We've gotten 1/2 gal. of ivory enamel (only 98<cent/> one pale!) to paint the wicker set, high chair, basket, chest-of-drawers &amp; perhaps the baby bed that Maude (Ol's sister in law) gives us. <underline>Are we thrilled</underline> over this, too!? We gave Art a gun &amp; he wants to swap us the baby bed for same! - A good trade - eh? Also we hope to stretch the enamel to a bit of trellio &amp; window-box painting too! I'm going to cover the high chair pad with a chintz piece of some cute pattern, possibly blue or pink.</p>
<p>I made a batch of roll today - were good again. Also, some cinamon rolls &amp; 3 loaves of bread. We took Mrs. H. some rolls &amp; they seem to <underline>go</underline> for them too! Wish Hil &amp; Al &amp; Sig would happen out tomorrow <sic>nite</sic>! I've asked them many a time to come - but guess it's too far! Maybe Sig <underline>will</underline> happen out!! The kids are all so busy.</p>
(Next day - April 5th)
<p>We ate cinamon rolls for breakfast &amp; we just can't get enough of those darn things!</p>
<p>Just rec'd your card Mom, &amp; were <underline>so</underline> happy for it! Ol painted the first ivory coat on the wicker rocker last <sic>nite</sic>. Little by little we'll get all the things painted. the wicker will need two coats we find. Then it'll be even <underline>more</underline> fun putting the upholstery on it and making the pillow covers for the small pillows! This is Sat. already! Time surely flies when Ol is home! Mom, I didn't mean to give the wrong impression about the big dresser! You knwo we can always put it upstairs. Jack H. &amp; Ol can get it up easy</p>
94b
3
<p>when the drawers are out &amp; mirror is off, I believe. But, there's no hurry, surely. We won't be changing the sunroom until after the place is <sic>thru</sic> being used - about June or July, I guess. Ol's Mom may come soon for a visit &amp; we wouldn't want to have her go upstairs - or you &amp; Dad either! Too dangerous at <sic>nite</sic>.</p>
Loads o' love,
Ollie &amp; Enid
<p><underline>P.S.</underline>
We're both feelin' fine. How are you feelin'? "Bunny" gives me a nudge or two every once in awhile! It's so very sweet!</p>
<p>Mom, abou the bread pans - you know how little time Ol has at noon! We'll send them, tho' just as soon as possible!</p>
<p>We have been ordering groceries from that ABC Mkt. on Lackland lately. They have "Creamo" also, which is <unclear/> cream. We like it better than any we've had so far. We have two red glasses &amp; now fine Creamo gives an adorable heavy galss with tasty colored Morning Glories on it. Now we want a set of those! Ha. We'll fill in on the red ones whenever we go to Food Center. We've always been crazy about the ABC Mkt., tho' &amp; they have started to deliver only recently! Their juices are very decent &amp; <underline>as good</underline> in<underline> most</underline> things as Food Center &amp; A-P.!!</p>
<p>So long!</p>
Love -
Enid &amp; Ollie
over
<p>We'll be glad to see you again! #Ol's having a great time now with the dynamo,etc. Bill Camp was deeply struck too! He gave Ol a few tips on using the lathe when he was here the other nite. Ol's finishing the cocktail table too now! There are <underline>more</underline> things to do!! How can anyone ever be bored! I can't remember being that way!</p>
<p>I decided to make a nursery rug out of the silk pieces, Mom, as I need one, &amp; the colors are so well suited for such. I want to make a wool afghan throw for settee someday? That is, <underline>if</underline> I'm not busy knitting child's clothes, etc.</p>
Love,
Eny
<p>Write when you can!</p>
<p>Love to Max, Joanie &amp; Elaine!</p>
<p>Ol sends his love &amp; says he's so busy - but this is from him too.</p>
<p>Mom, I got a white silk crepe slip the other day - has brassiere top with elastic.</p>