<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
23b
Aug 17, 1942
Monday
Dear Mom;
<p>Yes, it seems every summer I have a seige. I was so afraid is be as sick as I was down home but I immediately got busy and took one deKKih after another and a dose of custor oil to end up on. The wubs too were sort of down so they rec'd the same treatment. It was indigation and colds &amp; a touch of intestinal flu. Hilda has also had it and we have been miserable together, unfortunately. Hil feels better as do I today and of course the wubs are fine. It seems to taKe them less time to recover than it does grown-ups. Joan weighs 43 lbs, Elaine weighs 40 lbs. Joan looKs thinner but I can't decide whether she is just lengthing out or <strike>just</strike> really thinner. According to the scales she is lengthening having weighed 42 lbs about a month ago.</p>
2.
<p>The heat really was sicKening and I feel very lucKy to have the wubs well as long as I did.</p>
<p>they miss Branson so much, and how they want to see Dr. George. They talk about him so much.</p>
<p>The other morning Elaine looKs up at me &amp; said, "Mamma, GaKi is sicK." I didn't pay much attention but noted it because she was very serious. The letter arrived from Dad telling about his bonchial attacK and I Knew she had received the news from some other source. Bless her! They are such dear, good babies and getting nicer in so many ways. They never fail to say their prayers and only once or twice did. They need to help when they were feeling too bad to say them. Joan always has insisted on them while Elaine has felt more than once that she was too sleepy &amp; tired.</p>
<p>Give Amama our love. We are sorry too that she will not</p>
3.
<p>stay longer. It is strange how little one can help those whom one most wishes to help. I guess they are happiest going their own way. I am sorry she is having a hard time.</p>
<p>I feel, since we have given fate every opportunity to give us a chance in war production and nothing has come of it - in fact every thing has seemed to arise to keep up out of it; that now is the time for us to get into music. So with that uppermost in mind - the way prepared. As carefully as possible - we are going to Chicago to maKe a stab at what we really want. If the worst comes to the waist we can return to our job here and try again later. Sig is in fine shape to play now as he has practiced hard as often as he could has practiced hard as often as he could this summer. He plans to play for all the conservatories &amp; music schools, all the good pianists that are there and some good agents. If that doesn't pan out we are going to</p>
4.
<p>plaster the college with letters to say he is available for a piano dept. Degree or no degree he could get in now. he will not he drafted and even if he were he would at least be used in some mechanical way. So that is my attitude and I feel it is not wrong. Its up to us to maKe the jump.</p>
<p>Let me find out what is going to happen to us before I decide what to do about my vast number of possessions! I will Know iin two weeKs.</p>
<p>Yes, Joan &amp; Elaine will go to Doziee school just around the corner from us here where you went to find out about the sugar for us, if we stay here!</p>
<p>I'm thrilled over the "Dream" wish I could see it.</p>
<p>Stokers address is 530 N. Union but I will tell her if you want me to that her comb is not there!</p>
23c
5.
<p>Alice looKed wonderful while here and said nothing about having had the curse yet so I don't Know. <strike>But</strike> Hil doesn't Know either out I'm sure she is oK. Strange isn't it - she seems in perfect shape.</p>
<p>We feel too, <strike>that</strike>, more and more and oftener &amp; oftener as the weeKs &amp; months go by - how lucKy we are to belong to you &amp; GaKi. there is always a feeling of strength when we thinK of you. And we need it too.</p>
<p>Tell GaKi that $3 was the cost of the plate being fixed - no more, no less. So glad the worK ws oK &amp; the time involved so <strike>small</strike> short.</p>
<p>I'm hemming some little prints I got for the wubs here so guess had better close &amp; get busy.</p>
Endless love from us all-
Max &amp; family!
<p>P.S. we are so thrilled about Kemper - feel sure it will worK out.</p>