<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
171 Fink Collection 62
Feb. 12, 1940
Neihardt
Branson, 
Mo.
BRANSON
FEB 13
3 -PM 
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O.F.Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St. Louis 
County
63
Monday
Darling Enid:
<p>This has been a lovely day; the Sun has been glorifying it and making it easy to wash and clean and bake - all of which I have been doing to day as Maxie has been having her monthly need for rest, and it has made me so happy to be able to save her at such times - because I remember how much easier it is to keep going the rest of the month when one can rest at that time - Keep off of one's feet. She is so very appreciative that it makes it easy to help her. Needless to say, she is not idle; she had been typing loads of letters today and yesterday and the day before she did a lot of Knitting and cutting of old things into strips, and sewing them together to be made into crocheted rugs or braided ones later on.</p>
64
2
<p>Daddy adn I were so glad for your dear letter - and your planning for a way we might live nearer together. But as yet we don't see the solution - I Know it will appear when the time is right. In the mean while Daddy is feeling in much better spirits than I have seen him for a long time and in better health. He is able to go on with Jed, the next part - I am glad to say. The men, it appears now, are not likely to be going to St. Louis - That city seems a hard nut to crack for Sigurd. I mean there is less response there than any other city of its size that he has approached. So they are going to go directly to the Carolinas and back - a rather abort trip this</p>
65
3
<p>time. We think Daddy will get along very well with Jed before he has to go out for Summer engagements.</p>
<p>Now what about Alice this Summer Enid dearie? How do you feel about her presence in your home? I Know she <underline>is</underline> dear, and you too are dear, and I want to Know the <underline>truth</underline>, just how do you feel about having her there this Summer yet? If she could remain until she comes Home for her Summer vacation with Hilda may be, then when they return to St Louis in the Fall they could be together again. There will be a way to do what <underline>is right</underline> for both of you. So please tell me <underline>just</underline> what you think and don't fear any misunderstanding for I Know there will be none.</p>
66
4
<p>Daddy does <underline>not</underline> really want a job - and you Know how be dislikes any city - even Overland does not sound good to him. In fact he feels better about Branson than for a good many years. He talks of having a cow again, and I want chickens - so you see we may have a miniature "farm" by the time you come back to spend another vacation here. I am trying to feel that Alice is just away from home doing what she wants to do in place of going to college which is right and natural enough. Yet I have a sneaking hope deep down inside of me that somehow or other I <underline>can</underline> be near her again - Who Knows? All one <underline>can</underline> do is pray. And be patient - Dad does</p>
67
5
<p>not have George Ward's address - or you might write him and try to get that first Wolume of Spengler. Sig does all of Daddy's correspondence.</p>
<p>Please tell Ollie I think the cutest thing about his <unclear>spark</unclear> is the baby - pot! It is something <underline>I</underline> can recognize!! and tell him too that I would love to have a word from him about his very own, dear, good self. I am all excited about that chance for higher salaries at the P.D.-</p>
<p>I hope you do get breaded-pans and back regularly - as your family will enjoy that a lot.</p>
<p>We listended to Orson Wells last night in Mr. Deeds comes to town and it was mighty good. I dislike the Chase and <unclear>Sanburn</unclear> hour now adays- and we have so much</p>
68
6
<p>interfereince that the Ford hour is about spoiled for us here. We enjoy Muin and his two lovely ladies imensely though. We love the W.R.U.L. short wave programs because they are <underline>always</underline> good and have not selling of goods in between - those long announcemetns irritate me unspeakably.</p>
<p>Your flowers sound so good to me - I am going to start hollyhocks in doors this year. Our fish are alive and seemingly very happy - but there is a leak in the cement we are going to have to find where the weather is warm once more.</p>
<p>I'm going to see the red bud bloom this year!</p>
Loads of Love to my two dear children - as well as to my baby - Devotedly 
Mother - Mama