<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
4a
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>Thanks so much to both of you for the wonderful time you gave us! The little plants <underline>all</underline> are growing. Enid dear. They look happy this morning!</p>
<p>I planted the foliage plant in teh big <unclear>Horine</unclear> pot I told you of - and it is beautiful there. I still have no <underline>permanent</underline> place for the others.</p>
<p>Daddy adn I are missing you all so terribly - but we are going to be very happy after we get adjusted to our new life. Enid darling, please Keep me in touch with you and every little thing you do for life is made up of those little things in the Home, is it not?</p>
<p>I am trying to put things in order here, and soon the place will look right again. Then I will look right again. Then I want you and Ollie to come down <underline>any</underline> time you <underline>can</underline>. There is room, and there will always be such a big welcome for you. If you go ahead with your big plan, Enid darling, let me Know just how you are progressing, <underline>please</underline>.</p>
Endless love to you from 
your devoted Mama
Mother.
4b
THE ADVISORY BOARD
OFFICE OF THE
CHAIRMAN
JOHN G. NEIHARDT
BRANSON
MISSOURI
UBI LITERAE
IBI LUX
THE ORDER OF BOOKFELLOWS
Next Day
Dear Enot and Oddie:
<p>Arrived at 5:20 in good shape, but, golly, how empty the house seemed! Heavy rain here yesterdcay, and more in the night and this forenoon. There has been no sun at all today.</p>
<p>Enot, I was just about to give in once or twice and stay another day with you. Really wanted to stay. But Mama &amp; I will drive up now &amp; tehn, Why not? I do want your dream to come true, and believe it will. It's necessary to have youngsters around. As for this life, it's certainly good in a <strike/> million little ways and in some really big ways. As a matter of fact, the <underline>only</underline> bad thing is the economic racket, and that can be licked reasonably well. When I see these "pinkling" cans and little tables and tiny chairs scattered around over the place, I know kids are mighty desirable. So you just be happy in your plan, and of course it will happen.</p>
<p>Bless your hearts, Oddie and Enot! I've never known any finer people than you are</p>
Love always
Dad.
4c
BRANSON.
SEP4
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
<stamp>UNITED 
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3</stamp>
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland,
MO.
(St. Louis Co.)