<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.38.43">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, August 4th 1929</title>
<author>Neihardt, Culler Alice</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4b.38.43</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to John G. Neihardt, August 4th 1929</title>
<date when="1929-08-04">August 4th 1929</date>
<extent>6 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1929-08-04"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, Enid</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Carney, Mary Jo</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4b.8.38.43.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">38</fw>
<note type="curatorial">701 Fine Collection 31-34?</note>

<opener>
<dateline>Sunday [August 4, 1929]?
</dateline>
<salute>Enid darling:</salute>
</opener>

<p>It is so nice to get your letters I jut eat them up and try to feel that you do care a little for your silly Mamma <unclear/> of her queerness! 
We went to a number of country places yesterday. Mr Turner took no in his Chevrolet. We did see some lovely homes but the fine ones were over $10.000, and the others were not a patch on <del>one</del> our Branson home - and at </p>

<fw type="curatorial">39</fw>
<fw type="letterhead">UnderStand America</fw>
<p>that so much more expensive. I feel it wrong and foolish for Daddy to slave for a place near St Louis, when we do not any of us need St Louis.
If we are all very careful this Winter, we can save more money than we have done any other year, and Daddy and I have figured out the cost of making a beautiful home of our Branson place in dollars and the whole thing comes to less than #1000. Now we can 
<unclear/> MISSOURI </p>

<fw type="curatorial">40</fw>
<p>save that much money this year. Without touching Daddy's investments. And in his investments he has enough to keep us going and more till he has written the Messiah - after that he can do something from Branson he has a couple of plans that are possible. He will tell you about them himself. 
I am so anxious for you to get a years experience at the Post Dispatch, and for Sigurd to get a mechanics apprentice job. Then you two fine "kids" will </p>

<fw type="curatorial">41</fw>
<p>be earning money of your own. And will hold you up sill you can get jobs in Springfield. I feel so grateful for you, Enid dear, and I think you know how to appreciate your good Daddy, don't you dear? Sigurd is sure eager to earn, and is doing well in his work at teh Field. 
I sent your Music. Also I sent Grandma the price of your shoes be fore you told me you had borrowed. <del>Could you</del> Have you any money left now dear? Tell me how much if any. It is terribly hot s
UnderStand America </p>

<fw type="curatorial">42</fw>
<p>muggy here. 
I wish Daddy could take a longer vacation - I think Grandma woudl get so much pleasure out of it and she use of she car too. 
Please tell me how Grand-ma happened to fall over the lawnmower - Did you leave it in the wrong place after doing the mowing? Oh Enid deaer do be careful!
I am so glad you are doing most of the ironing for I 
! </p>

<fw type="curatorial">43</fw>
<p>know that really helps. 
It is so nice that you have found such a good friend in Grace Pearl, please remember me to her. The snap of you two was nice - also the one of Grandma But not good of Hilda and Alice. Do please take them in their bathing suits again for me. </p>
<closer>
<salute>Love, Oceans of it, </salute>
<signed>from Mamma.</signed>
<fw type="footer">UnderStand America </fw>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>