<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<div1 type="enclosure">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.64.23"/>

<fw type="curatorial">23</fw>

<dateline>Thursday, November 2, 1972 Wisner News-Chronicle</dateline>   <fw>9</fw>
_______________________________________________________________________________________
<head><hi rend="bold">Neihardt Foundation Buys Land for Center</hi></head>

<p>by <hi rend="caps">MAXINE KESSINGER</hi></p>

<p>The Board of Directors of the John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt Foundation have announced that land has been purhased for the future development of the Neihardt Center at Bancroft.</p>

<p>The buy has been made possible by the generosity of one of the town's civic-minded citizens, George <hi rend="caps">P.</hi> Diedrichsen, who shared costs with the Foundation in the purchase of the three lots and house of Margaret Buchholz at the auction sale on Oct. 13. Also the Foundation has obtained the option to buy the three south adjoining lots from Leo Buchholz.</p>

<p>This land transaction is the assurance for future growth and development of the Neihardt Center. Tenative plans include the building of a shrine, a research library and a museum where scholars and tourists can come to learn, study and to experience Neihardt and his work. Much of Neihardt's manuscripts will be housed in the new center.</p>

<p>Dick Cavett has been named the Honorary Chairman of the national fund raising effort.</p>

<p>The Neihardt Center will be a unique tribute to the Poet of the Prairies who has used his art to communicate facts and history through the medium of words. He has vitally contributed to the understanding and preservation of our midwestern heritage.</p>



<fw>20</fw> <dateline>Lincoln Neb. Journal,Tuesday Oct. 31, 1972</dateline>
__________________________________________________________________________________

<head><hi rend="bold">Foundation Buys Land in Bancroft</hi></head>


<head><hi rend="bold"><hi rend="italics">Neihardt Center To Grow</hi></hi></head>

<p>Bancroft &#8212; Acquisition of three blocks of land across from Neihardt Center here represents what the John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt Foundation considers 
<figure>
<figDesc>Nebraska</figDesc>
<p>Bancroft
<hi rend="caps">LINCOLN</hi></p>
</figure>
a major step in its plans to enlarge the center.</p>

<p>The land was purchased by the foundation from Margaret Buchholtz pf Bancroft. A Bancroft cattle buyer, George <hi rend="caps">P.</hi> Diedrichsen, shared half of the $2,750 cost, according to Maxine Kessinger, a foundation director.</p>

<p>The foundation also took an option to buy three more blocks directly across from the downtown center, which consists of the Sioux Prayer Garden and the restored cottage study where the Nebraska poet laureate wrote his most famous works in the early part of the century.</p>

<p>Tentative plans for the expansion, announced on Neihardt Day last August, call for a Neihardt shrine, a research library and a museum, Mrs. Kessinger said.</p>

<p>"Indications are, and we are hoping, that it will be one the top cultural centers in the Midwest," she said.</p>

<p>The center, established with the prayer garden in 1965, draws several thousand tourists annually now, she added.</p>

<p>The foundation is sponsoring a nationwide fund-raising campaign under honorary chairman Dick Cavett to carry out its plans, which Mrs. Kessinger said, "represent a great tribute to our poet laureate, who did so much to put our historical heritage into words."</p>




<dateline><note type="curatorial">Lincoln Star 11-5-1972 P. 6</note></dateline>


<head><hi rend="italics"><hi rend="bold">Across Nebraska</hi></hi></head>

<figure>
<figDesc>Nebraska</figDesc>
</figure>

<head type="sub"><hi rend="italics"><hi rend="bold">Neihardt Center Expansion Planned</hi></hi></head>

<p>Bancroft &#8212; Land has been purchased for the future development of the Neihardt Center at Bancroft, according to the board of directors of the John <hi rend="caps">B.<sic>G.</sic></hi> Neihardt Foundation. George <hi rend="caps">P.</hi> Diedrichsen of Bancroft shared costs with the foundation in the purchase of three lots and a house recently. Tentative future expansion plans for the center include a shrine, research library and museum where scholars and tourists can learn and study the works of Nebraska's poet laureate.</p>
</div1>