<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
10 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 70
[August 23, 1940]
Friday evein
Dearest Maxie.
<p>Your sweet and thoughtfull words make me realize again how <underline>wonderful</underline> it is to have such good and loving children. Indeed, you must believe me, I am far happier knowning <underline>your excellence</underline>, than I could possibly be in <underline>any</underline> other way. At my age <underline>I</underline> enjoy through <underline>your</underline> joy so much more than I could possibly do first hand. This is fact and also truth. My</p>
71
<p>life has been peculiar, and I have become more and mroe happy as I grow older- so I am truly blessed. It would be tragedy <underline>for me</underline> if you allowed the feeling, that I should be taking this trip instead of you, to <underline>spoil your <unclear>fure</unclear></underline>. So please dont' do that. I Know one must be your age to get a Kick out of the things you will be doing on this trip - I <underline>really honest</underline>ly am happier here in this dear quiet -</p>
72
2
<p>Your sweetheart babies are darling companions - Joanie is at my elbow just now, and she says to tell you she loves her new bed in the blue room, -that we had a <sic>picknick</sic> outdoors.-that she was a good girl to Elaine, that she has been doing lots of work, and playing ball, and that we're having a wonderful time and that we're eating at the little table in the Kitchen and on the back porch, and that she picked some lettuce</p>
73
<p>for our supper last night in her blue dress. I guess this is enough news-! Joanie says too "I hope you're having a good time"!! 'Laine is very busy out doors yet - I don't doubt all this important news will relieve you a lot - Oh Yet! Joanie says "Tell her the blue flowers are growing"! (meaning the Iris is out in 2 or 3 spots)!</p>
<p>I was so thrilled over the news that you <strike>saw</strike> would see Carmen - I read it out loud to Joanie, who duly sympa</p>
74
<p>thized with my out burst of delight! You deserve a whole lot of pleasure and I am so tickled you are having a good start in that direction! - I'm going out to bring my <sic>buzy</sic> baby - for it is getting closer to bed time every minute! --</p>
<p>2 hours have passed - I came down just now after the Wubs were sound asleep to finish this to you! Baby Laine had had such a huge accident (?) that I wondered if I could ever get her clean again - but I really did, and she is as sweet and good looking a baby</p>
75
<p>now in her white pajamas as though she never did a naughty thing! I little dreamed the cause for her quiet enjoyment of the Kiddy car when Joanie stood beside me as I was writing to you, meant what it did!! I am racking my brains now as you used to do, to find <underline>some</underline> way to impress her with the awfulness of soiling her pants!! How funny not? yet it <underline>is</underline> serious. I took the underwear and burned it as it was too full to try to wash - and this impressed Joanie who started to cry - but it did not</p>
76
4
<p>seem to worry Elaine a bit!!</p>
<p>Tomorrow we are going to play "men" and work out of doors all day if the weather permits. We are going to wear pants all of us! Elaine is "Jimmy" and Joan when I wanted to call Joe or John does not like the idea - although she thinks it swell for Elaine to be Jimmy! I am not Nannie but Gaki! Well we'll see how well we put it over! In any case it will be funn.---</p>
<p>this is the way we sleep.</p>
77
<figure type="hand drawing"/>
<p>Blue room.</p>
<p>1 = Baby 'Laine
2 = Nannie
3 = Joanie
4 = Your Vanity dresser
5 = Grandma's "
6 = Children's book case.</p>
<p>The Wubs each face South, I face North with my feet close to the back door. Joan has the <underline>pink</underline> fluffs on her comforter, Baby Laine the blue - they each have the pillowcases to match. Joanie moved all of her clothes, and Baby sisters' out of your dresser into theirs - They both seem delighted with it all!</p>
<p>I believe the <underline>only</underline> pieces of furni</p>
78
5
<p>ture. I have not moved upstairs and down, are Sigurd's Piano and Daddy's desk!!! Everything looks lovely, and the beds are all placed with regard to getting as much air as possible in hot weather. I hope, adn I feel sure you will like the changes I have made. I have the bathroom floor so that it looks swell by using the Kitchen strip. Now I will give the Kitchen floor <underline>two</underline> coats of paint. Then I'll not be ashamed to have people</p>
79
<p>look at this place. I put the ad in the paper.--</p>
<p>Your Daddy has been <underline>so</underline> kind - and both days has mailed a letter to you immediately upon receipt. One from Montgomery, the other from the second place at which John lectures. Please tell Sigurd there has been <underline>no</underline> other mail so far. I'm not expecting any till the change of the Moon, but I'm looking for lots then.</p>
80
6
<p>I hope all this is not just silly to you - I think one should Keep in touch with all the details - or else one is cut off - and that is <underline>my</underline> idea of Hell - to be cut off form those we love.</p>
<p>Thanks again for your dear note and looking forward to your description of Carmen.</p>
I am your own devoted
Mom.