<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
338 <strike>339</strike> - Fink Collection 146
Box 167
Branson, MO.

BRANSON JUL24 3 -PM 1942 M.O.

UNITED STATES POSTAGE 3 CENTS 3

Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
147
Friday
Dear Enot, Ollie &amp; Nei
<p>I'm wondering if the short-hand books may not have been loaned. Did Hiddy use them when she was first at the Consulate? The two I sent were found together, and as only the most needed ones are missing, it seems likely they were put to use by someone.</p>
<p>I believe I left my old teeth somewhere in or about the chest of drawers in "our" room. I've broken a couple of teeth, and I'd be grateful no end if you'd send me the old plate for use while I have my other plate in dry dock!</p>
<p>Stamps enclosed, as I know you may not have them on hand at the moment. It's the quality of the teeth that causes my trouble. The plate itself seems unbreakale. My glasses are at Erker's too! Very funny!! The <strike/> fram just came apart without strain.</p>
<p>It's good to hear about your activities, &amp; I'd like to be there a part of the time to do this or that with you.</p>
148
<p>The beans next door dried up, but since our rain they may come back. I worked our oild stove over - made new burners, better tahn the original ones, &amp; now the stove is new &amp; burns bluer &amp; hotter than in its youth. The new stove costs $5.50, &amp; I spent 60<centsymbol/> making the old one new.</p>
<p>Ollie, it seems the potatoes didn't yield as they should, even considering the gravelling. I wonder about that moon theory of the old folks. Did you get your latest planting in during the dark of the moon? It would be fun to plant to rows side by side, one in the dark &amp; one in the light of the moon - just to see what!</p>
<p>The weather and the place here are heavenly. I wish you could drop in with old Nei. The little cuss - crawling under his Dad's knees and coming up through!!</p>
<p>Everything harmonous <unclear>&amp; happy</unclear> here.</p>
Endless love
Dad