<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
34
Branson, Mo. 
October 20th 38
My dear Mr Holm, 
My husband hav-ing asked that I should reply to your request for more information on the Poet's home and our children I will now do so to the best of my ability. 
I have always felt there was some thing wrong with the assumption that a man of Genius must live in an excentric manner, and have ^a low standard of morals if any - and I believe the time has come when the world can point to one major poet as proof positive that the greatest work can be achieved by one whose moral and spiritual life is of the highest, and that married life is not only necessary but condusive to the working out of tru inspira-
tions into perfection of form. 
We were married at the home of Keene Abbot just 30 years ago in Omaha, Nebraska. John and I having come from entirely different environments, but being alike in our passion for the higher values in every field of life and Art - our friends viewed the experiment with misgivings. However <del/> our marriage has been a most wonderful success. Not that we have been spared the most painful periods of adjustment which I believe are common to marriages, but having the same funda-mental belief in what is good in Art as well as living, 
OMaha Pub. Lib 

35
together we could work it out. 
Today I feel sure there is no happier family "close Knit in the fabric of things" than is ours. 
We have four children: 
Enid, who up until her marriage recently has been her fathers secretary, accompanying him on his trips into Indian reservations, taking down all data for "Black Elk Speaks" acting also as secretary at the Post Dispatch in her fathers' editorial and critical work. 
Sigurd, our only son whose fore most talent is Music. He was born with "Perfect Pitch" and is a rare Pianist whose ultimate achievement cannot yet be known. He is also interested in mechanics and has gradu from the Ranken School of Mecha-

5 
school in St Louis. Her report cards always show 4 ES! Her chief in-terest outside of school is Classi-cal Ballet, and she may choose to make this her life-work. 
In our Home, Mr Neihardt was a most unsually pa-tient, sweet father. With four active children there was ample chance for irritation - but while of fiery temperament he never seemed to be irritated with the little ones. When I was too utterly weary or sick he would walk with the ba-bies and he had made a "sleepy song" than never failed to put the youngster to sleep - it must 
6
36
have had magic in it! When older the "kids" were always seen stringing along after him on his walks and rambles, and not only his but the neighbors' as well! He enjoys close contact with children and animals. Of a chill evening it used to be common to find him seated with the children beside a bonfire-and close at hand the family cow, the riding horse, a goat, the cat and the dog - all seemingly in a state of bliss. At such tiems very often John has spoken poetry to them. When very young Enid and Sigurd would ask Daddy to please sing poetry "a most descriptive phrase!
As a son, John was very close to his mother, whom he supported through out of our married life. She al- had her own little home next 

7
37
door both in Nebraska and later in Mo, where she chose to accompany us in order to remain near her son and his family. 
As grandfatehr, John is as sweet a one as he was a father. His first grandchild "Joan" who is named for him, although scarcely 3 already says: "Come on, Grandan lets go..." pulling him to go down into woodsy places, where the world is so full of a number of things, and where one sings to the evening star, seated on the big couch in that most beautiful "fontroom"-
So thanks to him, our lives full of beauty and rich, 
ness, and with the advancing years he becomes kinder and mellower and altogether great-er. 
As for Dr Houe, we was a dear and encouraging friend. He believes in John with an almsot feminine devotion, at a time when there were few such believers. No history of Neihardt would be complete with out mentioning this friendship 
Hoping I have bene able to give you waht you wanted I remain yours sincerely
Mona Neihardt. 

38
Branson, Mo. 
Octover 20, 1938
My dear Mr. Holm, 
My husband having asked that I shoudl reply to your request for more information on the Poet's home and our children I will now do so to the best of my ability. 
I have always felt there was something wrong with the assumption that a man of Genius must live in excentric manner, and have a low standard of morals if any and I believe the time has come when the world can piont to one major poet as proof positive that the greatest work can be achieved by one whose moral and spiritual life is of the highest, and that married life is not only necessary but condusive to the working out of true inspirations into perfection of form. 
We were married at the home of Keenn Abbot just 30 years ago in Omaha Nebraska. John and I having come from entirely different environments, but being alike in our passion for the higher values in every field of life and Art--our friends viewed the experiment with misgivings. However our marriage has been a most wonderful success. Not that we have been spared the most painful periods of adjustment which I believe are common to marriages, but having the same funda-mental belief in what is good in Art as well as living, together we could work it out. 
Today I feel sure there is no happier family "close kind in the fabric of theing" than is ours. 
We have four children: 
Enid, who up until her marriage recently has been her fathers secretary, acc-ompanying him on his trips into Indian reservations, taking down all data for "Black Elk Speaks" acting also as secretary at the Post Dispatch in her father's editorial and sribical work. 
Sigurd, our only son whose foremost talent is Music. He was born with "Perfect Pitch", and is a rare Pianist whose ultimate achievement cannot yet be known. He is also gifted in mechanics and has graduated from The Ranken School of Mechanics. He is his father's lecture Manager and plays solos at his father's readings. 

39
Hilda, our third child is gifted in language. She has graduated from the Nebraska University of Lincoln receiving high honors and majoring in German, But her outstanding gift is a lyrical, bird like voice which is now being trained in St. Louis. Hilda is secretary to the Swiss Consul in that city, is entirely self supporting although she graduated just one year ago at the age of 20. 
Alice is our baby who so far excels beyond all our children at school. She has always been on the honor roll in grammar school as well as at Solden High School in St. Louis. Her report cards always show 4 E's. Her chief interest outside of school is Classical Ballet, and she may choose to make this her life-work. 
In our home, Mr. Neihardt was a most unusually patient, sweet father. With four active children there was ample chance for irritation-but while of fiery temperament he never seemed to be irritated with the little ones. When I was too utterly weary or sick he woudl walk with the babies and he made a sleepy song that never failed to put theyoungster to sleep-it musthave had Magic in it. When older the "kids" were always seen stringing along after him on his walks and rambles, and not onlyhis but the neighbor's as well. He enjoys close contact with the children and animals. Of a chill evening it used to be common to find him seated with the children beside a bonfire- and close at hand the family cow, the riding horse, a goat, the cat and the dog--all seemingly in a state of bliss. At such times very often John has spoken poetry to them. Whene very young, Enid and Sigurd would ask Daddy to please sing poetry, a most descriptive phrase. 
As a son, John was very close to his mother, whom he supported through most of our married life. She always had her own little home next door, both in Nebraska and later in Mo. where she chose to accompany us in order to remain near her son and his family. 
As grandfather, John is as sweet a one as he was a father. His first grandchild "Joan" who is named for him, although scarcely 3 already says: "Come on, Grandan, let's go..." pulling him to go down into woodsy places, where "the world is so full of a number of things, and where one sings to the eveng'tar, seated on the big couch in that most beautiful "font woom"--
So, thanks to him, our lives are full of beauty and richness, and with the advanc cing years he becomes kinder and mellower and altogether greater. 
As for Dr. House, he was a dear and encouraging friend. He believed in John with na almost feminine devotion, at a time when there were few such believers. No history of Neihardt would be complete without mentioning this friendship. 
Hoping I have been able to give youwhat you wanted I reamin yours sin erely
Mona Neihardt. 
