<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
153 Fink Collection 145
Neihardt #610
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.

GALESBURG, ILL.
NOV 10
2 -PM
1939
Mr. and Mrs. Ollie Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.,
Overland,
Missouri
(St. Louis Co.)
146
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
Friday Morning
Dear Enat and Oddie:
<p>I had a real Enat letter for breakfast this morning, and yours, Oddie, is already several days old. Mighty glad for both.</p>
<p>It has taken a little time to bore in here, but I'm almost in there now, and if I were sticking around much longer, it would become a really happy experience. Things have been going very well, and better and better lately. They're discovering the fact that I'm a "human bean" (as Ben would put it), and it is true that young people get way under my skin. So much about to happen to them that they can't suspect - and they so eager about it! I'm all for them. I spiel about three times a day - sometimes four; and there are occasional dinners &amp; luncheons to be eaten, with some sips of</p>
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
147
-2-
<p>4 o'clock tea. I had to talk to Rotary at the Galesburg Club yesterday - a large &amp; unusually mature group of really fine men. I liked them, and I've heard they liked me. I feel pink &amp; didn't want to do the job, but the <underline>feel</underline> of them awakened me.</p>
<p>The other day I had an English class, and my purpose was to induce the young <unclear>hushies</unclear> to realize that poetry is not effeminate. That had been their <unclear>coulention</unclear>, and the Prof. (a fine, sensitive lady) tipped me off &amp; asked me to woek on them with the objection in mind. I thook them in the flank &amp; rear! Began by asking if they had felt so, &amp; got a frank admission. Then I told them I was glad <underline>they felt so</underline>; but, as it turned out, there was something else to say; and by indirection I lead them to a point where they actually admitted that they saw differently.</p>
148
HOTEL CUSTER
GALESBURG, ILL.
UNDER
SCHIMMEL DIRECTION
-3-
<p>It's the honesty and eagerness of such young people that move me. They are actually <underline>frank</underline> when questioned.</p>
<p>I was with the Adelphi fraternity (.journalism, literature) last evening. Among other things I told them that rather funny Indian story about how young High Horse won his girl. They had supposed Indians were always serious and sort of dumb!</p>
<p>My cold is in my chest - not sore, but a breath-taker. The weather is soft &amp; muggy. That's what's the chief trouble.</p>
<p>It gives me real happiness to think of you two really happy together. People claw their way hysterically through a whole life time trying to "get" something, and so</p>
IN OMAHA, NEBRASA
HOTEL BLACKSTONE
IN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA
HOTEL CORNHUSKER
149
-4-
<p>utterly miss being it. It's pitiful &amp; fainly silly. Surely it's living that matters.</p>
<p>But since you have the best thing, Ollie, one of these times you will find the opportunity &amp; the desire to write something good. There's a quality - and a slant - in you letters that should be real assets in creative writing. I <underline>do</underline> believe you can do a very human novel.</p>
<p>If we just had a chunk of money for a good farm ranch combination! By gosh, we'd do some sane living. Who knows? It's an illogical world and doesn't seem to care what happens. Maybe <underline>that</underline> will happen.</p>
Love always
Dad.
<p>See you at Branson</p>