<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 24
(Jan 17 1940)
Albuquerque
Sunday near noon.
Dear Ones:
<p>I've worked well again this morning. Yesterday at 3 P.M. we went to Falkenberg's home, stayed for dinner (buffalo steak!) and had a happy time. I found out, however, that there's no newspaper opportunity here. The salaries are <underline>very</underline> low. Falkenberg managing editor until October, and now city editor, gets only $45 a week! The Journal &amp; Tribune, rival papers separately owned, actually use the same desks &amp; the same plant - to save money! And yet the</p>
25
-2-
<p>owner of the Journal is making an excellent income from the paper. Falkenberg didn't think of the place as being in any way notably cultural in its interests, and they think of Santa Fe as nuttily "arty"in the main.</p>
<p>There is a charm about this country, surely, although it may be higher than necessary, and does seem so. If there were any special financial reason for morning here, we could be happy, no doubt. And, also, vacant land bought now near the rapidly expanding residence section, would make good money automatically,</p>
26
-3-
<p>But what we want is some setup that will give us each a small income to supplement the lecture-recitals. There are so many other places - charming too. At any rate, the solution of our problem is not in coming here.</p>
<p>If we drop down to El Paso, the total added distance will be no more than 400 miles. Altitude there is 3700. It's really warm in winter, being farther south and 1500 feet lower. No doubt summers are hotter, but they are blazing hot here, except in the shade.</p>
27
-4-
<p>Our week is up here on Tuesday. So I think we'll drop south, using afternoons for travel and mornings fo rmy work. It is a bare possibility. El Paso might yield something for us. Population 100000. No harm in trying.</p>
<p>Anyway, we're planning together, feeling around in the fog for a new road, while Jed is moving on. Of course There <underline>is</underline> a road for us, a good road if we hang on, as we will.</p>
<p>I know you are pounding away there at the engagement</p>
28
-5-
<p>business, and theres no lack of appreciation here.</p>
<p>It will be great to hear the new piano played! I'll bet it's a dear! Don't think I was cross in my former letter. It's just the old feeling of the pattern tending to turn into scrambled eggs, or at least to seem so. Your need of a piano isn't questioned. We'll make out.</p>
<p>My bronchial trouble has vanished, but it stayed in a relatively mild form for ten days &amp; cut short the normally small supply of oxygen up here. We both feel well, but we both wonder if we'll not feel much better at 3700 feet.</p>
29
-6-
<p>I found that altitude perfect on Wounded Knee Creek, and at Bison too. I'm afraid the Old Lady's nose would get too dry &amp; crack inside up here.</p>
<p>But O the mountains are lovely - adn the never - forever feeling gets you! Why not the same near El Paso? Mountains there too.</p>
<p>Gaki thinks of the Wubs &amp; feels kind of wild wanting to hug them! I'll write Mrs. Brown all by herself soon.</p>
<p>Sneer! Our Branson home seems to offer more possibilities as a result of being here! It could be made so adequate &amp; beautiful for a few hundred dollars</p>
Love always
Dad Gaki
(over)
30
<p>And, who knows? Maybe we will not <underline>need</underline> supplementary incomes after the Cycle is completed &amp; published as a whole!</p>
<p>A fellow went to a restaurant and said to the waiter: "Bring me a cup of coffee <underline>without cream</underline>".After about a half hour the waiter returned and said: "Mister would you just as soon have your cup of coffee <underline>without milk</underline>? We're all out of cream!"</p>