<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.7.8-9">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper, February 8, 1927</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.7.8-9</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper</title>
                    <date when="1927-02-08">February 8, 1927</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Piper, Mildred</term>
                    <term>Conn, Ulysses Sylvester</term>
                    <term>House, Julius T. (Julius Temple)</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                    <term>Beethoven, Ludwig van 1770-1827</term>
                    <term>Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907.</term>
                    <term>Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849</term>
                    <term>MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Kirkwood (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>St. Louis (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Buffalo (N.Y.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4393739">Kirkwood (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Piper, Mildred</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1927-02-08"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.7.8-9"/>
                <note type="curatorial">8</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>446 Miriam S Kirkwood</addrLine>
                    </address> 
                    <note type="curatorial">Piper Collection</note> 
                    <salute>My Dear girlie:</salute> <dateline>-Feb. 8th 1927</dateline>
                </opener>
                
                <p>Your photo sits on my <unclear/> by my side and Has hardly had time to get warm since the Post man brot it-I look and look and then some more - you surely have not changed except your hair and it is so pretty.- Of course they are satisfied I have known it thru Dr Comm and Dr House- Mona said this morning where we got the photo-"Oh darn it why doesn't some good man grab her"-you must be very busy and I'm glad you are satisfied-It is so sweet of you to want to know about</p> 
                <p>sure she will do something with the violin yet Alice-will to my notions is the finest of them all-she was started to school after they came to Kirkwood-but the little thing got so homesick and she is not in school now-she is not standing still how ever is spelling every thing and writing to, and the questions she asks would keep a wise man buy. So we think she will <unclear/> little by being out this year. - She was five in Aug. When she saw your photo she said I think that is a nice face.-We are hoping she will sing, she is the only one of the children who ever sang around their play. - I expect to go home in a couple weeks. - am going to St. Louis to visit some people I met in Buffalo tomorrow. We go to a reception given for John by the Literary association of Kirkwood tonight will tell you all about it later lovingly alice m. neihardt.</p> 
                <p>am in a big hurry</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.7.8-9"/>
                <note type="curatorial">9</note>
                
                <p>children</p> 
                <p>Course you must know that they are just kids and individualists-no two have the same ambitions tho each in his way excell except in their school grades-<del>they</del> Enid and Sigurd make their grades but not as their daddy did - but out side of that have remarkable ability-Sigurd is doing wonderfully well in music His teacher has a music conservatory in Webster an other Suburb of St Louis and he is very proud of Sigurd the boy practices at least three hours a day He is playing Bethoven, Greeg, Chopan and McDowell-McDowell <del/> and is just part 14 - Enid will be an expert in Stenography. - Her father says she has a wonderful understanding of words and an insight for <del>with</del> the things he shoudl take care of-they are such good friends and she loves her father dearly.-Is a beautiful girl and no matter of fact and just past 15.-</p>
                <p>Hilda, Ten. has her father's mind is a great reader, her repart cards are alway dissected with E's and S's once in a while an M. Her mother started her on the violin but she is happier when she is doing things with her brain-So at present we are not very encouraged about Hilda's music altho I feel</p>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>