<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
52b
January 20, 1941
Sunday
Dearest folKs;
<p>Eny just called and told us of your special delivery letter. What seems to be the trouble - a cold settled in a muscle? I am so sorry and wish there were something that could be done to relieve the pain. I Know you are doing everything tho. This damp weather is so bad for such things. Above all you must taKe care of this condition. I have hesitated to say this but I wonder if you are going to be warm enough at Enids. If the winter is mild as it has been so far it would be alright but if it is severe I Know you would be miserable. Honest to goodness - I'd never buy a house with hot-air heat. There is nothing worse than being cold. You Keep so snug down there. Don't thinK I'm being mean or catty when I make these remarKs. I have no such idea in mind but I just thinK being cold is so much harder on anyone than anything other single thing I can think of.</p>
<p>Today Sig plays over the radio. I'm sorry you won't be here to hear it but there will be other times. We hope it will worK into something profitable in the way of music. I believe it will. This StarK is at least not a showman or a pretender. His credentials  are honest. He has Kept his word in every way and bacKed up his promises with <strike/> the best of evidence. He hasn't said anything he can't prance at least. He says he was brought up with white people and he has marvelous insight into the colored race. He told me, with only birth date to know from, about Joan &amp; Elaine - (a telephone conversation). Joan, he says belongs to the air spirts and needs lots of fresh air. She is a born musician &amp; a mixture of personalities. She needs proper understanding to bring out her best. (Such as Nanny &amp; Gaki give her). elaine is the do'er. She is a water baby &amp; needs to be near water &amp; home lots in her!! She is psychic as he says. Also a sentimental &amp; loving child &amp; very sensitive.</p>
<p>He told me I was a hard-worKer (brag-brag) and whatever I attained I would Keep. Sort of a bumper for Sig &amp; help Keep others balanced. So evidentally I have a definite <strike/> purpose in life. Ha! I had a suspicion. It seems most people do have if they just find their niche to fit into. You both helped me to find mine. No- I found it but you helped me to maKe myself fit into it. I've been gratefl many times over.</p>
<p>So taKe care and Know how much we -think of you.</p>
<p>Gaki, Joan is so worried. She nearly cries everythime we mention Gaki and says hurriedly "Oh lets not talK about it." She came to me this morning after Eny called and said with her serious grey eyes on the verge of tears - "Mama, will Gaki play outdoors with me any more, will he be alright so I won't have to go for walKs alone?" She certainly thinKs Gaki is the top. Elaine takes it more calmly for she doesn't really Know what pain is. She says "Poor Gaki, has a crick in his bacK."</p>
<p>I will close. Do taKe care of yourselves. Know always we love you so.</p>
Max
<p>Joan just camp up &amp; said "I want Gaki's back to get well!"</p>