<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
102a
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland, Mo
Apr. 8, 1941
Dearest Mom &amp; Dad:-
<p>Were very happy to receive your card!</p>
<p>Well, Sunday is Easter isn't it? I hope I can get Hilda &amp; Alice &amp; Sig together out here for "dinner at eight"! I'm going to try hard. Maybe they can get out early Sun. &amp; hunt eggs. Ol &amp; I are a - <unclear/> some. Fritz won't be out Easter as he's coming Fri. <sic>nite</sic> &amp; stay till Sat. noon. He'll thereby miss out on Easter dinner but he says he'd rather be at church! We dont' get it, but ----! We;ll let him hunt eggs Sat. am. if he wants, but otherwise I fear he'll miss out on that fun. I'm going to bake! Ha!</p>
<p>it's surely spring. We're going to have late jonquils, as we planted them in November last fall. However, the jonquils are blooming everywhere up here now in great profusion!</p>
2
<p>We had one jonquil! But we have lots more. Tulips &amp; roses &amp; iris, etc. are coming along very well! Couldn't plow last Sat. as it was too wet. I hope he can this Saturday. We surely do want to get our garden in!</p>
<p>I'm waiting for my grocery order! I'm out of stuff to eat &amp; I'm hungry! So is the "Bunny"! He's kicking me in a robust, but <underline>sweet</underline>, manner! Isn't it a wonderful sensation <sic>tho'</sic>? In fact, we can hardly believe we're actually being blessed that way! Ol is so tickled about its kicking &amp; all, as am I!</p>
<p>We have (Ol has) the rocker painted now &amp; are waiting for time to paint the other two pieces. We hope to have all the things donw when you come up, but perhaps we won't! We have the garden to put in &amp; I haven't the right to paint! Ol says it's bad</p>
3
<p>for me! He's surely a dear? He just looks out for me!</p>
<p>I was so happy. Sig stopped Mon. a.m. to say hello. they (Hil &amp; he) had spent Sun. afternoon practicing so they couldn't get out here. They had wanted to however. Sig is a dear. He wants to drop out again soon. I told him that, whenever he was out this way at about seven or so, to be sure &amp; eat with us. I think he will.</p>
<p>Sue wants Alice to show her how to bring their black horse into &amp; out of her five gaits. I have seen her do three distinct gaits while they were riding her. She never trots. They're worried as to whether they'll get to sell the brown beauty. I think Jack prefers it to the other!</p>
<p>Mrs. H. went to Sears Roebuck yesterday &amp; Mrs. Tacke &amp; I went along for the ride. We had a lovely chat while Mrs. H. did the</p>
4
<p>shopping. It was fun to get out that way. Mrs. H. gave a darling rattle!!</p>
<p>I'm going to see the doc next week, as it's the <sic>fwe</sic> months the 23<underline>rd</underline> &amp; the babe is surely a lively little dear! We're going to get our car because right away.</p>
<p>Irwin called us the other day, He siad he wants to bring us a bunch of <strike>glad</strike> canna again! We're tickled as we're low on canna. Irwin is a peach. anyway.</p>
<p>It's beginning to get charming here now. Grass is gree &amp; leaves &amp; Forsythia are coming out.</p>
<p>Mom, I'm making a nursing rug, with pink, blue &amp; green predominating. I chat a rug would be more useful than a throw. Do you mind?. It's going to be nice. </p>
<p>Ol will write. Said he wanted to last <sic>nite</sic>, but it was so late &amp; he was so tired!</p>
<p>Love to Max &amp; Wubs.</p>
Loads o' love,
always Enid