<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
67 Neihardt Collection 73
October 7, 1939
New Orleans, Saturday A.M.

Dear Ladies (Four of 'Em):
<p>As Sig must have told you, we had nice people, very beautiful campus. We arrived here at 3:30 P.M. yesterday. Rode along the Gulf shore for a couple of hundred miles. The Ocean and the Cumberland Mts are the best things we've seen. Everywhere we've been, the country in general is sordid, even the poverty outside the big towns (which are generally beautiful) is overwhelming. We saw 1/3 of Florida, and it's no better than the rest, except in the richer towns. Waste land swamp, scrub timber, sometimes snatches of good yellow pine forest - and <unclear>shack</unclear></p>
74
<p>shacks, poor whites, poor niggers! Gamesville is a beautiful town. We were told that Florida gets even drearier as you go south, the beautiful parts being merely the resort development on the coast. Fla. is a vast sandbar, without a hill, &amp; covered with swamp &amp; more or less worthless growths of brush &amp; scrub timberx <crossed>with <unclear/></crossed>. It is funny to compare such a land with California!! Fla. has only a sea coast &amp; a warm climate, <underline>nothing</underline> else at all. Sig &amp; I have wondered where people get their food. We've seen almost <underline>no</underline> foodcrop growing anywhere. But the cities buzz &amp; hum with a show of wealth. Of course, farther south in Fla are citrus groves;</p>
75
-2-
<p>but only near the coast. The rest is mostly waste. The mosquitoes are thick in the South. We are told that alligators aboung in all the swampy country. Along the Gulf of Biloxi &amp; Gulfport, Miss., are exquisitely beautiful homes for the rich. Sig &amp; I will sell you our interest in the whole South for 20<centsign/>, and you may have 100 years to pay without interest. Of course, you'd have to pay <underline>a heavy sales tax</underline>. We'd reserve the Cumberlands, the Ocean shore &amp; the lovely live oak trees heavily f4estooned with Spanish moss.</p>
76
<p>Yesterday P.M. we drove around New Orleans - a brawling American city <underline>like any other</underline>, save for the old part, through which  we drove. That is mildly interesting, but nothing to cry out loud about. As a matter of fact, Mona, I'm afraid you'd expect much more than you'd find. I did. We'll drive some more this morning, but I doubt if we'll see much more.</p>
<p>The mockingbirds all over the South are darlings. They sing by day as well as night, and their songs are more detailed &amp; lengthy than in Missourix I wonder why they sing. If I <underline>had</underline> to live in most places down South, I'd learn to weep long and bitterly.</p>
77
-3-
<p>Many of the bigger towns <underline>are</underline> beautiful, because of the foliage and the concentrated wealth. But, dear God! what a poverty sticken land for the most part! And the nice people we meet are <underline>so</underline> smug, so reactionary! We find everywhere, from loafers at filling stations to professors, the <underline>same</underline> opinion on the international situation. They <underline>all want war with</underline> Hitler!! <underline>No</underline> exception in our experience. We say nothing, but draw them out+ A lovely lady (prof's wife) said to me: "Oh I'd hate to see any social change</p>
78
<p>in our country!" Of course, I too mildly deplored that remote possibility!!</p>
<p>We, personally, are not unhappy. That is not the meaning of this letter. But, be sure, when we move, it will not be toward the South. And yet, we've been treated beautifully &amp; have had appreciative audiences.</p>
<p>We'll leave here Sunday P.M. Are having our laundry done up.</p>
<p>Branson country, we agree, is more beautiful by far than anything we've seen in the way of landscape except the Cumberlandsx</p>
(over)
79
Endless love
Jno
Dad
Grandan
Gaki