<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.4.4-8">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper, January 14, 1923</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.4.4-8</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper</title>
                    <date when="1923-01-14">January 14, 1923</date>
                    <extent>5 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Piper, Mildred</term>
                    <term>Bailey</term>
                    <term>Brown</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Lulu</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Neil</term>
                    <term>Neihardt-Ballinger, Grace</term>
                    <term>White</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Hastings (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Omaha (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Minneapolis (Minn.)</term>
                    <term>Grinnell (Iowa)</term>
                    <term>Sioux City (Iowa)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>Omaha World-Herald</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Piper, Mildred</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5069802">Hastings (Neb.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1923-01-14"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>

            <div1 type="envelope">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.4.4-8"/>
                <note type="curatorial">4</note>
                <note type="curatorial">11 Piper Collection</note>
                <note type="curatorial">January 14, 1923</note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    BRANSON JAN 14 13 PM MO. 
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="stamp">
                    U.S <figure/> CENTS 1923
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    #145 Branson Mo. 
                    Miss Mildred Piper
                    809 North Hastings av
                    Hastings
                    Nebr. 
                </ab> 
                
            </div1>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.4.4-8"/>
                <note type="curatorial">5</note>
                
                <opener>

                    <salute>My Dear little Girl;</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>I have been home three days would hve written to you while away if I had just taken your address with me. I surely felt reproached when arriving home I found my lovely kodak diary and those beautiful stockings. Dear girl don't feel hurt that I did not remember you other than in my thots. But its a long laane that has no turn.</p>
                <p>I wonder if you read <del/> any of the acounts of the affair at Omaha the 10th of Dec. if you have. Not would like to send you some of the articles in the "World Herald" and the "News". It was a most wonderful time for me. I wish I had you here so that I could tell it all to you.</p> 
                <p>I did not dream that I was to do the unbeliev-ing until I preached the Library that day. I thot at first that I could not do it But Judge <unclear/> haler, John's friend, assumed me I was the one. The Library was crowded to its limits many old friends were in the crowd and <unclear/> I was dazed, just dazed! but I think I must have "gotten away with the goods" better than I thot or else people were very considerate of my feelings. I stopped with the Baileys and Mr. Bailey said "you made a hit." sounds funny I know, and I could not tell it to any</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.4.4-8"/>
                <note type="curatorial">6</note>
                
                <p>like I can to you. It surely was a lovely affair. then afterward they held an informal reception and I did not know it was a recep-tion until the right day when I read the papers. Had such a lovely visit with the Bailey in their beautiful new home. was with them from Friday evening until Tues. noon. Went from there to Bancroft and stayed with Mrs. Brown until Thurs. morning, when I left for Minneapolis, preached there the same evening Lulu is quite well again. We went a lot, to the art Institute to the auditorium to hear the Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra downtown at least a half doz. times. Had our fortunes told by a clairvoyant, long car rides around the Lakes and watched the sports on the ice, went out to one of Lulu's friends for New Years dinner. Had a dinner party and cake on my birthday. Lulu said to the boys don't you think it would be nice to have some company for Grandma birthday and they said oh yes! but don't let's invite women lets have the boys so three of their chimes were invited and we had a gay time. There we had callers and returned calls. You see we had a very full time. Neil, Lulu's eldest has made and erected a radio and we listened</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.4.4-8"/>
                <note type="curatorial">7</note>
                
                <p>church services, concerts &amp; solos all day christmas and in the evening dance music was broadcasted and on three of the lakes large crowds danced on the ice on skates. It was surely a most wonderful time, but I was glad to come home where everything is same. It would just kill me to have to like such a fast life. I left Minneapolis for Grinnell Iowa the 3rd of Jan, visited there a wreck with my sister and then home bringing my mother with me. I left a snow covered country and came home to summer, last night we had a big thunderstorm, a little cooler today but surely not winter.</p> 
                <p>John left last Thursday <del/> his midwinter lecture trip. <del/> in Omaha today, speaks you about the portrait, It is wonderful! When you are in Omaha please go and see it I know you will think it fine.</p> 
                <p>I went thru Sioux City on my way up to Minneapolis, but could not stop. My time was so limited and mother was waiting for me to get her. I thot of your people and looked around won during if by chance I might meet one of them and know them:</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.4.4-8"/>
                <note type="curatorial">8</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> Girl, your diary bring back so many pleasant times of your visit with us last Summer, I wish it were going to be repeated this summer again. 
                We are expecting Grace sometime ^after the <unclear/> of File. They have sold and are expecting to locate here! Won't that be fine.</p> 
                <p>Mother likes it here and I hope will be satisfied to stay with me.</p> 
                <p>Mrs. Brown is well and so anxious to get away from Bancroft. I do hope she can come down here this spring. Met mrs. <unclear/>. She had fallen on the ice and hurt her self badly, had a supper with her. Mrs. Brown and I took Supper with her. She asked about you. as did Mrs. Bailey and mr. White. I was glad to get out of Bancroft. walked around our places but it did not make me home sick.</p> 
                <p>Dear little girl I thank you so much for your thotfulness to me and come again next summer.</p> 
                <p>My best love to you my dear girl and best wishes for the New Year and all the years.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>from</salute> 
                    <signed>Alice M. Neihardt</signed>
                    <dateline>
                        Branson Mo 
                        Jan. 14 1923.
                    </dateline>
                </closer> 
                
            </div1>

        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>