<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
143 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 1
September, 1940
Dearest Boy
<p>Your good letter today has made me so glad and grateful because of what you say about this Home. I have been so afraid we were going to lose it next year, and I have <underline>no</underline> faith in any decency where Mrs Evans is concerned. I think it is the unthinkable terrible thing, that John Neihardt should have landed in the power of such a creature. How could <underline>any</underline> body in trying to make up a funny story think up anything so funny and sad as that. It is simply preposterous. I do not often mention this to Dady because he does not like it, to say the least; but I believe he thinks about it as much as I do. Now your hopeful letter about the lectures and about yours and Hilda's ability at a pinch to borrow money for the Home makes me feel <underline>so</underline></p>
2
<p><underline>relieved</underline>! You know we can save a lot between now and next Fall, if we are fiven the chance to take in money. I think Daddy will be on teh Post and then we can save all the lecture fees and more too. It costs us so <underline>little</underline> to live. Our Groceries come to $2.50 per week adn our lights and water are $5 per month. We have only the car to worry about which is $20 per month. But we do hate to think of losing it, and I think it very bad business to let it go if we have any lectures at all; for we owe less than 400 on it now, and this car can last us for very many years - in fact always. When you go into the lecture business with Dad and may be the girls, it will be for you to buy the car and manage everybody adn everything! Next time you will drive Dad, not Dad let you drive him!! Some day all this we are now going through will seem but a cog</p>
4
<p>in the great wheel of events._ I think too that if we get along fairly well we will be driving up to see you all again about Xmas. In the mean while Jed is progressing. We are taking it along on this October trip, and I have a strong hunch it will be finished sooner than Daddy thinks. This has always been the time of year when he has written most easily and most steadily, between now and February.</p>
<p>What do you think of the idea of buying a St Louis Home? There are such marvelous buys now, and we look them all over so often! You Know we still <underline>might sell</underline>. A Buyer drops into Branson occassionally! Do you folks really favor the idea or would you <underline>rather not</underline> be there?</p>
<p>i have the queerest feeling every once in a while I feel as though I were not going to be here long!</p>
<p>We are <underline>so</underline> proud of you Sigurd, and so very grateful to all you darlings up there, for being <underline>so fine</underline>!</p>
Devotedly
Mom.
3
Maxie Darlin'
<p>It is really cold here. I cover the geraniums every night to keep them a while longer outdoors before potting them and brining them in for the Winter. I am wondering when it was Summer this year! It was too short. I am sitting by the range keeping warm, and watching some whole wheat bread rise!</p>
<p>Am getting along nicely with my dress and coat. If it is cold I'll not have a chance to wear the latter and I'll wish I had made my Winter coat <unclear>over</unclear> in style. But it'll be O.K. anyway. Will it be time enough if I don't make Joanie's coat till I return from this trip? Please tell me. Are you planning a birthday party? How is your nose?!</p>
Lovingly
Mom.