<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
70 Neihardt Collection 99
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
Oct. 17, 1939.
Dear Mama:
<p>I am most grateful for your letters, and I know that you do realize just how very busy we both have been on this tour. Seems as if it were a continual buzz of circumstances.</p>
<p>We have in all cases been most enthusiastically received. Dad is always very, very splendid in his appearances, to say nothing of that guy that does the "Hot-Jazz" on his programs. Ha!</p>
<p>Sister Madeleva &amp; all are just simply sweet to Dad &amp; me. They loved his Messiah &amp; Lyrics this A.M. Tomorrow Dad gives Poetic Values, in a form especially well sinted to his audience. I shall play to entertain a bit after dinner at the College tonite. At Kalamazoo I'm on the program again!</p>
<italics>Air Conditioned Banquet Facilities</italics>
100
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
<note>little blurb is in Mona's handwriting</note>
<p>*A world. Pianist Friend of Johns from long ago- It has been Sigurds dream to get to him!</p>
-2-
<p>I, at last, know Kreider.* His experiences have been vast of course. He has <underline>nothing</underline> as d composer! He does have a well trained technic, however <underline>not</underline> comparable in many ways to mine. He heard me at my best, admitted that <underline>I</underline> have a <underline>soul</underline> in my playing, takes my technic for granted, &amp; remarked: "<underline>No</underline> criticism whatever!"</p>
<p>It all goes to show that by Gosh I'm going places. Kreider, honestly was noticeably thrilled to hear me do that smooth, colorful, soulful performance on his piano!</p>
<p>You see, I had put several hours of practice into me, &amp; <underline>on</underline> his own Mason-Hamlin, before I let him hear me!</p>
<italics>Air Conditioned Banquet Facilities</italics>
101
250 COMFORTABLE ROOMS - WONDERFUL BEDS - MODERATELY PRICED DINING ROOM and COFFEE SHOP
HOTEL LaSalle
LEONARD MENNUCCI
PRESIDENT AND MANAGER
SOUTH BEND, INDIANA
-3-
<p>Well, you know what this has done for me. A re-assurance that I have the genuine thing. Kreider is an "old-hen" when it comes to criticizing, &amp; his knowledge indeed is <underline>vast</underline>. He did not however, differ with me in a single principle of piano playing. <underline>His technic</underline>,<underline> is</underline> indentically mine in principle, &amp; we agree in every sense. Only criticism was that we <underline>differ</underline> as to our valuation of crescendos. He says <underline>don't</underline> build a cresc. anywhere in that Paradise Foccata. I say "No" to him on that, &amp; he still says he believes in "<underline>fadeout</underline>" at the end of that gorgeous climax in the Foccata. He's "wet" on interpretation, &amp; even Dad says <underline>my</underline> playing is far more poetic &amp; <underline>virile</underline>.</p>
over over over
102
Oct 17, 1939
<p>Please understand tho' that this is one of the greatest, most beneficial times of my training. Kreider <underline>is</underline> a whizz, a regular encyclopedia on the world Musical library of Classics. <underline>From</underline> him I'm <underline>getting, "stealing"</underline> you might say, a tremendous amount of additional knowledge of where to find all kinds of gorgeous 'gems' of piano music I'd never heard of before.</p>
<p><underline>We</underline> go back to Noble's on Fri. A.M., stay in his home with hime some <underline>more</underline> over the week-end.</p>
<p>Must stop for now, with all kinds of love for my Mom.</p>
<underline>Sig.</underline>
<p><underline>P.S.</underline> At Kreider's I'm cooking, Dad is cooking, also Noble is cooking. We have a grand time of it!</p>