<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
375 Fink Collection 99
Neihardt 
4920 S. Blackstone
Chicago

CHICAGO, ILL.
JUN 10
5 PM
1943
STOCK YARDS STA.2

Mrs. O. F. Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St. Louis
100
June 10th
43.

Enid Darling:
<p>You <hi rend="underline">should Know</hi> that my heart is set on being with you at your confinement, surely in a world where so many things are all wrong, we should not change the really good and right things, should we dear? I think this is one good and right thing: that you want me, and I want to be with you. So don't let us question this any more.</p>
<p>Daddy has good glasses, and after having drops put in his eyes twice by two oculists, the result is that he has <hi rend="underline">very</hi> good</p>
101
2
<p>sight for his age, and <hi rend="underline">no</hi> morbid growth of any sort such as cataract, Thank Heaven.</p>
<p>But he <hi rend="underline">must not</hi> use his eyes too much, certainly not 8 hrs per day. So he has quit Esquire, and has gotten a new job with the Iron Fireman Stoker Co. which he likes and which I pray will not require too much eye strain. It is a refined job, and yet quite a hard one, but not as hard on the eyes, and he sits at a fine desk most of the time. He likes the men too and I can only say that. I hope and pray he will stick it out. He gets over $45.00 per week.</p>
102
3
<p>counting some overtime, and works every day but <hi rend="strike_through">Saturday</hi> Sunday.</p>
<p>The same terrible "Amama situation" has developed and I have written Uncle Ottocar to please save the day for all concerned by writing her to come East immediately, or else to go to Hot Springs sooner than July 20th - as I don't went an explosion here now, of the classic Amama type. <hi rend="underline">Too</hi> bad - <hi rend="underline">but time. So please</hi> join me in hoping and praying for the best. As soon as she leaves I will take a temporary job till July 20th - then go to you, afterwards <hi rend="strike_through">returning to</hi>taking the job I <hi rend="underline">really want</hi> with</p>
103
4
<p>the censor department. There is likely to be a vacancy later on - but if not, I'll apply with the Pullman Co., and stick with them. They need people but I cannot take it for a short time and then quit. So I'll wait and see if I get a translator's job first.</p>
<p>For several years than I shall much enjoy holding a job and joining Daddy in earning a nice little old age <unclear>pantene</unclear> of our own!</p>
<p>We'll get a <hi rend="underline">good</hi> price for our Branson Home yet by waiting and then for a farm and you to take care of it in your own little home upon it!</p>
<p>Such a good dream, not?</p>
104
5
<p>Hilda and Albert are truly touchingly sweet. Hilda's eyes are big with tears and the heartache is saddening to see - I try to make them feel lucky because Albert <hi rend="underline">is safe</hi> as yet. But that does not console them <hi rend="underline">much</hi>. I feel <hi rend="underline">if</hi> Albert is not called overseas, they have a very happy life ahead.</p>
<p>Alice remained in Laredo Texas to earn some money before returning. George Leon has sent his Chicago Telephone no. to us for Alice to call him when she gets here. I am looking with great longing for her. She evidently has had a valuable, beautiful experience but not a good</p>
105
6
<p>money-making one.</p>
<p>I am hoping she may work into something very good with Hilda may be. I'm so glad you <hi rend="underline">do</hi> like Hilda's voice; it is truly beautiful.</p>
<p>Have you had very much rain again? Evidently you are not having the cold we have here, since Nei has a tan already. Bless him and his dear, dear parents.</p>
<p>Have you heard about the washing machine yet?</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">So</hi> sorry about Mrs Seymour - but she managed to make connections and travel through to Chicago. Thanks for your desire to entertain her - maybe some other time. By the way,</p>
106
7
<p>Agnes Martinsen, Uncle Rudolph's wife (remember?) is sending you some baby things now and will send you more later on. She is so truly the <hi rend="underline">right, good</hi> sort of a woman - I'm hoping you'll write her your thanks when you receive them, please dear. Her little new grandson is out growing things which are good, and so she asked me if you might like them - Of course I said yes - and she was so truly tickled - She's the same person who sent Sig and You the two big teddy bears you had when little in Bancroft!</p>
<p>Endless love, and please Keep writing to Daddy and</p>
107
<p>me as much as possible.</p>
<p>I believe Agnes said there were little shirts among the baby things, and I told her I Know you could always use more of them.</p>
<p>So much much love from your devoted,</p>
old Mom
Nanny
Mother.