<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
20f
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
January 28, 1943.
Friday
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>We are sitting here in our room taking a bit of a siesta, for it is certainly June in January here in Laredo. Lovely weather - really actually tropical. The sky is an unbelievable Mediterranean blue, such as one sees <hi rend="underline">only</hi> in such countries as this, the sun is <hi rend="underline">hot</hi>, and the birds sing in the heavy-laden orange trees. "<foreign>Fout les joirs ils chantent dance les orangiers</foreign>" a dit Madame Perdu. In the evenings we walk 'neath the brilliantly starry, cloudless sky</p>
(2)
<p>amid the song of evening birds - and with the soothing breeze caressing our hair! How <hi rend="underline">romantical</hi> Oh! but it really <hi rend="underline">is</hi>!</p>
<p>How we are again siesta - ing (Saturday) after having eaten lunch on the veranda (I did a barre thereafter in the sun), sunning ourselves awhile, and talking to our next-door neighbors from Buffalo. Everyone here is telling us the wonders of Mexico - and yet, we must wait awhile yet to go.</p>
<P>I must now explain all to you of our present situation. We are in a queet sort of fix - and are momentarily what one</P>
20g
(3)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>might call stranded. It is through no fault of ours that we cannot go on now to Mexico City, for the three of us girls are free to go, and George has both applied for and received all but <hi rend="underline">one</hi> of his needed papers - his re-entry permit. This paper is, for some stupid reason, being help up in Washington. Not knowing anyone close enough to the core of things there to have this matter hurriedly cleared up, George can do nothing but wait. He has, however, contacted our agent in Chicago and</p>
(4)
<p>has directed her to have Washington called again by telephone to see if matters can be cleared up  thusly. You wee, our Mexico City agent, Senor Valencia could influence officials on the Mexican side, but <hi rend="underline">not</hi> here. Things are stricter now because of the war - and slower.</p>
<p>By all rights, George's and Mme. Perdu's papers <hi rend="underline">should</hi> be here <hi rend="underline">now</hi> but they aren't. Now - as we must make the best of the situation here (<hi rend="underline">Though</hi>, in Mexico City, <hi rend="underline">meanwhile</hi></p>
20h
(5)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>we are being advertised to appear next week at the Polies Bergere <hi rend="underline">and</hi> the El Patio - <hi rend="underline">both top</hi> places there!), our plans are the following: We shall have to take a two-week lay off here, during which time we shall rehearse. Then we shall work in Dallas and San Antonio till the papers are finally settled. M.C.A. will place us in the best spots in Texas while we wait. <hi rend="underline">Then</hi> we go into Mexico. That is a vague description of things as they</p>
(6)
<p>stand now. Also we are wanted for Exposition here, but we'll see what happens all around. It is just one of those things - wanted muchly where we cannot, for the present, go! If you know <hi rend="underline">any</hi> angle we've overlooked - or anyone of influence (Senator, etc.) who could help hurry this up - please <foreign><hi rend="underline">por favor</hi></foreign> tell us! Just when we need the money <hi rend="underline">so</hi>, too. However, it can't be helped, and we shall not be entirely idle - although this is a real vacation for us, besides a lay-off.</p>
20i
(7)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>We will get there eventually - don't worry - but all such matters as this are terribly slow now. Please pray for this to be helped along.</p>
<p>The other day we went to a Mexican singing festival - very informal you see, for it was a group of students from Mexico City who sang for us alone. They could speak almost <hi rend="underline">no</hi> English at all - and were gay and fiery and <hi rend="underline">very very</hi> gallant. We <hi rend="underline">sampled</hi> Tequila and learned words to "<foreign>Alla en el Rancho Granto</foreign>"</p>
(8)
<p>We even had a mock bull fight with el toierro, one of the real bull fighters of old Mexico (a young one)! Also, I tried on a Mexican sombrero <hi rend="underline">and</hi> scrape - and got names and addresses of all in Mexico.</p>
<p>We must now City go apt. hunting. Adios. Buena Tardes!</p>
<p>Alicia
I've been reading "Licha" "Jed" - and the other night read to the others you request. They loved it - and, I could see were really amazed at the otherwise unheard beauty workmanship, and inspiration of <hi rend="underline">all</hi> your work, Daddy!</p>
20j
(9)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>Sunday:
We arose at 10:00 this morning (had quite a late evening of talking last night), dressed, and went out for breakfast. Before we left, however, George came in to say that Senor Valencia had called him long distance from Mexico City last night, and that he had given him a new course to follow in arranging a quicker entry. This we shall try tomorrow so we happily may have another chance for <hi rend="underline">now</hi>. Pray that it has taken place by the time this reaches you, for such would be a God-send. We shall see.</p>
(over)
(10)
<p>Eny, we are using a delicious jelly already. We have lunches on our veranda and have been enjoying graham crackers and delicious plym jelly for several days now! Madame Perdu a dit "<foreign>C'est superbe, excellente!</foreign>" and George showed his approval by action more than words. Really, it is a great treat for us all, and it reminds me always of you and <hi rend="underline">all</hi> your dear family, Eny! It was certainly grand being home with all of you - and in <hi rend="underline">your</hi> lovely home, Eny, and I do want you to know my appreciation for everything. We are a bit undecided at present - but we shall soon be settled again, and I</p>
20k
(11)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>shall be able to do something nice for you.</p>
<p>Mama, the clothes are <hi rend="underline">so</hi> nice. It is certainly a huge help to have everything nice for a change. Are you able to do the costume? Sans moi? It would be a marvelous help. You know what I promised - and it is my sincerest desire and intention to do just that, as soon as we are straightened out. I shall consider it a great privilege <hi rend="underline">at last</hi> to be able to do with my money what I have always <hi rend="underline">wanted</hi> to do with it.</p>
(12)
<p>Have been reading both Collected Poems and "Jed." The latter is so fascinating - so beautiful - so full of a simplicity and wisdom, that I cannot begin to express my feeling for it. Now it means <hi rend="underline">so</hi> much more than when I read it before. "The Valley was beginning to forget The dead June day,
But Southward clearly yet
The Peaks remembered." <hi rend="underline">God</hi>, Daddy - it is so unbelievably, inexpressibly (to me!) beautiful. Then, the unfolding of the tale is so skillfully done - the humor seeming absolutely natural, yet a profoundness reigning</p>
20l
(13)
BENDER HOTEL
LAREDO, TEXAS
<p>over all. And <hi rend="underline">Jed</hi> - what a character to carry as one inspiration. How he believed, always - and how right he was in doing so. Oh! I can only say I am <hi rend="underline">grateful</hi> to be something <hi rend="underline">near</hi> the creator of such beauty. And that is meant as sincerely as if I said "The sun is shining." You shall see.</p>
<p>Yesterday, we three girls were sitting on a bench in a nearby square (plaza) when one of a gang of little bootblacks approached up, asking for a chance to practice his trade upon our sadly soiled</p>
(14)
<p>and dusty walking shoes. Having little change to spare, we discouraged him as best we could (for he knew little [un poquito] anglais!) This availed noddings, however, for a another ambitious youngster soon ventured over to try his hand at luring dos centavos from those <hi rend="underline">rich</hi> Americanos, adn then, close on his heels came the whole hollering, scampering, grinning tribe. A very interesting situation arose thusly, for, before going on, our shoes were as brightly polished as the noonday sun - and we were searching for a bit sadly through our purses</p>
20m
(15)
BENDER HOTEL
LARDEO, TEXAS
<p>for those heretofore carefully conserved nickels and dimes. Good business men, these little Senors! They even enveigled (sp?) another nickel out of me by giving a stormy, gleeful, and never-ending rendition of "<foreign>Alla en el Rancho Grande</foreign>" as special request. Their little Ranho Villa inherited the nickel, however. George and Madame Perdu were waiting for us across the street at the little Mexican Drug Store, <hi rend="underline">Walgreen's</hi>, when they heard the gleeful shots of our captors, and came over just in time to hear the finale of aforementioned song</p>
(16)
<p>A bit of real <hi rend="underline">atmosphere</hi> - and really very amusing! How cute those little Mexicans are! When I think of Nei amongst them - like a white goose among crows! Or night and day! Strange how different are human beings - almost like a different species of animal.</p>
<p>Today George will write out several letters of introduction to people in Chicago who may be of help to Hilda. Tell her I shall send them at once upon receiving some. Both he and Madame Perdu are <hi rend="underline">really pleased</hi> (excitedly so) with Albert's beautiful knife.</p>
<p>All my love to you, dear ones. Don't write anything of importance here. We may not be here - and it would take <hi rend="underline">days</hi> to be forwarded!</p>
<foreign lang="spanish">Hasta manana,</foreign>
Alicia