<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
49
Fink Collection 
91
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
BRANSON SEP 1 1938 M.O. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Fink 
9716 Hawthorne 
Overland, Missouri 

50 
Branson, Mo. 
Thursday A.M. 
Dear Ollie and Enot:
I played along the road and reached home at sundown - with the old light shining inside of me after the darkest and wildest week I can remember. No one san deserve the eager welcome and the happy eyes that were waiting here; but what comes through me has been and will be worthy, I know. I feel cleansed - but at what a cost to you! You will probably forgive me, and I am endlessly grateful for your goodness. After all, it is true that there are generally stars in that pool. 
But, above all, you must remember that if any shadow at all remains, it should fall on me alone. 
Sig has been working a hard on the lecture business, almost pathetically eager to be of real value to me, and he is doing a fine job. If I go on with lectures, he will be a most effective agent, and 

51
-2-
I'm sure that if he^begin work in December for the season of '39-'40 he will drag in more engagements than I'll need or want. He's headlong about it, and clever too. (His boy eyes!) 
Mama is doing a stunning thing of Elaine - her best, it seems to me; and we'll be casting it soon. We'll set it with a clump of roses for back ground where the drain pipe crosses the point of the garden in the driveway. That place is always damp and will produce luxurious bloom. 
We are happy together, and I'll be working soon. 
I think of the priceless thing you two hav eand am profoundly grateful. You are at least as fortunate as I am. Don't let it ever get dark as I did. 
I do love you both - singly and together. 
Dad 
Do you know that look Mama gets? Roses in sunlight! That's the way it is now. 
(over) 

52
I'm eager to hear about the Fort Worth trip, and what happens in the office of Thompson doesn't return. Remember that the gods to love us. 
Mama will write about the zinnias. 