<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
85 Neihardt Collection 96
3532 Halliday (Home)
Sunday, April 6, 1941
Dear Daddy and Mama, and Max,
<p>I was so happy to get your good letters. It must be very lovely for you all to be together there, and under the circumstances it certainly is best.</p>
<p>I'd certainly be thrilled if I could see the face now. It must be glorious - and the fish pond idea sounds swell.</p>
<p>Now I have some good news to tell you. I am going to get to be in an opera - "<unclear>Lortrarata</unclear>" I think! Sylvia and I were so thrilled we didn't know what to do when she told</p>
97
<p>us last Tuesday evening. Rehearsals are Tuesday, Friday, and Sunday - evenings of the two former and afternoon of the latter. We're or rather they are working on "Mignon" now, but we're also starting to learn steps for "Frairata", adn I love them. Do you know the music?</p>
<p>Hil came to my lesson Tuesday and Madame told her I'd done 5 yrs. work in 2 yrs. It truly thrilled me when Hil told me that! We did have a good lesson.</p>
<p>We like living here very much. Our room is <underline>so</underline> pretty all rose where and blue, and it is kept in tip-top shape always. We have our pictures all hung up and they look lovely. Mrs. <unclear>Athoff</unclear> cooks more <unclear>welously</unclear> and is a lovely intelligent person as well. We have nice time talking with her. The other girls here as very nice too.</p>
<p>Mama, I took the stump baby complete with flowers to Madame yesterday, and she really loved it. She and Eileen think it looks like Elaine and like all the rest of the Neihardt children! So it was meant, yes?</p>
96
(4)
<p>I want to tell you about the flowers I got for it. Mrs. <unclear>Athoff</unclear> told us that our next room neighbor makes wood fire flowers as a hobby and for extra moeny, and suggested that a bunch of them would look very lovely in the Baby. She, as well as everyone else, just loved it. I went to see the flowers, and the woman said she could make me a lovely bouquet of tiny pastel flowers and buds set off by stark green leaves. Well, she did, and the rest result was truly adorable. These flwoers can be in the stump until soiled</p>
98
(5)
<p>or until violet time. Madame's birthday was April 3<underline>rd</underline>, Thursday, but she has been having birthday all week. Eight of us grils contributed a dollar toward a chart of the human body and all its muscles back and front, and life size to book which Snippy ordered whole sale for Madame. It hasn't come yet, but we sent her a card telling her something is on its way. As gray as day as Thursday was, Madame was simply beaming anyway.</p>
<p>I'm sure the bust must be absolute per</p>
99
(6)
<p>fection if <underline>you</underline> admit it is good, Mama dear. However, I know you were not satisfied before because you know what is really good, and this one must be that. I'm certainly looking forward to seeing it. That is a grand idea to have it <unclear/> at the same time as the Epic Cycle of Daddy's.</p>
<p>I bet Joan and Elaine are gloriously happy. It is so right for them to be there, espesically during spring and summer. No one should miss gather together such memories of green grass, thunder showers, sun, and flowers as we were privileged to gather. They will undoubtedly profit</p>
100
(7)
<p>greatly by being there in stead of in the city.</p>
<p>I feel very much as you do about our home, Mama. I think it holds memories and a goodness about it which we should keep, as well as its outward beauty.</p>
<p>Maxie, how are you feeling by now? Hope you're all well. We did have a good time together, didn't we? Moreover, I'll never forget your dearness and true sisterly sweetness.</p>
<p>Sig called us last night. Hil's going to practice with him today.</p>
<p>Now we're going out for a walk. It's gorgeous outside.</p>
Loads of Love,
Alice