<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
1
44 Piper Collection 
BRANSON JAN15 3-AM 1929 MO. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 2CENTS2
Miss Mildred Piper
Wayne State Normal 
Wayne
Nebraska 

2
Jan 15-1929
My Dear girl-
Just see how time flies-the calendar say the Middle of Jan, soon it will be time for you to pack your little car and start for the Ozarks - I won't begin to look up the street for you yet a bit but before I have time to turn a round I will be getting ready for you - Dear girl it is so kind of you to want me to come to you, and dear if I were not so rheumatic and it were summer time I surely would be there-just to see you if for nothing Else, But isn't it just won-derful how things do develop-who would have thot when John was ringing the bell there-that not so many years would elaps before a lovely building on those grounds would be dedicated to him - oh Miss Piper it thrills me thru and thru, so many lovely things have come to me and they, 

3
<unclear/> the hardships, stand out - Indeed every thing is a haze but the good friends, and John, I'm so glad I have been priv-ileged to live and see all these things and I'm so grateful, -Just so busy being grateful that no place is there for self pity for being down here alone, - I am happy in my little home too, and the children are all so lovely too me - a better son never lived and his wife is a close second-Lulu and Grace are so thotful and good and I never worry anymore how my <unclear/> bill and the groceries will be paid for In fact I am here with out a care that money can relieve, - not a lot of money but plenty-my wants have always been loudest as you know.-
Thank you so much for the in-vitation-but I am best at home your mercury acts up so - or rather it acts down so we have had no zero weather yet-but I'm think a cold spell in sneaking in upon us from outside - Nebraska for instance - dear I always love you the same. - form your friend 
Alice Neihardt 
P.S. I am still making rugs same your undies and stockings