<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
183 Fink Collection 36
John G. Neihardt
BRANSON, MISSOURI
BRANSON 
MAY 2
3 -PM
1940
M.O.
Mrs. O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave.
Overland,
Mo.
St Louis
County.
37
Thursday 
Afternoon
May 2nd
Dearest Enid and Ollie:
<p>The pictures of you are swell and mean a lot to me - you are looking so well and Alice has reached the blooming out stage, hasn't she? She looks so well! You will be enjoying the peace and quiet you have a right to now, and I surely do appreciate the</p>
38
<p>big lift you have given us by Keeping Alice so long.--</p>
<p>I trust you can find time to help Hilda with her painting Enid dear - you are more experienced in such things and have the time as well as the patience it takes.</p>
<p>Did Daddy say any thing about moving up there? Please tell me.</p>
39
<p>I am so anxious for us to do so. This is Death unless you have a big money income - as it is we cannot do the things that would reconcile me to being away from all of you - namely telephoning when I'm worried or driving up once in a while - and Life is too short to spend it away from those we so dearly love.</p>
40
<p>ollie what would an Ad in the Post Dispatch cost liek this : Modern 8 room Home with beautiful grounds at Branson Mo (for Sale) and <underline>your</underline> name to inquire form. I think it would be a sensible thing to do. Please advise me.--</p>
<p>Mrs Lund spent 2 nights with me I like her <underline>very</underline> much.</p>
<p>Judge <unclear>Vinsonhaler</unclear> dropped in for a wee visit and our Wubs acted like ladies - He was quite struck with them!</p>
41
<p>Enid please tell me what you have actually done for Alice in the way of sewing. If you have not yet done any, please let me have whatever patterns or materials you may have intended to use, will you? I want to sew for her, and don't Know where to start.</p>
<p>Our place is prettier than ever adn all of the flower seeds are now planted - but it has been very cold</p>
42
<p>lately and <underline>so windy</underline>. Iris is blooming, and all the trees are leafing even the Walnuts and Mulberries. There are loads of cherries - green ones of course. The Spirea is blooming and the Wisteria starting. --</p>
<p>Our babies are no dear and we have a wonderful quiet time together. - Loads of love and end</p>
43
<p>less appreciation of the two of you from your own old</p>
Mom - Mother