<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
64
[November 6, 1938]
Sunday a. m. 
Dearest Young Ladies:
Congratulations to Mlle. Chancellors! That was a bully letter. Hiddy, and deserves a better one, in return than this will be One of These times, Alice, you will write me again, but don't feel obliged; I know how you use your time, and if you don't write, I can imagine a letter. 
We like to think of you together there. I'm sure it's happy arrangement. 
We expect to see you around Thanksgiving. Mama had a chance to go up with Jaeneckes, but decided to wait. I wanted her to go. She gets very lonesome for you girls. 
Wasn't that a lovely rain? Grass is coming back here, and the air has an April smell. 
I've been working on a couple of ivory rings - one a 

63
34
Petri Collection 
Neihardt Branson, Mo. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> WASHINGTON 3CENTS3
BRANSON NOV 5 3-PM 1938 M.O. 
Miss Hilda Neihardt 
c/o Consulate of Switzerland, 
Ambassador Bldg., 
St. Louis, MO. 

2-
65
setting for Mama's beautiful ^card cameo x 
It's a distinguished thing. Another is set with jade - for old lady Max. I set Mama's shell cameo in iron wood - and it's beautiful as a pin. High polish, as I used the end of the grain for surface. O gosh! was it a job to dig out the ^deep bowl - like frame! I've a notion to make a one - piece iron-wood ring, marquise top set with lapis laguli. Beautiful blue on black! Ivory makes a fine effect with colored stones - and the rings are strong, though thin enough to be comfortable. I may insert thin silver or gold bands for <del/> added strength. Was getting on fine with Jed until I hit one of those inevitable snags several days ago. As always, there's nothing to do but wait for a change of consciousness, or whatever it is. Anyway, the whole <unclear/> setup has to rearrange itself somehow. No use trying force. 
We're all happy together here. I doubt if many families run so smoothly. Never any invitation, altho JOan and 'Laine are awful bad guls! Joan is learning to read some words & spell them x. Grandan is her professor. 
Endless love, 
Dad, at least, Herzbrun in Hollywood is submitting "Three Friends"! 