<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
45 Thompson Collection 71
May 18th 43.
Alice, ma cherie:
<p>Ta lettre, francaise est vraiment charmante - et je te remercies bien l'avoir voulie melecrire.- Il y a, a peu pres de 35 annees depuis que jetais a Paris, France; et depuis 1907 jusqua ce jour-ci, je n'ais pas parle le Francais. Ainsi tu me comprends quard je te dis que en ai trop aublie. Je sais pourtant que je ni'en rappellerais, si jauais l'occasion de te parler; mais pour le momentil m'ais tres difficile de penser en mulle autre langue que l'Auglais! En lisant ta lettre joy drouve quel ques faulas - et je suis certain que tu en tranveras beaucoup dans les miennes.</p>
<p>Corrertions!!
Ne dis pas "Ca serais" (it would be) mais:
"<hi rend="underline">Il serait</hi>."
Ne dis pas "<hi rend="underline">Partire au</hi>" theatre, mais:
"<hi rend="underline">Partir pour</hi>" le theatre.
"<hi rend="underline">Ce</hi> n'est pas tard" "<hi rend="underline">Il</hi> n'est pas tard"
     wrong                            right
"Je <hi rend="underline">l'ai ecrite</hi>" = Je <hi rend="underline">lui</hi> ai...<hi rend="underline">e'crit</hi>.
     wrong                  right
</p>
72
<p>"faire autre-choses", not faire <hi rend="underline">des</hi> autres choses. "Je <hi rend="underline">n'en</hi> suis passur," not "je <hi rend="underline">ne</hi> suis pas sur conibeu de temps not resterous..."</p>
<p>Le "Samedi dermer, hous avous <hi rend="underline">comimence danser</hi> au Folies Bergeres"....not: "Nous avous commence a danser le Samedidermer...."</p>
<p>"<hi rend="underline">N'en parlez-pas</hi>, s'il vous plait is better than: "ne parlez-pas <hi rend="underline">de ca</hi>...."</p>
<p>...."Parcequ'il fant que <hi rend="underline">nous ne nous concluons avant 2 heure</hi>s du matiu" is better than ".pas plus de boubeur que...) "C'est <hi rend="underline">une</hi> tres <hi rend="underline">bellelangue</hi>" is better than "<hi rend="underline">un</hi> tres jolie langue"</p>
<p>Jaurais bien reoulu le voir' is better than:" Jaurais" bien aime' a le voir"</p>
<p>"<hi rend="underline">Avnt de quiter ce pays</hi>" is better than "Avant de partirout de cette campagne"</p>
<p>"Je voudrais bien l'apprendre" is better than: "Je veux l'apprendre bien" So Darling I can still correct <hi rend="underline">you</hi> but cannot with any case write to you in</p>
73
<p>French. I'll try again maybe, but for the present I do want to give you the news you so wish for.</p>
<p>Daddy has a very good editorial position with Esquire, paying him $50.00 per week now, but promissing to pay $75 soon - He is getting along very well physically and otherwise. I am so glad to be able to stay at home with Amama who <hi rend="underline">truly needs</hi> me - but she is such a good sport - I'd not want her to think that I felt that way about it. She is going to have her eyes examined very soon, as she does not see well anymore in St Louis told her he dared not give her glasses she needed to go to a specialist.</p>
<p>She is planning to remain with us till I go to Enid's to be with her for the advent of her new baby, about the middle of July. Then she wants to go to Hot Springs for a sure, and remain there till I am ready to return to Daddy here when she too will return here, meeting with me in St. Louis on her way back. We heard from Mrs Cantwell that some M.D. wanted to buy our Home, but Daddy wrote her about the deal, and since then we have heard no more, so we are left in the dark. <hi rend="underline">If</hi> we sell our Branson Home, we will buy a place near Chicago</p>
74
<p>so that we can all go to it weekends at least - Maybe a Michigan farm with plenty of good apples, and a house big enough to hold our library and our memories - and all you dear childreens' <unclear/> etc. We are hoping that Albert will be moved to Chicago too - it <hi rend="underline">is</hi> possible - so pray for it to come true! Hilda is <hi rend="underline">all</hi> in her <hi rend="underline">Music</hi> - She must be improving very greatly and her teacher is doing so much for her - giving her 6 lessons for the price of one a week!! She is singing "The Wren" now.... Remember Gallicurci?? Sigurd is getting a raise in salary after having possed the necessary exams for promotion. So they are happy, and sort of hoping Sig will <hi rend="underline">not</hi> be sent to Brazil. Joan writes most remarkable letters! I write her back as though  she were big! -</p>
<p>We are right across the street from Seymours. And Hilda is staying with them as before - but she comes over quite often.-</p>
<p>I am so sorry about Doris' knee - Mr Assman the medium say you and <hi rend="underline">George</hi> doing stunts alone together! Did Max like your dancing, and enjoy the Program? You did not mention that he did, so I <sic>conidered</sic>! He musta have wonderful to you; I <hi rend="underline">am so</hi> glad!</p>
Love to you, my dear, dear birdie, always your
Devoted Mama.