<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
82
Fink Collection pm December 9 (?) 1958
99
9? 
BRANSON DEC 1938 M. O. 
UNITEDSTATESPOSTAGE <FIGURE/> 3CENTS3 
Mrs. O. F. Fink
9716 Hawthorne
Overland, 
Missouri 

83
Here, Today, 1938.
Dear Enot and Ollie:
I'm glad the ring pleases you. I didn't get it done very fast. When I asked for your ring size, Enot, it was all finished except for slightly enlarging the finger hale to the proper size. I was more than a week getting over that bronchial spell, and making the ring was good for me. I didn't do the filigree in the gem cup because the cup would have been too large if I had, and I liked <del/> the severe sufficiently with that particular gem. When I set a smaller stone for you, I'll do the fancy stuff. I'm dreaming out a inlays on the ivory shanks. Some fun! But I did like. The amethyst ring. It gave me a kick. No easy job getting that close fit around the gem. And I was glad the thing could be made no clumsier than a gold mounting. Remember that the ivory is from Martin Johnson's last elephant. 
I've been working over a very old Persian knife for Mrs. Decker, wife of the President of K. C. University Golly! What a job! But it is really beautiful and it makes me happy to look at it. The Persian 

84
scamped his concealed work - Thought God wasn't looking, probably! And I had to do every bit of the work over and add new brass, ivory, iron wood and a gem! Gosh, it's lovely! 
I'm getting on finely with Jed again! So many difficult problems in strategy - as well as tactics. The background all has to be built as by conversational accident between three speakers of widely differing characters - to the end that one, who is finest in fibre, may break loose later in the night with the story of the crossing of the desert. The <del/> whole reason for The "Song" is in that recital. It's <del/> a sort of glorified character sketch with a steadily increasing high overtone of meaning concerned with what I have come to call "the otherness of things". Read that sentence again. The <del/> final portion, as I often half hear and half see it setting here, seems to have a wild, terrific sort of beauty in it. That's when Evans becomes illuminated, partly through liquor, which has sent the others to sleep. The dog has the last 'word'- Evans' dog! 
I need to make things iwth my hands while doing a job of this kind - especially when I get stalled. Success with the hands 

85
-3-
releases the other somehow. I'll do some exquisite things yet as a result of this need to make with the hands when the other making lags. <del/> And I do love to make beautiful things and give them away. 
Everything fine here, as usual - just a smooth, steady stream of days, and never any frictions between us. Remarkable, when you come to think of it; for we have two babies and three generations in the house. There could well be some friction. 
I'm interested - that clock you mention. 
Hail Hitler! Sick 'em, Mussolini! Hurrah for Chamberlain and perpetual peace! Now! 
With love always to both Dad - 