<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.2.43-48">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Mona Martinsen Neihardt, November
                    21, 1921</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.2.43-48</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Mona Martinsen Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1921-11-21">November 21, 1921</date>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>6 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Sterling, George, 1869-1926</term>
                    <term>Ellwood, Charles A. (Charles Abram), 1873-1946</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler </term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Howard</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Portland (Or.)</term>
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Berkeley (Calif.)</term>
                    <term>Eureka Springs (Ark.)</term>
                    <term>Lake Taneycomo (Mo.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</persName>
                    <placeName>Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1921-11-21"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">43</note>
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Monday, Nov 21,'21
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Ones:-</salute>
                    
                </opener>
                
                <p>Well, the time is passing, thank goodness, and soon I will be on my way again as I surely long to be. I will leave here thanks going evening I reach wall a wall a Sunday evening, laying over in Portland all day Saturday the distance is tremendous; all distances are out here.</p> 
                <p>Have been having what is known as a very good time; cut my idea of a good time is</p> 
                
                <note type="authorial">-2-</note>
                
                <p>being at home, slowly. forging ahead, and with all of you very close. No, no! No
                    city for me! No "civilized life" for me! The single, sweet, unhurried, honest
                    things are all that matter. Branson is the place to live. It would make <del/>
                    me heart sick to think of moving you all out here. I don't want you here. I
                    don't want you here, &amp; I don't want to be here, in spite of many attractive features Don't think I am homesickness I am not, tho' I long to be at home. I spent Sunday P.m with Howards in Berkeley (across the Bay).</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">44</note>
                <note type="authorial">-3-</note>
                
                <p>I'll spend Thanksgiving Day over There. We'll have a picnic on the grass! Then
                    I'll leave at 10:10 P.m., for Portland. Am going by rail, tho' it costs more the
                    ship would <unclear/> me out &amp; the foggy weather is dangerous. I don't like the sea, except as an alien spectacle. I'm prairie-bred, certainly.</p> 
                <p>The other might Sterling took me to a party, given in a <del/> <unclear/> studies
                    in honor of him. I'm glad I went. It was a scream. All clever people, of course,
                    &amp; some bully man. The women made me sick. It was a World Babylonian affair,
                    sure enough. There was claret punch &amp; some got properly scourged. I enjoyed it
                    tremendously. We stayed till 3 a.m &amp; then went on to you Sabern's studio until 4 a.m. You sobern</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">45</note>
                <note type="authorial">-7-</note>
                
                <p>I was afraid he'd find it in me-really afraid. But he found not a trace of it my
                only weaknesses are in the nose &amp; in the appendix. Some puss in the region of
                the nose &amp; a very little in the appendix. He wanted to treat me for nothing, but I can't stay long enough. He claims to have proven that genius is caused by a localization of congenital syphilis in the <del/> brain Poets, he says, have</p> 
                
                <note type="authorial">-8-</note>
                
                <p>a localization of congenital syphilis in the region just back of the forehead on
                    top. He told this to the doctors present before he tested me for it, &amp; he
                    found a strong trace there. He turned to me &amp; said "I can remove that in two weeks, but you'd better <unclear/> it. I wouldn't take a million dollars for mine, tho it is bad for my nerves." Now all this sounds like backburner. But let me tell you, it is astonishing</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">46</note>
                <note type="authorial">-9-</note>
                
                <p>how unnerving he was to on the cases I saw. he would test an unknown patient by a
                    drop of blood only. Then he'd call the patient in &amp;, in most cases, even a
                    layman could see. I'll tell you when I come home. One of Abram's disciples is at
                    Eureka Springs. You must go there, Mama, &amp; <unclear/> of your rheumatism:
                    It's caused by focal infection-<unclear/> somewhere, probably in your <unclear/>
                    &amp; your appendix. Abram will write a letter to the war in Eureka Springs for
                    me, &amp; <unclear/> it won't cost much. My bowel trouble is from my appendix. When we was examining my blood, he said "How long ago did you have that trouble with your appendix." I said that in 1896 I had</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">47</note>
                <note type="authorial">-10-</note>
                
                <p>walked six blocks doubled up with a <unclear/> in my side. He said, "of course",
                    &amp; beamed like a kid. He's a simple soul, &amp; is certainly a genius He is not a father I saw too much to behave he is. I am receiving no mail these days. Of any returns to Branson do not be alarmed, as I ordered it so at Palo Alto after nov 21, today. I was uncertain of my movements.</p> 
                
                <note type="authorial">-11-</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> <unclear/> have been after me, but I'm not going down there. I don't want to go. Kiss my precious wubs all around. How I love them all and then are kisses for all of you, of you cook-and so much <unclear/>.</p> 
                <p>This trip, in a way, was a mistake; or, at least, it has seemed so. But then, one
                never <unclear/>. I'll be home just as soon as I can get there, you bet! I want to
                get to work, &amp; I want to get plain good meals, &amp; I want to</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.2.43-48"/>
                <note type="curatorial">48</note>
                
                <p>our Jersey cow!</p> 
                
                <note type="authorial">-12-</note> 
                
                <p>see the fog come up off Taney como; and I want <unclear/> to jump all over we,
                    and I want to be kissed roughly by Mrs. Bessie. I like her <unclear/> better
                    than my lady I've seen on the Coast so far. She's prettier &amp; has better <unclear/> too.</p> 
                <p>I'm sending only two prints. Divide them. hadn't very good lunch. So many were
                    damned ugly, &amp; I couldn't find a single cherry blossom picture. I may try again before I leave here.</p> 
                <p>am hanging on to my money desperately. but a certian small size happens just the
                    same Howard is paying for my room &amp; board here. I signed the meal checks, &amp; they are turned in</p>
                <p>so much love to all of you. Be happy there. It's a good place to be. O we are fortunate!</p> 
                <closer><signed>Jno</signed></closer> 
            </div1>
                
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>