<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
45a
May 10, 1940 - 8:30 
5611 Enright Ave.
St. Louis, Mo.
<p>I'll send the <unclear/> you asked for. I'd still love the Spring coat you spoke of making.</p>
Dear Mama,
<p>I'm so very happy to knwo that you like your sweater so well. It was really supposed to be for Mother's Day, but I am not at all sorry that you have already seen it. I meant to write you before you received it, but you know what I meant to say anyway, don't you? I know no one has ever had a more wonderful mother, and that I can never be too grateful to you and to Daddy for all you are doing and have done for me. making a sweater is certainly a very, very small "manifestation" of my love and gratitude. I thought making something would be in my case, a much better idea than simply buying something with Daddy's moeny. I got a lot of pleasure out of knitting it for you, too. By the way, does it fit? Do you think it is too long? I made it especially long so that you would not think it too short. Besides, long swea</p>
(2)
<p>ters are definitely in sytle - do you like the color? I as well as everyone else, think that it will look very lovely on you, with your hair, etc. If you wear it with either a navy or a gray skirt it will be very lovely. It is undoubtedly too warm now for you to wear it very often, except when you ride, etc. without any other coat, but you can wear it next fall.</p>
<p>I bet the place is gloriously beautiful now. The snow balls must be a sight to behold! The leaves are quite heavy here too, but not completely blossomed out yet on some trees.</p>
<p>I think you should ride Diamond. Of course you can! Just be watchful as you ride him if he is feeling rather well, and be careful to hold the reins tightly when you get on him, so he won't start off before you get aboard. I do hope he is still there when I come home in August. He must be a very happy horse with all the lovely green grass and the 3 pails of water you</p>
45b
(3)
<p>give him at a time. It's more that the Wubs like Diamond. I shall be thrilled if you wear my sweater with Hil's pants when you go riding!</p>
<p>I saw a marvelous picture Wednesday evening. Sophie and I went together to the S'recno Art Theatre to see it. "The Ballerina" is the title. It is a Grench Picture, starring Mia Slavenska of the Ballet Russe and the Premiere Danseuse of the Paris Opera. The story was truly a very beautiful one and extremely inspiring. Sophie and I both felt like taking class after we'd seen it! I'll tell you the story sometime.</p>
<p>We start our rehearsals for recital on Sunday at 2:00. I'll tell you what we're going to do when I find out definitely. I think we're going to do "<sic>Pupenfee</sic>," Carmen, a big classical ballet, a Spanigh pantomime, and other numbers which I've heard nothing about. It should be marvelous experience and very thrilling besides!</p>
(4)
<p>What does Daddy think about affairs in Europe? Everyone seems very upset abou tit all. If American can only mind her own business and stay out of it!</p>
<p>I have a pretty had cold but I'm feeling much better today, although still quite woozy.</p>
<p>Max is coming for dinner tonight.</p>
<p>Our lesson is at 1:30 today instead of 3:00. Since Ruth Sexton, Virginia Hasagen, Virginia Lane, Lucille Cartier, Eileen O'brien adn Doris Padgett got in the Muny Opera, our class has greatly diminished in size our morning classes are composed of only 4 or 5 and evening classes of about 10! It is truly marvelous for <unclear>us</unclear> who take. Yesterday we had a marvelous lesson on fundamentals.</p>
<p>Give my love to everyone there - to Daddy, Sig, Max, Joan, and Elaine,</p>
and to you, dearest
Mama,
Alice
45c
Alice Neihardt
5611 Enright Ave.
St. Louis, MO.
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 1
MAY 11
7 -PM
1940 
BUY U.S. SAVINGS 
BONDS
ASK YOUR POSTMASTER
UNITED
STATES
POSTAGE
THOMAS 
JEFFERSON
1801-1809
3 CENTS 3
Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Mo.



