<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.6.1-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper, January, 1925</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.6.1-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt to Mildred Piper</title>
                    <date when="1925-01">January, 1925</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                    <term>Piper, Mildred</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Fish</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Hastings (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Buffalo (N.Y.)</term>
                    <term>Los Angeles (Calif.)</term>
                    <term>Omaha (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Grinnell (Iowa)</term>
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Ozark Mountains (Ark.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4378219">Branson (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Piper, Mildred</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5069802">Hastings (Neb.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1925-01"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>

            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.1-4"/>
                <note type="curatorial">1</note>
                <note type="curatorial">
                    Piper Collection
                    Jan. [1925?]
                </note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        <unclear/> Feb 1? 1928
                        Branson Mo.
                        January? 1925
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>My own dear Miss Piper;</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>I know the evidences are against me. But if you have the patience to follow me around. Date
                beginning of August or even six weeks earlier, I am sure you will believe me when I say I love you
                just the same as I always have. Early in June I turned my house all around, or rather the inside, to
                make convenience and comfort for Mona's Brot. His wife from Los Angeles, the brother a writer of
                short stories, their stay lengthened into five weeks, and at the end of that time I <unclear/> up
                and got ready for a music teacher from</p>
                
                <p>child, she hired a girl to take care of her when she is there giving my sister in law a chance to
                get out. The girl is in the High School, is home early every afternoon and Sat. and Sunday. So I
                came home to try to get well, I have been so poorly all the time but it seemed to be needed so much
                that I just kept up somehow. I've been home two weeks and the dear little basket with its pot of
                bulbs is decorating my window and is growing beautifully. And that is not all your</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.1-4"/>
                <note type="curatorial">2</note>
                
                <p>Omaha who was to spend her two weeks vacation with me but for the purpose of giving Sigurd extra
                work in music and I cooked and washed for her, albeir I loved her and was glad to do it, but I was
                busy all the time, you know my garden and yard always claim a great deal of time -- well we are now
                up tp the last of July and I was trying so hard to get well enough to go to Wayne for the unveiling
                of the monument to John, I went, you no doubt heard an account of it in the papers and I want you to
                know that I thought of you and just helf expected you there that 19th day of August last. I had
                hoped to have some time to visit in Wayne some of the old friends and in just a few days I was
                summoned to Grinell Iowa to my mother who was very sick at the time and stayed with her a month and
                at the end of that time she had gained sufficiently to be taken to Lincoln and I was with her a weel
                there when I returned to Branson. Was home just a month where I recieved a telegram to go again to
                Lincoln and I stayed 14 weeks. In the mean time mother regained her strength again, but she is
                nearly blind and her mind in like a little</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.1-4"/>
                <note type="curatorial">3</note>
                
                <p>my house was so damp and cold having had no fires all winter and it is only now that the place is
                warm and livable. Received a letter from my br. today saying mother is failing again but I won't try
                to go back even tho she passes on. My dear I wonder just where I can begin to tell you all the
                things I think you might like to know. First I wish you could see how near a young lady Enid is, she
                is taller than I. Which I know is not saying much. Sigurd just a little shorter, they are going to
                the School of the Ozarks a sort of an academics and are doing very well. They are making good
                grades, Enid is doing good normal work in music, but Sigurd we think will do something woth while in
                music, It is really quite wonderful how he has taken to it. Hilda is a wonder in her school work.
                She is not in school, John teaches her arithmetic and Grammar. Mona, History and Geography, Hilda
                has never been very strong, our school is poor and they thot it much better tha tthey teach her at
                home and give her more. Alice is four years old and she is in a class by her self. She is surely the
                dearest and</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.1-4"/>
                <note type="curatorial">4</note>
                
                <p>Best of all the children, They are planning to leave the Ozarks in a year or two and maybe even
                sooner. Mona is well, much stronger than she has ever been, and John is doing the same as you have
                always known him. You probably hear of him now and then. They all send love and best wishes to you,
                I had a letter from Miss Fish and she no doubt is very bust with her three babies it does not seem
                possible, remem-ber me to your family and dear girl write me soon and tell me a lot about yourself I
                no doubt interested in you just as I always have love to you my dear girl - Alice M. Neihardt</p>
                
                <note type="authorial">2</note>
                
                <p>Photo sister on the mantel looking down at me right now, and I should feel lost if it were
                removed, many thanks dear girl for your kindly remember that have found me every year for so many
                years.</p>
                <p>We are just getting over one of this most terrible storms, the likes of which the oldest Hill Billy
                has noth-ing which to compare the snow was 10 inches on the level and drifts three ft or more, and
                that is saying nothing of the snow that fell for a day and night and melted before it could make the
                ground white</p>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>