<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
28 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 39
1940
[October 2, 1940]
Wednesday
Dearest Children <underline>all</underline>!
<p>Today on our Joanie's 5th birthday, (God bless adn Keep her) we had such good things happen! It was or is a beautiful day, and Nannie began it by doing our last washing till we return from our trip; next she baked 4 beautiful loaves of whole wheat bread to take along - as we are going to live on this trip just as though we were at home - which means that our living expenses will be <underline>in</underline>side of 50 cents per day for the two of us! We are taking our little oilstove, Enid, along, and also our Kitchen utensils even dishpans <strike>so</strike>, and our provisions - so that there will never be any extra expenses. Besides I can really Keep house decently anywhere. All these things go in the trunk part of our dear Hudson. Then we'll have the backseat-part for our baggage and clothes.</p>
<p>We found the contracts Maxie</p>
40
<p>in that reddish case as you said, and we marvelled once again at yours and Sigurds neatness and exactness about <underline>every phase</underline> of the lecture business!</p>
<p>then this wonderful day brought us packages from our Hilda, for which <underlin>so many</underlin>, many thanks, dearest girlie! the hat trimm is absolutely perfect - adn the earring tops are swell, and will be returned to you after our trip.</p>
<p>Then came that good letter from you Maxie, and you Alice, both of which make us so happy and grateful! Alice, Daddy and I <underline>do not</underline>  think of you as a burder; <underline>no</underline> indeed! You are such a privilege to do for - and besides you are the <underline>last</underline> one but not the least of our dear, dear worthwhile children. I have always felt we owed something more than food and clothing to our Wubs - and the worst thing that could</p>
41
<p>have happened to us, is not to be able to help each one of you children to make life worth living; The <sic>worthwhilness</sic> is not to be found in material existence alone.</p>
<p>I am taking the housecoat you girlies gave me, and the warmer rose robe Ollie and Enid sent me last Xmas. I have my new self made coat and hat, and my two velvet dresses, one long for formal wear and the other short. The rose dress for informal wear, adn the dark blue suit with the pink satin blouse you gave me Hilda. Daddy bought me nice shoes and hose and gloves - so I feel most ritzy! I'll wear the Topaz set for evening and the white ivory pin for day wear! I feel <underline>so</underline> thrilled and Daddy approves of all my things since they all <underline>fit snug</underline>ly! So three cheers for our grand trip together!</p>
<p>Daddy fixed the lock in our Kitchen door, and Mrs Cantwell is going to have the Key, and</p>
42
<p>look after things here for me, and also use the washer while I'm gone, and mother my plants, and out Kitty too. She is so good and dear! By the way she wants her sister to buy this place or letter her brother in law - and I'm hoping this will work out, <underline>It should</underline>.</p>
<p>We stacked all our Kitchen wood up high in the workshop, and it looks so neat! I have canned 82 quarts in all - and our cellar looks really nice with all those pretty jars, and some green pears laid out on papers neatly on the cement floor.</p>
<p>Daddy is now talking with the coal-amn. We have two new tons of coal, and there is at least one ton left from last Winter</p>
43
<p>I'm hoping Jed will be finished before we need any more - and that we will then be seeing you up there!! Now comes the best news!</p>
<p>Hilda, our Radio is working swell, and we heard Richard <sic>Crookes</sic> on the Firestone hour Monday evening!</p>
<p>it is so wonderful to hear <underline>real</underline> Music again! So many thanks Hilda dearest once more! the German Broadcasts have been discontinued so <underline>that</underline> ends <underline>that</underline> - I suppose they realized it was useless to try and make the U.S. see their side. So we are actually at War once again with Germany! I am deeply sad over this situation but since it is that way I am all for the U.S.A.</p>
44
<p>and try hard not to talk about the War at all. I can truly feel happy that Wallace is running for Vice President for form his book, he Knows what is what. So here's hoping and praying that our men are <underline>not</underline> going abroad.</p>
<p>Dearest Children, this letter is not important but it tells things you may want to hear, and they are not worth writing twice, so please share them between the two houses.</p>
<p>No Enid, I do not have the baby bed; the one Daddy made was lost in the wreck that time, and it's substitute was not much good. I believe Ollie can duplicate the one Daddy made and you can make the mattress with my help sometime maybe?---</p>
<p>Alice I am taking your beautiful sweater to wear with my dark blue suit!</p>
Loads of love to the eight of you, from your devoted
Mama


