<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
265 Fink Collection 78
Neihardt 
Branson, Mo.
BRANSON
FEB13
3 -PM
1941
M.O.
Mrs. O. F. Fink
9917 Emerson Ave
Overland
St. Louis County Mo.
79
1
Darling Enid:
<p>You must have wondered why you did not hear, but this fact has been due to my being sick as well as Daddy. I am all O.K. now again so please don't mention it. Daddy is really improving dailing now. He began the last part of Jed Smith yesterday morning and sleeps without taknig any medecine now. Poor Daddy has certainly been through the mill, but thank God he has come out of it without any bad results.</p>
<p>I am sorry Ollie and you both have been sick</p>
80
2
<p>with colds - This is a bad time of year for such things. When we do finally feel well enough to drive up, you will see we will all have a wonderful time together, untroubled by aches and pains I trust. So our newest Baby is 3 months along! Bless its little person! It does not Know that it will have to turn upside down and stand on its head before long!! If we only could Know it, nothing should worry us, for what seems terrible is really not so when we get to it! Just that our</p>
79
3
<p>lives may be good enough to be "songs in the ears of men here after"! I Keeping seeing your baby a a boy, Enid girlie, somehow it seems that way - but I hope I am wrong, selfishly speaking! We already love, it no matter whether it be John Neihardt or Mona Lisa! When Mona Lisa does come however, its Nanny will be unable to pry herself away from her, how about it?</p>
<p>It seems Max and the Wubs are going to come Home for the Spring and Summer, since Hilda has decided to take</p>
80
4
<p>her vacaation in March. I think she is doing right, and we will be so happy to have Max and the Wubs here.</p>
<p>Sig will doubtless room somewhere, and I hope Alice may stay with you till she does to the Summer Camp where she almost certainly has a job teaching dancing for <strike>the</strike> a salary as well as her living free. Maybe you do not know about this yet so please don't mention it if you have not heard about it from Alice herself.</p>
<p>This change will mean that Hilda will want you to take her furniture, may</p>
81
5
<p>be Max too will want to store her things in your <sic>attick</sic>! You see how very necessary you are to us all! Now if Hilda does not want to go into an unfurnished apt. again in the Fall - her dresser as well as the Sunroom furniture will be yours. But even if Hilda does not Know for certain whether she will or will not need those things in the Fall, it seems to me you could make good use of them this Summer, not? That wicker set would look lovely in your front porch room - and the dresser would be fine in your second bedroom. I sort of feel that Hilda will do what she can get a job in Mexico and</p>
82
6
<p>why not? If she does so, the furniture is yours, Enid. I wrote Maxine that I will have to have the beds <strike>brought</strike> sent back down here as we'll need them very much. Of course we will be up there with you before any of this happens - but I did want you to Know our palns since you may not have seen the Children lately.</p>
<p>I Know how you feel about Dr. Starck. The children will have to make their own experience, and I have not said any thing antagonistic neither has Daddy.</p>
<p>It may be a good thing for the present, giv</p>
81
7
<p>ing them all more self confidence. Sigurd shows what he feels days down by not allowing his name to be given. He is right; Hilda feels the way you do and Alice I believe does too, but neither say much about it. Hilda sort of jokes about it. Alice is mum.</p>
<p>Always I want "The Glory of the search for God" to be theirs and yours - different as your ways of searching and finding may be._</p>
<p>It will be so good to see you both - We may come this week end - but don't look for us definitely till you see us!</p>
Always endless love
82
8
for you all three
from 
your devoted
Mama Mother