<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
90 Neihardt Collection 54
Neihardt
5611 Enright,
St. Louis, Mo.
SAINT LOUIS, MO. 4
AUG16
12 -M
1940
Dr. and Mrs. John G. Neihardt
Branson, Missouri
<underline>over</underline>
<p>Those 3 books are the most exhausting books to read for you go from feeling to felling in such strides with such rapidity that its hard to take. I feel as <sic>tho</sic> I had done a hard days work after reading in them. Still it is stimulating &amp; new each time. How do you figure it out?</p>
55
[Aug 15, 1940]
Thursday
Dear Mom and Dad:
<p>Thanks so much for your letters. I am very glad Sears has been so accomodating and hope that you get exactly what you want in the way of a stove. It's too bad the buying of that stove has made so much trouble for you. We will be more than glad to pay the Sears account and we know they can do nothing if we are paying at least $5.00 per month on the account. Naturally we will pay as much as we can. Do not feel that we think it unfair to pay this balance. That is foolish, for whatever we are able to do we <underline>want</underline> to do regardless of what form that takes. Actually we feel xxxx responsible for the account for in the first place it was in our name, we started it, and there is no drawing a line as to who got the most out of the questionable aid that it seemed at the time. For I say any time payment is a questionable aid no matter how needed the article is that you must have. Still it seem<strike>e</strike>s one can not get around them every way. But since ours are in number only two we feel we can manage.</p>
56
2
<p>to make things easier for us. I <underline>mean</underline> the words I am saying. I look with amazement on your life that has been as equally balance with ups as with downs and wonder how faith and hope and love could survive without deep bitterness. If that can be accomplished then life is indeed worth living for it means there is something more than just living, something you have reached together that few people reach. My admiration will no doubt increase as I grow older and time begins to teach me that life has to be fought not lived, and fought with a hardness xxxxx and as much cool foresight xxxxxxxxx and ruthlessness as possible. Naturally the first law is self preservation in the world and that is the way one has to look at the world. And pity for the fact that one has to look at it that way.</p>
<p>As you well know it would be impossible to count in dollars and cents the the immense <sic>debit</sic> we owe you. Even the round figure of $5000. would hardly cover it. How happy we would be to be paying a monthly amount to you instead of to these other places, then we would feel the money actually accomplished something. But enough talk of money. We have all done the best we can. We have x made mistakes and probably will make more but not in a financial way. We want to help and this is the first time we have had a chance to do so and the plan must be worked out. Slowly things are taking shape. If the manager rents this place by Sept. 1 we will move to an unfurnished apartment immediately. If she can not rent it until Oct. 1 we will stay here still paying half the rent. It seems that four can manage here for a month. We will get a rollaway bed ( Ollie says they are selling for $5.00 with a pad now) and Sig and I will sleep on it. What if we are crowded for that short a time. I think we are all good enough sports to stand a little inconvenience for so short a time. Ask Alice if she would be willing.</p>
<p>By October 1 Sig and I could have enough saved to easily make a move for the better for all of us. It will mean being away from the babies which makes us heart sink but if that is the sacrifice I have to make very <gap = "cutoff"/></p>
57
3
<p>that is alright with me. Sept. 1 I xxxxxx will be able to send something toward your keep of them there until a move is made. I have not the slightest uneasy feeling about the babies, do not think that. But naturally I miss them with all my heart.</p>
<p>Between now and Sept. first many letters will be written to be sent on that date. Already I have a bunch that look good for this year out for us to start on. We will do all we can toward xxxx getting them, perhaps using the new folder and stating that Sig will be unavailable this season. Naturally we will spend as little as possible on stamps hitting only those that have previously answered us favorably.</p>
<p>At a store meeting last night Sig found out why Hargas was fired. It seemed for his position of 3rd man at the store he has making too much money and not giving the salesmen as much of a chance as they needed. Burns, the manager, said that they need not feel their jobs were insecure, for he said unless the store went under naturally the salesmen would be needed adn if you are a good salesmen naturally you will be kept. If the store went under they would try to find all their men jobs at other western auto stores. The blue banner sale starts today and lasts through August. Great advertisments in the P-D and other papers are being put in and always business picks up when they advertise like that. Between now and Xmas business will be good. Sig was 10 man in St. Louis on his sales average last month and he is in the worst store in the city for cash average. He averaged around a dollar and a half per person which is extremely good. He has sold 32 tires already this month and his quota is 50. He is up to par with batteries and oil and he sold 4 radios also which brings his radio quota up to the mark. So there is reason why he was kept and they other man fired. So he plans to go to town this month on commissions and certainly has opportunity to do so.</p>
58
4
<p>Night before last Sig and Max went to buy Max a car. He will go to Mexico tomorrow I believe. They found him a late '37 Crysler Convertable Coupe new tires, radio and heater and in excellent condition having been driven 22 thousand miles in the city for $350.00. Max was very well pleased adn was more than happy to pay that price rather than $600.00. The car also has over-drive and gets around 17 miles to the gallon. It's price was $395.00 but since Max paid cash Sig got them down to $350.00. We were so glad Sig could do xxxxxxx a good turn for him.</p>
<p>I must iron now and wash a few dishes so will close. It's stuffy hot here again, must be going to rain again. We have been having a four o'clock rain nearly every day!</p>
<p>Kiss my babies for me and remember we love you all so much.</p>
Max.
[Neihardt
5611 Enright
St Louis]
<p>Thanks Alice for tending to the babies hair. I'll bet xx they both look lovely. And I'm so glad Joan is fatter. She could stand a little more fat. P.S. No.2. Dad - I have reread Hugh xxx Glass and Three Friends and the Messiah adn each time I get something new and revealing from them. It's such wonderful stuff.</p>
<strike>August</strike>





