<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
43 Sigurd Neihardt Collection 5
New Years Day, '<underline>43</underline>
Dear Max &amp; Sig:
<p>that was another good old fashioned letter. Many thanks!</p>
<p>I see no reason why you shouldn't go ahead and try for engagements. As I'm supposed to be in New York in the Spring (exact date not given) to "receive the Diploma of the Institute", requests for my engagements down East could well be tied up with that event. Don't forget Dr. Rollo Walter Brown, Cambridge, Mass., who has Harvard &amp; other connections. Not mush use trying <underline>in</underline> New York City, I understand, as so many clamor</p>
-2-
<p>to appear for nothing there - anything to get looked at! But this may not be the whole truth about the situation.</p>
<p>I'll send the files as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Amusing about the night-school for Sig! But if he gets paid its all to the good. They have to have rigid rules, of course. I'm so glad you're <underline>in</underline> right, Sig, and that you're not a grease-monkey!</p>
<p>N.Y. Tiems paid me $25 for a review - god words. They should pay $50, but it was my fault. They asked for a longer review than I sent. Sat. Review of Lit and Herald-Tribe will send me books too. Anything may break soon - but who knows.</p>
6
-3-
<p>I hope you had a pleasant time with <unclear>Gothan</unclear>, Sig, if you were able to catch him. He seems to mean business this time.</p>
<p>The announcement of the Institute elections will be made soon - perhaps next week, I don't know; but they wanted a picture in a hurry, &amp; I sent one yesterday by air.</p>
<p>There may be something to the Secretaryship of the Neb. Hist. Society. The seed is planted, Governor likes the idea, I'm told. etc.</p>
<p>It would come by secret election &amp; invitation.</p>
-4-
<p>Maybe, if it comes, I won't want it! We'll see.</p>
<p>I thik you'll hear good news from old Albert soon! <underline>And</underline> Hiddy!</p>
<p>We think so often of our two lovely Girl Ladies. How I wish we could be together awhile &amp; visit with old Doc! Doc hasn't written his Uncle a single letter, but I'll bet he has though <underline>and</underline> thought <underline>and</underline> thought about it. I'm sure he is takign good care of the home place. He is a good people!</p>
Love to each of you and to all four-in-one,
Dad
Gaki