<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4b.6.14-19">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt, March 1924</title>
                <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4b.6.14-19</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, Alice Culler</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Alice Culler Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1925-03">March 1924</date>
                    <extent>6 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>6 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Lulu</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Donald Jr.</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Donald</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
                    <term>McDonald, Neil</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Jenkins</term>
                    <term>Neihardt, Alice Culler</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Minneapolis (Minn.)</term>
                    <term>Buffalo (N.Y.)</term>
                    <term>Branson (Mo.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Neihardt, Alice Culler</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5037649">Minneapolis (Minn.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName></persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1925-03"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">14</note>
                <note type="curatorial">
                    Missouri Collection 
                    
                    [Minneapolis, March? 1925]
                </note>
                
                <opener>
                    
                    <note type="authorial">We write you just before leaving here</note>
                    
                    <dateline>
                        Monday Morning
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear boy;</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>It seems so long since I wrote to you all alone, not that I ever say anything that would Exclude Mona either but just the selfish feel, I suppose it would be called. I have been so busy since I am here with so many different things that I feel like a "hodge podge" and am mable to even think orderly, if I ever did I do want to tell you tho of some things. The mediums, first, have put me in a state of mind that I can't describe. I never felt before the great importance of things as I do now, and the necessity of worthiness, mercy! They did not hesitate a minute when they took my hands, to say you have a</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">15</note>
                
                <p><unclear/> son, or "you will be made very happy thru your son, but there is an other Man there," they both told me that, here and both told me the same thing in Buffalo that puzzles one, I won't worry about it tho. She said I would be well and happy nothing very bad could come to me if you are there: the one here said you will move very soon, but she did not see me going along. However that is, may be it will be the right way, I have never felt since leaving Branson but August that we would live together again as we were then. I'm not "<unclear/> <unclear/>" Just what ever comes I'll be ready for, going back tothe Mediums again, one said "you will have three things in the Movies. There will be a very trying delay with one. But there will be all kinds of money for him." One said you have nto yet written your masterpiece, I asked if you are working on that now she said, "Well maybe." The same one has told Lulu twice that she will be a widow not far off. If I ever see you again I will have so many things to tell you</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">16</note>
                
                <p>I will have so many things to tell you</p> 
                <p>Little Donald has the <unclear/> but getting better. Lulu and I went to the Art
                    Institute yesterday after noon and left Donald to keep house, and when we left
                    there we took a car down town and went to the <unclear/> saw and heard "Harry
                    Snodglass" of Mission Penitentiary fame &amp; He is a wonderful Pianist and so young and fine looking I'm so glad he is getting an other chance.</p> 
                <p>Are you planning on going to Lincoln soon? It seems to me for the children's sake you will have to amek a move. It is too much to Expect Mona to give them their regular lessons and do all the other things that are expected of her with out a great strain on her.</p> 
                <p>And Sigurd's music is an other good reason. Isn't it just wonderful how the
                    little <unclear/> is progressive, I'm so proud and happy Donald is taking music
                    lessons but the <unclear/> made the progress Sigurd has Neil has stopped his
                    music. He has so much to do in School He sits down here in the Evening like a
                    grown up, and indeed he is Tallis than his mother and when he talks it sounds like big Donald, and gets his Latin, &amp; his M thematic which sometimes, as they teach msuci is : alaska and somtimes</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">17</note>
                <note type="authorial">2</note>
                
                <p>is :alaska and something</p> 
                <p><unclear/>, just like a man, He is surely a fine boy very dynam-ic and his teacher his Scant master and Every one who comes in contact with him feels his efficiency in what ever he does. Little Donald is one of the dearest most lovable boys so considerate of "mother", and is doing well in music, and in school. They dote on "Uncle mona and aunt John. Just recieved your letter. Hope you have heard from me long before this. I did neglect writing to you the first couple days as I shoudl have done. We were very much occupied. Have heard the sym-phony concert visited the Art Institute heard a good lecture on art besides writing here at home and <unclear/></p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">18</note>
                
                <p>Inaugural address, and lots of good things besides over Neil's Rade's that he made two years ago. I'm so glad Sigurd is looking forward to one going home I love the little lad and always have unless I have had to feel that 20th Century disrespect the kids have, but I won't care for that ^anymore He is a lovable boy, and no donate will be a wonderful musician and I hope a composer. Enid-dear sweet girl will not disappoint you the world nude more Enids and my Hilda, well-I just smmell up inside with pride when I picture the fail little thing so masterful my Alice will not be the least talented the medium says "The little one will be a great dancer, it won't please her father at first but he has too much sense and too much love for the arts to hinder her." Yes I got the receipt for $20. from Mrs. Jenkins for Dec. and you said $3 on Jan. That is all right boy. But do you think they will have</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4b.6.14-19"/>
                <note type="curatorial">19</note>
                
                <p>But do you think they will have my thing to pay up the rest of the time when they leave? I don't think the ground should be planned yet a while? I cna't tell yet just leave it for a little while. <del>yet.</del>  So glad about the trees recieved the check boy, will see an other medium soon thanks. Lulu is very much interest Ed and me will go together again. Lulu is far from a well woman, but is always ready when her boys need her.</p> 
                <p>I have diminished the dreams boy, and have concluded that the distortions came from me. I won't have that again I see more clearly that we do nothing into ourselves and only selfishness ex-pects more. Think I may stay here over next Sunday, they all want me and it will depend on Grandma of course. Love to you all my dear boy. Mona, Enid, Sig, Hilda and my baby, and you my dear boy Lulu and everybody sends love to all of you</p>
                <closer><signed>from-Mama.</signed></closer> 
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>