<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
12 
Petri Collection 
28
<figure/> 
MPLS <UNCLEAR/> TR 2 JAN 23 1934 R.P.0. 3
U.S. POSTAGE NRA <FIGURE/> 3 
BREEN HOTEL 
M.J. BREEN, MGR. 
St. Cloud, Minn. 
Miss Hilda Neihardt 
767 Elm St., 
Springfield, 
Missouri 

One of the Finest in the Northwest 175 Rooms Strictly Fireproof 
<figure/> 
BREEN HOTEL 
H.J. BREEN, MGR. 
St. Cloud, Minn. 
29
Jan 22 '34
Dear Hiddy:
Mama sent on your letter about the fix you have been in, and I'm more soryr than I can say, I can't see how it happened, unless my first letter containing money and map reach you - or maybe it was the second. 
Anyway, I don't want it ot happen again! Surely there is no need of it, 
I've had a very fine trip. Will read here tonight & catch the 5:50 tain for Minneapolis tomorrow morning, then take the 9:20 train from there for Grinnell. Will reach home Thursday. 
(over) 
One of the Finest in the Northwest 175 Rooms Strictly Fireproof 
    <figure/> 
    BREEN HOTEL 
    H.J. BREEN, MGR. 
    St. Cloud, Minn. 
Hiddy, it's a shame you had to be chagrined for each of money! It mustnt be. Endless love, Dad. 
-3-
P.S. 
10:30 P.M. same day! 
Am through here. Swede audience, or at least very largely swede. They fell for it as usual, & called me from behind the curtain when I had really quit. They are not so quoteably civilized here as in Moorehead - Fargo, but they are quite all right. 
Hiddy, I've just read yoiur lette rover two glasses of beer after the show. It's a great letter, Old Kid! I needn't tell you how dear you are to me & how highly I appraise you. 

30
I went into that place in Minneapolis & saw the <unclear/> with holster that was advertised. It is practically new - no sign of wear anywhere inside or outside. I wanted it a lot, but of course it would be foolish to buy it. 
The weather has been five up here - even at Moorhead what is as far worth as Duluth. I arrived for the January thaw. They have had 30 below at Moorhead 25 at Minneapolis
Endless love, Hiddy, 
Dad,
Comradely greetings to Elanita! 
2 
I am really happy about much, and you are a large part of the muchness! 
Had an ambrosial evening with Dr. Richard Scammon, Dean of Medical Sciences at U. of Minnesota. he is a very distinguished man. You know, he is my old "Dick"- one of my best boyhood chums, We were inseparable as she ages of 9 & 10. We got together in five shops. He & his son & their University crowd are flaming Reds. The song is leader of the Farmen Labor Party in Minnesota, & he is only 18! the kid is 5ft. 5 1/2 in tall & weighs 260 lbs, also, he has a brain big enough for a such a body. 
I feel he will get killed early in teh inevitable row. But he will be heard from How they, & another Prof., did endorse my prophetic guesses. 
(over) 