<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
70a
<header>Hotel Cerro Gordo
OWNED AND OPERATED 
BY CERRO GORDO HOTEL COMPANY
150 ROOMS
POPULAR PRICED CARE
Mason City, Iowa
OPPOSITE SOUTH WEST CORNER CITY PARK</header>
September 6, 1942
Dear Daddy and Mama,
<p>It has been so long since I've heard from you. How are you, anyway? Please <underline>do</underline> write me at once to Huron, <strike>Mich</strike> South Dakota, General Delivery. We leave here for there tomorrow morning at 4:15. It is a long ride.</p>
<p>I do hope and feel sure as well, that everything is O.K. with everyone - but ok! how I'd love to hear from all of you.</p>
<p>We have been enjoying our performances immensely, and are really gaining <underline>so</underline> much by each one</p>
(2)
<p>We get splendid <unclear type="unclear"/> especially on our Russian, and publicity, as you will not, too! The same picture with different <unclear>blurh</unclear> (branding us, as should have been done on this, as the Leon Dances) will appear in tomorrow's paper. George got the negative of this picture and also another one they took. Considering that we had ridden all night in a coach previously to having this taken, it is quite good. You will note the write-up of whole Revue - and also our co-billing with the war! Seriously, though, it is a bit of good publicity.</p>
<p>This is our biggest "city" so-far-and it really</p>
70b
(3)
<header>Hotel Cerro Gordo
OWNED AND OPERATED 
BY CERRO GORDO HOTEL COMPANY
150 ROOMS
POPULAR PRICED CARE
Mason City, Iowa
OPPOSITE SOUTH WEST CORNER CITY PARK</header>
<p>is a nice little city. Eager for Huron too, now.</p>
<p>I'm enjoying working is line too. It is really good experience, enjoyable and lucrative ($25 <underline>extra</underline> per wk. besides my $35 per wk. salary from George) I shall send Madame Cassan $25 this week end. I sent Hil and dentist some - and I shall soon be able to save a bit for safety. Wish the fairs lasted longer. This is <underline>very</underline> good for us for prestige too, however, as well as experience and money. We're to be in demand now! Have other things in the</p>
(4)
<note place="upper_left">Have <underline>never</underline> felt better. <underline>Really healthful life</underline>.</note>
<p>offing now.</p>
<p>The line rehearsed (I with them in a large hotel yesterday, so I stayed afterwards to practice ballet. Then, as usual, we went out to dinner (chicken in basket with all the trimmings plus coffee, for 29¢!) Afterwardsm we dressed and left on bus for Fair Grounds. Had good performance without one dull moment for me, for I'm now in all four production numbers, and am well warmed up by our Russian. We even got whistles of <sic>aplause</sic> last night! Nice, enthusiastic crowds.</p>
<p>Please do write me, I think and pray so for you always - and Love you <underline>so</underline> much.</p>
Your Alice