<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
40a
6234 Southwood
St. Louis, MO.
1/18/41
Dear Dad &amp; Mama:
<p><sic>Tonite</sic> is another Sat. <sic>nite</sic>, &amp; we're all looking forward to sleeping late in the a.m.</p>
<p>A week from thsi Sun. I'll play a group of numbers over Radio Station WTMV, 1500 Kilocycles, 4:30-5:00. It is Dr. Frederick Stark's Astrology (Acquarian School of Higher Thought, Inc.) program. I've been teelling him that his music on these programs is 'lousy'. So, he wants me to talke full charge of the musical side of it from now on. He has a contract for 11 weeks yet on this small station. Then, he says he &amp; I will make 'Big moeny', with this program, over station KWK, on the National-hook-up. At present I'll make no money at it, but it's one of those things that <underline>could</underline> be a step to much else. I'm not even sure you can get station WTMV at Branson. It's <underline>not</underline> so good. This "Acquarian Sch. of Higher Thought" is one of those things designed to capitalize on the present</p>
over
-2-
<p>world break-up, I believe. Starck is my negro Astrologer Acquaintance, &amp; we sort of like eachother. Until I decide whether or not I like the idea of connection my name with such a program - I'll play 'unknown'. My name, I insisted, is <underline>not</underline> to be announced. I want to use Hilda quite often on these programs, should they become something worthwhile.</p>
<p>He (Starck) has rec'd large numbers of letters from listeners, complimenting him on his Astrological viewpoints with regard to present world chaos. Quite a graft, &amp; it could make money. He is known all over U.S. &amp; South American, &amp; has been conduction thsi 'save the world' move through hundreds of representatives working in various sections of the two continents. Ha! Strange thins is that from all over, thsi organization receives donation checks with which to buy their radio time etc. See? Well, anyway we'll see what comes of it all!</p>
<p>I feel hopeful, &amp; even <underline>believe</underline> still that I shall sell an organ this month. Several things <underline>look</underline> probable. Only thing that does worry me is that same old right arm congested condition. Maybe rhumatism or</p>
40b
-3-
<p>something. Dr. Starck, who is a Chiropractor, tells me that he'll fix me up with a calcium &amp; iron tonic, to fill a deficiency which he says 'Saggitarius' often has. Lately, it seems the cold weather brought this condition on. It isn't always with me. Only sometimes.</p>
<p>It will be rine to see you &amp; mom next month. Perhaps the weather will be less severe then than now. I hope that the old plan for us all to make a town together will work out someday. Your readings, Hil's singing, Al's dancing &amp; my accompaniments &amp; solos.</p>
<p>The war situation really looks bad, doesn't it! Pitiful how serious a predicament England is facing. Joanie &amp; Elaine are well, &amp; still wild about Gaki &amp; Nannie.</p>
<p>Please be <underline>happy</underline>, &amp; careful of yourselves.</p>
Endless love
from all,
Sig.