<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
78a
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
Feb. 26th 
1940
9917 Emerson
Overland 
Mo.
Dearest Mom:-
<p>I was so happy to get your last letter, as usual. And, I am so happy that you do understand my stand in the matter discussed &amp; that there may be a solution after May. It isn't that Alice isn't just loved &amp; admired a very great deal, for <underline>she certainly is</underline>! it's just as I said, it is nicer for us not to have anyone of that particular age at this time. And, Alice <underline>is</underline> adorable. She certainly wants to do a lot more than she needs to do here. Her work at studies is so strenous, too, that I don't wnat her to do too much work when she's home. And, I've told her that I don't expect her to work to stay here; just to take care of her room mainly &amp; to do anythign else she feels inclined to do. She insists on doing the dishes &amp; scrubbing floors</p>
2
<p>occassionally which is nice. It would be nice if Hilda could arrange something after her vacation which would be more to her advantage as well as to Alice's, as you mention. Hilda really needs a piano too, I should think. Maybe they could find a home, something like that of Mrs. Henerson's in Springfield where she stayed while going to college. That, I think would be ideal &amp; possibly as resonable for the two of them as Clubs is for Hilda alone, or practically so. What do you think? I'm anxious to hear what Hilda says to you.</p>
<p>We had a nice time yesterday. Jack Harrison has bought a horse with his own money. Alice went over with us &amp; got acquainted with the Harrisons. She thinks too, that they are some of the nicest people she ever met! Nice, isn't it? She &amp; Susan are going to knit together &amp; Mrs. Harrison invited her to come over any time &amp; practice her dancing in their basement</p>
78b
3
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>playroom! Susan is so anxious for Al to show her all that! You know how young girls are! Jack told Al as soon as he gets a bridle &amp; saddle, she may ride whenever she wants to. Nice? She &amp; Hil could come out Sundays &amp; ride horseback even though they weren't staying out here. I believe Hil would like it, too. Jack built his stable &amp; the fence around it all himself &amp; paid for everything with the money he'd saved up from his odd jobs - mowing lawns, etc. during the summers. And, besides, he bought his mother a new stove for Xmas. I think he's an unusually dear &amp; fine boy. Only 17 too! We think a lot of Harrions. Mom, Mrs. H. asks of you nearly every time I see her. She says Alice looks like you! So do I. Al is a dear kid &amp; Ol &amp; I surely</p>
4
<p>wouldn't care to hurt her &amp; we want both of them to come out as often as possible. I want Hil to birng her friend out soon.</p>
<p>Mom, I'm having such fun on my little baby sweater. It's <underline>so</underline> cute! I've finished the back &amp; am half down one side of front. The little neck is <underline>darling</underline>. I already have an undershirt &amp; panties in mind to make when I finish this! I'll send Max's learning book soon. It's a <underline>grand</underline> help. Was for me.</p>
<p>Hope 'Laine got the gift on time!</p>
<p>Al is making mittens-- Mrs. H. &amp; Susan are going to help her, for they know how to do it &amp; I think it'll be nice for Al to have Susan to knit with, don't you? She can go over once inawhile of evenings. Then she can have a little recreation. I think every young girl needs that, don't you? That's another thing she doesn't get being with us all the time which she'd get with Hilda.</p>
78c
5
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p>Mom, I'm sending to Aut Jenny's Garden Club Los Angeles, California for 5 packets of swell flower seed. You can do it. Just buy a 1lb. can of Spry &amp; take the cardboard disc off the top, write your name &amp; address on back of it &amp; send a dime &amp; you'll get the seeds. They sound swell. Try it. They are really good seeds, I belieive, &amp; aren't things you don't want. I'll do it for you as soon as I buy another can of Spry. Is this okay? I think that'd be a nice idea. So one of these days you'll be getting soem seeds. Ha, ha!</p>
<p>I'm having another period, but it's better than the former ones. I'm in so much better condition now.</p>
6
<p>Ol sends all his love, Mom. Lots o' love to Max &amp; kiddies too.</p>
Loads o' love to you, Mom,
always,
Enid
<p>P.S. Can we have a sort of list to write to Dad &amp; Sig by? -<underline>Eny</underline></p>
<p>Sandage called Ol up the other nite, as he often does, he's so lonely! And he gave us an address in So. Carolina till the end of the mo. So we can write once before you send a list.</p>
(See next page)
78d
7
ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH
EDITORIAL DEPARTMENT
<p><underline>P.S.</underline>
Mom, just rec'd your letter after writing last few pages.</p>
<p>That's swell about Hilda's hope to have Alice. I presume she'll start on that after her vacation?</p>
<p>Mom, I've forgotten to thank you for the bread pans! They're just grand! I've made two extra good bakings! It goes beautifully! Ol &amp; Alice both love it as well as do I! The last two were white bread, but this week I'll make whole wheat. It's a howling success all right. They really love it!</p>
<p>Thanks to you both for the addresses of Dad &amp; Sig!</p>
<p>Max, I'll write you very, very soon. Thanks for the swell letter. As Mom says, you &amp; I should be able to "make homey things together". It'd surely be fun all right! I'd love to see Joanie's hood! Bet it's darling! Am sending the book &amp; thanks so much for having the yarn catalog sent to me! I'm tickled</p>
8
<p> to death &amp; so is Alice..</p>
<p>Must write the folks now. I think it's swell about 'Laine's "Betty" doll. Bet it looks darling!</p>
Love to all four of you at home, 
always,
Eny





