<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
369 Fink Collection 55
[April 8, 1943]
CHICAGO
MAY 8
5 PM
1948
ILL.
Ni and 
4920 Blackslove
Chicago

Mr. &amp; Mrs. Oliver Fink,
9917 Emerson Ave.,
<hi rend="strike_through">Chicago,
Ill.</hi>
Overland,
Missouri56
4920 Blackstone Ave.,
Chicago
Sat. Apr. 8, '43
Dear Enat, Ollie &amp; Nei:
<p>it was good to hear from you, as always, and I was thinking a latter at you when yours arrived. The <hi rend="underline">above</hi> is <hi rend="underline">our</hi> address - right across the street from Seymour's. We have a really <hi rend="underline">nice</hi> comfortable kitchenette apartment, not to be compared with one on McPherson. It's on the second floor, and there's a big stone front porch for hot evenings. Furniture &amp; rugs are lovely. I feel that Mama &amp; Amama will be delighted. We paid $10 on McPherson for the two rooms. Here we pay $12.50, which doesn't seem possible. Rents must be considerably lower here. This is the Hyde Part district - 3 or 4 blocks to Fake Michigan and a good beach. Transportation is fine - &amp; bus line - all near! <hi rend="strike_through">It's</hi> Various fine apt. hotels all around, also fine theatres within a couple of blocks. And <hi rend="underline">restaurants</hi>! Amama feels the necessity and get swell scenery with her food!</p>
(over)
57
-2-
<p>The people at <hi rend="underline">Esquire</hi> are all of a rather high class, apparently, and I like Gringrich. The Pal Olive Bldg. is north of the Chicago River about 8 blocks, in the Gold Coast District - right next to the Drake Hotel. Surely a nice place to work.</p>
<p>There's no way to know how things will work out these days, but I like what I'm doing and <hi rend="underline">evidently</hi> Gingrich plans to use me somewhat differently a little later. The M S department is not yet well organized, &amp; even now it is easy to see how to make it more efficient.</p>
<p>Yesterday I had the privilege of reading Stefan Zwaig's <hi rend="underline">last</hi> novelette in M S. Done just before he killed himself in Brazil. Fine piece of work.</p>
58
-3-
<p>Did you know that I could probably have the editorship of Unity publications in Kansas City?</p>
<p>I often think of Nei &amp; see his face. Mama says his development is surprising. Sentences already?</p>
<p>You wouldn't have much garden if you were up here, Odie. It's been coldish mostly; and only now are the leaves coming out on the trees.</p>
<p>I'll be so glad to see Mama &amp; Amama in that near apt!</p>
<p>Enot, I think of you too, and of the little girl (?) who will soon arrive. Mama says you are blooming like a rose! Keep cheerful &amp; be sure that everything is absolutely as it should be. With <hi rend="underline">you</hi> that's to be expected. You're a real Mama.</p>
<p>I love all three of you together &amp; separately.</p>
<p>Many many thanks for so much goodness!</p>
Dad.