<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
108 Neihardt Collection 59
[April 25, May 2, 9 1943]
Sunday Morning
Precious Mona:
<p>It has been impossible for me to make a definite plan, but I've thought of this: Would it be good for you to give notice there tomorrow evening and take the slight chance? I certainly expect this to be successful here, but it's all strange &amp; I can't be <hi rend="underline">absolutely</hi> sure. <hi rend="underline">I can</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">will</hi> do my part, but I don't know the <hi rend="underline">set</hi>-up at Esquire, &amp; I'm naturally cautious. But, at worst, I think we'd be as safe here as in St. Louis. Yesterday Hiddy &amp; I looked at a lovely 2nd floor apartment across the street. It will be vacated in a couple of days. The bldg is fine &amp; high class, all the furniture lovely &amp; comfortable. Front porch to sit on in <unclear/>! Two large rooms separated by sliding double doors. A tiny kitchen in a sort of closet. When this is closed, there's no sign of cooking. Overstuffed stairs, good, <hi rend="underline">unworm</hi> rugs, stairway with padded carpet. Lovely entrance. $12.50 a week for this - &amp; you're paying $10 for that one room there! No comparison whatever,</p>
(over)
68
<p>When the double doors are open, there's room for guests. <hi rend="underline">Very</hi> nice in every way.</p>
<p>I'm hoping we can be ready in time to grab this &amp; get started with living. We three can be happy in such a place. Three or four blocks to the to the Lake, a stores &amp; two swell movies <hi rend="underline">near</hi>.</p>
<p>Hiddy will see you Saturday &amp; can tell you much.</p>
<p>I went t an osteopath, 3 clocks form here, yesterday. He did make me feel much <hi rend="underline">newer</hi>. It's going to be all right. He thinks one treatment a week may do.</p>
<p>I made $23 last week - less several taxes. Get soaks, paid $3 to Dr., etc.</p>
<p>I do love you, &amp; I'll be so glad when you're here.</p>
<p>Amama, dog on it, it'll be good to look at you making toast!</p>
Jno
<p>Hiddy &amp; I think the sooner you come the better. I wish I <hi rend="underline">could</hi> grab that apartment now.</p>