<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
29 
Missouri Collection 
Enright, Thurs. A.M. [August 25, 1938]
My own Mona: 
I'm mildly homesick, or worse, and I'm waiting for the postman. The dentist took an impression yesterday, and I'll see him again today. Friday, he will pull teeth and sock the new plate in I dread it, since I'm keyed a bit high; but it will be a good penance for losing the light. This is Olhe's day off and I'll have lunch there. I slept here last night, and there was a very cool wind - almost cold - after a broiling day. Olhe told me about Bovard's final letter to the staff, giving in detail his reasons for resigning x (over) 

30
-2-
The letter was read by Reese to a chosen company of Old-timers and the doors were locked. The letter was destroyed after it was read. Mrs. Profiled was there, and she said there was something about me. One reason, Bovard wrote was teh way I had been pushed out without consulting him, and he added that a great deal of the spiritual power of the paper was lost when my page was discontinued and I was sent away.
Not so bad! 
Am advertising man told Ollie he bet old Keeler would be asking me back one of these days. 

31
-3-
Anyway, I went not without honor in my own country! 
You must know, Mona, that you are built into the wall of my world. Also, if "The Ghostly Brother" ever had any sort of meaning, it still has. I wish you, could see inside of me. It's all right in there, but sometimes it's a strange place - so damned beautiful and sad. When I get harnassed, something worthy should happen. But more than for anything else, I pray for plenty so that I can give with full hands. I know this is utterly sincere, for I know the still, deathly feeling that comes with the ride. 

32
-4-
<figure/> 
I'll stay here a day or two after Friday so that my jaw may we too sore when I drive back. 
Everything is fine here. Girls very happy. Old Betty nearly got a $1700 job teaching German at Kearney, Neb. Too bad she missed it - just because the letter was, unreasonably delayed She's a fine girl. And to think that they're making her teach "Business Law", as tho' it mattered - as though there were any really! 
Poshwan not here yet. I'll wiat some more. 
x x <figure/> 