<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Missouri Collection 68
THE PROGRAMS OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT
ASSISTED BY
SIGURD NEIHARDT, PIANIST
BRANSON, MISSOURI
April 12, 1939
Precious Mona:
<p>I have some good news. Started writing thsi morning and got 12 lines. I can go ahead now for awhile without the slow terror that has been gnawing me.</p>
<p>A gellow near Berlin, Germany, write for my autograph to put with a collection in "the castle archives". Lenzfried seems to be the castle. Got this nearly a week ago.</p>
<p>I've been working all over the place. Yesterday I mowed the myrtle under the hedge in the fountain garden &amp; took off two wheel-barrow loads of rock. Cannas planted garden back of the dry pool <unclear/> - raking, mowing, etc. Place looks nice. I'm putting the last fine touches on the crystal ring. It is <nearly>nearly</nearly> perfect, so far as I can see.</p>
<p>You have rec'd my letter reassuring you about staying there as long as you're needed. I'm so glad you're there. Too bad the girls had to be sick. And now old lady Alice and her tooth! Dog on it!</p>
(over)
<note>letter referred to here is in files</note>
69
<p>I do hope Hiddy will get through without too much suffering. Here's love enough to wrap her up snugly. It stretches.</p>
<p>You didn't suppose I'd be put out because the girls needed you, did you? That would be funny.</p>
<p>I do hope that, sometime in the summer, you and I can get away to a cabin out West where we can feel timeless and I can push through with the last of Jed. Nothing wrong here, of course. I love the kids &amp; Sig &amp; Max, who is, in her own way, something of an angel. But I want the feel of no time to get the hell into that last terrific part of Jed when Evans is talking, to no ears but the dogs!</p>\
<p>Endless love to you and the naughty gals. (Good people don't  ever get sick! It's the sin coming out on 'em!)</p>
Jno 
Dad.
<note>sentences below are in margins of letter</note>
<p>Would you care to visit Mrs. Bayles? Might be <unclear/></p>
<p>When I was dressing this morning at sunlight, somebody bustled through the hall &amp; down stairs. I thought it was Max; There was no one! <gap reason="cut off"/></p>