<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.n1b.2.13-14">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Stanley C. Smith, February 14, 1970</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.n1b.2.13-14</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Stanley C. Smith</title>
                    <date when="1970-02-14">February 14, 1970</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Young Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Smith, Stanley C.</term>
                    <term>Turner, Frederick Jackson, 1861-1932</term>
                    <term>Dickinson, John Ada</term>
                    <term>Crazy Horse, approximately 1842-1877</term>
                    <term>Roman Nose</term>
                    <term>Spotted Tail, 1823-1881</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
                    <term>The Song of Three Friends</term>
                    <term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                    <term>The Frontier in American History</term>
                    <term>A Cycle of the West</term>
                    <term>The World's Best books, Homer to Hemingway: 3000 books of 3000 years, 1050 B.C. to 1950 A.D., selected on the basis of a consensus of expert opinion</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName>Smith, Stanley C.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1970-02-14"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.n1b.2.13-14"/>
                <note type="curatorial">13</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine Street</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska 68505</addrLine> 
                    </address>
                    <dateline>February 14, 1970</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Stan,</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>It was good to hear from you again, as always.</p> 
                <p>Of course I am interested in what you say about The Song of the Indian Wars. Here are a few points
                that you might be able to use. First, as to the acceptance of the book: When it appeared in 1925 it
                was chosen from world literature by a national committee as one of the 500 books to constitute the
                White House Library. Second, Dr. Frederick Jackson Turner of Harvard, author of the famous book, The
                Frontier in American History, read The Song of the Indian Wars and remarked when he returned the
                copy to one of his graduate students, who had been my student also: "After all, perhaps the poet is
                the best historian." Third, while it is true to recorded history, most of the material was obtained
                from those who were in the Indian Wars, both whites and Indians. I was the first civil-ian member of
                the Order of the Indian Wars, and knew officers who had fought on the Plains.</p> 
                <p>As you know, The Song of the Indian Wars deals with the great westward migration which took place
                after the Civil War adn with the last great fight for the bison pastures between the westering white
                man and the Plains Indians--the Sioux, the Cheyenne, and the Arapahoe. It is interesting to note
                also that The Cycle of the West, which includes the Song of the Indian Wars, was chosen as one of
                the best 3000 books appearing in the 3000 years form Homer to Hemingway. These were chosen by a
                consensus of expert opinion aver a period of thirty years. The book, The World's Best Books from
                Homer to Hemingway, edited by John Ada Dickinson, is available in any large library. The foregoing
                points are given merely to suggest the importance of the book.</p> 
                <p>As to heroes, the prefatory material in the school edi-tion of The Song of Three Friends and The
                Song of Hugh Glass</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.n1b.2.13-14"/>
                <note type="curatorial">14</note>
                
                <p>gives the reason for regarding the movement as typically epic and the heroes as epic heroes. This
                edition is now a collector's item, and if it isn't available to you, I will xerox the pertinent
                material. The Cycle of the West, including The Song of the Indian Wars, has been characterized as
                teh first democratic epic, the heroes being common men. If you will read it through again (How many
                times already!), you will find that heroism occurs often adn at various levels in The Song of the
                Indian Wars; at the highest level in Crazy Horse and at a lower level in Condon, standing on his
                barrel of beans and telling Death, the blackguard, what he thought of him. In order to choose the
                heroes you need only to read the Song again. Beecher's Island has several examples of heroism, both
                white and Indian (remember Roman Nose), and so have the Wagon Box fight and the Custer fight. 
                Think of the heroism of Spotted Tail, who put the death paint on his face and offered himself to be
                punished for his depredations on the Platte, thus shielding his warriors. You could find, I think, a
                score of unquestionable examples of heroism on various levels.</p> 
                <p>I should think that it would not be necessary to argue the importance of this American theme and the
                American heroes, both Indian and white.</p> 
                <p>I know that you know these things I have pointed out, but I am only tyring to remind you. I suggest
                tha tyou write out a statement including all the opints that I have made, using my order and as much
                of my own wording as seems desirable. In fact, yoiu may make any use of this letter you like.</p> 
                <p>I am glad that you would like to teach my stuff, becasue I know the power of your enthusiasm.</p>
                
                <closer>
                    <salute>With the old love for you, Alicia, and the youngsters,</salute>
                    <signed>John G. Neihardt </signed>
                </closer>
                
                <note type="authorial">JGN:fmb</note>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>