<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
August 4, 1970
Mr. Otha D. Wearin
Nishna Vale Farm 
Hastings, Iowa
Dear Mr. Wearin:
When "Bright Eyes" (Susette LaFlesche Tibbles) died in 1903, she and her husband had been living on
their farm about 4 miles north of Bancroft. Tibbles and I were well acquainted. He was not very well
liked in the community largely because of his Populist activities. The family of "Bright Eyes" was
not friendly to him. When Susette died Tibbles sent word to me asking if I would spend the ngith
with him and his dead wife. I suspect he did this because he had no intimate friends in the
community. 
I was glad to go because I respected the man's political and social views. He was a pioneer both in
the physical and the intellectual sense and he was far superior to some of those who disliked him.
The night I spent with Tibbles was a strange and beautiful one. her body was lying in the bedroom
off the front room where we sat and talked. Ever now and then we would go out to change the wet
cloth on her face. I think the body was not embalmed else we would not have done this. He would
stand there with his shoudlers shaking saying, "Isn't she beautiful: Isn't she beautiful:" And she
was beautiful, even more beautiful in death than in life. All night long Tibbles talked about his
life with her. And what a book it would make if we had a copy of what he said that nigth: Sometimes
he would forget that she was dead and some amusing incident would cause him to laugh heartily. Then
he would remember and we would go in together to loko at her dead face. 
I did not go to the funeral. Somone came after me before breadfast and that was the last I saw of
"Bright Eyes". 
Mrs. Green's book on the children of Iron Eye has a paragraph on page 149 telling of my
relationshipo with Susette's famous sister, Dr. Susan LaFlesche Picotte. Nothing is told of the
night I spent with Tibbles and his dead wife. I made reference to it in a speech I gave at Bancroft
several years ago when the highway marker was being dedicated. The reference in that speech and this
letter are the only written accounts of the matter so far as I can remember at present. 
With all good wishes, 

