<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
6
July 13, 1973
Members of the Lemmon Chamber of Commerce, ladies and gentlemen:
It was my intention to be with you on this great day, but owing to illness I am unable to come. My
old friend, J.D. Young, has kindly consented to read this message to you. You may be sure, however,
that my heart and soul are with you there, and I thank you for your thought of me. 
When I was a young man in the heyday of my writing years it was my habit to dedicate my books to
the children of my family as they came along. When my Song of Hugh Glass was completed after three
years of devoted effort, I dedicated it to my only son, Sigurd, then scarcely three. The dedication
ran thus:

TO SIGURD, SCARCELY THREE 
When you are old enough to know
the joys of kite and boat and bow
and other suchlike splendid things
That boyhood's rounded decade brings, 
I shall not give you tropes and rhymes;
But, rising to those rousing times,
I shall ply well and craft I know 
Of shaping kite and boat and bow,  
For you shall teach me once again
The goodly art of being ten. 
Meanwhile, as on a rainy day
When 'tis not possible to play, The while you do your best to grow
I ply the other craft I know 
And strive to build for you the mood
of daring and fortitude 
With fitted word and shapen phrase,
Against those later wonder-days
When first you glimpse the world of men
Beyond the bleaker side of ten. 

That was in 1915, more than half a century ago. I have kept my promise to the boy of ten and made
kites, and boats and bows; I have built the mood of daring and of fortitude for the growing man,
exemplified by old Hugh Glass. 
I watched my boy grow old -- and full of sleep -- and now that it has been getting later and later
for me recently, it thrills me to think innumberable men, women, and children will spend happy times
in this recreation park near where Hugh Glass fought alone for life. 
And may many learn the great lessons set forth in Hugh Glass. For instance: 
"nor might treachery recall the miracle of being loved at all." 


And also-
"The duty and the beauty of endeavor, the privilege of going on forever, a victor in the moment!"
Again, I thank you for this very special honor that has come to me in the dedication of this Hugh
Glass Park. 
Sincerely,
(signed) John G. Neihardt 