<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.n1b.1.13-14">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Melvin B. Yoken, February 21, 1969</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.n1b.1.13-14</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Melvin B. Yoken</title>
                    <date when="1969-02-21">February 21, 1969</date>
                    <extent>3 page</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Young Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Yoken, Melvin B.</term>
                    <term>Young, Myrtle</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Columbia (Mo.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>All is but a beginning : youth remembered, 1881-1901</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/56742154">Yoken, Melvin B.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1969-02-21"/>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.n1b.1.13-14"/>
                <note type="curatorial">13</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine Street</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska 68505</addrLine> 
                    </address>
                    <dateline>February 21, 1969</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Professor Yoken:</salute>
                </opener>
                
                <p>As my friend, Mrs. Young, has written you, I have had two operations on my eyes and have been recuperating for some weeks. I find myself able now to take up my correspondence. Your letters of November 29 and those in January and February have been read again--with delight, I need not to tell you. I see that I have neglected to answer your questions in a manner satisfactory to you, and so I will try again.</p> 
                <p>You asked what are my present activities, I am simply having the time of my life writing what is called my autobio-graphy. I dislike the term and hardly know what to call it. The title will be "The Old Man Remembers." I have a farm five miles from Columbia, Missouri, where my daughter and I raise gaited horses and train them. For most of the past year I have been living with my friends, the Youngs, here and spending all my time on the book. It should be completed during this year--completed so far as it is possible for me to write a complete "autobiography." When I am at home I play with my dog and the horses. Also I have done a good deal of lapidary work in the past and enjoy it as I used to enjoy writing lyrics. That's as near as I can come to answering your first question.</p> 
                <p>Your second question asks who are my authors of predil-ection (American, English, French, etc.) The answer is simply that I no longer have any predilections. The time has been when I would have said the Greeks were my favorites, and after them, various others. But I have come to feel that my favorite is simply poetry itself, and I care very little who writes it. You see, this is the answer of an old man who has loved poetry for the better part of a century.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.n1b.1.13-14"/>
                <note type="curatorial">14</note>
                
                <p>You asked also how I view the present world situation.</p> 
                <p>This is, of course, a tremendous question, but a fairly intelli-gent answer can be given. I spent nearly a quarter of a century writing criticism bearing on what was happening to our values. Someday I hope the best of these essays will be collected. If they ever are, they will give you a much better than I have for you now. My present answer is a brief one. We are in a period of cultural anarchy which began in this country in 1912. One sees the operation of the anarchic principle through-out our society. In the essays referred to, I trace the cause of our dominating time mood, beginning with the invention of the steam engine and following through the French Revolution and the triumph of the laissez faire theory.</p> 
                <p>I appreciate your attitude toward me more than I can tell you, and especially since you are a young man and will be going presumably long after after I am with my fathers.</p> 
                <p>Hoping we may meet some time.</p> 
                
                <closer>
                    <salute>Your friend,</salute>
                    <signed>John G. Neihardt</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <note type="authorial">JGN:fmb</note>
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>