<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
March 8, 1970 
Dear John,
I was delighted to receive a letter from you after so long a silence between us. I have thought of
you often, wishing that I could see you again; but my thoughts of you did not get into a letter. 
First I want to say that I am very glad to know that you are married and happy. You have been doing
such inter-esting things, and I wish I could be with you to hear about them from your own lips. I do
know about your South Ameri-can photography. Next, I want to say that I am much inter-ested in your
idea about a documentary on me and my work. 
A great deal has happened since we were together, and I wish it could be talked to you instead of
written; but here are a few things that would concern you if you should do a documentary. 
I think you do not know that my old home town, Ban-croft, Nebraska, where I did so much of my more
important work, has restored the old cottage which I used as my study and has developed a Sioux
Prayer Garden on the grounds in memorhy of my creaive years there. They have organized a Neihardt
Foundation, Inc., and in 1968 the Governor of the state proclaimed the first Sunday of August of
each year as Neihardt Day, which is celebrated with an appropriate program in Bancroft. I think you
would find Bancroft more appropriate than Columbia for the photography. Of course you might like to
use both places, and you might also like to take some shots of me here in Lincoln as my desk at work
on my autobiography. 
Did you knwow that a bronze bust of me, made by my wife Monda, was placed in the rotunda of the
Capitol Building here in Lincoln in 1961? You may know that I recieved the Thomas Jefferson Award
from the University of Missouri two years ago. I think that this is regarded as the highest award
for a professor. 
My TV program is still running at M.U. It is a con-tinuation of the old "Epic America" and is
concerned with The Song of the Indian Wars and The Song of the Messiah. The title of the course is
"The Twilight of the Sioux." It is very popular. 

16
I have been doing much public reciting and, much to my surprise, the response seems to be even
greater than formerly. Standing ovations are commonplace. 
The University of Nebraska Press will bring out Splendid Wayfaring and When the Tree Flowered in
August and September. They already publish The Lyrics, The Cycle, The River and I, and Black Elk
Speaks. Before the year is out, they will bring out the youth section of my autobiography. As for
the biography, it is completed and we here are wait-ing to know what the author intends to do with
it. I know that the University of Nebraska Press wants it, however. 
Mrs. Young, in whose home I am living and who has attended to much of my correspondence, is sending
you some material that you will find useful. Although I plan to con-tinue living and writing here in
Lincoln, I still own Sky-rim and return occasionally to Columbia. I can arrange to be whereever you
want me for photography. 
This letter is long enough for the first one. Per-haps you will have questions that you will want to
ask me, and you may be sure that I will do my best to answer them. 
Give my affectionate regards to your dear lady, hug those two youngsters for me, and pat Andrew on
his nose. He won't know who I am but I love him. I have a poodle dog, Jacquot, who takes care of me
ngith and day and is easily the most photographed dog in this section of the country. His French
accent is very noticeable in his barking. 
Your old friend,
JGN:fmb John G. Neihardt 