<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, May 9, 1960</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.28.13-16_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1960-05-09">May 9, 1960</date>
                    <extent>8 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0001a" />
                <note type="curatorial">Aly Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                <dateline>Skryim, 5-9-'60</dateline>
                
                
                <salute>Dear Lucile:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>You see, I'm here! And what's more, Alice and the Girls are here too, and the place lives again with happy voices!!! Alice &amp; Mr. Cook have moved their horse business back here. They were successful down south, and in nearly two years they got ahead very definitely. But they (and I) had 14 horses here on Skyrim - all but two <add>of them</add> fine Saddle
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0001b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    Horse prospects and Hackneys - mostly young stock getting ready to be developed. Why spend their lives developing other people's horses and neglecting theirs? They came back with <del><unclear>five</unclear></del> five fine horses. Two of these are fine mares (really "tops") and one is Bourbon Stonewall, a 3 yr.-old stallion. The latter is as fine as horses ever get. He is the "horesness of horses", the Platonic horse
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0002a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                    
                    We raised him here. His mama is Orlawn Lolita, owned by Alice. This mare was undefeated, and she made all <del/> the big shows. I do wish you could see Bourbon. I'll send a picture as soon as we can get a good one. You'll see what I mean.</p>
               
                <p>Now we have 19 horses - all registered and exceptionally fine, excepting two ponies, which are just nice ponies
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0002b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">4</fw>
                    
                    for kids - a palomino mare and a bright chestnut colt with white mane and tail. The Girls are such darlings. Old Lynn has grown <hi rend="italic">tall</hi>, and she is a real woman already. Erica is really very pretty and so good. They are happy kids and make friends readily.</p>
                
                <p>I'm glad you are not too far away. You seemed very far before your latest letter came; but that, I suppose, was my fault.
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0003a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                    
                    Dear lady, my good friend, don't hesitate to ask any questions that may occur to you. I don't mind remembering at all. Also, I'm the <del/> <hi rend="triple underline">best</hi> source of information you have for that biography. Even my nearest and dearest don't <del>know</del> know my life as I do. So ask me, and I'll try to be honest.</p>
                
                <p>My classes are most satisfactory. I have 176 in Epic America - but I think I told you. The Critical
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0003b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    Essay class is successful too. I'm always surprised, because each time I begin that course I wonder if I'll fail. It always <hi rend="underline">has</hi> succeeeded<sic>succeeded</sic>. Yesterday I rec'd <hi rend="underline">another</hi> letter from a former student who took the course <add>some years ago.</add> He says fine things, and he is now a daddy and a man of the big world! Bless him! O I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> wish I <hi rend="underline">could</hi> really <hi rend="italic">bless</hi> <hi rend="underline">all of them</hi>!</p>
                
                <p>Lady friend, I'll be 80 years old next Jan. 8th!! 
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    Isn't that a helluva good joke on me?!!?! You see, I didn't really know I was getting that old, and I don't know how it happened! Within about 3 or 4 years I'm due to start for Heaven (!!) For many, many years I've thought I'd live to the age of 83. The figure is probably wholly imaginary, but it has stayed with me for at <del/> least 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.28.13-16_0004b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                    
                    half a century.</p>
                
                <p>I wish you could know all about the way my classes have impressed students. So much is lost. Maybe it doesn't matter anyway. And you probably know enough.</p>
                
                <p>Lucile, there will be a Neihardt Memorial Library in the new wing of the <del/> Uni. Library, and it will be a nucleus for a growing Western Americana library. I'm to make a list of books I'd buy (<del/>if I had $20,000 to spend for books.</p>
                
                <p>I do hope you feel well. Please tell old Stewart I'm fond of my honorary grandson. And pet sweet darling Perky for me.</p>                 <closer><salute>Love,</salute> <signed>John</signed>.</closer>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
