<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.43.10-18">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, June 16, 1964</title>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4c.43.10-18</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
<date when="1964-06-16">June 16, 1964</date>
<extent>8 pages, plus envelope</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>8 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kendrick, M. Slade (Myron Slade)</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Neihardt, Enid</term>
<term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
<term>Chittenden, Hiram Martin, 1858-1917</term>
<term>Fülöp-Miller, René, 1891-1963</term>
<term>Dickinson, Asa Don, 1876-1960</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Eugene (Or.)</term>
<term>Ithaca (N.Y.)</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term>Poems</term>
<term>A Cycle of the West</term>
<term>The Song of Jed Smith</term>
<term>The Song of the Messiah</term>
   <term>The World's Best books, Homer to Hemingway: 3000 books of 3000 years, 1050 B.C. to 1950 A.D., selected on the basis of a consensus of expert opinion</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1964-06-16"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName>Eugene (Or.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
   <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0001" />

<note type="curatorial">Aly Collection</note>
<fw type="curatorial">10</fw>

<note type="authorial">
<p>I have several clippings to send you when I hear from you again.</p>
</note>

<note type="curatorial">209-8</note>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">ROUTE 7 SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

<opener>
<dateline>June 16, '64</dateline>

<salute>Dear Lucile:</salute></opener>   <p>I'm deeply sorry to hear about our dear little dog friend, Perky. The news of her death brought back something of the old empty feeling that can hurt worse than pain. I had been looking forward to seeing her again.</p>
   
<p>Dr. Kendrick of Cornell visited me lately and I heard from him that Bower will be visiting professor at Cornell the coming year! No doubt this is a step up for Bower, and I congratulate him heartily, but I would not trade Eugene for Ithaca, altho' I liked the latter and have been happy there.</p>

<note type="authorial">I have great difficulty seeing what I write.</note>

<ab><milestone unit="section"/>
<date><hi rend="underline">June 26</hi></date></ab>

<p>Things have been rather upset here lately. Enid broke a leg. Christian College discontinued its horsemanship program (which, incidentally,

<note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0002"/>
<fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
<fw type="curatorial">11</fw>

was very successful, and ended with two fine shows.) Alice will hold forth at Skyrim, and the horses are being brought here. <hi rend="double underline">What horses</hi>! My! My!</p>

<p>Enid's leg is doing finely, and she is getting a good rest. She looks better (and more beautiful) <del><unclear>that</unclear></del>than she has looked for many years.</p>

<p>Your Poems article still perplexes me. The general tone seems tentative, <del>hesitant</del><add>hesitant,</add>, doubting; and at the end I wonder if you believe in the Cycle. Surely the article leaves a sense of doubt and suspicion. I must believe this is a matter of mistaken judgement, not of intention. Why did you <hi rend="underline">want</hi> to give renewed life to a spiteful attack of years and years ago, and introduce it into the minds of readers who, presumably, were hearing of the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi> for 

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0003"/>
<fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">ROUTE 7SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

the first time? I wish you had thought to add a brief sentence correcting the absurdly false statement. It is a matter of fact, not opinion.</p>

<p>There is so much of value in the Cycle for a critic to reveal, and is not that your job? Criticism is properly a search for value and a revelation thereof. If my work is so doubtful, why a book about me?</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">Please do tell me if you have the first volume of Chittenden</hi>. The Library has bound the other two volumes, and I need the first now. <hi rend="underline">Please</hi>, if you have it &#8212; </p> 

<p>I am happy to know that <hi rend="underline">The Song of Jed Smith</hi> has taken on new <del>meaning</del> meaning for you. It is a very important vehicle for the expression of my attitude towards my cosmos and life in general.</p>

<p>I feel that, sooner or later, you will have some such experience with the other <hi rend="underline">Songs</hi>. Especially I feel that <hi rend="underline">The Messiah</hi> has much more for you to experience. <del>In</del></p>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0004"/>
<fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>

<p>In considering <hi rend="underline">The Messiah</hi>, you should keep in mind the sentence from Fulop-Miller quoted on the title-page of the first edition. I profoundly believe in the <hi rend="underline">emergent meaning</hi> of the <hi rend="underline">Messiah</hi>; and I feel strongly that it has more <hi rend="underline">concentrated beauty</hi> than any of the others. This is not a matter of relative merit, but of difference. For only one example, read again, and carefully, as though you had never read it before, the first four or five pages of the poem. Then read again <del>the</del> the absurd attack you quote. (For that matter, open <del>at</del> the book of 600 pages anywhere at random and read!)</p>

<p>I've often told you that every re-reading of the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi> brings out more beauty and meaning. It is not really very surprising that this should be so. When I began writing it I had already lived more than most people, and I had been reading great literature since I was 12 years old, <add><note type="authorial"><hi rend="underline">not</hi> at random either</note></add>. I worked 

   <pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0005"/> 
<fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">ROUTE 7 SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

<del>on the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi></del>
<lb/>
on the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>, as you know, a whole generation, pouring into it the distilled essence of my experience (personal and vicarious) during the rich, growing, creative years. <hi rend="double underline">No one</hi> can get the <hi rend="double underline">result</hi> by a casual reading. It requires some <hi rend="underline">growing</hi>, as you say. This is not because <hi rend="double underline">I</hi> am so profound; but because of the way the work grew. It is a matter of concentrated <hi rend="triple underline">years</hi> against <del/> <hi rend="double underline">hours</hi>.</p>

<p>You know I believe in you, Lucile &#8212; and you are dear to this old man. You can and will do a fine job. <hi rend="underline">Your</hi> job is <hi rend="underline">simpler</hi> than you think now. It is a matter of <hi rend="underline">telling people about the work</hi>. There are so <del><unclear>very</unclear></del> many who will thank you, "late or soon".</p> 
<closer>
<salute>The same love</salute> &#8212; <signed>John</signed></closer> <note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0006"/>
<fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>

<postscript>
<p>In addressing honest-to-god people, you need have no thought of our modernistic critics who <del>support</del> favor the incredible stuff now called poetry. In their state of consciousness, all my values automatically cancel out to zero. But think of the effect the work has on <del/> audiences and on students!!! It is rather overwhelming.</p>

<closer>&#8212;<signed>J.</signed></closer>
</postscript>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0007"/>
<fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>

<fw type="letterhead">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">ROUTE 7SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</fw>

<postscript>
<opener><hi rend="caps">P. S.</hi></opener> <p>Have you attached any significance to the inclusion of <hi rend="underline">A Cycle</hi> among the "3000 best books from Homer to Hemingway" &#8212; 3000 books from 3000 years, 1050 <hi rend="caps">B. C</hi> to 1950 <hi rend="caps">A D.</hi>? The volume is entitled <hi rend="underline">The World's Best Books</hi>, and is edited by Don Asa Dickinson, Librarian of the University of Pennsylvania. The snap-judgement on this title would be negative; but it would be wrong. No person or committee has presumed to name "the world's best books".! Instead, the choice <hi rend="underline">results</hi> from a <hi rend="underline">consensus</hi> of expert, authoritative opinion <del>f<unclear/></del><add>from</add> <hi rend="underline">all sources over a period of at least 30 years</hi>. The books <note type="authorial">(over)</note>

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0008"/>
<fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
<fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>

thus chosen <del>may</del><add>can</add>not be "the best" in the (impossible) absolute sense; but the consensus over so long a period surely has meaning! No <hi rend="underline">one</hi> of the authorities even knows, necessarily, that his choices were considered. It's wholly impersonal. <hi rend="underline">All</hi> the accepted classics, ancient &amp; modern, are in the list. <hi rend="underline">Somebody</hi> &#8212; quite a few somebodies &#8212; held <del>no</del><add>no</add> such doubtful view of the Cycle as that I've been considering.</p>
   
<p>I'm eager to see you. <hi rend="underline">Please do</hi> see my point.</p> <closer>&#8212;<signed>John</signed></closer>
</postscript>

</div1>


<div1 type="envelope">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.43.10-18_0009"/>

<fw type="curatorial">18</fw>

<ab type="return">
<hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>  
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">SKYRIM FARM</hi>
<lb/>
<hi rend="caps">COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi>
</ab>

<note type="authorial">____
   <hi rend="underline">Air</hi></note>
<ab type="postmark"><unclear cert="high">CO</unclear>LUMBIA, MO. JUN30 <unclear>1</unclear>PM <unclear cert="high">19</unclear>64</ab>
<figure>
<figDesc>8 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
<p>8¢ U.S. AIR MAIL</p>
</figure>

<ab type="address">
<address>
<addrLine>Dr. Lucile Aly,</addrLine>
<addrLine>1138 22nd Ave., East,</addrLine>
<addrLine>Eugene,</addrLine>
<addrLine>Oregon.</addrLine>
</address>
</ab>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
