<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.24.27-32">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, May 21, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.24.27-32</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1959-05-21">May 21, 1959</date>
                    <extent>12 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>12 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>12 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Youngberg, Norma R.</term>
<term>Bennett, Mildred R.</term>
<term>Cather, Willa, 1873-1947</term>
<term>Vinsonhaler, Duncan M.</term>
<term>O' Leary, Mary</term>
<term>Streamer, Volney, 1850-1915</term>
<term>Sterling, George, 1869-1926</term>
<term>Ledoux, Louis V. (Louis Vernon), 1880-1948</term>
<term>Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935</term>
<term>Engle, Emma</term>
<term>Diana</term>
<term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
<term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
<term>Neihardt, Maxine Melton</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>San Jose (Calif.)</term>
<term>Red Cloud (Neb.)</term>
<term>Omaha (Neb.)</term>
<term>New York</term>
<term>Memphis (Tenn.)</term>
<term>Los Angeles (Calif.)</term>
<term>Santa Ana (Calif.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
<term>Man-Song</term>
<term>A Bundle of Myrrh</term>
<term>Vylin</term>
<term>Come Back</term>
<term>When I Am Dead</term>
<term>If This Be Sin</term>
<term>Let Down Your Hair</term>
<term>The Sound My Spirit Calls You</term>
                    <term>To the Earth-Goddess</term>
<term>Modern Photography</term>
<term>Du, du liegst mir im Herzen</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1959-05-21"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; validation</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0001a" />
                <note type="curatorial">49-6</note>
                
                
           <opener>     
                <dateline>Skyrim, 5-21-'59</dateline>
                
                
                
                <salute>Listen, Precious Lady!</salute></opener> <p><hi rend="underline">I have news</hi>!</p> 
                
                <p>Yesterday (Wed.) two ladies made a "pilgrimage" (they called it) to Skyrim and spent the day here. They are old fans and had planned the adventure for several years. One was Mrs. Youngberg, a teacher in the "Unified School System" of San Jose, Calif. The other was her sister, Mrs. Mildred Bennett of Red Cloud, Nebraska, who is in charge of the Willa Cather Memorial and the biographer (ultimately the definitive one) of Willa. In the course of our talk about you and your work, Mrs. Bennett said: "I know where there are some letters 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0001b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    Mrs. Aly will want &#8212; <hi rend="underline">the Vinsonhaler letters</hi>, a shoe-box full!!"</p>
                
                <p>The Judge gave them to Mrs. Mary O' Leary, The Matthews Book Store, 1620 Harney St., Omaha, Neb. Several years ago, Mrs. Bennett saw the letters and read a half dozen of them. She is sure Mary O'Leary (golly! what a love of a lyrical Irish name!) will be glad to give you access to the collection! <hi rend="underline">Wow</hi>! <hi rend="underline">These women</hi>! They are indeed "a great nation of people," as my hill-billy friend
                    <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0002a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                    
                    once remarked to me! I'm betting on them every time 100 to 1! (And, since Mona went so far away, according to me you are the first citizen of that "nation"!)</p>
                
                <p>This <del>is</del> Mrs. Bennett went further, and she is a sane, sensible person. I spoke of the Streamer, Sterling, Ledoux, <add>Robinson</add> letters, and she said she knows a man in New York who can and will find them <hi rend="underline">if they are</hi> still in existence. She knows him through her Willa Cather research. She has written him &#8212; or will write &#8212; putting
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0002b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                    
                    him on the scent.</p>
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">Good gosh golly</hi>! What fun if we find these precious letters! <hi rend="underline">and</hi> what fun to have Vinsonhaler's, <hi rend="underline">which cover the writing of the</hi> <hi rend="italic">Wars</hi>!</p>
                
                <p>Your letter, dated the 13th, arrived on the 18th. Where was it all that time, I wonder? Anyway, the blessed thing arrived, and what's a day or <del>to</del> two in the eternity of spirit?</p>
                
                <p>I'm very happy about your experience with the choral reading of the <hi rend="underline">Wars</hi>. I know it is corking, and I must hear it before I am tucked away with the
                    <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0003a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                    
                    "kings and councilors of the earth who made desolate places for themselves". (They hadn't ought to of done it, Lucile!) Do you suppose you can work up the choral presentation of the <hi rend="underline">Wars</hi> <del/>as a whole by next winter? If so, by golly I'll fly out, have a look at you, and experience the choral reading!</p>
                
                <p><del>About</del><add>As to</add> the notion I have expressed in both prose and verse about the likeness of the violin and woman. When did the notion come to me? you ask. It must have been in my teens. I was always strangely and deeply moved by violin music and
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    my feeling for the woman spirit was similar in kind and intensity. (I began <hi rend="underline">living</hi> very young, long before most boys begin). The <hi rend="underline">shape of the violin</hi> must have suggested the fusing of the two feelings very early in my teens. <hi rend="underline">The idea still thrills me</hi>. (There's a poem in Man-Song, isn't there? And the idea is found in the <hi rend="underline">Bundle of Myrrh</hi> as well as in the short story, <hi rend="underline">Vylin</hi>: "She is my violin") <hi rend="underline">O my god</hi>, I wasn't trying to make a noise
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0004b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    like poetry when I wrote that!<del/></p>
                
                <p>You ask me about Emma Engle and her relation to <hi rend="underline">A Bundle of Myrrh</hi>. Your <del/><add>idea</add> as expressed in yours of the 18th, is <hi rend="underline">essentially</hi> right. Several of the poems 
                    <hi rend="underline">were</hi> done with her specifically in mind &#8212; <hi rend="underline">Come Back</hi>, 
                    <hi rend="underline">I Shall Be Lightning</hi>, etc. Even in these, and one or two others, the situation indicated was, to some, extent, imagined. This gal never ran out on the Little Buffalo! (I came to wish she would!) But I loved her much for a couple of years and she <hi rend="underline">was</hi> beautiful in a cold
                    <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0003b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                    
                    Diana-like fashion. (I <hi rend="underline">called</hi> her Diana, <hi rend="underline">never</hi> Emma.) But even in the poems that referred definitely to her, the ghosts of other women entered. As you say, she was a <hi rend="underline">symbol of woman</hi>. I found that out in good time.</p>
               
                <p>There is so much to tell in this realm of my experience; but I feel like a cad in talking about any of it. Some of it was <hi rend="underline">so godawful beautiful</hi>!! I mention the matter only because you, dear lady, are my best friend in the world of my life work, and, anyway, I had
                    <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-31_0005a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-9-</fw>
                    
                    not yet found Mona and you were not yet born. You will know, from the foregoing, that "If This Be Sin" and "Let Down Your Hair" were <hi rend="underline">not</hi> written to <hi rend="underline">E. E.</hi>. It <hi rend="underline">is</hi> true that "I Would I Knew Some Slow Soft Sound" referred to her in the earlier years of enchantment. Incidentally, <hi rend="underline">E. E.</hi> was 4 years older than I.</p>
                
                <p>In <hi rend="underline">Man-Song</hi>, I <hi rend="underline">was</hi> finding Mona. Definitely in 
                    <hi rend="underline">Gaea</hi>.</p>
                
                <p>This last week the Journalism School held its annual Photographic Workshop &#8212; a national affair. Two photographers were assigned to get me. One was the editor of Modern Photography in New York. The other
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0005b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-10-</fw>
                    
                    was a fellow from the Uni of Ohio at Athens, O. The latter followed me three days and took more than 500 shots. From there, he told me, eight or ten will be selected to make a sequence intended to reveal the subject!</p>
                
                <p>It's a long, long way to the end of July! Your Greek books are with the binder, and will be ready before I leave on June 6th for Memphis. The binder discouraged my idea of repairing. So there'll be nice new bindings for you to handle!</p>
                
                <p>I have <hi rend="underline">not</hi> yet surprised you, Bower, and Stewart sitting ghostlily (!) in the backyard, but perhaps
                    <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0006a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">11</fw>
                    
                    <del>in</del> at the end of July the four <del/>of us may actually be there together for a little while. I hope so.</p> 
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">Is</hi> Bower feeling strong again? Tell me about his book.</p>
                
                <p>Sig and Max will locate near Los Angeles. He is feeling much better and is in a constructive state of mind. Max has a transfer from here to the same firm in <choice><sic>Santa Anna</sic><corr>Ana</corr></choice>, at a raise in salary! Sig can get a job easily in the aviation industry anywhere. Soon he will take a part-time job.</p>
               
                <p>I assure you with the utmost insincerity that I don't like you and I hope you don't like me too.</p>
                <closer>
                <signed>John N.</signed>
                </closer>
               
               <pb facs="nei.j4c.24.27-32_0006b"/>
                <postscript><opener>P. S.</opener>
                    
                <p>There are a good many letters around here that must go to you. I'll build up steam enough to collect and pack them one of these times.</p>
                
                    <p>The next line runs:<lb/>
                    
                    Du, du liegst mir im Sinn.
                    <lb/>
                    (Naturlich, im Herzen <hi rend="underline">auch</hi>)</p>
                
                <closer>
                <signed>J. N.</signed>
                </closer></postscript>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">32</fw>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
