<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.27.26-29">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, February 24, 1960</title>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2013</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4c.27.26-29</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
<date when="1960-02-24">February 24, 1960</date>
<extent>8 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>8 hand-written pages</p>
</msContents>
<physDesc>
<objectDesc>
<supportDesc>
<support></support>
<extent>8 pages
<dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
</extent>
<condition>
<p></p></condition>
</supportDesc>
</objectDesc>
<handDesc hands="1">
<handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
<handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
</handDesc>
<typeDesc>
<typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
</typeDesc>
</physDesc>
<history><origin></origin>
<provenance></provenance>
<acquisition></acquisition>
</history>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>House, Julius T. (Julius Temple)</term>
<term>Aly, Stewart</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term type="from"></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term>St. Louis Post-Dispatch</term>
<term>Kansas City Journal-Post</term>
<term>Minneapolis Journal</term>
<term>Goldenrod</term>
<term>John G. Neihardt, Man and Poet</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1960-02-24"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; assigned recipient</change>
<change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
<change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0001a" />
<note type="curatorial">101-4 Aly Collection</note>

<opener>
<dateline>
Route 5, Columbia, Mo.
2-24-'60
</dateline>

<salute>Dear Lady:</salute>
</opener>
<p>Every time I receive a letter from you, it's like a nice rain after a dry spell! Yours of the 17th was a sun shower &#8212; very good for this old man!</p>

<p>There are so many things to say, that I don't know what to say first. Your comments on individualism mean a great deal to me. Indeed, I was <hi rend="underline">not</hi> influenced by existentialism. On the contrary, I have regarded it as another manifestation of the anarchic spirit of our time. When I was elaborating my thesis on the mood of our <hi rend="underline">time</hi> and its cause, existentialism had not yet become widely <del/> known and discussed over here. But I think of it as a further proof of my contention as found in so many of my articles in the P-D

<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0001b"/>
<fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>

(and in the Journal-Post and even the Minn. Journal). In the P-D there must be several articles on the subject, as I remember; and you seem to have at least one in mind when you refer to the sort of person who thinks he is intensely individualistic &#8212; a non-conformist &#8212; when, in fact, he is <del/> <hi rend="underline">slavishly</hi> <hi rend="italic">conforming</hi> <hi rend="underline">to the dominant fashion among "sophiscates"</hi>. I recall an article on the sort of self-styled socialist who is anarchic in his thinking &#8212; while socialism connotes the exact opposite. This <hi rend="underline">is</hi> very common.</p> 
   
<p>What you say about "a follower of the crowd" <del>is the</del> indicates that you must know

<fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0002a"/>
<fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>

some of my articles bearing on this matter <add>(Was this in the Goldenrod?)</add> I have have always been, in fact and in expressed theory, an individualist. But I have always <hi rend="underline">been</hi> profoundly aware that the individual is important only as a component of social and cosmic pattern. In Dr. House's book this was stated, as you will remember. This is it: <hi rend="underline">I</hi> am nothing in myself; but as a part of a vast pattern, I can partake of the greatness of the pattern; and I am under what I may well regard as

<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0002b"/>
<fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>

divine compulsion to contribute as much to the pattern as it is possible for me, by effort and sacrifice, to contribute.</p> 
   
<p>O Lucile, <hi rend="underline">dear lady</hi>, I've done that, even tho' what I 
<hi rend="underline">was able</hi> to do <del/><add>may not</add> matter very much; but I know it matters far more than much that was done under a different compulsion.</p>

<p>I'm genuinely glad for the message from Old Man Stewart, whether he actually told you to send it, or not. I know he feels that way, and he knows I am deeply fond of him &#8212; if he ever thinks about the matter. He is going to be <hi rend="underline">such a <del>fine</del></hi>

<fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0003a"/>
<fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>

<hi rend="underline">fine man. I know he is</hi>. And I'd feel greatly flattered if sweet, precious little Perky should have even the vaguest dream-like memory of me. She probably hasn't, but I'll bet she'll be sweet to me when I come back.</p>

<p>Animals mean a very great deal to me (<hi rend="underline">Animals!</hi> How funny!) Somewhere someone has remarked that a profound love of animals indicates a nearness to the other world. I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> feel the thrill of truth in this. Last Sunday I went out to Skyrim to visit the darling horses. Four of them were obviously delighted to see me. They crowded against the paddock fence, thrusting their

<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0003b"/>
<fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>

noses <hi rend="underline">through</hi> the bars and striving to get all the petting, each for himself. They all wanted to be kissed; <hi rend="underline">and they got kissed on the soft place</hi> between the nostril and the mouth. It's a wonderful feeling. There's a touch of ecstacy in it!! The sweet things! Neither they nor I wanted anything in a selfish way. We just felt very close to each other.</p> 
   
<p>Lucile, <hi rend="underline">that is something very good; And very beautiful too</hi>

<fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0004a"/>
<fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>

Lucile, I'm constantly being surprised and delighted as I go about the campus and the town, at the way people treat me. So very many, whom I do not know, speak to me as though they felt affection. Why should this be? It frightens me, sometimes &#8212; for I fear I may outlive the feeling people have towards me; and I often wish I could <hi rend="italic">go</hi> <hi rend="underline"> before the mood changes</hi>.

<pb facs="nei.j4c.27.26-29_0004b"/>
<fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>

I do hope my heart will give out in time &#8212; before an anti-climax can begin!</p>  

<p>As for Perky, you just wait until she really gets big, and knows it! I'll bet she will take care of her precious family! I'd hate to be a <del/><add><unclear/></add> around there when she is in full charge!!</p>

<p>Old Yo-Yo has some gray <del/> hairs, but she is still very active in social affairs, and the she often tells me where to get off!</p>  
<closer>
<salute>Love to each of you &#8212; meaning Gramby too, of course.</salute>   <signed>John</signed>
</closer>

<fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
