<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.25.35-41">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, September 5, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.25.35-41</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1959-09-05">September 5, 1959</date>
                    <extent>12 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>12 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>12 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Gray, Sanford</term>
<term>Dale, Harrison Clifford, 1885-</term>
<term>Jones</term>
<term>Moffett</term>
<term>Kendrick, M. Slade (Myron Slade)</term>
<term>Stafford, William, 1914-1993</term><!-- ? -->
<term>Wagstaff, Blanche Shoemaker, 1888-</term>
<term>Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1878-1962</term>
<term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
<term>Petri, Gail</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Moscow (Idaho)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>Man-Song</term>
<term>The Splendid Wayfaring</term>
<term>The Ashley-Smith Explorations and the Discovery of a Central Route to the Pacific, 1822-1829</term>
<term>Who's Who</term>
<term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1959-09-05"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName>Eugene (Or.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; validation</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0001a" />
                <note type="curatorial">83-6 Aly Collection</note>
                
                
                <opener>
                <dateline>Skyrim, Sep. 5, '59</dateline>
                
                
                
                <salute>Dear Lucile:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>This is Saturday, 9:30 a.m. - 7:30 a. m. in Eugene. Within the next few hours you three should be taking over the beautiful new home; and as I think of it, I too feel happy and excited along with you.</p>
                    
                    <milestone unit="section"/>
                    <ab><date>Later, p. m.</date></ab>
                    
                    <p>You <hi rend="underline">were</hi> lucky in your book-hunting! <hi rend="underline">Man-Song</hi> and <hi rend="underline">Wayfaring</hi> are both a bit scarce. I hope your dealer was not aware of the scarcity. You say you <del>are</del><add>are</add> reading <hi rend="underline">Man-Song</hi> again. Last night I <del/> dreamed I was reading it, and I came across a corking passage I had not known in a
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0001b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                        
                        poem I had never heard of &#8212; but it was mine. For a moment after waking I almost knew the passage, but it evaporated. I can tell you <hi rend="underline">it was good poetry. It felt great!</hi> I wish I could find it again. (Incidentally, there must be some really good poetry down in there someplace, waiting to <del/> be found.)</p>
                   
                <p>Sandy Gray is here! He has re-entered the graduate school, and he says he has 30 hrs, on a Ph.D <hi rend="double underline">But</hi>, he is married and everything, and there is a baby on the way. They are living in a trailer which she owns.</p>
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">35</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0002a"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                        
                        <p>She has a teaching job at Hickman High. (Sandy has grown obese.) We are supposed to move ahead with recording. I hope it may be so.</p>
                 
                <p>So you were in Moscow! I wonder if my old friend, Harrison Clifford Dale (sometime president of the University &amp; author of the <hi rend="underline">Ashley-Smith Explorations</hi>, is still living. I wish I could have rejoined you for that Idaho trip.</p>
                
                <p>We begin school here a week from today, Sep. 15. (You see this is a serial letter, and already it's Tuesday). I was in my office several days ago and met young Dr. Jones
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0002b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                        
                        who follows Moffett and will be next to my desk. He is a lovable fellow, &amp; he was clearly happy to see me. Evidently someone had said something nice about me to him. We'll click, I know. But, Lucile, something good and dear has ended forever. For 10 1/2 years Moffett and I sat there side by side, speaking <hi rend="underline">when</hi> and <hi rend="underline">as we pleased</hi> about this, that, or anything. <hi rend="underline">We knew each other, &amp; there were no fences. That's</hi> <hi rend="double underline">through.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Blessed years</hi>!</p>
                
                <p>But why should anything last forever? Why should
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">36</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0003a"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                        
                        I be as fortunate as I've been and am? As I look back, I note so many <hi rend="underline">great changes</hi> in my life. Each one seemed saddening; and yet I would not return to the far side of any of those changes for anything. 
                        <hi rend="underline">The pattern is good</hi>. You'ns are 2000 miles away, but that makes you dearer, requiring more effort to see you. <add>(I can "zuzz" out to see you! Can't I?)</add></p>
                   
                <p>My friend, Dr. Slade Kendrick of Cornell University spent Sat. afternoon with me. He is a dear. His specialty is Finance with emphasis on taxation. He will testify before a 
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0003b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                        
                        Congressional committee again this month. Your dissertation was mentioned and he said, "I want that lady's address. She is going to get a letter from me, for I have something to tell her." So I suppose you'll hear. I hope he uses a typewriter. His handwriting is a bit trying! (How's mine?!)</p>
                
                <p>I don't know the poet Stafford, and he isn't in <hi rend="underline">Who's Who</hi>; but if he likes my stuff, he is a gentleman and a scholar. Just the same, <hi rend="underline">nice lady</hi>,
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    I'm glad you beat him to those books!</p>
                   
                <p>Yes, someday we will <del/> watch a horse-show together. Maybe my Creation's Queenie will be showing. If so, maybe you will help me yell when she comes by <hi rend="underline">floating high</hi> in that marvelous trot of hers! (She is a fine-harness pony, you know). Or maybe the two (or three or four ) of us will stand at the turn of the track as the five-gaited horses charge by &#8212;  big, beautiful, sleek
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_00004b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                        
                        creatures! And as they turn, we'll feel their fragrant, explosive breaths on our faces! It's a wonderful feeling! They are so gorgeously alive, so haughtily beautiful!</p>
                
                    <p>It's queer, Lucile. Old, half-forgotten pieces of patterns have been coming back the last two or three years &#8212; completing circles. A number of old acquaintances or friends have suddenly remembered me after many, many years, and written me. Recently there was Blanche Shoemaker Wagstaff, and now here comes William Stanley Braithewaite,
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">38</fw>
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_00005a"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-9-</fw>
                        
                        of all people! He begins by explaining who he is (!!) Says he was one of the first to praise Hugh Glass &amp; refers to his <del/><add>review</add> in "the old Boston Transcript." (As tho' I <hi rend="underline">could</hi> forget that wonderful article!!) He wants me to contribute a poem to an anthology on the Civil War! Of course, I cannot.</p>
                
                <p>Do you ever have time to go back over our trip in imagination? I do that, and it's a joy.</p>
                
                <p>I may have had an "experience" last
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_00005b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-10-</fw>
                        
                        Sunday. Hilda &amp; Gail were here an hour or so, and they did some woman-magic about the place. I was in the basement under the dirty clothes chute, &amp; they were directly above in the region of the bathroom and adjacent bedrooms. There was a mess of dirty clothes on the concrete floor instead of being in the basket. I reached down to gather them up, and there came a sound as of knuckles tapping a solid wooden surface &#8212; 1, 2, 3, 4. 5, 6. Then, after a brief interval the sounds were repeated.
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">39</fw>
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35_0006a"/> 
                        <fw type="authorial"><del/>-11-</fw>
                        
                        The sounds seemed <hi rend="underline">close</hi> to me &amp; were quite distinct. I rushed upstairs &amp; asked if Hilda or Gail had heard the sounds. They had not, and they said they had done nothing to make the sounds. Since I am the only witness, I don't make too much of the matter, <hi rend="underline">but</hi>, <hi rend="double underline">according</hi> <hi rend="underline">to me</hi> it was very clear &amp; I can't explain it.</p>
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0006b"/>
                        <fw type="authorial">-12-</fw>
                        
                        <p>It has been very hard to get this letter written, because I don't like you at all, and I don't like any of the Alys.(*) (<hi rend="underline">Or do I?)</hi> That trip we had together was a perfectly horrible experience, and I hope it may happen again as soon as possible.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Love to each of you Three.</salute>
                    <signed>John</signed>
                </closer>
                
                    <postscript><p>(*) I do <hi rend="underline">too</hi> like you! The very idea!! <hi rend="underline">Who</hi> said I didn't?!</p></postscript>
                    
                   <fw type="curatorial">40</fw> 
            </div1>
            
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.35-41_0007"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">41</fw>
                
                <ab type="return">    
                    John Neihardt
                    Route 7
                    <hi rend="underline">Columbia</hi>, Mo.
                </ab>
                <note type="authorial">_______
                                        Air<hi rend="underline">Mail</hi></note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">COLUMBIA, MO. SEP 9 230 PM 1959</ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢ IN GOD WE TRUST LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>4 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>UNITED.STATES.POSTAGE FOUR 4 CENTS</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                    <addrLine>Dr. Lucile Aly,</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>1158 <hi rend="underline">22nd Ave.</hi>, East,</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Eugene,</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Oregon.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>