<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4c.25.23-27">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly, August 23, 1959</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2015</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4c.25.23-27</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John G. Neihardt to Lucile Aly</title>
                    <date when="1959-08-23">August 23, 1959</date>
                    <extent>12 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>12 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>12 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Neihardt, Sigurd</term>
<term>Neihardt, Maxine Melton</term>
<term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
<term>Neihardt, Alice</term>
<term>Thompson, Lynn</term>
<term>Petri, Gail</term>
<term>Thompson, Erica</term>
<term>Petri, Coralie</term>
<term>Cook, W. B. "Dick"</term>
<term>Skilling, Edna</term>
<term>Wagstaff, Blanche Shoemaker, 1888-</term>
<term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
<term>Amama</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Aly, Martha</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>Phoenix (Ariz.)</term>
<term>Kansas City (Mo.)</term>
<term>Albuquerque (N.M.)</term>
<term>Memphis (Tenn.)</term>
<term>Salt Lake (Utah)</term>
<term>Forrest City (Ark.)</term>
<term>New York</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term>A Bundle of Myrrh</term>
<term>A Cycle of the West</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1959-08-23"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords; validation</change>
            <change when="2014"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0001a" />
                <note type="curatorial">59-6</note>
                
                
                
                
                <opener>
                <dateline>Skyrim, Aug. 23, '59</dateline>
                
                
                
                <salute>Precious Lady:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter just about saved this poor dog's life! I was feeling as though I had fallen out of a tall tree with no friends in sight, when I found it in in Skyrim mail box. Sig, good boy and trusted pal, had sent it on by air mail. And you ask me not to forget you'ns "now that we are no longer in the same car space." 
                    <hi rend="underline">Lady</hi>, is <hi rend="underline">that</hi> your idea of <hi rend="underline">being funny</hi>? The fact is, <hi rend="underline">I'd</hi> rather be back in that car with you'ns &#8212; <hi rend="underline">going anywhere</hi> &#8212; than be
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0001b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                    
                    anywhere else I know. I wish we could all take a trip to the moon. Yes, it's a wonderful world, Lucile, as you remark &#8212; wonderful "that we could meet and be friends". It's wonderfuller than I have tried, or shall try, to say. And so I <hi rend="underline">do</hi> love this somewhat cock-eyed, never-never-goodbye-forever world; It hurts, but it's sweet.</p>
                
                <p>Since I saw you I've done this and that with considerable <hi rend="underline">tempo</hi>. I <del><unclear>was</unclear></del>had a fine flight to Phoenix, stayed four days &amp; nights with Sig and old lady Max; then flew
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0002a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw>
                    
                    to K. C., stopping 30 minutes at Albuquerque, and on to Columbia by air. When I reached Hilda's place, she was preparing for a try next day (Friday morning) to Memphis &amp; Alice's diggings. I was weary, but I decided to go along. So there were 1000 more miles by car! Had a bully time at Lockwood Stables (Alice's joint).
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_002b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw>
                    
                    No one expected me, of course. Thought I was in Salt Lake. Well, when I got out of the car, Lynn, Gail, Erica, and Coralie <del>come</del> came galloping up horseback (Gail &amp; Coralie had been visiting a week). The four gals leaped off their horses &amp; ganged me! There were the two dogs also (Spot, the Dalmatian, and Lassie, the collie), and they had to have immediate attention, too. It was <hi rend="double underline">dear</hi>; my god! It was
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0003"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-5-</fw>
                    <note>8-23-59</note>
                    
                    worth what life costs, to be loved by those four sweet girls and the two happy dogs! (Just the same, Lucile, it <hi rend="double underline">is a never-never world</hi>.)</p>
                
                <p>Well, Alice is doing wonderfully well. She &amp; Cook sold a filly for $3500.00 and were sorry because, as a matter of fact, that filly will <del/> sell for $7500 in a year <hi rend="double underline">if</hi> she goes on improving.
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23.-27_0004a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-6-</fw>
                    
                    The filly is "Blondy" <del/> raised here on Skyrim, and trained for fine harness <hi rend="underline">only about 5 months</hi>. They have at least 3 horses in training that should make champions, and they will take my fine Hackney filly, <hi rend="underline">Creation's Queenie</hi>, for training this fall. We expect to make her a $10,000 mare.
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0004b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-7-</fw>
                    
                    She is <del/> half-sister to <hi rend="underline">most</hi> of the Hackney fine harness champions. I find I have 11 horses here at Skyrim, and I should sell some, keeping only stuff that could reach the top. There's no use in handling second-rate horses. They <hi rend="underline">must</hi> be at the top or it's a losing game. Alice &amp; Cook have now <del/> sold 
                    <hi rend="underline">two</hi> of the best horses in the Memphis area. They are <hi rend="underline">very</hi> effective trainers &amp; are gaining a reputation fast. Saturday night last (<del/>Aug 22nd) we went to a horse show at Forrest City, 
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0005"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-8-</fw>
                    
                    Arkansas (40 miles west of Memphis). Lynn gave a <hi rend="underline">solo</hi> demonstration of five-gaited riding, with the announcer explaining to the <hi rend="underline">big</hi> crowd what she was doing with her hands and knees, and praising her skill. <hi rend="underline">She was beautiful</hi>, in her dark habit with her long golden hair down the back <hi rend="underline">and</hi> she was mounted on a beautiful, a gorgeous <hi rend="underline">golden</hi> stallion who
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0006a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-9-</fw>
                    <note>8-23-59</note>
                    
                    is, quite obviously, in love with her &#8212; the big handsome mutt! (He shows good taste) She soloed about 15 minutes, and the crowd liked it.</p>
                
                <p>Rec'd a letter from Mrs. Skillings. It seems I can send her some electric table gadgets for the moment, and later, perhaps, you can tell me something else. (She would like some jade piece of mine, she says; but I haven't any.) What could I make?</p>
                
                <p>Here's a queer business! You may remember Blanche Shoemaker Wagstaff; you
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0006b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-10-</fw>
                    
                    may have seen a letter of hers, altho' I did not intend to keep any. Well, she was the principal pre-Mona girl of the <hi rend="underline">Bundle of Myrrh</hi> affair (in N. Y.) She was beautiful, wealthy, swank. Amama saw her several years later at the Poetry Society meeting, <hi rend="underline">and curled a lip</hi> when she spoke of the experience. (I'm sure you get the idea, knowing Amama!) Well, the old lady wrote me, remembering,<hi rend="underline">like a lady</hi> and
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0007a"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-11-</fw>
                    
                    quite casually, but <hi rend="underline">remembering</hi>. I'll send you the note. Sometime, if you want to hear, I may tell more. But what matters is the Pattern with Mona, the Cycle, and you in it.</p>
                
                <p>I'm glad you have a nice semi-camping set-up, and I would indeed enjoy sharing it with you'ns. Soon you'll be in your House of Happiness!!</p>
                
                <p>Bower seems to be too damned busy. I know that what he is doing must be
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4c.25.23-27_0007b"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">-12-</fw>
                    
                    important. But I'd like, someday, to see him idle awhile and happy doing nothing with gusto! We'd be good comrades if we could be together, with time to become comfortably acquainted and thoroughly aware of each other.</p>
                
                <p>I have a letter from (guess who or whom, as you prefer) &#8212; Martha Aly! She seems to have liked some of my remarks about recreation.</p>
                
                <p>Next time I'll tell you about my little dog, bless her faithful little heart.</p> 
                <closer>
                <salute>You are dear.</salute>
                <signed>John N.</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>    
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

