<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 18
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

Sept. 9, 1970

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt and the Youngs:
<p>Mrs. Young's letter came while I was in Europe. I spent three weeks touring the Alps and had a wonderful time. I got homoe the 9th of August, much too late for Dr. Neihardt Day at Bancroft. I know it was a great occasion and one that I would have enjoyed.</p>
<p>I am glad Dr. Aly has finished her book. When will it come out? Will the U. of N. Press publish it? I just received for sale copies of THE SPLENDID WAYFARING. I am so glad to see it in paperback.</p>
<p>It is too bad Dr. Neihardt fell on the stairs. I hope he is fully recovered now.</p>
<p>When I go home I had a letter from some woman who wanted to know if Dr. Neihardt and Willa Cather ever knew each other. Esther Montgomery was here and I gave her the letter to answer. It seemed to me that the two of you: Dr. Neihardt and Willa Cather got your honorary degrees from the U. of Nebr. the same year. I couldn't find any proof of it. Esther said she would call you and set it straight.</p>
<p>After I got home from Europe, I had a house guest for a week, then Dr. Bennett took off two weeks and we went to Wyoming and to Omaha where our son is interning at the U. there. His wife teaches special education across in Iowa. They are very busy and we saw little of them while we were there.</p>
<p>Then when I came home, there were mountains of tomatoes to can and some peaches. I am just now catching my breath and catching up on my correspondence.</p>
<p>The Woods people will be here the 19th to see how we've spent the money they gave us. We are hoping they'll be happy over what we have done. We have had a lot of tourists this summer, but I have been out of touch so much of the time that I don't kow what VIP's may have been here while I was gone.</p>
<p>Now that fall weather is here, I hope you are all feeling fine and able to work. Hope the biography comes out soon and that the autobiography is not far behind.</p>
<p>We remember your visits here with great pleasure and hope you can come again. Greetings to all and to Jacquot.</p>
Affectionately,
<signed>Mildred</signed>
Mildred
Page 19
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

-9-11-70
Ansd.
<underline><unclear>Set</unclear> 22nd</underline>
Ink Stamp: RED CLOUD, NE SEP 9 PM 1970 68970
Stamp: UNITED STATES 6c
Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505