<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 19
<underline>Ans</underline>
10/17/68
EASTERN KENTUCKY UNIVERSITY
Richmond, Kentucky 40475
OFFICE OF ACADEMIC AFFAIRS
<italics>Division of Instructional Service</italics>
September 30, 1968

Dr. John G. Neihardt
R. D. #7
University of Missouri
Columbia, Missouri 65201

Dear Dr. Neihardt:

<p>Eastern Kentucky University, in an attempt to acquaint its teaching staff with advantages and limitations of closed-circuit television, is offering this fall an Instructional Television course designed for the faculty. In order to show what other institutions are accomplishing, we should like to show representative samples of college level courses to this class. Mr. Don R. Mitchell, Associate Director of Instructional Television at the University of Missouri has informed us that it would be necessary for us to obtain your permission in order that we view the materials we requested from him. If you will please grant us your approval so that he may ship the tape to us, we should appreciate your cooperation. The tape we are interested in seeing is the lesson fo:
English 279 Epic America
Thank you for your consideration of this matter.</p>
Cordially,
<signed>James S. Harris</signed>
James S. Harris
Director

JSH/klm
Note to Nereze -M.M.Y
1. Write Don. R. Mitchell, Associate Director of Instructional Television at <unclear>Uni of MO</unclear>
2. Inform them of Twilight of the Sioux

Page 20
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
October 17, 1968

Dr. James S. Harris, Director
Office of Academic Affairs
Eastern Kentucky University
Richmond, Kentucky 40475

Dear Dr. Harris:

<p>I have your letter of September 30, 1968 and in accordance with your request I have written Mr. Don R. Mitchell, Associate Director of Instructional Television at the University of Missouri, giving the permission to loan the tapes for my course "Epic America" (English 279).</p>
<p>I gave "Epic America" for a number of years at the University and' then substituted another course entitled "The Twilight of the Sioux." Do you know about this course? k It, too, has been very popular at Missouri. </p>
<p>You xxxx will know that I am very glad you are interested in this matter.</p>
With all kind thoughts,
