<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 33
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

Nov. 19, 1968

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt:

<p>How wonderful it was to get your letter. I enjoyed Saturday night so much. I loved hearing you read your poetry again and marveled that you could do so much from memory. Then I thought the play was very fine. It is a timely play, showing so much about human nature. I wouldn't have missed it for anything.</p>
<p>I heard you on television yesterday in the interview with Ron Hull. I wished Ron had just let you talk and not tried to ask questions. You could have filled half and hour easily without interruption. I enjoyed the program, however, and especially the poem with which they started and the poem with which they ended the program.</p>
<p>Helen Obitz and I came home soon after the program. We stopped and talked to Stan and Alicia Smith for a few minutes. They seem to be enjoying their school work. I hope you had a chance to talk with/them. There were so many people crowding around you that you had little time for yourself.</p>
<p>Yes, everyone was happy at the program. I admired Jacquot's attention. I was hoping he'd bark at the mean woman again, but he was a perfect gentleman.</p>
<p>We are all waiting eagerly for the completion of your book. It is going to be a triumph and it will be wonderful for everyone. I don't see why you couldn't use the title "The Story  of My Heart." No one will remember a title used that long ago, and I don't believe a title can be copyrighted can it?</p>
<p>What thrilling news about Right-As-Rain. He was a champion for sure. Are you sorry you sold him? He has certainly found his place.</p>
<p>And it's good news about the movies wanting Hugh Glass. I hope they get to work on it right away. It would make a wonderful movie.</p>
<p>My sister, Norma, whom you met, has just finished helping our brother-in-law write the story of Norma's life with her husband in the jungle of the orient. It was an emotional task for her, and I'm sure she would understand what you say about crying on the inside when you write. She was so involved that she got sick when she had finished the book. She is better now.</p>
<p>I am getting along with my book about the deaf boy. I will have to interview him again before I can do much more. I am hoping it will be an inspiration to other handicapped people.</p>
<p>It was wonderful to see you and the Youngs again. Take care of yourself.</p>
Love from the whole household.
<signed>Mildred</signed>
Page 34
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

Ansd-J.G.N.
by hand-
11-20-'68
Dr. John G. Neihardt
c/o J. D. Young
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505
Stamp: U.S. POSTAGE 6 cents FRANKLIN D. ROOSEVELT
Ink Stamp: RED CLOUD, NB NOV 19 PM 1968 68970