<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
March 3rd-68
68
<underline>16</underline>
2
<unclear>Aly</unclear> Ansd
Page 5
March 3, 1968
Dear John,
<p>Many thanks for the letters- two of them. Please give my best regards to the Youngs - I remember their lovely house and all their graciousness, and I'm glad you can be there.</p>
<p>Would your friend with the plane consider flying all the way to Oregon? It would be wonderful if we could go over the revised chapters before they are typed, and I <underline>think</underline> I will be ready to do it sometime in April. I'm getting along with the last section, which I want to send you in <unclear/> when it's finished. Like the other parts it builds to a climax about your work and you lose the effect if you read it partway. I'm also about to</p>
<p>write Mr. Michall that I hope to have complete manuscript sometime in May. That may <uncelar/> having it typed here, which would disappoint me because I've always wanted Enid to do it - but if <underline>you</underline> were here it might be wise to have you see the final pages too. So what you think. I wish you and Enid could both come out!</p>
<p>John, are you by any chance going to be in Omaha? I have a problem I'm having trouble with - I took notes on the material in the Omaha Public Library files - they're clippings mounted on heavy card paper, but I don't like to do final checking against notes. I have written the library to ask about having the files <unclear>Xeroxed</unclear>, and they just don't answer. If you should be over there for any reason and can find out anything I would be most grateful. I <unclear/> them I would pay all the costs.</p>
<p>My father is a little better some days, but not really. It is agonizing to watch him endure so patiently. He wants to come home and if we could manage the care we would try to persuade the doctors - but he needs trained people around the clock. We see him as often as we can, and feel thankful for the days he is not confused and unhappy.</p>
<p>Do you think you might get out here the last part of April? I'll have the final section out to you before that of course, but probably not the <unclear/> lyrics section or the epic parts. I am redoing the whole analysis of the lyrics - I know more now.</p>
<p>Bower and Jingle send love too. Jingle says come on out to Oregon - the beer is fine! And will celebrate the mailing of the whole manuscript!!!</p>
Love,
Lucile