<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 20 
THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA
IOWA CITY, IOWA 52240
FOUNDED 1847

Department of English
Sept. 22, 1970

Dr. John G. Neihardt
c/o Julius Young
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebraska

Dear Gaki:
<p>It is three weeks since my visit with you and Enid and Hilda in Columbia, and I am sorry not to have written sooner. But I wanted to read a little and ask some people up here about a few things; and I've also been taken up by Fall Registration and the beginning of classes.</p>
<p>Our conversations started me thinking about many things. I think one of the greatest reasons why BLACK ELK SPEAKS is so far superior to xother Indian life histories is that as a writer you wanted <underline>to learn from</underline> Black Elk, instead of just learning <underline>about</underline> him like the anthroplogiats. And I think my examination of Enid's transcripts can support this.</p>
<p>But I would really have to study the transcripts in much greater detail to say that, if you want me to say it. On the matter of differences and similarities between the transcripts and the book, well, this is really not my primary concern. I am interested in autobiographies, visions, and the social meaning of utopian visions; and I think your love of and achievements in the epic is of that kind. Nor, at present, am I really very informed about the stylistic differences between the transcripts and BLACK ELK SPEAKS. They seem to me so close and the improvements so sensitive and subtle--that is, in stretches of narrative where they are close enough to be compared--that it would take much more time than I had in Columbia to come to any detailed conclusions. You understood xxxx Black Elk, I think, because you loved him and wanted to learn from him, as he wanted to teach you, and you turned those loose and informal conversations into beautiful art, from which other people can learn too, because you were, unlike him, a literary artist. He, like Socrates, was a great teacher and oral artist. You, like Plato, were the perfect student and great literary artist.</p>
<p>You will be interested that a number of my students and friends here have asked many questions about my visit to Columbia. (Some had seen the short article on you in <underline>Telenews</underline>, the flyer from the Northwest Bell Telephone Co!) And I have spoken to Merle Brown, the editor of our new <underline>Iowa Review</underline>, and he would very, very much like to consider publishing a portion of the transcripts of the conversations. The portion I suggested was the narrative of the vision, which is, as you say, "the heart of the book," and which would make a piece of about the right length. The review pays $15 per printed page, and I figure this would come to between $200 and $300. But more than that, it would</p>
2
Page 21
-2-
<p>contribute a little to your academicxxxx critical reputation. And this might balance your popularity among the hippies with popularity among the professors! Finally, it would contribute to BLACK ELK SPEAKS' use as a textbook and so to greater information about Indians and Indian literature, the greater appreciation of your other work, and recognition of your specific achievements here. (The <underline>Review</underline>, on the other hand, would naturally, as a distinguished but young publication, like to grow by your reputationx! I'll have a copy sent to you.)</p>
<p>I can't say more about the differences between the transcript and the book versions of the vision because I did not note them closely when I was in Columbia. The only differences in content that I noted was very small. (On page 32 in the book the horses charge a blue man, a symbol for drought, and fail. Then Black Elk, "Eagle Wing Streches," charges the blue man with his spear, and the blue man becomes "a harmless turtle," and the drought ends. In the transcript, however, (p 9) this blue man is a red man, which seems more appropriate to a drought in some ways but might also be wrong because this is different from the red man who appears in other places in the vision.) So your fidelity to Black Elk will not, I think, be questioned. The transcript version is also stylistically much less readable. It isn't as pleasing. What makes it interesting, however, are the occasional interpretations which Black Elk was able to give you conversationally. For example, it is noted that <underline>eyapi kaga</underline> in Sioux means "word maker or lyric poet" and <underline>han balogala ga</underline> "chanter of words or epic poet." The Rainbow tepce is called a cloud house. The <underline>powers</underline> of the Red Road and Black Road come from the directions <underline>alongside</underline> their actual course, rather than the directions they go between, which I think is interesting.  In another place Black Elk says that people wore helmets of the buffalo head because the buffalo head meant endurance. And I think this kind of information will increase people's understanding. Indeed, this is why, for my own information, I would like to ask if I might have the whole transcript Xeroxed for my own use in teaching the book.</p>
<p>Can I then, make this request of you? 1) Authorization to Nancy Prewitt of the Western Historical Ms. Collection for Xeroxing of the transcripts of the Black Elk conversations. 2) Permission to show the transcripts of the vision to Merle Brown of the <underline>Iowa Review</underline> for possible publication. And 3) Permission to publish, you to receive $15 per page.</p>
<p>With publicationx we could arrange either an interview with you or a short appreciation of BLACK ELK SPEAKS. The kinds of things I think might be interesting are the things you were telling me about in Columbia--that the editors in 1931-32 wanted to leave out the vision or make it an appendix, Ben Black Elk's remark that he didn't know the old man knew so much, the book's discovery by Carl Jung, and its various translations and popularity abroad. All of this, and some of the other things I have said, woudl "set the record straight," as you say. And I think this is very important, to yourself, to scholarship, and the truth.</p>
<p>I am sorry to have been so long in writing, but I hope you like what I propose, and I look forward to hearing from you.</p>
Page 22
-3-
<p>I am also sorry that this has become such a long letter. I think of your eyes. My next letters will, I promise, be briefer. But perhaps you can get some help in reading it from Mrs. Young. I would like bery much to meet her.</p>
Very sincerely,
<signed>Robert f. Sayre</signed>
Robert F. Sayre
Assoc. Professor
English Dept.

RFS/ss