<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.17.2-3_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt, February 24, 1936</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.17.2-3_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1936-02-24">February 24, 1936</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.17.2-3_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">2</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">CHARLES KELLY</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    473 First Avenue
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">SALT LAKE CITY . UTAH</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Feb. 24, 1936</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was glad to hear that you are still planning that trip across the desert. It appeals to me as something that ought to be done, as not one has ever made the crossing on horses since pioneer days.</p>
                
                <p>I have done some planning, in case we do go. At first I thought we would start from Skull Valley in the afternoon, and keep going until we reached Pilot Peak or else. But after thinking it over I believe it would be better to cover the entire trail in daylight, in order not to miss anything of interest. It would take longer, but could be done in more comfort without sacrificing anything but fatigue, of which there will be sufficient anyway.</p>
                
                <p>Inclosed<sic>Enclosed</sic> is a rough map of the route, with mileages indicated. From the springs in Skull Valley to Cedar mountain (Hastings Pass) is about 18 miles. A mile or two west of the pass we cross the highway. We then travel over a ridge and a wide flat covered with "shadscale." We then strike the sand dunes, which will be hard on the horses. From the pass to the edge of the mud flats is about 15 miles. A prospector's auto trail, which can be negotiated in the summer, runs north from Knolls, a service station, and intersects the old trail in about five miles. A truck could be taken in there with water and horse feed to make a cache for us in the dunes near the mud flats. We could make the first night stop there, sleeping on the sand, which would be drier and more comfortable than the mud, which is damp and cold. Next morning we could make the big dash across the mud flats, 35 miles or more to Silver Island.</p>
                
                <p>Another prospector's trail runs along each side of Silver Island, and water could be trucked in <del><unclear>the</unclear></del> 20 miles from Wendover. We could spend late afternoon and part of the next day on the island if we cared to, leaving only about 12 miles to Pilot Peak across more salt flats. Or we could make it to Pilot Peak in one jump from the first cache, if we had to, although it would be a hard ride, finishing after d<del><unclear>d</unclear></del><add>a</add>rk. By making it a three day trip we would get more rest and have more time to examine different points along the trail.</p>
                
                <p>Dan Orr has a new truck and would probably be available for making the caches. The first one would not be difficult, but the second would be an all day trip to Wendover, as the trail is very rough. It would require two full days of his time to make the caches and another day to get back home, besides the same length of time to gather up his barrels, unless it would be cheaper to leave them.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.17.2-3-0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">3</fw>
                
                <p>I see no reason why you should not make at least part of your expen<unclear>se</unclear>s by writing up the story. It ought to make a good yarn, w<unclear>ith</unclear> photographs of the desert and a synopsis of its history. In fact I believe you could sell it to a syndicate and make more than you would by having it appear in only your own paper, unless they want to make it an exclusive feature. It is a country which has never been in the news, and the journey will be unique in several respects.</p> 
                
                <p>The best time to go, of course, would be in May. But I am usually very busy at that time of year and can't get away. In August the days would be hotter, but the nights would also be more comfortable and require less bedding. By making a cache of water and horse feed at two places, danger of ruining the animals would be largely eliminated; it would also make it easier to obtain horses. I think Orr can get the horses for us.</p>
                
                <p>As soon as you have definitely decided to go, let me know about when you will be here, and I will see Dan Orr and make arrangements. During his haying season he won't be able to leave, but I will find out when he will be at liberty.</p>
                
                <p>The local papers will probably want a story on the trip, but won't pay for it, unless you are a better salesman than I am. If you should write or contact them, don't mention my name, as they wouldn't print anything with which I was connected if they knew it.</p> 
                
                <p>Heard a radio review Sunday of Mrs. Altrocchi's "Snow Covered Wagons," the Donner party story in verse. Haven't read it yet. Dr. Stewart, also of Berkeley, will be out right soon with a history of the Donner party. All this will stir up interest in our trip. The California papers might be good prospects for your story, especially Sacramento and San Francisco. I don't know much about the newspaper syndicate business, but it seems to me at least four or five papers could be interested. Or perhaps a magazine article would pay better. I'd like to see you make expenses anyway. It would be the 90th anniversary of the Donner party.</p> 
                
                <p>Let me know your ideas on the above plan. A three-day trip would be safest, unless you would rather duplicate exactly the pioneer crossing (with a quart of water for eleven men)!</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Charles Kelly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

