<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 5a
FAIRBURY UNITED METHODIST CHURCH
6th and E Streets Box 423 Fairbury, Nebraska 68352
<italics>Nebraska Conference</italics>
MINISTER
A. O. Ernest
608 G Street
Fairbury, Nebraska 68352
Home Telephone 729-2511
<italics>Geneva District</italics>
ASSOCIATE MINISTER
D. G. Williams
806 4th Street
Fairbury, Nebraska 68352
Home Telephone 729-6295
Church Office Telephone 729-2247
JULY 22, 1968
DEAR BROTHER-FRIEND:
WE WERE PLEASED TO RECIEVE YOUR FINE LETTER THIS MORNING. WE ARE SORRY THAT YOU ARE NOT GOING TO BE ABLE TO GO WITH US TO HILDA'S LAKE HOME--WE ARE ALWAYS HAPPY FOR YOUR PRESENCE AND WE FEEL LIKE BETTER PEOPLE WHEN WE ARE IN YOUR COMPANY. I DO THINK WE WILL ACCEPT HILDA'S INVITATION AND GO ANYWAY, AS WE ARE ALL IN NEED OF SOME QUIET TIME AND DEEP SLEEP AFTER THESE HECTIC FIRST DAYS IN A NEW CHARGE. 
I HAVE ATTACHED A CARD TO THIS LETTER WHICH GIVES YOU THE NAME OF THE MOTEL WHERE YOU WILL BE STAYING. AS THE MAN WHO OWNES IT IS A FRIEND OF MINE, HE GAVE THE "LUXURY SUITE" FOR YOU AND THE YOUNGS TO STAY <crossed>HERE</crossed> IN WHILE YOU ARE HERE. IT HAS A KING SIZE BED AND TWO SINGLE BEDS. THEREFORE, IF GAIL IS IN LINCOLN, THERE WILL BE ROOM FOR HER. A DIVIDER CAN BE PULLED, IF DESIRED, TO SEPERATE THE SLEEPING AND DRESSING QUARTERS. ITS A REAL WILD AND BEAUTIFUL SUITE. IT HAS AN ELECTRIC FIRE-PLACE, COLOR CABLE-TV, LARGE BATH, DRESSING AREA, BEAUTIFUL FIXTURES, RED VELVET WALLS AND RED CARPETING AND YOU PEOPLE WILL BE THE FIRST ONES TO STAY IN IT. PLEASE NOTE THAT WHEN YOU COME TO US, WE LAY DOWN THE RED CARPET. THE MANAGER IS EXPECTING YOU AND WILL BILL THE CHURCH FOR IT--I HAVE INSTRUCTED HIM THAT UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES IS HE TO ACCEPT MONEY FORM ANY OF YOU.
EXCITEMENT IS RUNNING HIGH ABOUT HAVING YOU HERE, AND I AM SENDING A CLIPPING FORM THE FRONT PAGE OF OUR LOCAL PAPER. THEY WILL RUN ANOTHER ARTICLE ABOUT YOU LATER THIS WEEK. WHILE THE CLIPPING MAY NOT BE 100% ACCURATE, I THOUGHT IT WAS A GOOD "WRITE*UP." I EXPECT A NICE CROWD. WE WANT YOU TO SPEAK ON BLACK ELK AND THE SIOUX RELIGION JUST AS YOU HAVE IN MY OTHER TWO CHURCHES. I'LL HAVE THE "HOOP OF THE WORLD" IN PLACE, AND WE HAVE A P.A. SYSTEM WITH A CORD AND SPEAKER THAT GOES AROUND YOUR NECK. 
I'LL PLAN ON PICKING YOU ALL UP AT 8:OO FOR BREAKFAST SUNDAY MORNING. LET US KNOW WHAT TIME YOU WILL BE HERE ON SATURDAY NIGHT, AS WE WOULD LIKE TO VISIT WITH YOU IN OUR HOME FOR A SPELL. YOU CAN CALL US WHEN YOU ARRIVE AT THE HOTEL. OUR HOME NUMBER IS 729-2511 AND THERE WILL BE A PHONE IN YOUR ROOM. I HAVE ALSO ARRANGED FOR THE MOTEL TO HOLD YOUR SUITE FOR YOU TO TAKE A NAP AFTER THE DINNER. SINCE THEY DO NOT FILL UP THE MOTEL ON SUNDAY NIGHTS, THEY SAID YOU COULD USE THE ROOM ALL SUNDAY AFTERNOON AND THEY WOULD JUST HAVE THE MAID CLEAN ON MONDAY INSTEAD OF SUNDAY--NO EXTRA CHARGE.
OUR SERVICES HERE ARE BORADCAST OVER THE RADIO ON THE FIRST SUNDAY OF EVERY MONTH--HOWEVER, I'V ASK THE RADIO STATION TO "TAPE" YOU AND THEY WILL PLAY YOU INSTEAD OF ME ON THE FOLLOWING SUNDAY. THERE WILL BE NO TAPE RECORDER IN YOUR WAY, AS THEY TAP INTO OUR MIKES AND PIPE IT TO THE MAIN STATION VIA TELEPHONE LINE.
GLAD TO HEAR THAT YOUA RE COMING ALONG SO WELL ON YOUR BOOK...AND MOST IMPORTANT...THAT YOU FEEL LIKE DOING IT. I KNOW IT IS A REAL JOY FOR YOU TO BE SECRETING THE CREATIVE JUICES AGAIN.
GAKI, THE OFFER TO TAKE YOU ANY PLACE, ANY TIME STILL STANDS, IF YOU EVER NEED A BREATHER AND WANT TO GO HOME FOR A FEW DAYS OF ANYWHERE ELSE, JUST LET ME KNOW.
WE LOOK FORWARD TO SEEING YOU SATURDAY,
WITH KIND AFFECTION, AND ALL WARM THOUGHTS.
Art Ernst