<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 6
LINCOLN PUBLIC SCHOOLS
JOHN PRASCH, SUPERINTEDENT
LINCOLN SOUTHEAST HIGH SCHOOL
BOARD OF EDUCATION OF LINCOLN NEBRASKA. COMMON SCHOOLS THE HOPE OF OUR COUNTRY.

Dr. Wesley V. Lauterbach, Principal
Mr. Rex Mercer, Vice Principal
Mr. Donald G. Darnell, Asst. Principal
Student Affairs
Mr. David Myers, Asst. Principal 
Instruction
PHONE-402-488-2349
Mailing Address:
2930 South 37th Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68506

January 20, 1971

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>The Lincoln Southest Faculty and Student Council are very pleased that you will speak at the Honors Convocation on Tuesday, February 23, 1971.</p>
<p>During the second semester of each school year, we have an assembly to recognize those students who, by their superior scholastic performance have earned a place on the Honor Roll. Also, at this time we award membership in National Honor Society to those seniors who qualify in the areas of scholarship, leadership, character, and service.</p>
<p>Immediately after the Honors Assembly, we have arranged to have an assembly for the English classes. At that time, and if you feel up to it, we would appreciate it if you would speak to these students.</p>
<p>Prior to the Honors Convocation, a coffee hour will be held in the cafeteria for parents and faculty, from 8:00 to 8:45 a.m. If possible, we would like to have you attend the coffee.</p>

Accredited by North Central Association and Nebraska State Department of Education

Page 7
Dr. Neihardt
Page 2
January 20, 1971

<p>Upon your arrival, you will be greeted by Michael Shuptar, a member of the Lincoln Southeast Student Council.
<underline>HONORS CONVOCATION SCHEDULE</underline>
Place: Lincoln Southeast High School Auditorium
Date: Tuesday, February 23, 1971
Coffee Hour: 8:00 to 8:45 a. m.
Convocation: 8:00 to 10:00 a. m.
Dr. Neihardt: Will speak from 9:00 to 9:15
<underline>SPECIAL ASSEMBLY FEATURING DR. NEIHARDT</underline>
Place: Lincoln Southeast High School Auditorium
Date: Tuesday, February 23, 1971
Dr. Neihardt: Will speak to English classes from 10:00 to 10:30 a. m.</p>
Sincerely,
<signed>Donald G. Darnell</signed>
Donald G. Darnell
Assistant Principal
Student Services

mvh