<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.29a.18-19">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Frank M. Rarig to John G. Neihardt, April 6, 1961</title>
<author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.29a.18-19</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Rarig, Frank M. (Frank Miller), 1908-</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Frank M. Rarig to John G. Neihardt</title>
<date when="1961-04-06">April 6, 1961</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>2 typed pages</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Atherton, Lewis Eldon</term>
<term>Smith, Joseph F.</term>
<term>Glass, Hugh, approximately 1780-approximately 1833</term>
<term>Empédocles</term>
<term>Homer</term>
<term>Reid, Loren Dudley, 1905-</term>
<term>Aly, Bower, 1903-1977</term>
<term>Neihardt, Mona Martinsen</term>
<term>Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term type="Neihardt">The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
<term>Odyssey</term>
<term>Iliad</term>
<term type="Neihardt">A Cycle of the West</term>
<term type="Neihardt">When the Tree Flowered</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Rarig, Frank M. (Frank Miller), 1908-</persName>
<placeName>Minneapolis (Minn.)</placeName>
<date when="1961-04-06"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> transcription and encoding</change>
<change when="2017"><name>SDSU</name> transcription</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">Aly Collection</note>
<note type="curatorial">19</note>

<fw>Frank M. Rarig<lb/>
111 Orlin Avenue S. E.<lb/>
Minneapolis 14, Minn.</fw>

<opener>
<dateline>April 6, 1961</dateline>

<address>
<addrLine>Dr. John Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Missouri</addrLine>
<addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
</address>

<salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>It was gratifying to read Professor Atherton's letter to "Friends and admirers of Dr. John G. Neihardt," in which he said that the University of Missouri is to make one day notable by setting it aside in your honor. I have been an admirer of yours ever since the summer of 1924 when Joseph F. Smith, at the University of Wisconsin recommended that I read "The Song of Hugh Glass." I read it then and many times since, and each time I have been moved to the depths by your delineation of the character of its hero whose action is motivated by the primitive instinct to survive and who is driven by the "lust of vengeance," and yet who, when he finds Jamie, blinded by the bursting of his own gun and hears Jamie's story of his remorse, and haunted as he has been by the "Black Robe," finds his lust of vengeance drowned in a flood of pity. Besides the Christian motive working in Hugh, I seem to find in Hugh's telling of his tale, and its effect on his hearers, another motive, when

<quote><lg><l>At Kiowa, Songlike his voice arose,</l>
<l>The grinning gray mask lifted and the eyes</l>
<l>Burned as a bard's who sees and prophesies,</l>
<l>. . .</l></lg></quote>

he makes of the story of his betrayal a bond with fellow men. Unlike Empedocles, who in the bitterness of his resentment against his fellow human beings, leaped to a fiery death, Hugh gave his emotions a form, a poetic expression which was for him a survival of his human kinship.</p>

<p>It is a grand epic. As in Homer's Illiad and Odyssey the setting is the earth and sky. In summer heat and winter frost. Unlike Homer's heroes your white men and Indians are actors in an historic struggle which seems fated to happen, too vast to have been foreseen or forestalled. No gods or goddesses animate your heroes; they act of their parts in all your Songs from such a wide range of motives that they become protosype of universal man. Seen through the eyes of a seer, and presented by a creative poet, a poet whose understanding precludes conventional judgments, they profoundly stir in the roots of our being a sense of tragic fulfillment.</p>

<p>A Cycle of the West would have been enough to fix in this history of the Great Plains the fame of any poet, but to top it off you have


<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">19</note>

given us the mellow philosophy and rich humanity of Eagle Voice, whose glinting humor animates and enlivens the pages of When The Tree Flowered.  At random, I open the book at page 133 and read the prayer of Blue Spotted Horse, in words that "...went with eagle wings, ...to the power that makes live and destroys. To the place where the Great White Giant lives he turned and prayed to the Power that cleanses and heals.  To the place whence come the morning star and the day, he prayed to the Power that gives light and understanding and peace.... At last he leaned low and prayed to Maka, the mother of all that live."</p>

<p>These two books are cherished treasures.</p>

<p>We have many reasons to be greatful to Bower Aly and Loren Reid for inviting me to teach at the University of Missouri.  It became a wonderful reprieve from final and complete retirement.  Besides my being occupied with interesting students, we made many friends among whom it was our happy lot to count you and Mrs. Neihardt.  We often recall the Sunday afternoon we spent with you and her.  We were grieved at the news of her passing away, and although we remained silent, our hearts yearned for you. We are glad to have seen the bust she made of you, and to admire its strength and truth. I still recall with deep appreciation your reading of your poems, the rich variety of sound values and liveliness of movement which made us listeners participants in your poetic faith.  One poet who could read his own poems!</p>

<p>I used to be amazed --and stumped--by remarks you made to me when we were judging students' readings, your generous 'giving out' to the effect that I really knew something you learned "the hard way," you're a creative poet and story teller, I am a mere parasite on the works of creative artists!</p>

<p>Thinking of you, my thoughts go to Abou Ben Adhem.  Whether Leigh Hunt wrote the poem about him before of after his two years in prison, I do not know, but I am sure that in whatever self-imposed prisons we may languish--prisons of uncharitableness, of pre-judgment, of withdrawal from the world of struggle and adventure, of haunting resentments, of misanthropy and humorlessness, of presumptions of racial superiority, and above all, the prison of the dull imageination, unawakened to the power and glory of great art--it is into every nook and cranny of such prisons that your readings, your 'Golden Books,' and you your self shed a great light and have won for you the accolade of "...one who loves his fellow men."</p>

<closer>	<salute>With deep affection and fond recollection. </salute>
<signed>Frank Rarig</signed></closer>

<note type="authorial">My congratulations to you and the University of Missouri!</note>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
