<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 17
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970
April 11, 1968
Dr. John G. Neihardt
Route 7
Columbia, Mo.
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>Your letter made me very happy. I am glad that you are having all these honors and successes, and that the new book is going well. I had heard form Stan Smith that you were in Lincoln, and then I read Tom Allan's article in the <underline>World Herald</underline> about your working on the book. It is wonderful that you can do this. I am glad that you can do lectures form memory now, and that you don't have to depend on a book. That makes your future unlimited, doesn't it?</p>
<p>I think I am gradually feeling better. Some mornings I do not have that terrible sinking feeling. The doctor says part of it is chemical reaction of the body. It is a form of illness that will gradually go away. I don think I'm making progress.</p>
<p>Our son and his wife will be home tonight. They had their car stolen over two weeks ago and no trace of it has been found. They are driving my old car now.</p>
<p>By all means come down and see us. Let us know when you will come so that we can be prepared and at home and all that. We would be delighted to see you.</p>
<p>What did you think of the article in <underline>Western American Literature</underline>? I found it quite interesting, but of course, I was not as familiar with <underline>The Divine Enchantment</underline> as I was with <underline>The Song of the Messiah</underline>.</p>
<p>On the 20th of April when you are at the dedication of the bronze bust at the Library there in Columbia, we will be having our spring Cather Conference. Wish you could be with us too.</p>
<p>I had a letter from Mrs. _____ I can't think of her name, anyhow the woman who heads up the work in Bancroft. She asked about several things that we do here that they wanted to consider for Bancroft. They were making application for a $10,000.00 grant from a firm in Minnesota. I hope they are successful in getting what they want. It seems they want to restore the old post office and use some mannikins. I sent her the address of the woman from whom we get our mannikins.</p>
<p>We finally got copies in paperback of <underline>The River and I</underline> here at the Memorial to sell. We are looking forward to having your autobiography to sell too before too long.</p>
<p>Thank you for your good letter and your strong words of encouragement.</p>
<p>They do help.</p>
With love from all of this household,
<signed>Mildred</signed>
Mildred
Page 18 
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970
<unclear/> for Address ->
informed of J.G.N. <unclear>eye op.</unclear>
May 3rd -M.M.Y._
Dr. John G. Neihardt
Route 7
Columbia, Mo. 65201
Ink Stamp: RED CLOUD NB APR 11 PM 1968 68970
Stamp: 6 cents FRANKLIN D. ROOSEVELT U.S. POSTAGE