<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.16.37-38_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt, October 22, 1935</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.16.37-38_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Charles Kelly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1935-10-22">October 22, 1935</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.16.37-38_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">37</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">CHARLES KELLY</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    473 First Avenue
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">SALT LAKE CITY . UTAH</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>Oct. 22, 1935</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>After we have made our trek across the Salt Desert --I take it for granted that we will--we ought to spend a few days out there looking for "buried treasure." I neglected to tell you when you were here, that two years ago a couple of teachers from the Grantsville high school went out there on the old trail, guided by a man who was with me when I found fragments of the Donner dishes. When these there<del>e</del> men reached the spot where I found the dishes, the guide began wandering around and finally discovered a faint wagon track leading off at right angles to the main trail. He followed it half a mile, and there found a buried cache. The stuff had been merely laid in a wagon box and abandoned--not buried until afterwards by the windblown sand. The entire wagon box was there, but not the running gears. There were two ox yokes with bows, a bushel of broken dishes, a feather bed, a large quantity of iron, traces of leather-bound books, a small quantity of rosin, and various other articles, including pieces of furniture. Nothing of any monetary value, of course, but a lot of fine relics which are now in the Grantsville high school museum.</p>
                
                <p>I should have found that cache, but was in too big a hurry. I merely tell this to show that there are probably several caches out there along the trail waiting to be discovered. In the vicinity where the five wagons were abandoned there had been at least one cache, but it had been dug up a long time ago. However, by searching for wagon tracks leading off from the main trail, as his man did, we could no doubt find several other caches of goods, possibly including James <hi rend="caps">F.</hi> Reed's cast iron stove. It would be fun to search, anyway, and if we did, we could establish a base camp out there in the vicinity of this last find, which is as far as we can go in a car unless we have another exceptionally dry year. I have searched the west side of the desert quite thorou<del/><add>g</add>hly, but not the middle of the desert, where the stuff was probably buried....If we find any unbroken bottles of 1845 whisky, they're mine!'</p>
                
                <p>The natives around Grantsville believe there was a big treasure buried on the desert. None of them have done any searching for it, but they accuse me of being a treasure hunter. I also heard of a man a few weeks ago who used to dig for treasure at the Mountain Meadows ever<sic>every</sic> summer for many years after the massacre. An old man in Grantsville swears there are twenty wagons still standing on the salt flats <hi rend="underline">south</hi> of the railroad, but I think he's a liar. Still, there was an abandoned wagon found near Wildcat mountain, which lends some plausibility to the yarn. Then there are the lost wagons at the foot of the 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.16.37-38_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">38</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">CHARLES KELLY</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    473 First Avenue
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">SALT LAKE CITY . UTAH</hi>
                </fw>
                    
                    Hog mountains north of the lake. I have made four trips out there without success, but have had so many reports from reliable men that I am satisfied they are there. All agree they were headed <hi rend="underline">east</hi>, but there is no record of any such party. The skeleton of an old man was found in a rock shelter on the mountain nearby, with an old Kentucky rifle. I have seen the skull.</p>
               
                <p>So if you want to spend a few weeks on the desert next summer, there are still plenty of things to look for. Some "Spanish coins" are said to have been found in one of the wagons at "Hogup."</p> 
                
                <p>Yes, I'd like to read "Wives of the Prophet." Hadn't seen it reviewed in the "Deseret<sic>Desert</sic> News." Sounds interesting.</p> 
                
                <p>I have been working on an article about the polygamous colony at Short Greek, Ariz. You have probably seen some of the newspaper reports. It goes a lot deeper than shows on the surface. Won't be able to finish it until after the trial in Phoenix on Dec. 9.</p>
                
                <p>Just received my copy of the Stuart Journal. It is undoubtedly the finest job of editing ever done on any western journal, and proves conclusively that Stuart went through South Pass; but I can't understand why he doesn't make more of the fact in his record. You'd imagine, after crossing Union Pass in the Wind River mountains, he'd rave over the discovery of South Pass, which was almost no pass at all in comparison. Anyway it's a wonderful record, and Rollins has topped them all in research and editing.</p>
                
                <p>Remember us to Enid. We'll be seeing you next summer!</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Charles Kelly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
