<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.32a.11">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile F. Aly to John G. Neihardt, September 4, 1968</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.X.X</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile F. Aly to John G. Neihardt, September 4, 1968</title>
<date when="1968-09-04">September 4, 1968</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>River and I</term>
<term>Dawn-Builder</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1900"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.32a.11.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>September 4, 1968
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>Here's the <hi rend="underline">Tree</hi> chapter and I am so sorry not to have gotten this off
earlier. I have been in a terrible bind, as you guessed. The doctor thought Daddy would be better
off at home, and we had an unexpected hang-up on the arrangements for people to help me, so I had to
do it all myself. It was a pleasure to take care of Daddy, but it took all my time and more than all
my energy; we finally got set up with nurses and aids, and then he had a bad collapse and we took
him to the hospital two days ago, ambulance and all--but they didn't this time blow the siren, thank
goodness. So now I'm at work again; Bower and Stewart xxx are spelling me at the hospital, and I am
going to finsih within the next three weeks. I am revising the second chapter which I will send you
as soon as possible--it's the lyrics and <hi rend="underline">River and I</hi> and
<hi rend="underline">Dawn-Builder</hi>, which, by the way, is a really good book. I'm so glad I didn't finish this biography five years ago when this chapter was written--I didn't see then what I see now! You will like this version. I have completely scrapped the section on the lyrics and rewritten it; also I have shifted the chapter around to get the analysis at the end so that it focuses emphasis on the lyrics themselves. This is the pattern in the other chapters, so I decided to treat the lyrics as one group.</p>

<p>I am so sorry I couldn't get to Nebraska for the Neihardt Day. I felt real grief about that--but I'll come to see you yet, some way. I appreciated Mrs. Vogt's letter; she has worked hard for this event, and it means a great deal to her. Can someone take a picture of you with the gold wreath for me? Just to be sure I have them all, before I wind up the last chapter, make me a list of the honors of the last eight years, will you? I don't want to leave out any of the laurel sprigs.</p>

<p>This isn't much of a letter; I'll do better as soon as I get this chapter done. Also, I'll try to write to Mrs. Young tomorrow--I appreciate everything she does. I'm looking forward to reading your manuscript.</p>

<closer>
<salute>
Much love. I hope this doesn't sound too hurried - we're all a bit upset.</salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>