<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.22a-22b_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, October 18, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.22a-22b_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-10-18">October 18, 1957</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.22a-22b_0001"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">22a</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        2094 Hilyard Eugene, Ore.
                        October 18, 1957
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Many, many thanks for the letters; I appreciate your sending them to me. I will write to Mrs. Newton and I'm glad you know about her. You certainly have devoted friends all over the country; everyone I write to is lovely about giving me information and always they say it is good someone is writing about you. I feel the same way; I wish I could tell you how deeply satisfying it is to be doing this job, and what a strong sense I have of doing something important and necessary. Nobody could read the things I'm reading and not be impressed with the value of getting it into the permanent record.</p>
                
                <p>Your letter about Tagore I enjoyed doubly because I remember the delight I felt in Tagore's writing when it had a flare in the late twenties. I have a notebook full of bits I copied out, but I really didn't have the background to evaluate what I liked. Do you think Tagore will be read again with some of the same enthusiasm?</p>
                
                <p>May I ask some more questions of the fact about small points? Here are some details I have run into:
                    <list>
                        <item>What was the Traumerei that Mrs. Neihardt made; was it an Ozark Baby?</item>
                        <item>One of the letters mentions a biography of Bovard. Was it published? and if so, do you know the author and title? I would like to read it.</item>
                        <item>In one of the Sterling letters you mentioned Red Crodd<sic>Cross</sic> work that might keep you from making a trip. Were you doing Red Cross work in Bancroft?</item>
                        <item>What is the Three Bears House?</item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                
                <p>Also I would like to ask you a bigger question. I'm beginning to pull your expression of ideas together, and I will feel easier if you are willing to check me for understanding as I go. Two words, which you say in one letter are after all just words that have to be defined, are <hi rend="underline">socialism</hi> and <hi rend="underline">totalitarianism</hi>. Several places you discuss socialism and its "inevitability" and as the various statements add up your definition of socialism sounds to me like the same essential principle you saw in totalitarianism. You didn't use either word in the con-
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.22a-22b_0002"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">22b</fw>
                
                    ventional political sense, did you? That is, even though you might have meant nationalizing of the mines or other basic industry, the <hi rend="underline">principle</hi> was the real point, was it not?--the integration of people, willingly, to do things both socially and economically the most sensible way for the protection of every individual and his chance? In the illustration you use for totalitarianism--the watch--don't you make the same point? If things are to work, the parts have to mesh and fill their assignment. Is that basically different from the kind of socialism you believed in? Actually it is integrated, cooperating society, isn't it? Have I understood? This is different from the socialism of political men because it is less hardened into positive procedures. Am I straight on that? If you have time to answer all these, I shall certainly appreciate it. There is no special hurry, and I know this is an unusually busy time of year.</p>
                
                <p>I would love to hear more about the cr<del>itical</del><add>eative</add> essay class. What are you reading in it? Students who can take that course with you are certainly fortunate; however much they know it now, they will know it even better in years to come.</p>
                
                <p>Please give my best regards to Mrs. Neihardt. I am enjoying the sleeping baby, which I don't use as a paper weight because I don't want it to <hi rend="underline">do</hi> anything except just <hi rend="underline">be</hi> what it is. And say hello for me to Alice and Lynn and Erica and Yo-<del>T</del><add>Y</add>To. We have a Siamese cat that came with the house, but she's a very touchy beast without half the personality Yo-Yo has. I hope the flu misses all of you; do take care of yourselves.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Aloha!</salute>
                </closer>
                           
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

