<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 35
EARL THOMPSON
CHALET LES FRAQSSES
1882-BARBOLUESAZ-GRYON
SWITZERLAND
DEC 18, 1970

Dear Dr. Neihardt;
<p>Here we are in the Chalet of a Baron of all Belgains, on a sunny <unclear>alpin balcon</unclear>, overlooking practically everything. -Except to wish you once more a joyious and satisfying season. I only wish you were here to sit by the fire and gaze out at a Christmas Card seem that would be carry if it were not real. And perhaps life a small glass of the local wine, as delightful as sunshine.</p>
<p>I hope you have received a copy of my book by now. Though I am reluctant for you to read it. It is not heroic. For I do not come from heroic people. We on the wrong side a <sic>Culoden</sic> Moor and on the wrong side at Shiloh and we are on the wrong side again. We were for the Indian, the working man, the black and the widows + orphans before this was even the flare of movements that burn brightly until Judeo-Christain  <unclear>passion wanes</unclear> or wants to kill <unclear>somebody</unclear> - preferably by remote control,</p>
Page 36
2.
<p>So, we were always on the wrong side - barbarian and losers to great quaking christians like Nixon and all his righteous brothers.</p>
<p>I keep hearing Gustav Krupp tell his son Alfried: "We've hired Hitler."</p>
<p>I don't expect my book to be like for the right reasons anywhere but in <sic>Scandanovia</sic> + perhaps The Netherlands. Consequently, I have a contract which permits me to handle all rights to my work in those countries.</p>
<p>Were in Switzerland to ski, and look for a place to establish another permenant base. They killed all the fish in Lake Tahoe. Colorado, Nevada, + New Mexico are radioactive. Everytime I publically protest some outrage, a deadfaced man who looks like an assistant secretary of defense snaps my photo for some great cross-reference somewhere of folks to be scooped up - just in case - when and if. I cannont live with the rage such thinking excites in me. Nor is writing a satisfying outlet for me. Less than 5% of Americans really read. Line up those who do, willing to see my side, and its <sic>Culoden</sic> all over again.</p>
* "Arms of Krupp" William Manchester.
Page 37
3.
<p>So, I'll talk to the Swedes. They straight away treat me like a citizen. It is a very good feeling that.</p>
<p>Got a new pair of French skis which immediately expressed their Gallic character by being totally unforgiving of slovenly techingue by pitching me headlong over the tri-color little cocks on the tips and bashing my left shin with a hard sharp edge.</p>
<p>The Dr. says after he draws off the fluid collected in a painful great bust. I could be skiing again by Christmas or perhaps New Years. "Anyway, there is no snow!" he explains agreeably. The consider nothing under a meter anything but a heavy frost. And the discoloration of my limb ought to be completely gone by April. If I had broken it, I'd be 50 pages into my next book by now. I think my editor sees a witch.</p>
<p>I do wish you could spend some time in these mountains with us. Think we can sleep 14. If you are up to the trip come along.</p>
<p>Jedediah doesn't talk a hell of a lot. But when he does, he means for you to listen, serious little fellow. May be well <unclear/></p>
Fondest regards
Deanne, John, Jamie + Jed.    Earl