<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.26-29_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, November 12, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.26-29_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-11-12">November 12, 1957</date>
                    <extent>3 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written page, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.26-29_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>November 12, 1957</dateline>
                            
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Many thanks for the good letter. You are wonderful to answer so many questions in such sparkling detail. Your letters are one of the joys of this job.</p>
                
                <p>Bower read the letter too, and he says the explanation of socialism, totalitarianism is the most intelligent he has heard yet. I am very glad to have it in your own words, and I appreciate your taking time to write it out.</p>
                
                <p>I do want to know about the <unclear>wave</unclear> of hysteria during the first World War. I remember a very little about it, and I once knew a man from a Missouri town who had suffered from such an outburst; his father's house was painted yellow in the night. It is good all around, however, that you could tell real duty, from outside pressure; the small-souled can't. You didn't say in so many words to Sterling that you were not free, <unclear>but</unclear> the implication is there in all your writing.</p>
                
                <p>One more item I'd like to get in detail is the rattlesnake story in the <hi rend="underline">Wars</hi> &#8212; the one about the men going for help and stopping a rattler with tobacco juice. Do you remember where you got the story? I thought I had it all in my notes from your class but I have only the basic outline.</p>
                
                <p>The news to date is good. I am seeing Mrs. Ryskind just before Thanksgiving. Also, I have turned up two more 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.26-29_0002"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                
                    <unclear/>ling letters (yours to him) at Mills College. Photostats are being made for me. The David Starr Jordan papers had only one letter, but I've got a reproduction of it and it's a very meaty letter about the Minneapolis <hi rend="underline">Journal</hi>. One set-back is the John Galen Howard letters; I heard from Mr. Howard's daughter, who has gone through all the boxes of letters without finding any from you. It is hard for me to believe that anyone would destroy a Neihardt letter, and they may yet turn up.</p>
                
                <p>This is what Mr. Morrison, first assistant in the Manuscripts Division of the New York Public Library writes: "No wonder you chose Neihardt! I've never read such a small group of letters that paint a more vivid picture. The first letter in the lot is in the form of a poem and it's a gem!!" He is assembling your letters in the Bob Davis collection to be filmed for me.</p>
                
                <p>Martin Schmitt, the Historical Society man, wants me to write an article about you for the publication. He is a real enthusiast, and I shall certainly write the article as soon as I can. Mrs. Schmitt edited the autobiography of General Crook, I discovered; he found the manuscript.</p>
                
                <p>I am having a gorgeous time reading the <hi rend="underline">Blade.</hi> You edited it from September 18, 1903 to January 27, 1905, if you ever want the exact dates. It is very good reading. Also I found the poem about McKinley's death, and several others that are jewels. Do you recall one about the <unclear>speaker Bixley</unclear>? or the one about a card game? They are something! I felt sorry for <hi rend="caps">W.J.</hi> Sinclair who preceded
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.26-29_0003"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                
                    <unclear>you</unclear> and Mr. Burke who followed you.</p>
                
                <p>May I ask you another political question? In the <hi rend="underline">Blade</hi> there are two editorials about Westward expansion, <add>one</add> giving in essence the thesis that runs all through your work. The other predicts gradual expansion of Russian influence, perhaps to inevitable dominance of the world. It referred to the rising spirit. I'm interested that your concept was well worked out so early--(your predictions are astute at every stage!) and I'm wondering whether you remember how you came to that idea? Was it reading or analysis of news reports or conversations or all three? or something else? Was your sympathy with Russia in the war with Japan with or against public opinion in Bancroft? You were right that anyone studying your life should read the <hi rend="underline">Blade</hi>. It's a rewarding chapter to study.</p>
                
                <p>I have read the reports in Eugene and Portland papers about your talks here. They were very successful; each one had about five write-ups.</p>
                
                <p>Again thanks for answering so many questions. I hope you will be in Columbia at Christimas time. I think we will be there during the vacation so that I can check footnotes. I'd like to see you while we're there. Some things I'd like to talk with about instead of writing, and I will have a manuscript for you to see.</p>
                
                <p>Best regards from us all.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I appreciate the lecture brochure too. I have Mrs. Watson's address.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.26-29_0004"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    2094 Hilyard
                    Eugene, Oregon
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    EUGENE
                    NOV 13
                    130 PM
                    1957
                    OREG.
                    PRAY FOR PEACE
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>U.S. POSTAGE 3¢
                    IN GOD WE TRUST
                    LIBERTY</p>
                </figure>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                
                <note type="authorial">ansd
                11-1<del/><add>7</add>-'57</note>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Route 7</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>