<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 29
November 3, 1968
Dear John,
<p>Many thanks for your letter; it always gives me a lift to see your handwriting on an envelope. I would have written sooner but I live on a split-second schedule in order to get anything done on my <underline>real work</underline>, and even though I haven't gotten a letter to you, I have been able to work on the book every day at least a little, and sometimes I get in a block of time by being ruthless about the telephone and letters. But you do need a progress report. Also many thanks for the clippings and late news; I shall need them</p>
<p><signed>Progress Report</signed> (kindly note professional tone of this here letter, what with headings and all!): Chapters 1 and 2 (all of Part I) and revised and being typed. Chapter 3 (Part II) is revised, awaiting final check of quotations, footnotes, and last reading. It is the <underline>Hugh Glass</underline> chapter with more on the two plays and the technique of HG, which I didn't more than touch on in the original. I touched up the ending too, and it now says much more of the deep things I think about it--also I speak out with much more confidence, and if people don't agree with me, the more fool they. I am about to revise Chapter 4 (<underline>Three Friends</underline>), and after that the revisions are not major--in the <underline>Wars</underline> chapter I began to write the book.</p>
<p><underline>Current Problems, Prosody Division</underline>: I'm not confused about the couplets. I may need to make clearer the distinction between couplet meter and couplet <underline>rhyme</underline>. I have tried to keep this clear, but I must have slipped in the <underline>Tree</underline> chapter. No, of course you didn't write in couplets like Pope and Dryden--My God from me too! I quote Sterling in Chapter 3 at some length, and that is the first go-round on the verse technique. The rhyming of two successive lines does mean couplet in one restricted sense--the closing of a thought in two rhymed lines is something else entirely. Don't worry about this confustion; I'll review every prosody section of the book, as you must too, but this is not a problem you need to work ober for posterity--every syllable you wrote is going to be gone over with a fine-tooth comb, and nobody four hundred years from now is going to call this heroic couplet; it will probably have a special name of its own--Neihardt meter, or some such. Did you know you wrote in sprung rhythm? That's a relatively late term, but you did. I've had wonder-ful fun with Hugh this round; it's a great poem, and I have hunted out some reviews I had not seen--by poking through every old magazine in the library.</p>
<p>The situation here is not better--in fact, it is worsening all the time. Daddy was in the hospital two weeks, and then was transferred to the convales-cent hospital, and he grows weaker every day. He cannot speak clearly now, and he is not himself except for a moment now and then. I go every day be-cause he still seems ot know I am there, but that's about all. He would have this if he knew, and it is terrible to watch the person blotted out of him slowly. He always believed so passionately in keeping control of one's self that this would be dreadful for him if he knew. In fact, it is dreadful; he was aleart several days ago for a while, and told me, "I am already dear." But I keep thinking that after this is over I shall be able to rejoice that he had a lovely year with us when we could surround him with love and deference and pleasure in his company. I'm glad I have so much to do..</p>
<p>We were in Corallis last Sunday for the Centennial, at which Bower represented AAUP. Mr. Jenson send you his regards and says to come see him when you get here again.</p>
Page 30
<p>I will send you the last chapter a little later on. I am holding up finishing it until I get the first four chapters revised so that I can stay ahead of the typist; I have hopes of putting a complete manuscript in your hads before long. I am really progressing faster than you might think. I'm not sure myself how I do it, considering. Keep the clippings coming; when I get to the last year of the Laurel Decade I shall have a heap. I'm really pleased to death for you, John. You deserve every bit of this, and I hope the book will add to your happiness too. As you say, it is needed--<underline>now</underline>--and I'm giving it all I can. I think it is going to be good.</p>
<p>Regards to everyone. I'm writing Mrs. Young a separate letter to thank her first-hand. Aren't the Youngs teemendous?</p>
Love--to Jacques too
<signed>Lucile</signed>