<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0001-9">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Major H. R. Lemly to John G. Neihardt, March 9, 1922</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.9.11-19_0001-9</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Major H. R. Lemly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1922-03-09">March 9, 1922</date>
                    <extent>9 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>9 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>9 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11_0001" />
                
                <note><hi rend="caps">N.<unclear>B.</unclear></hi> From the side of Gen. Crook and Col. Royall I <hi rend="underline">saw</hi> American Horse's surrender, etc.</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB 
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>March 9, 1922.</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I have yours of the 5th inst. and am very sorry that you cannot be with us next Saturday. However, the invitation is good while I live, and I hope you will be able to join us in the near future.</p>
                
                <p>I keep sending you data but with this letter you will have received about all I know.
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0002"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
                
                    Really, I cannot begin to tell you how this grand work of yours appeals to me. It will make you more famous than you now are, and will rescue from oblivian a wonderful story. <hi rend="underline">The people do not know it</hi>. You see, these articles in Service magazines, never reached them. Although years old, it will be new to the world and, in that splendid metre of yours, will 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0003"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">13</fw>
                
                    live forever. From the bottom of my heart I congratulate you.</p>
                
                <p>Briefly, the story of Spotted Tail's daughter was this. She was called "The Red Trail," because born near or on a muddy trail. The Sioux equivalent is <unclear>"Shawnkoo"</unclear> or <unclear>"Shaunkoo Teela".</unclear> I am not sure about the orthography. I saw her <unclear>after</unclear>, a pretty Indian girl, rather fair for her race and always wearing a red robe, the bodice of which was embroidered in or with stained porcupine quills and glistened "with the nacreous luster of elk teeth."</p>
                
                <p>At this time Spotted Tail's village was on the North Platte near Fort Laramie. "The Red Trail" fell in love with a young officer, a lieutenant (I think his name was Robinson). She came often to the post and while she never entered his quarters, in almost savage simplicity, she stood for hours with her face pressed against the windowpanes of his house, watching sweetly his every movement. Of course, the affair got raised about, among whites as well as Indians
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0004"/>
                    <fw type="authorial"><del/>2</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">14</fw>
                    
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB 
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON</hi>
                </fw>
                
                    and Spotted Tail determined to take her to the far north. From the day she left, she sickened and somewhere on the Powder <unclear>River</unclear> of the Rosebud, she died. Meanwhile <hi rend="caps">R.</hi> was a marked man and one day when he went hunting, he failed to return. A scouting party found him bound to a tree and pierced by twenty-seven arrows &#8212; the arms of the young braves. He was buried in the post cemetery.</p>
                
                <p>I should have said that this occurred <hi rend="underline">before</hi> Spotted Tail left
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0005"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">15</fw>
                
                    and was the principal cause of his departure. "The Red Trail"'s last request was that she might be buried, Indian fashion, on a high scaffold, on the bluff near the post hospital and overlooking the post cemetery <add>^at Ft. Laramie.</add> The last time I was at Laramie, her body was still there, because Spotted Tail brought her back as she had requested; but I believe that <hi rend="caps">R</hi>'s remains were subsequently disinterred and sent east to his relatives.</p>
                
                <p>Gen. Schuyler, whom you know, made one of the most
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0006"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">16</fw>
                    
                    gallant rides I ever heard of. In 1876 he had been appointed <hi rend="caps">A.D.C.</hi> to Gen. Crook, but arrived at Ft. Fetterman after the Big Horn + Yellowstone Expedition had departed. Nothing daunted, he followed our trail, entirely alone, through a hostile Indian country, for more than a hundred miles.</p>
                
                <p>At the Rosebud fight a trumpeter was shot through both hands or wrists as he was trying to control his horse, which was bearing him towards the Indian lines. Capt., then Lieut., John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Bourke, another <hi rend="caps">A.D.C.</hi> of Gen. Crook, dasked out and rescued him, under fire.</p>
                
                <p>Where Corp. Glass, 3rd Cav., was wounded at the Rosebud, a pretty Nebraska girl was discovered in soldier uniform, nursing him. He was her lover and <add>^ she</add> had gone out with the troops from Ft. Fetterman, but had not been discovered before. She was known as "Soldier Frank," and had been rescued from Indians near North Platte, Neb., by Lieut. <unclear>Schrratka</unclear>, afterwards an Arctic explorer. I met and talked with her several times. Glass had been in my troop. We were too far north
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0007"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">3</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">17</fw>
                    
                <fw type="letterhead">    
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB 
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON</hi>
                </fw>
                
                    to send her back and she remained with the troops, in uniform, until we returned to the Black Hills. There I think Glass took his discharge (expiration of enlistment) and married her.</p>
                
                <p>I think I wrote you about riding all day on <del>the</del> raw horse-flesh, packed on the withers of my horse, under the saddle blanket. It was warm and the sweat of the horse salted and made it palatable. I was shown this by my orderly, Patrick Scully, who had served with the British Army in the East Indies.</p>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0008"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <p>At the fight at Slim Buttes, Capt. Sam. Munson, <add>^9th Neb.,</add> wandering along a ravine, fell into it. We found it full of women and children, some of them dead and others wounded, a dead buck or two and American Horse <add>^ armed</add> and two bucks with carbines, in which latter, taken at the Custer massacre, shells were firmly lodged, making them useless. The chief of the village, <add>American Horse,</add> had a few cartidges left and fired on an approaching skirmish line of volunteers, under Lieut. Philo Clarke, whom Gen. Crook had ordered to dislodge the 
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.9.11-19_0009"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                
                    Indians. Whenever American Horse rose to <unclear>fire</unclear>, one of our men <unclear>dropped</unclear>, but the chief received a <unclear>volley</unclear>. At this time, "Buffalo Chips", a scout with long blond hair (friend of Buffalo Bill, who was with us,) was crawling almost like a cat, along edge of ravine, to get a shot at the concealed Indians. American Horse discovered him and sent a bullet thro' his brain. "Buffalo Chips" flattened convulsively and then ceased to move. Finally "Big Bat" (Interpreter) called on the Indians to surrender and American Horse pemitted him to enter the ravine. He reappeared with American Horse supported between him and Capt. Munson. American Horse had <unclear>those</unclear> cartidges left. 
                
                    He held his carbine in one hand and his protruding barrels in the other. That night he died, with never a word. Lt. von Luettwitz, 3rd cav., had been wounded in first light, his leg was amputated on the field.</p>
                
                <p>The last stand made by the Indians was at Wounded Knee, but Lt. Hawthorne, with a battery of mountain guns, killed a lot of them as they fled. The small cannon was "bad medicine" for the Indians. They could not reply to it &#8212; to its shells or shrapnel. It should have been used before. Just after Wounded Knee the 4th Cav. came near being wiped out by Sioux and Cheyennes, because this regiment had attacked them at little Big Horn, but Col. Guy <hi rend="caps">V.</hi> Henry with 9th Cav. (blacks) went to their assistance.</p>
                
                <p>As chief of the Cemeterial Division, <hi rend="caps">Q.M.</hi> Gen's office, I gave Mr. Camp (<hi rend="caps">U.P.R.R.</hi>) tombstones for all our men lost in these fights.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most faithfully yours,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>H.R. Lemly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>


