<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0001-16">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Captain H. R. Lemly to John G. Neihardt, March 5, 1920</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.7.20-25_0001-16</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter Captain H. R. Lemly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1920-03-05">March 5, 1920</date>
                    <extent>16 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>16 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>16 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0001" />
                
                <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB.
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>March 5, 1920.</dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I beg to answer your brief letter of the 20th ,<unclear/>, although I wrote to you only two or three days ago&#8212; and a regular <unclear>reference, ten pages</unclear> numbered, <unclear>twenty</unclear> in all! I am glad to be of any service.</p>
                
                <p>Yes, I love the things of ancient Greece, its history, literature and art. Of course I have read the Iliad and Odyssey but I went to West Point too 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0002"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
                    
                young to know much Greek.</p>
                
                <p>I fear that I cannot add much to my description in the article, of the death-song of Crazy Horse, it is so long ago&#8212; about 42 years.<del>ago.</del> He had been unconsious since his wound, say four o'clock, <unclear>p.m.</unclear> About 10 o'clock p.m. he recovered consciousness. He was lying upon a blanket on the floor of the adjutant's office, and raising himself upon one elbow, steadying himself upon both hands resting upon the floor, he began
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0003"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
                    
                his weird song. He told of his youth and why he had remained north instead of going to the Agency at Red Cloud. There were still buffalo above the plains and the Indians (Ogallalah<sic/> Sioux, Red Cloud, chief,) could manage to live on the meat and clothe themselves with the tanned skins. They thought themselves better off than subsisting upon the bounty of the Great Father at Washington by drawing rations and tents at the Agency. But the agent wanted more Sioux &#8212; the more 
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0004"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                
                Indians he had, the bigger his appropriation and the greater his importance. They were living quietly in the Big Horn region, their last hunting ground, when "Long Hair" (Custer) attacked and massacred them. They had to resist or none of them would have escaped, because in a charge, the squarro could not be distinguished from the bucks and their little children <unclear>more after</unclear> shot. It was a case of kill or be killed. They had no desire to massacre Custer's 
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0005"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                    
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB.
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                command but it was <unclear>Hobson's</unclear> choice. They were upon their own reservation, solemnly given them in treaty, by the Great White Father (President). Notwithstanding, their land was constantly invaded by the whites who sought gold in the Black Hills and even in the Big Horn.</p> 
                
                <p>After the Custer massacre he and his followers, with <del/> Sitting Bull, had been chased across the border into Canada, where they lived peacefully for two years; but at the instance of the Indian Bureau in Washington, 
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0006"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
                    
                they returned to the <hi rend="caps">U.S.</hi> side under pressure from the Canadian Govmt., and he surrendered to "White Hat" (Capt. Philo Clark, 2nd cav.) who gave him a safe-conduct and took him to Red Cloud Agency. There all went well until he married, Indian fashion, the daughter of the half-breed French-Canadian interpreter, Louis Richard. At the in-treaty of her father and the agent, his wife refused to leave him. Then the "Gray Fox" (Gen. Crook) sent troops against him that night, but he escaped with his village to Spotted Tail Agency,
                    
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0007"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
     
                where Spotted Tail, chief of the Brulé Sioux, received him with open arms. There he was content to live in peace, but the Gray Fox pursued him. Gen. Lee, the Indian Agent, persuaded him to return to Red Cloud Agency and the neighboring part, Camp Robinson, which he did under safe-conduct. Arriving at the post, where he was told he was to hold a conference with Gen. Luther Bradley, commanding the District of the Black Hills, instead of taking him to the latter's office, as he was told, he was taken to the guard-house and was a-
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0008"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                
                bout to be treacherously thrust into a cell and perhaps imprisoned for years. He attempted to escape and was again treacherously run through the bowels by a bayonet, in the hands of a soldier. He was unarmed except for a knife with which, in the struggle with Little Big Man, the Indian renegade and police, he had cut the latter's wrist. He repeated and insisted that all he had wanted and asked was to be let alone. He had been ready to live anywhere in peace.</p>
                
                <p>His voice grew fainter and finally, with the death <unclear>rattle</unclear> in his throat, he fell over dead.</p>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0009"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB.
                        <lb/>
                    WASHINGTON.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <p>It was then that his old father and mother, recognizing what had happened, <unclear/> him outside my pickets and rightly or wrongly, I admitted them. What I witnessed, almost unmanned me and I then and there determined to stop chasing Indians if I could. A few years later I exchanged to an artillery regiment in the east. I was there 2nd lieut. 3rd cav.</p>
                
                <p>Only "Touch the Cloud," "Big Bat" (Baptiste-French-Canadian scout and squaw man), the interpreter, Sergeant Mc.Gillycuddy and myself were present at his death. Gen. Lee (then Captain) had seen him during a few moments
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0010"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                    
                of consciousness, earlier in the evening, when I was not present. Gen. Bradley had sent for me and ordered me to take Crazy Horse in an ambulance, guarded by a troop of cavalry, at midnight, to Fort Laramie, thence via Cheyenne to Fort Marion, St. Augustine, Fla., where he was to be imprisoned. Gen. <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> did not know that he was fatally wounded.</p>
                
                <p>Yes, Custer was lovable and a rather rapid talker. I never saw him "waspish," but then I <unclear>knew</unclear> him only slightly. <unclear>The</unclear> youngsters were flattered by his being <hi rend="underline"><unclear/>-fellow-well-met</hi> with us. He was lieut. cap.,commanded his regiment and had been a major-general within a year of leav-
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0011"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                ing West Point, in the Civil War. He was deficient in his studies and did not graduate. After he distinguished himself, not yet 25 and a major general, the faculty at West Point reflected and sent him his diploma, but he refused it. I know Captain Marsh and wife and all of her family.</p> 
                
                <p>Gen. Edward <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Godfrey, <hi rend="caps">U.S.A.</hi>, Retired, Cookstown, New Jersey, can tell you all about the Custer Massacre.</p>
                
                <p>Gen. Forsyth was also a lovable fellow but then again, I did not know him very well. He was called "Sandy," I think, and rather went to pieces after his retirement.</p>
                
                <p>"The Song of the Sioux" has a pleasing alliterative sound, but you can scarcely leave out Dull Knife and Chief
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_0012"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
                
                Joseph, in writing of Indian wars.</p>
                
                <p>Capt. <hi rend="caps">A.E.</hi> Bater, 2nd Cav., afterwards Paymaster General (deceased), with his troop of Cav. and Co. of the 14th or 41st infty., once ordered to attack Black Coal's Arrapahoe<sic>Arapahoe</sic> village, by Gen. <hi rend="caps">E.O.C.</hi> and, <unclear/>. Dept. of Platte at Omaha, Neb. The Indians were hunting buffalo, but were almost unarmed and had wandered unconsciously a few miles off the reservation. Many of them, including squaws and pappooses, were killed. They could scarcely defend themselves, but of course made an attempt. Black Coal had another name then, but distinguised himself and had two fingers shot off. He thrust his sub of a hand in the living embers of a fire, to cauterize<del/> the wound. When he withdrew his hand, it was <hi rend="underline">black as a coal</hi>. Hence his name.</p>
                
                <p>I wrote up Crazy Horse's death for the <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi> Sun. Mr. Charles <hi rend="caps">A.</hi> Dana wrote me it was the finest <unclear/> correspondence he had ever published. This I attributed to the facts &#8212;the substance.</p>
                
                <p>I thank you for your very kind offer of books.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Most faithfully yours,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>H.R. Lemly</signed>
                
                    <note type="curatorial">[Major <hi rend="caps">H.R.</hi> Lemly]</note>
                </closer>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_00013"/>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE ARMY AND NAVY CLUB.
                        <lb/>
                        WASHINGTON.</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener>Postscript&#8212;</opener> <p>I tried to restrict myself to 12 pages this time, but when I begin to write about the old days on the frontier, I find it difficult to stop. I forgot one incident of the Rosebud fight.</p>
                    
                    <p>Capt. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Bourke, <hi rend="caps">A.D.C.</hi> to Gen. Crook, was a gallant Irishman. A trumpeter, I think of Capt. Mills' troop, was shot through both wrists as he was trying to stop, with both hands, hi run-away horse. His trumpet was suspended from his neck. Bourke saw his arms fall and hang listless, observed that his horse was carrying him into the Sioux lines, spurred his <unclear/> horse forward<del/>, succeeded in catching the run-away horse's bridle and brought him back, under <unclear>fire</unclear>, with
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_00014"/>
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">33</fw>
                        
                        his helpless aider, into our own lines. In England he would have neen given the <hi rend="caps"><unclear/>.C.</hi></p>
                    
                    <p>I am really very glad to tell you all these incidents but I beg you will excuse my hurridly written manuscript descriptions. I am in the office of the Quartermaster General and very busy, but have been unable to have <unclear>them</unclear> <add>type-</add>written.</p>
                    
                    <p>I am Chief of the Cemeterial Branch and as such have been able to send the regulation marble headstones to mark the graves of all the soldiers who fell at Rosebud, <unclear/> a rail<unclear/>
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_00015"/>
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">34</fw>
                        
                        assisted me. Gen. Anson Mills has marked <unclear/> Buttes with a monument.</p>
                    
                    <p>If anything else should occur to me, I will write it to you with pleasure and shall be glad to answer any further questions. Yours promises to be a wonderful and most interesting work.</p>
                    
                    <p>I need not tell you that, in my opinion, the death of Crazy Horse and the attack on Black Coal's village, were two of the worst outrages ever perpetuated upon the Indians. Nearly all
                        
                        <pb facs="nei.j4a.7.20-35_00016"/>
                        
                        <fw type="curatorial">35</fw>
                        
                        of the participants are dead; Sheridan, Crook, <unclear/> Bates, Bradley, <unclear>Kennington</unclear>, Bourke, Baptiste, Munson, Royall, Evans, <unclear>Morton</unclear>, etc.</p>
                    <closer>
                        <signed>H.R.L.</signed>
                    </closer>
                </postscript>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps"><hi rend="underline">P.P.S.</hi></hi></opener> 
                    
                    <p>Capt. Bates' fight with Arrapahoes<sic>Arapahoes</sic> was near his <unclear/>, Camp <unclear/>, Wyo.</p>
                    
                    <p>The Indian death-song, in this case Crazy-Horse's, as I understand it, is a recital on <unclear/> of the pricipal events of his life and of the circumstances leading up to his approaching and expected death, ending with a farewell to his family and friends. It is a sort of whining and piteous <del/> <hi rend="underline">récitatif</hi>, as the French wd.<sic>would</sic> call it, where it is not warlike, depending upon conditions present. It is his farewell.</p>
                    
                    <closer><signed>L.</signed></closer>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>