<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 8
THE PACIFIC HISTORIAN
AN illustrated quaterly of Western History....Official organ of the California History Foundation, the Jedediah Smith Society, and the Westerners Foundation
1851
PUBLISHED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF THE PACCIFIC, STOCKTON, CALIFORNIA 95204
Rt. 8, Box 397 Tucson, Arizona
EDITOR
LELAND D. CASE
EDITORIAL ASSOCIATES
R. R. STUART
THEODOSIA BENJAMIN
MARTHA O'BRYON
EDITORAIL CONSULTANTS
ROBERT H. BAHMER    
United States Archivist
Washington, D.C.
RAY A. BILLINGTON
Huntington Library
San Marino, Calif.
MANUEL HINOJOSA
Editor of Barsa
Mexico City
Edward Joesting
Past President
Hawaiian Historical Society
Honolulu
DON RUSSELL
Editor of Brand Book 
Chicago Westerners
ROBERT M. UTLEY
Historian, National Park
Service, Washington, D.C.
R. COKE WOOD
Director, Conference of 
California Historical Societies

U.O.P. MEMBERSHIP COMMITTEE
JOHN F. HIGGINS, Chairman
LEE APPERSON
Businessman, Stockton
DORIS T. DALEY
Past Grand President of Native
Daughters of The Golden West
CATHERINE P. DAVIS
Dean of Women
DAVID FREDERICKSON
Editor, Pacific Weekly
HAROLD KAMBAK
Director, Public Relations
ROBERT MONAGAN
President, Alumni Association
MALCOLM H. MOULE
Chairman of History Department
NANCY SANS
Junior, School of Speech
ERNESTINE S. SMUTNY
Serials Librarian
RICHARD K. WILLIAMS
Dean of Men
August 10, 1968
Dr. John G. Neihardt
Skyrim Farm
Route 7
Columbia, Missouri
Dear John:
<p>Have I written you since I returned the Univeristy of the Pacific to our cactused acres and our adobe abode over here at Tucson? I've forgotten -- but now matter, because I've got a new bit of news to report.</p>
<p>Its that finally I am getting myself phased out of the editorship of The Pacific Historian. I promised President Burns at the University that I would carry it on for awhile, and finally they've added Mrs. Martha Seffer O'Bryon full time to the staff so that she can take over.</p>
<p>The last time we exchanged letters, as I recall it, we had up the possibility of your doing a piece for The Pacific Historian on how you got interested in Jedediah Smith, but more particularly your special information about and insight into his death at the hands of Comanches over there on the Cimarron River. Remember?</p>
<p>Then, too, you had a manuscript of a book by Ezra Delos Smith - a novel I believe - which we were thinking might well become a part of the Jededian Smith collections. Remember?</p>
<p>Well, in as much as I am detaching myself from The Pacific Historian, I'll refer these two matters to Mrs. O'Bryon. I'm sure you will enjoy exchange of letters with her. She comes from Illinois, in fact went to Carl Sandburgs college at Galesburg.</p>
<p>I do hope the summer is treating you well - and ofter!</p>
Cordially,
<signed>Leland</signed>
Leland D. Case
CC: Mrs. O'Bryon
