<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 20
May 2, 1968
Dear John,
<p>I'm sorry about the delay in writing you, specially now, when I have been thinking of you so much and wishing you not exactly luck but the care from the Powers that you deserve. You haven't heard because Bower and I have been much preoccupied and disturbed about a family problem. I won't go on about it, but we are in a sticky law suit to take the twins (our oldest son's children) away from their mother--and knowing us, you must know the situation was serious or we wouldn't do it. Actually the suit is in Washington; the little girls are with Barbara and Bob, but we are financing it, and it have given us a great deal of concern. And that's all about that, except that it goes to court on the 10th.</p>
<p>And that's <underline>all</underline> about that! Rest well, and sleep because I'm finishing the las section within the week ,and more than half of it is already in draft type. I will ship it along as soo n as possible, and bless the Youngs for all their love and help. I am making some few corrections on the manuscript, but I will send as clear a copy as I can so it will be easy for Mr. Young to read.</p>
<p>My, but you have been flying around! I did get your letters, and I have a pile of clippings from Mrs. MCurdy and Lois KNowles, who always sends me the articles in the Columbia papers. I am so happy about the Jefferson award, and about the bust. I think of Mona looking down from somewhere with that ecstatic glow in her eyes. When I have a chance to see it I shall hear her vote saying "Isn't it wonderful!" in the tone I have heard her use many times for those words. I'm <underline>sure</underline> she was there, and proud she could help, but even prouder of you. </p>
<p>I'm typing this because my hand writing is even more difficult to read than my typing, which is bad enough. I appreciate your being willing to listen and comment when you might so easily just want to rest and do nothing. I hope you'll like the Chicago--it gave me a thrill all over again to write it.</p>
<p>My father is so-so; some good days and some in a pale mist--and he wants to come home and doesn't see why he can't. That part is awfully hard. </p>
Page 21
-2-
<p>I am delighted that you got the little loyal doggie back. Alice would stay with something like that, wouldn't she? You have a little dog lady friend here too--Jingle is busy taking care of me while Bower is out of town for a few days at a meeting, but she has time to say arfily that she is glad, too that your surgery went well and that you are all right. </p>
<p>I have written Mr. Nicholl that I hope to have a manuscript for him before the end of June. I have a typist here, because I will have to work closely on the proofreading, but it will not be put into final type till you have seen all the revisions. I am working till the small hours every night, and I still have a raft of checking to do. But I want you to hold the biography in your hands in its binding from the press--a real book. And you can't think I'm mad at you@ I sort of am you in a very biographer way, and if I were making a list of people to be mad at you wouldn't even be an also ran--so ther to, and arfffff from Jingle; she would never allow me to be angry at her special buddy. No, John. there is room for many, many books about you. You know the history of your heart as you say, and that's not all a biography is; besides I can point out of remarkable things in a way you can't. Moreover, some of the things I think are most remarkable you pooh pooh as perfectly natural, and the analysis I make of the writings you couln't do for yourself either. It has to be what someone else thinks. </p>
<p>And now I shall stop writing you and get back to work. I will write again though, and I am sending Mrs. Young a note. I shall be very grateful if she will let me know all about you and how you get along. Don't push yourself to work before you feel like it. You are too important to too many people to slow up your getting well in any way. I will be thinking about you and you know how much we love you.</p>
Lover,
Lucille                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                