<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 26
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970
May 15, 1969
Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>Thank you for your good letter. It was such a pleasure to see you and the time went so fast that the evening was over before it had started. I was so sorry to miss the Saturday program. I heard it was very good.</p>
<p>We have some very sad news in our family. My sister and her husband(this one you haven't met) were taking a tour around the world. Her husband took sick in Australia and they flew to Singapore where he was operated. He lived about two weeks and died last Sunday there. My sister buried him there where he had been a missionary for seven years, and returned to California arriving last night. We will all miss him so much. He was the only one of my family who could understand why I left the church. He was my friend when nobody else wanted anything to do with me. I shall miss him personally more than an ordinary brother-in-law.</p>
<p>The doctor says we face in this loss no more than thousands of other people face, and he is right. As my father used to say, "grief is selfish." and that is true. We are fortunate to have him in our family.</p>
<p>We are so proud of Bill and his good grades. He and his wife will be home a week from this coming week end. They can only stay a day or so as his senior year starts at once. Did I tell you he married a Catholic girl, but they seem to have no trouble about religion. She is a real doll.</p>
<p>I have had no word form the St Martin's Press about my book. I suppose the readers are having a go at it. I am eager to read your book. I know it is going to be fascinating.</p>
<p>We have had C"therland tours all this week. Today is the first day I haven't had to go out. I have taken it easy today. There will be tours tomorrow and Saturday. Yesterday the Red Cloud eighth graders took the Museum and House tour.</p>
<p>I thope the University Press sees fit to take your book as you have it. I am eager to see it in print.</p>
<p>We think of you with love and affection and hope you and the Youngs can visit us again this summer. Take care of yourself.</p>
Affectionately,
<signed>Mildred</signed>
Page 25
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68979
5-16-69__
Ans 6-11-69
Ink Stamp: RED CLOUD, NB. MAY 15 PM 1969 68970
Stamp: U.S. POSTAGE 6 CENTS FRANKLIN D. ROOSEVELT
Dr. John G. Neihardt 
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505