<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36a.10-11">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Hilda N. Petri to John G. Neihardt, June 13, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36a.10-11</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Hilda N. Petri to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-06-13">June 13, 1972</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.10"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">10</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="italics">Hilda <hi rend="caps">N.</hi> Petri</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">ATTORNEY-AT-LAW
                        <lb/>
                    ____________________________________________________________
                        <lb/>
                    110 N. EIGHTH STREET - COLUMBIA, MISOURI 65201
                        <lb/>
                    PHONE</hi> (314) 449-2929
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>June 13, 1972</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Gaki:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I am in a situation similar to that which many of your viewers find themselves. I have had several calls this morning from very sincere and very enthusiastic people who watched your program last night. They say that they want to tell me how much they appreciated it and enjoyed it, but "I just don't know how to express myself". I got a call from an older woman this morning. I thought her comments were remarkably good. She said that you had such a deep spiritual insight and were so sensitive, but that you were not "sentimental". I thought this was a very perceptive comment. I just got a call from a young lawyer here who just bubbled all over. He said that he also just didn't know how to express himself. He said that he just couldn't believe it!</p>
                
                <p>I enclose copies of letters from Shir-Cliff and from Mr. Muller's assistant. They are self-explanatory. About the need for reviews concerning <hi rend="underline">When The Tree Flowered</hi><add>;</add> I do hope that you there will be able to help me on this. I am going to see if any of us have the foresight to have saved the book jacket for <hi rend="underline">When the Tree Flowered</hi>. If I find any, I will photocopy them and send them to Mr. Shir-Cliff.</p>
                
                <p>I have had two telephone calls from some people in Hollywood concerning a Black Elk movie. The latest suggestion is that they would like to pay us some mon<del>is</del><add>ey</add> which would guarantee them nothing more than a first right to contract with us about the book if John Kurland doesn't get the job done. I think this might be of interest. I will keep you informed.</p>
                
                <p>I didn't want to keep Myrtle away from the program too long last night. We do want to have you down here for a stay sometime. I got the impression from Myrtle that maybe the period from July 11 to your Neihardt Day program might be a good time. Of course, it is up to you and to Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi> Let's make plans.</p> 
                
                <p><hi rend="underline">Much love to you as always,</hi> and to Myrtle and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi></p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Hilda</signed> 
                </closer>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <!--j4a.36a.10 belongs to a different letter; they are dated months apart-->
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.11"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">11</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">
                    Gaki
                    Page 2
                    <date>March 14, 1972</date>
                </fw>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I am just now leaving the office to go out to your place with a realtor friend. I will report to you what his opinion is of reasonable value for your place.</p> 
                    
                    <p>I think everything is really starting to bust out all over! Really wonderful things are going to happen for you, and that is great.</p> 
                    
                    <p>I'll get back to you as soon as I have any further news.</p> 
                    <closer>
                        <salute>Endless love ever</salute>
                    
                        <signed>Hilda</signed> 
                    </closer>
                </postscript>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi></opener> <p>I have just returned from Skyrim with Mr. Lieurance. It just so happened that we saw Alice while we were out there. It is Mr. Lieurance's opinion, just as it was Myrtle's and <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi>'s, that it would be better not to put money on the property yourself. He said you would have to spend a great deal of money, in his opinion more than just making a kitchen and painting the interior, before you could hope to get your money back or make something on the improvement. He said people in general prefer to fix something up the way they want it.</p> 
               
                    <p>He felt that it would be reasonable to list your house and 35 acres for $25,000. He also felt that if you sold the house, as it is, with something like 8 or 10 acres, you could not a<del>l</del><add>s</add>k much more than $15,000 for it. The reason we talked about the house and 35 acres was that Alice had made some comment about the barn and riding the ring area. Perhaps this could be separately sold to her.</p> 
                
                    <p>I have not called again the woman who was interested in knowing more about the property. If you want me to dosso<sic>do so</sic>, I will take her out and discuss possible sale with her.</p> 
                
                    <p>Why don't you think about this a little and give me the benefit of your thought. I am inclined to think that the property could be priced higher than Mr. Lieurance said. Of course, he is trying to price it at a figure for which it would be likely to move quickly. Let me hear from you.</p> 
                </postscript>
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>