<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 21
SOUTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY
BROOKINGS, SOUTH DAKOTA 57006
College of Arts and Science

ENGLISH DEPARTMENT

October 4, 1968

Mr. John G. Neihardt
5835 VineStreet
Lincoln, Nebraska
68505

Dear Mr. Neihardt:
<p>I was very pleased to receive your letter of September 26, as I had followed with interest Dexter Martin's correspondence with you and had listened to his praise of <underline>Black Elk Speaks</underline>, which I am ashamed to say I have not read yet but will shortly.</p>
<p>You ask about the details of our program, and I can't give these to you because they haven't been worked out. Our theme will be "The Last Frontier," and we plan a four-weeks' summer program of lectures, dramatic and music productions, and other presentations that will fit into the theme. We are hoping that we will be able to find individuals whose knowledge of the frontier will enable them to lecture to a group of South Dakotans on the history and literature of the frontier period. It will not be necessary, of course, that a person be here for the entire four weeks. If you are interested and have the time and energy, perhaps you could come for a one week stay or even for one lecture or talk, or whatever you would want to call it.</p>
<p>When we have made more definite plans for the program I will write to you. I hope you will be interested in coming and that we can look forward to seeing you.</p>
Sincerely,
<signed>Jack W. Marken</signed>
Jack W. Marken,
Head, Dept. of English
JWM/111
A land-grant university serving South Daotans through Teachign-Research-Extension
2
Page 22
5835 Vine Street
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505
October 17, 1968

Dr. Jack W. Marken, Head
Department of English
South Dakota State University
Brookings, South Dakota 57006

Dear Dr. Marken:
<p>I have your letter of October 4, 1968 and as I wrote you on September 26, I believe, I am greatly interested in your summer session. I cannot know definitely if I could coem until some time in February. My only trouble is with my eyes and I have xxxxxxxxxx had one operation for cataracts and expect to have another one in Juanry. I should 1know by xxx February 1 how my eyes and I are !going to get along together. The chances are in my favor I am told. As for energy I still seem to have kplenty of that and I still get standing ovations!</p>
<p>Anyway, tell me more about your plans and be sure that I am truly interested.</p>
With all kinds thoughts