<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 14
Tues., Sept. 10, '68
9:00 A.M.
Dear Sir,
<p>While we were both compaigning for Bobby Brown for Sherriff of Munroe County, Florida, the Flordia Keys, that is, (which we won, by the way,) I met an old friend of yours, Lester C. Gibbs. A pupil and admirer I should say! Whe I started coming out with my favorite excerpts from Oscar Wilde's "Ballad Of The Reading Gaol.", he asked if I weren't part Indian, (As I do look it,) and came back at me with excerpts from your "A Cycle Of The West," and "Song Of The Indian Wars,", and I must say, if we hadn't been working I would love to have been able to hear the whole thing.</p>
<p>Having been very hastily transferred by the Submarine Service to Newport News Virginia, I no longer had occasion to speak to your friend, but I would greatly appreciate it, if you could tell me where I could find your books in this decadent town!</p>
Page 15
II
<p>So far, <underline>all two</underline> book stores have promised to look into it, but I have received no further word!</p>
<p>I am only half <unclear>esquimaux</unclear>, but I'll bet we could sure square this vote away if they'de only give us back half?</p>
<p>From what Mr. Gibbs said, you are a most unusual man. If you ever are unbusy enough, I would surely love to hear from you. I am 35 summers, raise Pit Bull Terriers, (Strictly against the law,) and read! And I am entirely lost amongst these people. I worked one week and got fired because I was accused of making fun of the customers by using words they didn't understand. This is not conceit, sir, it is just that I have never met this type people before; as I only completed the 2<underline>nd</underline> year of High School myself.</p>
<p>Would thorougly enjoy hearing from you, if you ever have time.</p>
Page 16
III
<p>In the mean time Mr. Gibbs asked me to pass on his address which is,
LESTER C. GIBBS
SALES REPRESENTATIVE
615 CAROLINE ST., KEY WEST, 33040
and mine sir is
MRS. MARJORIE KELLEY HOLTZ
#LOT 9, 5959 JEFFERSON AVE.,
NEWPORT NEWS, VA., 23605<p/>
Thank You,
Sincerely
Marjorie Kelley Holtz