<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0001-6">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Elizabeth E. Graham to John G. Neihardt, October 27, 1943</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.20.19-24_0001-6</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Elizabeth E. Graham to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1943-10-27">October 27, 1943</date>
                    <extent>5 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>5 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>5 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0001-6"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        502 South State
                        Springfield, Illinois
                        October 27, 1943
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt, &#8212;</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your second letter embarrassed me, but I almost forgive my procrastination since it brought me <unclear>second</unclear> mellow note in which I find my pleasure surpasses my shame.</p>
                
                <p>I postponed mailing the books because I hadn't written. I didn't write because I had put out request to several people to hand me one or two sentences putting in writing comments made to me about the lift meeting you and hearing you gave them. Since two of these are still not in hand I've waited. The writers very sincerely want to give
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0002"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
                
                    me statements but we live in a busy world and the <unclear>firsthugs</unclear> of our hearts <hi rend="underline">do not always</hi> get first attention.</p>
                    
                <p>Springfield is still talking about the day. I have heard praise and gratitude from the three groups before whom the poet, Neihardt, and the man Neihardt apeared. The man is an able speaker and reader. There was full preparation of the audience before each reading of the poems. <hi rend="underline">Easter</hi> was especially praised. But it was evident that both youth and adults felt something more than intellectual pleasure. With simple clearness Mr. Neihardt budged the translation from objective details over to transcendental experiences which defy comprehension. His quiet faith in the divinity within men gave the uplift human hearts crave. The Spring-
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0003"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
                
                    field English club is proud to have brought <del/><add>Mr.</add> Neihardt and the audiences <hi rend="underline">express</hi> themselves as deeply grateful.</p>
                    
                <p>That testimonial you may use, trim or amend under my name or the name of the Springfield English Club. Mildred Norton 1943 <add>1944</add> President</p>
                    
                <p>And now for my own personal statement to the Neihardts. You were too generous with your time and yourself. Personally hungry for someone in touch with untangible realities, I found understanding of my experiences &#8212; too sacred to risk telling to the uninitiated. I am shy and silent about sharing what I also feel too
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0004"/>
                    
                    <fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
                
                    valuable to hide secretively. You gave me courage in my own faith in visions and spiritual contacts.</p>
                    
                <p>Now I <hi rend="underline">quote</hi> exactly:
                    <lb/>
                    My much loved friend wrote this note "Dear Elizabeth: In thinking over Dr. Neihardt's visit to Springfield it is the spiritual "left" which he gave in his informal afternoon talk at your home which lives in my mind. The simple humility with which he told of the religious insight he received from his long hours of communion with Black Elk was impressive. The portions of the Messiah which he read beautifully phrased this message. The glimpses Dr. Neihardt gave of his own personal life and work evidenced the sincerity of his belief in the message in the Messiah. For this rather intimate revealing of such a fine philosophy of life, I am greateful.
                    Most sincerely,
                    Lucy C. Williams</p>
                  
                <pb facs="nei.j4.20.19-24_0005"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                
                <p>"Being completely frank, I must admit that even after three semesters of literature, I had no interests in poets or poetry of any kind until I heard Neihardt. Poetry, which I had always connected with the feminine, has become real and close to life. The interest stirred by Neihardt has led me to the discovery of Walt Whitman"
                    <lb/>
                    James Maddox (H.S. Senior)</p>

                <p>"Books betray the character of their authors. In the epic literature of Neihardt I have detected a keen interest for human life, a hungry desire for the freshness of nature, and a sincere <del>lif</del> love for the philosophical,"
                    <lb/>
                    Jack Baldwin (Senior)</p>
                
                <p>"When I was very young, I got a big thrill from the stories of pioneers, Indian Wars and the old West. As I progressed in years, I grew out of this, and this type of story became distasteful to me. For the last three years I have heartily condemned any story of cowboys, Indians, traders or trappers.</p>
                
                <p>Then I read <hi rend="underline">The Song of Jed Smith</hi>. It interested me, puzzled me, set me thinking in a way I had thought no tale of exploration or the great west could again. Indeed it gave me a different slant on life &#8212; in that I had</p>
            
                <!--likely a page or some text missing here-->
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.20.19-24_0006"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Elizabeth <hi rend="caps">E.</hi> Graham
                    502 <hi rend="caps">S</hi> State Street
                    Springfield Illinois
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    SPRINGFIELD
                    OCT 28 
                    1 PM
                    <unclear/>
                    ILL.
                    
                    BU<unclear/>
                    WAR SA<unclear/>
                    BONDS AND <unclear/>
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p><unclear/>UNITED STATES POSTAGE</p>
                </figure>    
                
                <note type="recipient">Testimonials from Springfield Ill</note>
                    
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi>Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Joseph <hi rend="caps">S.</hi>Duncan Department</addrLine>
                        <addrLine><hi rend="caps">YMCA</hi></addrLine>
                        <addrLine>1515 <hi rend="caps">W.</hi> Monroe Street</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Chicago Illinois</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>