<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26c.49a-49c_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from M. Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt, November 7, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26c.49a-49c_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from M. Slade Kendrick to John G. Neihardt, November 7, 1958</title>
                    <date when="1958-11-07">November 7, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.49a-49c_0001-3"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">83-2
                    Neihardt Collection</note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">49a</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        225 Willard Way, Ithaca <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi>
                        Nov. 7, 1958
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear John: &#8212;</salute></opener> <p>How good it was to hear from you, and to get the news, not only of your television programs, your young horses, the exciting plans for republication of your lyrics and dramas, your engagements and the planting of your wheat, but more important <del>to feel</del> of the deathless spirit of you.</p>
                
                <p>And what a name you have for the horse, Bourbon Stonewall. It sings, and of the South.</p>
                
                <p>Well, I <del><unclear>have</unclear></del><add>am</add> up to some things, as you can see by the attached. I wrote to the program directors of the <hi rend="caps">N. B C.</hi> and the <hi rend="caps">C.B S.</hi> suggesting that each send a scout to Columbia to see you on television. The <hi rend="caps">N.B.C.</hi> man replied. I send his letter, my reply, and a letter from another official. Why do I send these? Well, I must seem now not to speak to the point. But, as it happens, one of my former students, a professor in the <hi rend="caps">U.</hi> of Hawaii, is trying to get me out there to teach in summer school. I doubt if it goes through, but even so his <unclear>thought</unclear> does me good. I appreciate it so much that is why
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.49a-49c_0002"/>
                    
                <fw type="authorial">-2-</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">49b</fw>
                
                    I am telling you about this attempt on my part to give you a wider audience. It may come to nothing, but even so I think you will want to know about it.</p>
                
                <p>I was in Philadelphia last week when I spoke at the annual meeting of the National Tax Association. The meeting was most pleasant. I met old friends, and I have made a few more. And then I learned a good bit. I took occasion also to visit the art gallery and Independence Hall. The time and circumstances are far away. Still it did me good to look into the very hall in which our nation was born.</p>
                
                <p>We were out to Jim's and Pauline's last Sunday. The young people whom we visited when you were here Jim still treasures your map of the Custer fight. Possibly you recall that he took a picture of you <add>with the <unclear>horse</unclear> as background</add> It turned out to be excellent. And now my copy stands on the mantle above the fireplace.</p>
                
                <p>We have had a glorious fall. Never, I think, <del>have</del><add>were</add> the colors more beautiful. The very air seems to be suffused with their beauty. The effect made me think of the Grand
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26c.49a-49c_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-3-</fw> 
                <fw type="curatorial">49c</fw>
                
                    Canyon when the colors seemed to swirl in the great deeps. Another singular event has been the great flocks of geese that have gone "Southering". While waiting for a half hour at a filling station I saw four or five such flocks. <del>Why</del><add>What</add> symbols of freedom they are, going on their own, paying no passage, and asking for no permission, these many many years.</p>
                
                <p>And now has come the season of my <unclear>heavy</unclear> drinking, nearly a gallon of sweet cider a week. But I drink more than <add>the</add> cider. I drink the sunshine and the rain of the summer, the fragrance of apple blossoms <add>with spring</add> and the <add><unclear>recent</unclear></add> sweetness of the earth.</p>
                
                <p>Nita is fine. Her teaching, as usual, goes well. And now and then she brings home things of surpassing goodness baked by her students.</p>
                
                <p>May all continue to go well, my dear friend.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Affectionately,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Slade</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
