<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 25
Sunday night, October 26, 1969

Dear John,
<p>Many thanks for the lovely letter; I've been up to the hairline in footnotes or you would have heard from me sooner. They are all checked now except for Laurel Decade, which I am working on. In fact, I'm right at the point you reached in almost every <underline>Song</underline>--so nearly though that it's a temptation to rush the job through and finish. But you resisted the impulse and so shall I; the tone of this chapter must be exactly right, and I decided last night that there is a bad gap. I have no <underline>current</underline> letters form "everywhere" and from famous people about your work and you. I know there are many, many--so I have rushed a request off to the Missouri library for Xerox copies. I f you have any there you would speciallly like to have quoted, send me a copy. Quick. I have plently of citations from letters in the 50's and early 60's, but since I got into the book I haven't pressed you to keep me up to date. This last chapter is close to lyric.</p>
<p>Thank you much for the quote from Gail. I have always liked Gail and I have great respect for her opinion. Also, bless her dear heart, she said the magic words--I made you seem real. You are real, but you are so made of light that poor gropers find it hard to believe <underline>anyone</underline> is like that. Perhaps that's the value of the book by me after all; maybe it will convince people you really are true.</p>
<p>So Willa was at Nebraska too--not there in person, but in hooding. She got them *both *(both degrees, that is!) then--I had no news accounts of the Nebraska one, but I did have news stories on the Creighton. She must have been following you. I do appreciate the copy--and tahnk Florence for me. When I get this all done, I shall write her a long letter of appreciation myself. She is tremendous.</p>
<p>Working with the letters from you in the 60's I have developed one very strong feeling--an achey sort of nostalgia for your visits here, and all the talk and gleam and glow of affection. I wish I thought you could ever be here again. I know you ought not to travel, and I wouldn't want you to have the long trip, but ths house was and is blessed by you, and we feel your spirit here. I think Jingle feels it too, and wishes you would come and drink beer with her. She has never tasted beer, but she knows things because the dog-people do;  maybe Jacques sends her messanges in the night winds. Anyway I hope I can see you in the spring or fall. When the book comes out I do think I ought to be there to hand you the first copy off the press, don't <underline>you</underline> think?</p>
<p>(I'm eager to see the new sections of the Memoires. Any repeated material will be reinforcing to both accounts; you must not worry about <underline>my</underline> worrying about our books conflicting. I'm totally, thoroughly, delightedly glad you are writing your memories; they should be written so that people hundreds of years from now can read them. You're not like anybody else, and the Spingtime Eighties of John Neihardt give a special depth to the memoires.)</p>
<p>About the review--Sergel did the one in the <underline>Midland</underline>, and it contains the passage you mean, I think; I still can't find any review by him on <underline>Friends</underline>. I've tried to think what publication he would be likely to write</p>
Page 26
<p>for; I would guess one of the Midwest quaterlies, but so far I haven't found a trace. What I want is the review that says what I said myself (perhaps I got the idea from you, though)--that Hugh Glass is Biblical and the Friends Greek. I have found some nice reviews of your work by William Lyon Phelps.</p>
<---<p>The manuscript is being typed, and as soon as it is all ready I will send you the whole thing. Laurel Decade I will send ahead, in my own type; it's not terribly long and I hope it won't have errors. As I said before, I wish you would cast your eagiest eye over the footnotes in the final manuscript; some of the corrections you wanted are taken care of there whenever they were the kind of qualification or addition that might have interrupted the flow of idea in the text. I have checked and rechecked, but I wouldn't want to say there are no errors. Sometimes, alas, the sources are wrong about details, especially if the citation is to a newspaper. If you find errors, I will catch them in the manuscript before it goes into proof; the publisher may have suggestions also. I don't think you need to bother with the bibliography, but I will include it for you to see; the mass of material about you is pretty impressive, even though I'm not mentioning everything--I don't want the bibliography to run longer than the book. Checking all these items (more than you can believe!) is a way of loving you, and I have enjoyed it--even the microfilm.</p>
<p>Well, I must get to work again. Please give my love to the dear Youngs and tell them I will write everybody when I can; right now I'm too deep in your laurels to stop for letters to anyone but you. Give my love to Jacques, the wise little dog-person too; Jingle sends both of you leaps and licks of love. Stewart also said to send him regards. He and Susan are estatic as they should be, and Stewart is a Very Responsible Married Man--old Stewart, who once kicked a Poet out of bed, is now Head of a House!</p>
<p>Rush me any late honors or significant news you want incorporated in the chapter--I can still get it in if I hear it now. Only, PLEASE don't get elected Governor or Senator or anything; that would take a new section! Are you thinking of doing the "I Could Be Young?" lyrics? One of the interview clippings mentions it. TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF HARD--it's getting flu weather, and we all need you well.</p>
<p>Love form me of the extra-special, high-grade quality, in great amounts.</p>
<signed>Lucile</signed>