<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.13.29-32_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lew Sarett to John G. Neihardt, December 28, 1928</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.13.29-32_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lew Sarett to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1928-12-28">December 28, 1928</date>
                    <extent>4 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.13.29-32_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">LEW SARETT
                        <lb/>
                    LAONA
                        <lb/>
                    FOREST COUNTY
                        <lb/>
                    WISCONSIN</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>December 28, 1928</dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear John Neihardt:</salute>
                    <note type="curatorial">St. Louis, Mo.</note>
                </opener>
                <p>So many times in the past half dozen years I've thought of you; so many times I've been moved to shout across from my Montana, Minnesota, and Wisconsin to you and your Nebraska, your Missouri River and your plains&#8212;&#8212;to throw you a big round friendly "Hail", and to cry out "I'm with you, lock, stock, and barrel".</p>
                
                <p>But the impulse would never get as far as paper. Perhaps because one is rather reticent; or disposed to be a solitary&#8212;&#8212;to go one's <del>one</del> way alone, taking no chances of personal rebuff and asking odds of no man. Perhaps because one is infernally&#8212;&#8212;and happily&#8212;&#8212;busy writing, so busy from month to month with university work, plat<del/><add>f</add>orm work, writing, that he rarely finds time to write the kind of letter that I've been moved to write. And so not<del>iw</del><add>wi</add>thstanding our community of literary interests, our <del>k</del><add>l</add>iterary kinship, we are still in a sense strangers. That shouldn't be.</p>
                
                <p>I wanted to write you when I read a most interesting article on you and on your work in a recent number of <hi rend="underline">Present-Day American Literature</hi>. It was an admirable s<del>ot</del><add>to</add>ry. It gave me a better grip of your work. Of course, I had know<add>n</add> admired "The Song of Hugh Glass" for years (it may interest you to know that the late Stuart Pratt Sherman first drew the book to my attention and read a long passage from it to me and spoke in superlatives of the poem). But the article <del/><add>reve</add>aled facts with which I was not so familiar. I thought so much of the story that I filed it for use in a course on "Modern Poetry" that I am organizing now and shall offer in a year or two&#8212;&#8212;and speci<del>l</del><add>a</add>lize in the rest of my life&#8212;&#8212;at Northwestern University.</p>
                
                <p>This morning I picked up the July number of <hi rend="underline">Present-Day American Literature</hi> which I had set aside against an hour when I could read carefully your article on "Contemporary Literature". I was so stirred by the story and I am in <add>such</add> unq<del><unclear>au</unclear></del><add>ua</add>lified agreement with litera<del>ry</del><add>ll</add>y everything you say that I am moved to break my reticen<del>s</del><add>c</add>e and to extend you my congratulations, a friend<add>ly</add> grip, and my most cordial wishes.</p>
                
                <p>I was so pleased by your attitude on literary matters, on the present literary vogue, on the left wing, on literary posturers and imposters, on the pontifical cliques and cults that are striving to tell us what is poetry and what is not. I've been fight for years all over this
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.13.29-32_0002"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">30</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">LEW SARETT
                        <lb/>
                    LAONA
                        <lb/>
                    FOREST COUNTY
                        <lb/>
                    WISCONSIN</hi>
                </fw>
                    
                    the smug bored metropolitanites, the <del/> blasè disillusioned decadents of New York City whose knowledge of life is limited and second-handed, if the aenemic aesthetes who have never known the cosmic beauty of the wild earth, who have never known the robust beauty of the wild earth, who have <del><unclear>k</unclear></del><add>n</add>ever known the robust beauty and the robust tragedy of the round raw laughter and the stifled weeping of the granitic folk of America&#8212;&#8212;if these prevail, then you and I may as well lay down our pens right now.</p>
                
                <p>But, my dear Neihardt, I am not laying my pen down; nor are you! I believe profoundly that every writer who is knuckling under to the vogues, the creeds, the high priests, that every such compromiser is committing literary suicide. You and I will live to see the day when their <del/> intolerant utterances will be under the dust of oblivion.</p>
                
                <p>Why do I feel that so profoundly.I'll tell you why. The human <add>race</add>,&#8212; you, I, and all of us,&#8212; always has found and always will find life quite meaningless, if not altogether tragic and futile, unless it has some high dream to fight for, to li<del/><add>v</add>e for, to strugl<del>l</del><add>e</add><del>e</del> toward, some star or cluster of stars to hold its eyes on, some beauty on which to nourish its soul. There are multitudes of stars in the sky.Each writer sees certain stars, and perhaps not others that are in the sky. Nature, heredity, environment,&#8212;&#8212;these make some of sensitive to certain aspects of the wor<del>d</del><add>l</add>d and others of us responsive to other facets of life. For you it is the high dream, the star, of the heroic American pioneer, the beauty of American frontiers etc; for me it <del>s</del><add>i</add>s the high dream of the beauty, the truth, the significance of the wild earth of America. For Robert Frost it is New England; for Carl Sandburg it is the Middle West, the social underdog, the sand and the syllables of America;and  so it goes. There are many many stars. It doesn't much difference what they are&#8212;&#8212;first magnitude, third, or fi<del><unclear>th</unclear></del><add>ft</add>h&#8212;&#8212;or where they shine in the sky. As long as they are stars toward which people may grope. The human race will always, eventually, reach for the things that put stars in the immense black of night. It will reach desperately sometimes; it may forget to look for a time, but it will inevitably come back. It has to hold its eyes on stars or else it will go down to death. And the human race knows that, senses that.</p>
                
                <p>And now I should like to ask:what stars do some of our literary friends put into the universe? our friends who discount with a sneer every decent clean sweet aspiration of the race? every effort of some of us<del>e</del> to lift ourselves out of the biological slime in which the
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.13.29-32_0003"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">31</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">LEW SARETT
                        <lb/>
                    LAONA
                        <lb/>
                    FOREST COUNTY
                        <lb/>
                    WISCONSIN</hi>
                </fw>
                    
                    country for the very convictions that are yours. I've uttered some of the things you express in your article. But, goodness, how admirably you put them here! I knew that you could write poetry of the purest water; I did not know that you were so skil<del><unclear>full</unclear></del>ful in prose. I envy you that skill! (Before I forget it, will you be kind enough to send me a copy of the address, or series of addresses, on poetry, etc, that you later embodied in a book; I don't know the title of it <add>is</add>, but I've heard good things of it and I want to read it now.Will you be kind enough to inscribe the book? and have your publisher send me the bill? I'll be very grateful to you.<add>)</add></p> 
                
                <p>There is so much I should like to talk with you about; and a letter is so inadequate. You and I are fighting much the same literary fight&#8212;&#8212;for the same ideals in writing, for the same high far clear stars. We are bucking&#8212;&#8212;and I shall buck until I die&#8212;&#8212;the same petty pontifical opportunistic decadent compromising literary cults, cliques, and high priests. You and I are working in the same field, America, her wild earth, her heroic primative people, her wilderness, her heroic story. Not that we are doing the same work! We do not overlap or crowd one another in the slightest; you are working in one section of the field and I am in another. You are splendidly equipped<del>to</del> to work in the stubborn rock in one portion of the field; by nature you are equipped to do the big swinging epic things&#8212;&#8212;not all of us can do that&#8212;&#8212;I can't do the objective themes so well. Myself, I am by nature more subjective than objective&#8212;&#8212;I don't know how to express <add>it</add>. <del><unclear>B</unclear></del><add>I</add>n any event, we do not overlap. And yet we are both working shoulder to shoulder to lay hold of the heart of America&#8212;&#8212;the America of forest and plain and mountain, of the heroic, epic, tragic, and true people whose strength and beauty are derived from the wild earth of America. In one sense we stand or fall together.</p>
                
                <p>If the present literary vogue prevails; if the present philosophy that underlies much of our literature&#8212;&#8212;the gospel of the futility and the frustration of life, the gospel of cynicism, iconoclasm, and bilious pessi<del>sm&#8212;&#8212;</del><add>mism&#8212;</add> if this shall continue forever; <del/><add>i</add>f the poetic cliques who are struggling to hold the focus of literature on manner rather than matter, on novelty of punctuation, syntax, and manner rather than on universality of them<add>e</add> and of experience&#8212;&#8212;if they succeed in fixing that focus forever; if the smart-alecks,
                
                <!--likely some text missing here, was not scanned-->
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.13.29-32_0004"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">32</fw>
                   
                <fw type="letterhead">    
                    <hi rend="caps">LEW SARETT
                        <lb/>
                    LAONA
                        <lb/>
                    FOREST COUNTY
                        <lb/>
                    WISCONSIN</hi>
                </fw>
                
                    human race was originally cradled? The glitter of Freud? To hell with Freud; no man ever saw sustained beauty in contemplating forever his <del/> navel and his organs. Of Nietsche? Some of <add>us</add> see more shining splendor in the gentle Jesus that he strove to annihilate (I am not talking about the the<add>o</add>logical Jesus and church formalism but about the Man who <add>left</add> the crass human race a bit more compassionate, gentle, tender). The star of <hi rend="caps">H.L.</hi>Menken and his tribe? To hell with them. I cannot believe, my dear friend, that the human race will long be content with <del><unclear>worshiping</unclear></del> holding its eyes on a firmament like that.</p>
                
                <p>And so some of us, some of us who see, or believe we see, beauty in the world and in the race, go our own way quietly, stoically, and confidentally. You are one. I am one. And there are many many others. And we are sustained in that confidence, many of us, by the many fighting loyal spirits who are likewise resisting the momentary pressure of this after-the-war age, who are <del/> thinking straight and true and high, and who are resolute. We are sustained <del/> by the consciousness of these fine kindred spirits.</p> 
                
                <p>Hence this letter to you; my thanks to you for your fine gallant article; and a warm friendly grip.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>
                
                    <signed>Lew Sarett</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P.S.</hi></opener> <p>Do read January <hi rend="underline">Poetry</hi> &#8212; Harriet <unclear>Moore's</unclear> editorial "Why Not Laugh?" It will move you to throw up your hat!</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
