<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36.22-26">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Gail to John G. Neihardt, February 15, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36.22-26</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Gail to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-02-15">February 15, 1972</date>
                    <extent>4 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>4 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>4 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.22"/>
                
                <fw type="curtorial">22</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        1972
                        February 15
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Gaki,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>How are you? We all certainly miss you. Of course, I am glad you are there since you were able to turn out an absolutely marvelous ending piece for this first part of your autobiography. Let me join the growing list of fans who have read it and think it masterful and jus<unclear>t</unclear> what the people of this coutnry need to hear. You really outdid yourself on this one. It is bully! (To borrow your favorite expression!)</p>
                
                <p>I am so glad to be working for mother and in a small way to help you. So many things are going on your pot is really simmering now <unclear>&#8212;</unclear> soon to boil over. I am delighted to hear of all the promoting of Neihar<unclear>dt</unclear> there in Nebraska &#8212; the Arbor Day affair sounds like a real honor. They picked a perfect tree for the celebration &#8212; the glory and hope of that tree "so high in such a happines<unclear>s</unclear> of air!" With such a symbol, nothin<unclear>g</unclear> but success will follow.</p> 
                
                <p>You know dear Gaki I am quite schizophrenic where you are concerned! I shan't go to any psychiatrist to get straightened out because this division of you helps me cope with a wonderful problem.</p> 
                
                <fw>1</fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.23"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial"><unclear>2-</unclear></fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                
                <p>First of all you are my dear wonderful Grandfather &#8212; I too think as the Indians that Grandfather is the term of highest respect, and love. I do love you dear Grandfather and I love to think of all the happy times you have given us as kids and now as adults. Swims in the "creek that runs and sings", moonlight poetry recitations by a happy fire, the making of arrows for home made bows, rides on the now famous "El Capitan" that could chase a squirrel up a tree (I really did believe it could and I hope I never come to think the contrary!) All these things, but mostly the love and concern that you show so well. It is all beyon<unclear>d</unclear> my poor power to describe, but know tha<unclear>t</unclear> I know I have a grandfather beyond all Grandfathers. you have given me so much a love for the Greeks and "the best that men have thought and done." I have sort of claimed your lyric <hi rend="underline">The Child's Heritage</hi> as my own, for you certain<unclear>ly</unclear> have passed on a great deal to me.</p> 
                
                <p>Secondly, of course, I think of you as the greatest writer ever to honor Americ<unclear>a</unclear> no, the world. You may think that extravagant perhaps, but I do not. For beauty, and flashes into deep insight, no one can surpass you. Each time I read your works, I am left amazed that you are truly a mortal &#8212; it is glorious to read what you have written &#8212; the consistent beauty and craftsmanship are astoundin<unclear>g</unclear> and I do believe a person could live well and deeply using the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi> as a guide.</p> 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.24"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-3</fw>
                <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                
                <p>So you see I must be a little schizophrenic <unclear>in</unclear> order to honor my two wonderful grandfathers rolled into one. I feel quite honored myself knowing that I am <unclear>an</unclear> member of your family by a lucky twist of fate. I want you to know all this because <unclear>it</unclear> is all too easy not to express deep feelings and I really want to tell you all this.</p> 
                
                <p>Are you hard at work writing more? I am eager to see more. I know you have difficulties; bu<unclear>t</unclear> you are getting Homeric!</p>
                
                <p>Bill and I are getting along just fine. Bill has been up late at night studying physics, chemistry and math &#8212; he is planning to take the medical school entrance test in May. The Ralston-Purina work does not really satisfy his need to work his mind and use to the fullest his abilities. I think he would make a great doctor, bu<unclear>t</unclear> I am not pushing too hard becau<unclear>se</unclear> I want this to be his decision. Of course, I shall not be found lackin<unclear>g</unclear> in the giving of encouragement!</p> 
                
                <p>Robin is giving guitar lessons now. He could easily be a master of classical guitar. I hope it works out that he can gain recognition of his 
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.25"/>
                
                <fw type="authorial">-4-</fw> 
                <fw type="curatorial">25</fw>
                    
                    talents in the future. He has a feeling for his music and he loves it so much. At times he feels down because he <del>cannot</del><add>feels</add> he should be providing for his family. But I think his family will only be really happy if he is happy but it is hard for him right now to see it. Laura is working at the Student Health Center at the University and she is quite satisfied with her job.</p> 
                
                <p>Alexis of course is working hard too! She has ever so many pictures to produce, clothes to fold and toys to scatter around. She talks about Goki quite often!</p>
                
                <p>Well, I guess that is about all. I am quite happy to hear all the good news from Nebraska and the many plans. They will all work out splendiferously I know.</p> 
                
                <p>Lots of love to you dear Gaki</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Gail</signed> 
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36.26"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    Hilda <hi rend="caps">N.</hi> Petri
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">ATTORNEY-AT-LAW
                        <lb/>
                    ___________________________________
                        <lb/>
                    110 NORTH EIGHTH STREET 
                        <lb/>
                    COLUMBIA, MISSOURI</hi> 65201 
                </ab>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    COLUMBIA, MO
                    FEB 15
                    PM
                    1972
                    6<unclear/>
                </ab>
                <figure> 
                    <figDesc>8 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>8<unclear reason="missing"/> EISENHOWER'US<unclear reason="missing"/></p>
                </figure>
                
                <note type="recipient">
                    <hi rend="underline">Gail's Grandfather letter</hi>: 
                
                    Ansd. <hi rend="double underline">2-16-72</hi> 
                </note>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>c/o <hi rend="caps">J.D.</hi> Young</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>5835 Vine Street</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, Nebraska 68505</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note><unclear/></note>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">26</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>