<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.8.6-7_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from H. B. Alexander to John G. Neihardt, June 19, 1921</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.8.6-7_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from H. B. Alexander to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1921-06-19">June 19, 1921</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.6-7_0001" />
                
                <fw type="curatorial">6</fw>
                
                <fw type="letterhead">
                    <hi rend="caps">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA
                        <lb/>
                    LINCOLN
                        <lb/>
                    
                    DEPARTMENT OF PHILOSOPHY</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>June 19, 1921</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                    <note type="curatorial">Branson, Mo</note>
                </opener>
                <p>I want to express to you my sincere regret that it was not possible for us to have some sort of a conversation during your all to<sic>too</sic> brief stay in Lincoln. This regret is heightened by the fact that your paper &#8212;&#8212; which aroused my unqualified enthusiasm &#8212;&#8212; touched so many topics which I should dearly love to prod about in your company. I was particularly pleased with your exposition of the office of poetry, which is indeed close to what I have been trying to expres in various ways, as also with the glimpses given of the metaphysics which underlies your doctrine,&#8212;&#8212; for I can clearly see that you are a poet with a philosophy (was ever true poet without one ?), and that philosophy the only one which has ever made poets.</p>
                
                <p>But I was also eager to take up more closely the questions of poetic art and qualities which you raised. In the main, I am wholly with you where the issue of "free verse" is up. Nevertheless, I have some qualms; for I find in my own endeavors that certain subjects seem to gain very much from the free style of treatment. In particular, I have seemed to find this true of Amerindian themes which I have undertaken. There is a certain reticence and ellipsis in Indian thought which somehow seems to get itself best expressed (so far as my own powers go) in the inconclusive lines which so readily find place in free verse. I do not, of course, mean to say that there is no rhythm present,&#8212;&#8212; the tonal rhythm which you so aptly characterized is certainly important, and beyond this is the form of the whole which is gained by repetition and return of phrase, but rhyme (for the most part) and too regular meter seem out of place. Occasionally, also, other types of theme have seemed to me to take naturally to the free poem form,&#8212;&#8212; just as naturally as
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.8.6-7_0002"/>
                    <fw type="authorial">(2)</fw>
                    <fw type="curatorial">7</fw>
                
                the demand for rigid adherence to meter and rhyme in the majority of my inspirations. I use this latter word in default: meaning by it such suggestions of theme and expression as come by nature,&#8212;&#8212; perhaps a line which builds its own stanza and defines its own poem; very often, a melody which, since it is born with words, adds its own tonality to the verbal. This latter propensity &#8212;&#8212; an inner singing in a literal sense &#8212;&#8212; I find to be an incumbrance to my own judgment. Once a "song" has come &#8212;&#8212; music with words for its notes &#8212;&#8212; I find it virtually imposible to read the piece with the ear unattuned; hence, impossible to see just how little there is in it. For such natural lyrics I certainly need the critic's aid, when it comes to matter of selection; and I should be thankful indeed were a man of your gifts near to lend me judgment. One reason which has kept me from undertaking the publication of such a collectionas you sug-gested has been my inability to form a satisfactory corpus : I find it difficult to form decisions which I feel I can stand by. It may be, however, that (encouraged by you) I may undertake the bringing out of a group. My "Odes" &#8212;&#8212; which you may have seen &#8212;&#8212; have been long out of print and are occasionally called for. I should like to reprint them along with other pieces. I have also in mind a volume of prairie and mid-west peices, to comprise the Indian interpretations. But for this I must wait at least a year, as some of them are to appear in periodicals, which take their own time for publishing. I hope, too, to be able to add to the number as a result of the planned vacation in the southwest.</p>
                
                <p>All this is much about personal affairs &#8212;&#8212; not exactly what I started out to write. I hope that you will forgive it, to your own expression of interest and to the fact that the topic of poetry is one in regard to which few care to converse. I am venturing to send you a few reprints which you may find of interest.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Very sincerely yours,</salute>
                
                    <signed>H.B. Alexander</signed>
                    <note type="curatorial">H.B. Alexander</note>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I have written to James suggesting that he send you the <unclear/> on Indian myth for review.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

