<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Page 23
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

Sept. 24, 1970

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505

Dear Dr. Neihardt:
<p>So good to see your handwriting again. I am so glad the biography is well on the way to seeing print. I look forward to it. Then it is good to see the SPLENDID WAYFARING and WHEN THE TREE FLOWERED both in print again. The University Press is doing well by you. Are they printing Mrs. Aly's book too?</p>
<p>I can understand your reluctance to go to Europe after you and Mona had made plans and hadn't been able to go together. It would be more fun to see it with someone you loved than to see it alone.</p>
<p>Stan Smith called me the other day to ask if I would read his thesis about you and your letters. Of course, I am delighted to do so. The thesis hasn't come yet, but I am looking forward to a good time with it.</p>
<p>I am glad to have in your own handwriting that you and Willa sat together and visited during your honorary degrees. I think you had told me this some time ago, but now I have it in writing. People sometimes ask me if you two knew each other.</p>
<p>Our son Bill is doing his internship in Omaha and is very happy with medicine. His wife is teaching retarded children(special education) across the river near Council Bluffs. She feels somewhat frustrated in making progress with them.</p>
<p>I have been doing a little writing for a company in Des Miones which wants concise studies on great authors for high school teachers to use in their notebooks. Right now I am doing John Milton. He is a most fascinating man. The thing that amazes me about great writers is that so often they aren't great men.</p>
<p>That is what gives me great pleasure in knowing you. You are both a great writer and a great man--and the combination is rare.</p>
<p>This brings all the affection from the whole family. Take care of yourself.</p>
Love from us all,
<signed>Mildred </signed>
Mildred

Page 24
MILDRED R. BENNETT
329 North Cedar
RED CLOUD, NEBRASKA 68970

Ink Stamp: RED CLOUD, NE SEP 24 PM 1970 68970
Stamp: <unclear reason="folded and smudged"/>

Dr. John G. Neihardt
5835 Vine St.
Lincoln, Nebr. 68505