<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.34.12.23">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, April 3, 1970</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile F. </author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.34.12.13</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Neihardt, April 3, 1970</title>
<date when="1970-04-03"></date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
<term>When The Tree Flowers</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/50467731">Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1970-04-03"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.34.12.13.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">12</fw>
<note type="curatorial"></note>

<opener>
<dateline>April 3, 1970
</dateline>
<salute>Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<p>I promised you no more delays, but I didn't count on Bower's landing in the hospital twice with gout, or an influx of Easter visitors. Nothing stopped the work, though; the manuscript is almost already. I enclose a copy of the bibliography, which is now being typed. This copy is almost right; it has the major corrections, but not all of the minor. I thought the time it would take for close proof reading could be better spent on the final copy of footnotes--checking those takes forever. This will give you the general idea, anyway--I thought you should see what a body has to read to write your biography!</p>

<p>I'm glad you are getting along with the memoir; it's fortunate for the world that you wanted to do it. Do you ever hear a lyric spinning in your head? The sales of the books are no more than should be--but I'm happy about them too. One of my teacher friends told me last week a girl in her class read <hi rend="underline">Black Elk</hi> and loved it; I lent the teacher <hi rend="underline">When the Tree Flowers</hi> to read to the class.</p>

<p>Tell me something. Did the Falling Star story ever come out separately as a book for children? There was some talk of it in the letters of the early 50's and then I didn't follow that up. Macmillan apparently had the idea of a children's book for a Christmas edition. Did it go through?</p>

<p>I've had a very fine letter from Ollie; he had just read the manuscript except for the last chapter, and he seemed to like it. I specially wanted his view on the Post-Dispatch part, and he filled in one or two details for me. Bower is waiting to read the last part also; both he had Ollie make comments that help, as you do. I really couldn't tell you how wonderful the whole process of the dissertation and the biography have been for me; I wonder if <hi rend="underline">anybody</hi> has had such a chance before to study a great man the world</p>

<note type="curatorial">13</note>
<note type="authorial">-2-</note>
<p>should know about, and also study his work? I'm glad Stanley likes the dissertation; I still like it too, and I get the impression now and then taht it gets around. One of the graduate students here told me the other day that she had run into a reference to it somewhere. That means a reference to you, which was the ultimate purpose of the dissertation.</p>

<p>I am also, as you see, enclosing a letter--a copy of mine to Mr. Nicoll. All along, as I told you, I felt obligated to send the manuscript to him first; he has sent me a contract which is the standard one put out by the Board of Regents, an dit looks fine. I wrote to Yale Press and talked to the Holt editors when they were out here. They are both willing to approach their trade men, but they cautioned me that commercial publishers are not much exhilarated by critical biography. Bower and I talked this over pretty carefully several times, specially after the contract arrived, and, as you see by my letter to Mr. Nicoll, I want to see what they plan for promotion before I sign. I would like to have Nebraska Press publish the book, because I think really they respect and know you as no other publisher would right now. <hi rend="underline">If</hi> they plan a real promotion, they might do a better job than one of the big companies that has hundreds of books to push--and a constant turnover of editors. That one things gives me pause on a commerical company; editors shift from house to house so much you may send the manuscript to an enthusiastic man who is gone before the readers' reports are in.</p>

<p>Bower is out of the woods, we think. He had terrible pain with this bout of gout--in the knee
this time, and dreadfull! It doesn't cheer him at all to be told that gout is a disease of intelligent men, common to the political greats. He doesn't at this point care who had it, he doesn't want it!</p>

<p>I must now go read footnotes--final copy. Take care of the Great Poet and DON't GET FLU! I wish I could come and see you this afternoon, but I'll get there in the summer. We all send love, and I'll write again shortly. I will also send you a copy of the <hi rend="underline">whole</hi> manuscript. </p>

<closer>
<salute></salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>