<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0001-4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Hermann Hagedorn to John G. Neihardt, July 30, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0001-4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Hermann Hagedorn to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-07-30">July 30, 1957</date>
                    <extent>7 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>7 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>7 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">14a</fw>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>Theodore Roosevelt, in profile, inside a circle</figDesc>
                        <p>MDCCCLVIII MCMXIX</p>
                    </figure>
                    
                    1858-1958
                    
                    <hi rend="caps">THEODORE ROOSEVELT CENTENNIAL COMMISSION
                    THEODORE ROOSEVELT HOUSE
                    28 EAST 20TH STREET, NEW YORK 3, N.Y.
                    TELEPHONE: ALGONQUIN 4-1700
                    
                    ESTABLISHED BY
                    ACT OF CONGRESS
                    APPROVED JULY 28, 1955
                    
                    COMMISSIONERS
                    EX OFFICIO
                    THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
                    THE VICE PRESIDENT,</hi> <hi rend="italics">Chairman</hi>
                    <hi rend="caps">THE SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE
                    OF REPRESENTATIVES
                    UNITED STATES SENATE
                    KARL E. MUNDT, SOUTH DAKOTA
                    JOSEPH C. O'MAHONEY, WYOMING</hi>
                    <hi rend="italics">Vice Chairman</hi>
                    <hi>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
                    STEVEN B. DEROUNIAN, NEW YORK
                    LEO W. O'BRIEN, NEW YORK
                    MEMBERS AT LARGE
                    MRS. HAZEL H. ABEL, NEBRASKA
                    C. NORMAN BRUNSDALE, NORTH DAKOTA
                    HAL DAVIES, NORTH DAKOTA
                    HERMANN HAGEDORN, NEW YORK</hi>
                    <hi rend="italics">Director and Secretary</hi>
                    <hi rend="caps">MRS. SHERMAN POST HAIGHT, CONNECTICUT
                    HERBERT MILLEN, PENNSYLVANIA
                    LOWELL STOCKMAN, OREGON
                    OSCAR S. STRAUS II, NEW YORK
                    _______
                    CONRAD L. WIRTH</hi>
                    <hi rend="italics">Fiscal Officer</hi>
                    <hi rend="caps">SIDNEY WALLACH</hi>
                    <hi rend="italics">Assistant Director</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>July 30, 1957</dateline>
                
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Skyrim Farm Route 6</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>In behalf of the Theodore Roosevelt Centennial Commission, I have the honor to invite you to become a member of a National Committee of Sponsors of the Theodore Roosevelt Centennial Observance. The enclosed folder will tell you in general terms the aims of the Commission and how we hope to attain them. Your name on the Committee will help us toward that end. No service or contribution beyond the use of your name will be asked of you, though we should naturally be grateful for any active cooperation that you might care to give in the formation of a state committee, or in other ways.</p>
                
                <p>Permit me to quote from a recent Interim Report of the Commission: "It is not a question merely of honoring one more great American. It is a question of establishing in the American heart a tradition that may change the course of history: the tradition of Theodore Roosevelt's courage, forthrightness and practical idealism; his passion for America and the principles of free government that it represents; his insistence that national strength and national greatness rest on individual character and the cultivation of moral and spiritual values." To this, let me add a passage from the Commission's inital report to Congress: "We of the Commission have set out to kindle in the American heart today the kind of fire that blazed in the heart of Theodore Roosevelt. If we are effective in doing this we shall do better than commemorate history; we shall be making it."</p>
                
                <p>May we hope that you may want to have a part in this endeavor? If so, please return the enclosed card with your signature.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Yours sincerely,</salute>
                    <signed>Herman Hagedorn</signed>
                    <signed>Hermann Hagedorn
                    Director</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0002a"/>
                
                <ab><hi rend="caps">CLOSING THE OBSERVANCE</hi></ab>
                
                <p>The dedication of the Island on October 27, 1958, the hundredth anniversary of Theodore Roosevelt's birth, will be the natural culmination of the centennial observance.</p>
            
                <ab><hi rend="caps">THEODORE ROOSEVELT
                    <lb/>
                CENTENNIAL COMMISSION</hi></ab>
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>____________________</ab>
                <list>
                    <item><hi rend="caps">EX OFFICIO</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    The President of the United States
                        <lb/>
                    The Vice President, <hi rend="italics">Chairman</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    The Speaker of the House of Representatives</item>
                
                    <item><hi rend="caps">UNITED STATES SENATE</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Karl <hi rend="caps">E.</hi> Mundt, South Dakota
                        <lb/>
                    Joseph <hi rend="caps">C.</hi> O'Mahoney, Wyoming, <hi rend="italics">Vice Chairman</hi></item>
                    
                    <item><hi rend="caps">HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Steven <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Derounian, New York
                    Leo <hi rend="caps">W.</hi> O'Brien, New York</item>
                    
                    <item><hi rend="caps">MEMBERS AT LARGE</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Mrs. Hazel <hi rend="caps">H.</hi> Abel, Nebraska
                        <lb/>
                    <hi rend="caps">C.</hi> Norman Brunsdale, North Dakota
                        <lb/>
                    Hal Davies, North Dakota
                        <lb/>
                    Hermann Hagedorn, New York, <hi rend="italics">Director and Secretary</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Mrs. Sherman Post Haight, Connecticut
                        <lb/>
                    Herbert Millen, Pennsylvania
                        <lb/>
                    Lowell Stockman, Oregon
                        <lb/>
                    Oscar <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Straus II, New York</item>
                    <milestone unit="section"/><ab>___________</ab>
                    <item>Conrad <hi rend="caps">L.</hi> Wirth, <hi rend="italics">Fiscal Officer</hi>
                        <lb/>
                    Sidney Wallach, <hi rend="italics">Assistant Director</hi></item>
                </list>
                
                <note type="curatorial"><hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT CENTER</hi></note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0002b"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">14b</fw>
                
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Portrait of Roosevelt</figDesc>
                    <p><hi rend="italics">Painting by Phillip De Laszlo</hi></p>
                </figure>
                
                A NATION'S GREATNESS LIES IN ITS POSSIBILITIES OF ACHIEVEMENT IN THE PRESENT, AND NOTHING HELPS IT MORE THAN THE CONSCIOUSNESS OF ACHIEVEMENT IN THE PAST. 
                <hi rend="italics">Theodore Roosevelt</hi>
                
                <hi rend="italics">1858 ∙ Theodore Roosevelt Centennial ∙ 1958</hi>
                
                <hi rend="caps">AUTHORITY</hi>
                The national movement to observe the centennial of Theodore Roosevelt was authorized by Act of Congress and is under the leadership of the Theodore Roosevelt Centennial Commission, appointed in part by the President of the United States and in part by the Vice President and the Speaker of the House.
                
                PURPOSE
                The Commission's purpose is to recall Theodore Roosevelt's dynamic Americanism and to make his spirit again a vital factor in American life.
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0003a"/>
                    
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Sagamore Hill</figDesc>
                    <p><hi rend="italics">Sagamore Hill, Theodore Roosevelt's home at Oyster Bay, New York</hi></p>
                </figure>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THEME</hi>
                
                <p>The theme of the observance is <hi rend="caps">RESPONSIBLE CITIZENSHIP.</hi></p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THREE PROJECTS</hi>
                The plan for the observance embraces three projects:
                
                <hi rend="caps">FIRST</hi>, an educational campaign to re-awaken and spread the appreciation of Mr. Roosevelt's teachings of the principles of free citizenship and to restore to its rightful place in the American tradition the example of his forthrightness, his courage and the fire in his heart for what America stands for in history;
                
                <hi rend="caps">SECOND</hi>, the completion by the National Park Service of the Theodore Roosevelt Memorial National Park in North Dakota, in the region where he had his cattle-ranches; and
                
                <hi rend="caps">THIRD</hi>, the development and dedication of the national memorial to Theodore Roosevelt on the island which bears his name in the Potomac River between the Key Bridge and the Arlington Memorial Bridge in Washington, D.C.
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0003b"/>
                    
                <hi rend="caps">THEODORE ROOSEVELT
                MEMORIAL NATIONAL PARK</hi>
                    
                <p>In a setting of bizarre and colorful bad lands, flanking the Little Missouri River, the visitor to the Park will touch the experience of a young man of twenty-five whose initiative and bold leadership served to bring law and order to a turbulent frontier.</p>
                
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Site of Roosevelt's Elkhorn Ranch, Theodore Roosevelt Memorial National Park</figDesc>
                    <p><hi rend="italics">Site of Mr. Roosevelt's Elkhorn Ranch,
                        in Theodore Roosevelt Memorial National Park</hi>
                        <hi rend="caps">PAINTING BY EMILE WALTERS</hi></p>
                </figure>
                
                <p>The Park and the Island memorial will silently &#8212; and far beyond the centennial year &#8212; expound the centennial theme.</p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">OPENING OF THE OBSERVANCE</hi>
                    
                <p>Since the opening of the centennial year, October 27, 1957 &#8212; Mr. Roosevelt's 99th birthday &#812; falls on a Sunday, the centennial observance will be launched in churches and in the religious press with the emphasis on the moral and spiritual values underlying a free society. Communities throughout the nation will also be urged to emphasize those values in the observance of the Fourth of July, 1958. Plans are in preparation for a national conference of clergy and laymen on the same them sometime during the centennial year. It is planned to hold the conference in the rotunda of the Capitol in Washington.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0004a"/>
                
                <hi rend="caps">EDUCATIONAL CAMPAIGN</hi>
                    
                <p>Mr. Roosevelt demonstrated responsible citizenship in every area of his many-sided life, but most conspicuously in the following:
                    <list>
                        <item>1. <hi rend="italics">The home and the family as the crucible of individual character</hi></item>
                    
                        <item>2. <hi rend="italics">The moral and spiritual imperatives of free government</hi></item>
                    
                        <item>3. <hi rend="italics">The citizen's participation in government</hi></item>
                    
                        <item>4. <hi rend="italics">The conservation of the natural resources</hi></item>
                    
                        <item>5. <hi rend="italics">The national defense</hi></item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">CHANNELS OF ACTION</hi>
                
                <p>It is in these fields that the Commission proposes to show Theodore Roosevelt in action. To this end, it expects to utilize all the media of modern mass communication &#8212; radio, television and motion pictures, the press, magazines, books, pamphlets and other printed matter, picture-books (comics), exhibits, film-strips, lectures and addresses.</p>
                
                <p>Other activities, relating to family life and the home, will be in charge of a Woman's Committee, headed by Miss Chloe Gifford, vice president of the General Federation of Women's Clubs.</p>
                    
                <p>A College and University Committee, headed by Dr. Arthur Fleming, a president of Ohio Wesleyan University, formerly chairman of the Office of Defense Mobilization in Washington, will present Mr. Roosevelt's teachings in relation to the citizen's participation in government. A committee of the Council of Natural Resources, an association of the leading conservation organizations in the country, is in charge of the Commission's work in the field of conservation.</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.14a-14b_0004b"/>
                
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>The Island Sanctuary</figDesc>
                    <p><hi rend="italic">Design for the Island Sanctuary</hi></p>
                </figure>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THE ISLAND SANCTUARY</hi>
                
                <p>The Island memorial is conceived as the centennial purpose expressed in stone and bronze: a sanctuary in which granite tablets bearing quotations from Theodore Roosevelt on the principles underlying a free society will be the background for an armillary sphere symbolizing free spirit. Such a memorial will be a challenge to Americans to be mindful of their heritage as well as a place of pilgrimage for the free, throughout the world, seeking fresh inspiration and the opportunity to pay tribute not only to the memory of Theodore Roosevelt but to the free spirit of man. Mr. Eric Gugler is the architect of the sanctuary and Mr. Paul Manship, the sculptor.</p>
        
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
