<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.32.11-12">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter From Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Niehardt</title>
<author>Aly, Lucile Folse</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.32.11-12</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Aly, Lucile Folse</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter From Lucile Folse Aly to John G. Niehardt</title>
<date when="1968-03-21">March 21, 1968</date>
<extent>2 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>

</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>


<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="places">
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="works">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Aly, Lucile Folse</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
<date when="1968-03-21"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName></placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc>
<person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name>Morrison, Ashley</name> Transcription</change>
<change when="2018"><name>Hasan, Sara</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">

<pb facs="nei.j4a.32.11-12.001" />
<fw type="curatorial">1</fw>
<note type="curatorial">1</note>

<opener>
<dateline>March 21, 1968
</dateline>
<salute>(I <underline>think</underline> I'm not sure what day it is!)
Dear John,</salute>
</opener>

<note type="curatorial">Page 11</note>
<p>I'm at the coast and I've been working on the book all day and thinking about you so much I've decided to take a few moments to write you a letter. I'm nearing the end - really at last, and if if doesn't have a new Song to write about, this is the "music of what happens," so I guess if really does hace a Song - the truest of all. I will have to type all this. I work the way you did, first in long hand in <unclear/>, with deep consentration and a <unclear/> of singing inside. I can hear the ocean, and taught I <unclear>own</unclear> full of love for the world. Everyone should write your biography. Imagine a whole library</p>
<note type="curatorial">2</note>
full of biographies of you, and each one someone's own song made with your music as a tree! <unclear/> <unclear/> would ever be the same again - <unclear/> be taller and better and full of singing.

<p>There is something I want you to know about this book. I have not really thought much about its sale or its effect on my "career" - horrible word. (my career is people). I did this for itself. I did it for love - of you and your poetry - and prose - <unclear/> for the people who need you to be in the world to prove its all true, and <underline>possible.</underline> I will be glad if many people read it, but not for myself. Partly for <unclear/>.</p>

<p>The delays have been more agonizing for me then you know. I am like you in this way too - I don't talk about my troubles, but the last few years have been full of the kind of problems one can't escape sometimes. Bower and I have been in a sort of trial by fire - not with each other - but with family things that shake us to the core.</p>

<note type="curatorial">Page 12</note>
<note type="curatorial">3</note>
<p>For my work, because this book is my <unclear/> work, it has been like your years in St. Louis, and I have wished more than once that I could tell you about it. But now that I'm on the point of finishing, I can look back and see that this was a pattern too. it was hard on you, and I'm sorry for that - but it's better book than it would have been if I hadn't had the struggle. I know the moments on the ridge too, and perhaps together we can help other people see that the aren't <unclear>insurmountable</unclear>.</p>

<p>Do I sound complaning? I'm not; I'm sitting under the flowering tree full of singing birds, may I call myself your official biographer now? I hesitated before because I wasn't sure I could earn the right.
One more thing. I want you to see the corrections in the whole manuscript. Rereading some of your letters I see that you may be a little worried about my</p>

<note type="curatorial">4</note>
<p>neglecting some of them, and I have never really replied to questions about it. You have read the manuscript in isolated sections, and sometimes you supported additions that appeared in other chapters. The whole book is a braid, and I don't want to repeat except for emphasis. When you read straight through I think you'll see what I <unclear/>. It's all these, but not every time. I will want to proof read the final manuscript after it is typed and if its possible to have Enid do it I would much perfer that she should. It may be a question of time, but in any case I'll have a copy for you to see before it goes to the press. </p>
<p>Do I have to stop writing to you when the book is out? I still have a lot to say about you in more books and in articles. I shall <unclear/> the academic world silly with all their <unclear/> nonsense and dissection of sick - sick myth theory. How would you like to launch a some school of critism?</p>

<closer>
<salute>Love - can't you tell?</salute>
<signed>Lucile</signed>
<note></note>
</closer>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>