<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.25.22c-22d_0001-2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, October 19, 1957</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.25.22c-22d_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1957-10-19">October 19, 1957</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 type written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.22c-22d_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">22c</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>October 19, 1957</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Your letter has just arrived, and it's a wonderful letter! I do thank you for it, not only the information, but the wonder-words. Sometimes I think you should do nothing at all but write letters, only then you wouldn't be teaching, and I certainly wouldn't want you not to teach. If the Henry Holt man can help locate the papers, that will be a big step forward. I have also written the Library of Congress, where Mr. Hill thinks they may be. And it is a very good sign that <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> might be republished. Perhaps then I can buy a copy--I'm signed up with a book store man in New York to try to find all your books, but a new edition would be good. I think lots of people will want copies. I wish the <hi rend="underline">Collected Poems</hi> could be republished.</p>
                
                <p>I will see what I can turn up on Jackson Barber. I got nowhere with it in Los Angeles, although I talked to almost all the libraries. I'll write the Bohemian Club, and also ask when I get to Berkeley in November if I haven't already found the book. I've been reading a lot of Sterling, partly to track down the poems you wrote about to him; it is beautiful, isn't it? I want to hear more about him when we can talk again.</p>
                
                <p>Thank you very much for the description of the afternoon with Mrs. Moody. Bower read it too, and said, "You realize this is <hi rend="underline">History,</hi> don't you?" If you are willing to reminisce about another event I would like to know what you recall of the dinner for Markham you were planning to attend in November, 1915? You wrote George Sterling that you were going--it was in Ann Arbor. Something else I wondered--<hi rend="underline">did</hi> he ever write "Lillith?" I haven't found it anywhere, but there is no complete set of Sterling's works anywhere I've looked.</p>
                
                <p>Last ni<del>t</del><add>g</add>ht at a dinner party I sat next to the man who is in charge of the Oregon State Historical Society room in the Library--rare books and manuscripts and such--and I asked him where the location of the Jed Smith massacre was (I thought if it was accessible to a highway I'd like to go look at it), and he wanted to know
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.25.22c-22d_0002"/>
                
                    <fw type="curatorial">22d</fw>
                
                    why I was interested in Jed Smith. When I told him, he almost shot up out of his chair, he was so excited. He is a Neihardtian from way back--has first editions of every one of your books, and thinks any amount of recognition you have had is much too little. "Tremendous" is the word he used. He has never known anything about you except your work, and I have promised to go up and talk with him; I'm going to take the pamphlets and magazines I have to show him, specifically the ones with pictures. He wants to know anything at all that will help him see "what makes Neihardt tick." An English department professor was there too, and he was much interested; he knows your work, of course, and wanted to know where you were and what you were doing. He thought it was wonderful that you were in a University where students would have an opportunity to know you. You are certainly not without honor in this country.</p>
                
                <p>I have worked through your letters to Mr. and Mrs. Fink, and now I am regretting bitterly that I didn't get acquainted with them both before I left. If they are in Columbia next summer I do want to confer with them about <del>a</del><add>t</add>he biography&#8212;and I would like to know them just for themselves. They are wonderful people; it's a Neihardt charactersistic, I've decided. It is too bad everyone can't know all of you.</p>
                
                <p>Bower and Stewart send their best regards along with mine. I hope I'm not pestering you with too many questions, but I miss talking with you, and it's the only thing approaching a substitute. You are good to take the time it must require to answer them. Please remember us to all the family.</p>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
