<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.n1a.6.1-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Julius Young to John G. Neihardt, Februrary 1, 1967</title>
                <author>Young, Julius</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.n1a.6.1-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Young, Julius</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Julius Young to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1967-02-01">Februrary 1, 1967</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Young Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>

                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="people">
                    <term>Young, Julius</term>
                    <term>Young, Myrtle</term>
                    <term>Danker, Donald F. (Donald Floyd)</term>
                    <term>Robinson, Bill</term>
                    <term>Ernst, Arthur</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="places">
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Wayne (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Wauneta (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="works">
                    <term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Young, Julius</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006"></placeName>
                    <date when="1967-02-01"/>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4575352">Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <person role="recipient"><persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt,
                    John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine M.</name>Initial Encoding</change>
            <change><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.n1a.6.1-3.xml" />
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                <fw type="authorial"></fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <note>Duplicate (carbon) To John</note>
                    
                        <address>
                            <addrLine>
                                To Dr. J.G. Neihardt 
                                Columbia Mo. 1
                                5835 Vine Street 
                                Lincoln, Nebraska
                            </addrLine>
                        </address>
                        
                    <dateline>Februrary 1, 1967</dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Friend:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>We cherished your two kind letters received since you were in Lincoln. I am preparing to mail to you soon snap-shots, news clippings, tape recording, open-house guest signatures, and a more detailed personal letter. This present one deals mainly with matters concerning organizations. First, however, my wife, our neighbors and open-house guests are still basking in the warmth of memories. Of course, I included myself in that statement too. Myrtle and I enjoyed it fully, and we have received many written and oral "thank yous" from many others. We cordially invite you and any of your "entourage" to return to the simple hospitality of our "pad" and "cuisine" as soon and as often as you like - Our american motors "pony-drag" awaits yoru every transportation need while here. Just let us know when, so we won't be out of town or have a house-ful of company - a common occurence. We could organize another and greater open-house. So send us your "yes" smoke signal soon:</p>
                <p>I saw Dr. Danker briefly in the corridor of the Historical Society Building  last week, and told him briefly of your visit here. Later, after you mentioned him in your second letter, I called him on the phone and tentatively agreed to meet again soon, on various matters. I have several projects going in the reading files there. It would be great to have some time with you there too, at your early convenience. Incidentally, through my South Dakota Historical Society membership I have several interesting leaflets and books. I showed you some, but had too few minutes with you for more. We slipped a Hugh Glass story leaflet in your pocket at Wayne</p>

                    <pb facs="nei.n1a.6.1-3.xml" />
                <note type="curatorial">2</note>
                <fw type="authorial"></fw>
                    <p>last July. It was written by Bill Robinson.</p>
                    <p>Now, for the part of this letter, which I hope will merit an early reply of "yes"! Could you return to Lincoln to be here Sunday April 2nd, and Monday April 3rd 1967? Of course, the Youngs at 5835 Vine Street hope you can come to be here even before, and after, those two dates if you can, - a completely different and earlier trip as previously suggested would be very welcome here too. The April 2 and 3 dates are to be explained more fully below.</p>
                    <p>Our Warren Methodist minister, Rev. Arthur Ernst talked with you here at our house. About having you participate in his Sunday morning service soon. You remembered having done some-thing like that while he was at Wauneta, Nebr. Stan Smith's town, Rev. Ernst ^and have been in conference several times since you were here; we even contacted some of the Centennial Commission aobut our Poet Laureate. He will supply the details about the church appearance if you can come. A date other than April 1st could be arranged, but I have aanother thing in mind for you here. April 3rd, so the two events could be linked. Here it is, and this April 3rd date is rather fixed, at least for several months in the future: - The Lancaster County Retired Teachers Association would be honored to feature your as their principal speaker at their regular April 3rd meeting which begins at 10:00 O'clock a.m. It lasts through the moon luncheon hour, and is to be at the  Cornhusker Hotel.</p>
                    <p>The details of exact time, duration, and</p>
                    
                        <pb facs="nei.n1a.6.1-3.xml" />
                        <note type="curatorial">3</note>
                        <fw type="authorial"></fw>
                
                        <p>nature of your performance would be determined soon, and your wishes would be considered first.</p>
                        <p>This local retired teachers organization has approximately 300 members. It is affiliated with state and national groups. Activities are recreational, social, civic, and cultural in in scope. Many of the old school marms and school masters have used our Great Poet Laureates works in school and (pardon the expression) "love the socks off of him"! So what choice has he but to come April 3rd?!! No admission is charged at these meetings, and normally there is no great provision for honorarium or compenesation. I am sure, however, that the groups concerned are so eager that any wampum necessary could be gathered from this village some way! While at a recent meeting of the Teachers' program committee I made the suggetion that you might be able to come. The idea spread like a well-known prairie fire I might mention (but won't!) and I was given the honor of doing the "arm-Twisting". So! I am glad to be of service in this. My wife and I are selfishly hoping for as much of your time with us as possible, but we want to provide an opportunity for as many others as can, to see and hear you - a privilege to the remembered.</p>
                    <p>Please be frank about any financial details necessary. I'll gladly be the "go-between" though I'm a novice at such mundane matters as fical figures. My great concern is to arrange for your return - with the greatest good to all.</p>
                        <closer>
                        <salute>Sincerely</salute>
                        <signed>Julius D. Young </signed>
                        </closer>
                        <postscript><p>P.S. Phoned Wayne Book Store last Friday p.m. and received 6
                            copies of Dr. House's book by mail next morning. In new condition $4.75 per.</p></postscript>
                    

                    <note>JGN:EN</note>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>