<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
3-27-70 20
Dear Dad; 
This will be somewhat hurried but wanted to get a check back to you as quickly as I could. I enclose $75.00 which represents the reimbursment by my company. They paid my airfare in full and returned my expenses <del/> for meals &amp; lodging. The balance I used to buy a coat and shoes for the colder climate. Since this was used for my personal needs I will need a little more time to repay you which I intend do - in full. You certainly saved my skin for it was important to me to feel well dressed. as I had never flown in a jet 

2
before the trip was sheer joy to me- in fact I had only flown one in my life before and that was nearly 20 years ago. This old earth of ours is very beautiful from upstairs. Especially the Rocky Mountains - snow-capped-breathtaking! 
You spoke of my leaving in a hurry. The trip had been postponed once before and I had no choice - had to take the date set-up by the boss. 
The training session in St. Paul was very fine - much of the work I had already been doing so ti was not hard for me. Personnel training was new and I thoroughly enjoyed this. Had a chance to see Minneapolis 

3
but not time to see Sig's birthplace. The training schedule was tight on time, also I had to contact people in Home office who will transfer to our new Service Center in Phoenix, You can see I was running all day - every day. They are a good group of people and it was my pleasure to be allowed to attend. 
Again Dad, my heartfelt thanks for your immediate help. My salary bracket will use - should by May 1. 
If you will bear with me a bit longer I can start paying the remainder. 
We rejoice with you and for you on the wonderful things that have 

21 
come to you - "the things that are mine will know my face" - I try to hold that faith for us. 
Sig will write soon again I am writing this time just to tell you about my trip & return part of your dough! 
Love you with all my heart. 
Maxie 

23 3-30-70 
PHOENIX. AZ 
PM
28 MAR
3A
1970 
10 c 
U.S. AIR MAIL 
<figure/> 
Dr. John G. Neihardt 
5835 Vine Street 
Lincoln, Nebraska 68505 
3-30
<unclear/>

Neihardt 
2050 W. Dunlap D-48 
Phoenix Ariz. 85021 