<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.n1a.9.33-34">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Jerry Turpin to John G. Neihardt, July, 27 1970</title>
                <author>Turpin, Jerry</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.n1a.9.33-34</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Turpin, Jerry</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Jerry Turpin to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1970-07-27">July, 27 1970</date>
                    <extent>1 page; 1 envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Young Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>1 page; 1 envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>1 page; 1 envelope
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>

                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="people">
                    <term>Turpin, Jerry</term>
                    <term>Aly, Lucile Folse, 1913-</term>
                    <term>Cheyenne</term>
                    <term>Ponca-Otoe</term>
                    <term>Caddo-Delaware</term>
                    <term>Calamity Jane, 1856-1903</term>
                    <term>Baby Doe Tabor</term>
                    <term>Snow, Eliza R. (Eliza Roxey), 1804-1887</term>
                    <term>Stewart, Elinore Pruitt, 1876-1933</term>
                    <term>Custer, George A. (George Armstrong), 1839-1876</term>
                    <term>Grey, Sandy</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="places">
                    <term>Enid (Okla.)</term>
                    <term>Columbia (Mo.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="works">
                    <term>A Cycle of the West</term>
                    <term>The Song of the Indian Wars</term>
                    <term>Black Elk Speaks</term>
                    <term>When the Tree Flowered: The Story of Eagle Voice, a Sioux Indian</term>
                    <term>The Song of Hugh Glass</term>
                    <term>Letters of a Woman Homesteader</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Turpin, Jerry</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5308655">Phoenix (Ariz.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1970-06-04"/>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5072006">Lincoln (Neb.)</placeName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine M.</name>Initial Encoding</change>
            <change><name xml:id="mjc">Carney, Mary Jo</name>Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.n1a.9.33-34.xml"/>
                <note type="curatorial">33</note>
                <note type="authorial"></note>
                <fw type="authorial">
                    PHILLIPS UNIVERSITY <figure/> UNIVERSITY STATION ENID, OKLAHOMA 73701
                </fw>
                
                <dateline>
                    27 July 1970
                </dateline>
                
                <fw type="address">
                    Mr. John G. Neihardt 
                    Skyrim Farm
                    Route #7
                    Columbia, Mo. 
                    65201
                </fw>
                
                <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                
                <p>I was fortunate enough to be one of your students in 1955  in your Epic America class at the University of Missouri. I want you to know that I have never taken a course that has meant more to me. I wrote you in 1964 to tell you that I was using your Cycle of the West in my classes. Since that time I have not only used it here at Phillips but I also had great success with it in my Oral INterpretation classes that I taught at the University of Southern California while I was doing my residency there for my Phd. I am now working on my dissertation in the area of contemporary Indian literature in light of Indian traditions, religious beliefs, etc. I would have liked to h ave done it on you, but since Mrs. Aly beat me to it by a few years I had to settle on something else.</p> 
                <p>Because of the love of the Indian that you nurturedf in me (and my wife who took your class on my suggestion in 1958) we now have three lovely adopted children. Our daughter is Cheyenne, our oldest son is Ponca-Otoe, and our youngest son is Caddo-Delaware. We are trying to do all we can to foster in them a love and understanding for their own traidiotns and a pride in their race.</p> 
                <p>At the present I am writing a readers' theatre produc-tion based on five women who somehwat typify the many brave    women involved  in the westward movement. It seems to me that witht he troubles in America as this time this kind of story needs to be re=told. I chose this form of presentation because I feel that only through readers' theatre can a story of this scope be told, and this is certainly the only way good literature that has been written on the subject can be presented and still be honest to the original literary work.</p> 
                <p>I have chosen for my women "Calamity Jane" Cannary, Baby Doe Tabor,  Eliza Snow (the Mormon poetess), Elinore Pruitt Stewart (Letters of a Woman Homesteader), and Kate Bighead (a Cheyenne woman who would be representative of all the Indian women caught in the press of the westward movement).</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.n1a.9.33-34.xml"/>
                <note type="curatorial">34</note>
                <fw type="authorial">
                    PHILLIPS UNIVERSITY <figure/> UNIVERSITY STAITON ENID, OKLAHOMA 73701
                </fw>
                
                <p>Because so little is known about kate Bighead's life, except for her account of Custer's death, I would like to  h a ve yoru permission to adapt and use portions of your Song of the Indian Wars, Black Elk Speaks, and When the Tree Flowered. I have read many, many books on Indian life, but I have never found any that had such depth of under-standing of the Indian as your books do. The changes I would make would be minimal, only those necessary to fit the change in sex and tribe, and I would be very careful that the change would not go against history or tribal traditions. If I decide to copyright the script, could I also have permission from you to use your material, with the understanding, of course, that I will give proper credit to you for the material used? I will never forget the story you told in class of the person who wrote the book on Hugh Glass and used much of your description of his journey as fact.</p> 
                <p>Again I want to thank you for the great influence you have had on my life and continue to have (I have both of your recordings that Sandy Grey made and find constant inspriation from your comments on the second slide of your Lyric record, a conversation that I wish could have gone on and on). May God bless you and bring as much happiness to your life as you have brought to mine.</p>
                <salute>Sincerely,</salute> 
                <signed>Jerry Turpin</signed> 
                <signed>Jerry Turpin</signed> 
                
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>