<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
47
April 28, 1971
Dear Dr. Neihardt,
I have just finished watching your interview with Dick Cavett on television. Thank you for your words and for sharing your life Thank you also for your books, although I have not yet read them, I know that they will have meaning for me. 
I am eighteen years old, and what you said about young people seraching for religion is true about me. I think part of my loss and uncertainty is because I have gotten too far away from the land. The Indians lived close enough to the earth to grasp the meanings of the only real things of life. And all the so-called civilization and wealth of material goods are nothing without the knowledge <del/> of the "unity and holiness of all life." 
It was strange and wonderful to hear you speak of personal experiences with people and events that are chapters in history books to me. It was stranger and more wonderful still to hear you, at ninety, raise the same basic questions that I have begun to ask myself at eighteen. But you perhaps have found your answers while I am only starting to know how much there is to ask and to feel and to live. 
Black Elk might have liked to know that his words and his life will touch me through you. Thank you. 
Gratefully,
Cynthia Browning 

48
Dear Cynthia,
I cherish the <unclear/> letter you wrote me and I want to thank you for your kindness. I have been swamped with letters since the Cavett show &amp; am unable to  spend much time on individual letters but be sure that this <unclear>note</unclear> <unclear>carries</unclear> <unclear>affec</unclear> good wishes for you. 
Sincerely



Cynthia Browning 
2000 Sterling Road 
Charlotte
North Carolina 
28209 
CHARLOTTE 
PM 
28 APR
1971 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
THOMAS JEFFERSON UNITED STATES 1c 
ansd 5/30/71 
Dr. John Neihardt
c/o the Dick Cavett Show 
American Broadcasting Co. 
1330 Avenue of the Americas
New York, New York 10019 