<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Duplicate Carbon
To J.G.N.
To Dr. J.G. Neihardt Columbia, Mo. 4
5835 Vine Street 
Lincoln, Nebraska
February 3, 1967
Dear Friend:
I trust you have received my letter of Feb. 1 in which I mentioned a letter would follow with several items included. This will fulfill that promise in part, but more is soon to follow. We have had many delays, some because of unexpected company, -pleasant, but not very favorable to the important things at hand. Here are 4 prints, part of the photo record and some news clippings. More photos, clippings, guest register and sound recording tape will be mailed to you tomorrow, Saturday. They will be in a larger container, unfolded for better filing. 
Today I had an hour with Dr. Danker at his office. He had his assistants make copies of the three sheets of the Neihardt open house guest register, made originally at our home the evening of Jan. 19, 1967. Then he listened to your interesting talk from the tape. It runs over twenty minutes on speed 3 3/4 and in very clear. He asked to make a duplicate for their files. I shall mail a copy to you tomorrow. Also, I visited with him relative to future disposition of Neihardtana (my "coined" word), both original and duplicate materials. I'm sure teh outcome of all our efforts should result in preservation and orderly filing of all materials, with full satisfaction to all concerned. I told him of the plan for your return to Lincoln in the near future, and invited him to meet with us at some time while you are here. This could be at our home and/or the Society building. He seemed very interested, and I shall make further plans with him after I hear from you. I explained that you had asked me in your letter, received last Monday, to confer with him. We are hoping to receive a favorable reply from you soon about yoru return to Lincoln. I hope my position in the arrangements to procedure is clear enough to you - We want you to come for the April 2nd and 3rd dates I mentioned if at all possble, - and again the Youngs invite you to their place at anytime! Remember, too, that necessary financing is possible. 
Sincerely Yours
Julius D. Young 
