<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.n1a.4.15-17">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Julius Young to John G. Neihardt, Nov. 12, 1964</title>
                <author>Young, Julius</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.n1a.4.15-17</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Young, Julius</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Julius Young to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1964-11-12">Nov. 12, 1964</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Young Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="people">
                    <term>Young, Julius</term>
                    <term>Winkelman, Phyllis H.</term>
                    <term>Weinkauf, Otto</term>
                    <term>Young, Myrtle</term>
                    <term>Culler, Charles F.</term>
                    <term>Young-Lesher, Addie</term>
                    <term>Lesher, Martin</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="places">
                    <term>Rawlins (Wy.)</term>
                    <term>Grand River (S.D.)</term>
                    <term>Lincoln (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>North Dakota</term>
                    <term>Minnesota</term>
                    <term>Iowa</term>
                    <term>Lemmon (S.D.)</term>
                    <term>Bancroft (Neb.)</term>
                    <term>Golden Springs (Neb.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="works">
                    <term>Omaha World-Herald</term>
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Young, Julius</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/5836068">Rawlins (Wy.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1964-11-12"/>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
                    <placeName ref="http://www.geonames.org/4575352">Columbia (Miss.)</placeName>
                    <date when="1964-11-12"></date>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <person role="recipient"><persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2017"><name>Weakly, Laura K.</name> correspDesc Encoding</change>
            <change when="2013-08"><name xml:id="jg">Gavran, Julie</name> <name>Weakly, Laura K.</name> Keywords</change>
            <change when="2012-02-29"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011-11-28"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.n1a.4.15-17"/>
                <note type="curatorial">15</note>
                <fw type="curatorial"></fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <note>Not exact copy. Letter sent from Rawlins improved, somewhat</note>
                    Rawlins, Wyoming
                    <dateline>
                        Nov. 12, 1964
                        Dr. John Neihardt
                        Columbia, Missouri
                    </dateline>

                    <salute>Dear Friend:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>Mrs. Young and I recently visited The Hugh Glass monument area near the forks of the Grand River in South Dakota. I am enclosing three color  prints and also seven reprints of negatives made in 1923, and I shall relate more after a few words about ourselves. you may remember having seen some of the 1923 snaps at Mrs. Winkelman's the evening of Dec. 7, 1961. She ^later had some copies made of them and 1923 news clippings for the State Historical Society.</p>
                <note>Included 7 1923 bl. &amp; whh. prints 3 1964 Color prints</note>
                <p>You probably recall that we were the newlyweds at the Hugh Glass event in 1923. After moving to Lincoln that same summer I taught <del>was a high school teacher</del> in Lincoln schools for forty years, and retired last June. We <del>are</del> now are traveling to the Pacific Northwest, and I am writing this in a motel in Rawlins. <del>We were too rushed a last </del> The rush of details before leaving Lincoln <del>presented</del> left no time for letter writing. We plan to cover all of the western states and visit many people and places before returning to Lincoln by next June. The Grand River trip was an "appetizer", and it included North Dakota, Minnesota, and Iowa. We enjoyed the North Dakota badlands, the Mandan Villages (replicas) and many other historic places. It was our first return to the Grand River area since 1923. The 1923 experience is fondly remembered and also the several times we have had the pleasure of meeting you in Lincoln, among the most pleasant was the delightful evening spent with you at Mrs. Winkelman's home after the ceremony in the Nebraska State House on December 7, 1961. The next day I had the honor and pleasure of introducing you to several hundred fortunate <del>pupils and</del></p>

                    <pb facs="nei.n1a.4.15-17"/>
                    <note type="curatorial">16</note>
                
                    <p>Lincoln High School pupils and faculty members at a special assembly. The young people and faculty had a most enjoyable and memorable experience when you thrilled them with your poems. We and many others have enjoyed your T.V. interviews over Channel 12, too, and we hope to see ^and hear more.</p>
                    <p>On our recent trip to the Grand River we <del>located</del> found, after inquiry at the Shadehill Post Office, a new marker placed in 1964 by <del>the</del> The South Dakota State Historical Society and others organizations. It is in an attractive setting of petrified wood and is situated in suitable parking area <del>just</del> adjacent to a maintained local road. One of the inclosed <del>snapshot</del> color  prints shows its inscription with difficulty we spotted with binoculars the old 1923 marker about 3/4 mile to the north and a few <del>very near to the lapping waters</del> rods from edge of the huge resevoir formed by the great dam below the Forks. We managed to find a faint trail for our Rambler Wagon and soon pulled up to the old marker. We eagerly searched the almost barren earth for signs of 1923 Model T tracks, and found some.</p>
                    <p>The bronze plate has been stolen, but the concrete is intact and has few weather checks. The view has changed since 1923 becasue of the large seale earth-moving for the dam, the inundation and the rapid erosion. <del/> <del/> <del>may eventually destroy the supporting bluff wall.</del> The entire area is dotted with the usual lake recreation facilities, but the old monument reminas isolated and few people will see it. Without its bronze plate nothing indicates its meaning, and the new marker makes no reference to it. There are a few local people who know about it, but we found some who thought it had been removed or destroyed.</p>

                        <pb facs="nei.n1a.4.15-17"/>
                        <note type="curatorial">17</note>
                
                        <p>We were surprised ^to find Mr. Otto <unclear>Weinkauf</unclear>, who <del>whose land</del> provided the site for the 1923 marker, still active and healthy, living in <unclear>Lemmon</unclear>. <del>He will</del> His 90th birthday falls on April 14th, 1965. Just a very few years ago he remarried after his first wife died. He is still full of memories of 1923, and is interested in all things and persons relating to the markers and their preservation. We concur with him that a suitable plate with the original inscription should replace the one vandalized or stolen, and that the <del>original marker</del> monument should be preserved where it is if possible. <del>Though he is</del> Mrs. Young joins me in expressing <del>our fondness</del> admiration for your and your splendid works, and we hope these snapshots and this letter may give you some pleasure. We enjoyed the recent account in the Omaha World-Herald of your return trip to Bancroft and the Dana College program. My parents were <del/> Nebraska Territorial pioneers <del/> not far from Golden Springs. My eldest sister was graduated from the Dakota City High School when Charles Culler was there, having stayed with her aunt Addie Young Lesher and her husband Rev. Martin Lesher. Later I knew and admired <del>him</del> Mr. Culler in Lincoln. Our home is near the Charles Culler Junior High School. <del/> at 5835 Vine St. If you should care to communicate with us <del/> <del>we are o</del> before next June mail would be forwarded to us from our home address.</p>
                
                <closer>
                    Wishing you many years of health and activity, as well as the coming Holiday Greetings, I am
                    <salute>Sincerely</salute>
                    <signed>Julius D. Young</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>