<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0001-7">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Thomas S. Jones, Jr. to John G. Neihardt, July 14, 1929</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.14.18-24_0001-2</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Thomas S. Jones, Jr. to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1929-07-14">July 14, 1929</date>
                    <extent>8 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>8 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>8 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneiseneau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">18</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        40 West 115th St., <hi rend="caps">N.Y.C.</hi>
                        July 14, 1929.
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>The Poems came safely yesterday, and in the Maine <unclear>woods</unclear> I shall read this truly-treasured book from cover to cover &#8212; easily, happily. I have slowly come to learn that no issues are forced, but that sympathy corresponds to sympathy, kin to kin; and this companionship with you has been one of the happiest facts in this past half-year. My hand-clasp with you will make my job easier at this end.
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0002"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">19</fw>
                
                    Early in life I thought that one could share what one had found: now I know that <unclear>lan</unclear> makes that impossible. Kin can only respond to kin, deep to deep.&#8212; I need not expand this to you, for you will understand.</p>
                
                <p>About the article.&#8212; Its value for me will be in <hi rend="underline">your words</hi>&#8212;your seal on what I have done. For these words, just as they would flow from you, would be the <hi rend="underline">right words</hi>. I wish you would <hi rend="underline">not</hi> trouble to write a <unclear>review</unclear>, or to touch on any specific part; but I should treasure deeply &#8212; and keep with the treasures of my life&#8212; a <hi rend="underline">short</hi>, spontaneous expression of your
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0003"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">20</fw>
                
                    own valuation of my work, just as the spirit would move you. I would treasure this, not only for the aid your words would give to me in St. Louis (the old home of Bob Laughlin, my best friend at College, and Bice Reedy who gave me my best review &#8212; <del/> knowing nothing about me&#8212; in 1906), but &#8212;and to me the great value &#8212;or the invisible connection of our lives in service to our Greater Selves. &#8212; Toward a brief summary, estimation, in your words I shall look forward with grateful appreciation: no burdening review, but a direct simple clarification of what
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-244_0004"/>
                    <fw type="curatorial">21</fw>
                
                    you feel to be the value of my book and life.&#8212; With the greater understanding of life, reviews and articles mean little to me; but the words of a friend &#8212; and in this case, <add>of</add> a great mind and man &#8212; mean more than I <del>could</del><add>can</add> ever say in these words of ours.</p>
                
                <p>Thank you for clear joy. &#8212; <unclear>All</unclear> that is unsaid I leave to your understanding sympathy.</p>
                <closer>
                    <salute>Faithfully</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Thomas S. Jones Jr.</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <p>I shall write you after I have fully read the book.</p>
                </postscript>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0005a"/>
                
                <ab type="return">
                    <hi rend="caps">T.S.</hi> Jones. Jr.
                    40 <hi rend="caps">W.</hi> 115th St.
                    <hi rend="caps">N.Y.C.</hi>
                </ab>
                <note><unclear/></note>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    NEW YORK. N.Y. STA J-1
                    JUL 14
                    2-PM
                    1929
                    REGISTER OR INSURE VALUABLE MAIL
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>2 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p><unclear/>2 CENTS 2</p>
                </figure>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">22</fw>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Mr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Editorial Department</addrLine>
                        <addrLine><hi rend="underline">St. Louis Post-Dispatch</hi></addrLine>
                
                        <addrLine><unclear>Tenth</unclear> Bvd. + Olive St.</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>St. Louis, Mo.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="authorial"><hi rend="caps">PERSONAL</hi></note>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0005b"/>
                
                <note type="authorial">You will find a sonnet on <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Louis in the <hi rend="underline">Later Sonnets</hi> of the Cross&#8212; p.<unclear>5</unclear>4&#8212; <hi rend="underline">The King's <unclear/></hi>.&#8212;Not one of the best poems, by any means.</note>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0006a"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Missouri Collection   with letter 7/14/2<unclear>9</unclear></note>
                
                <p>has been read with genuine pleasure by his reviewer. It is good, and clean, and honest, and it has a delightful naturalness.
                    <add><note type="authorial"><hi rend="caps">W.M.</hi> Ready</note></add>&#8212; <hi rend="italic">The Mirror</hi>, St. Louis.</p>
                
                <p>In his second book of poems, "The Rose-Jar," which has just been issued from the press of George William Browning at Clinton, <hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi>, Mr. Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., more than fulfils the promise of his earlier volume, issued by Badger two years ago...</p>
                
                <p>It is not easy to account for the subtle allurement of these verses &#8212;so delicate and so unmistakably poetic. Here is a lyric that reveals Mr. Jones' power&#8212;unusual in a young man of twenty-three&#8212;from whom great things are to be expected: ("In the Fall o' Year" quoted.). . 
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The New York Evening Telegram</hi></p>
                
                <p>A volume of lyrics and sonnets by Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., under the title of "The Rose-Jar," is worth the attention of those who love lyric poetry. . . . Whether the poems are grave or gay, they ring true and are well worth reading.
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Philadelphia Public Ledger.</hi></p>
                
               <head><hi rend="caps">THE PATH O' DREAMS</hi> <add><note type="authoraial">&#8212; 1905</note></add></head>
                
                <p>A charming little book of lyrical poetry is "The Path o' Dreams," by <hi rend="caps">T. S.</hi> Jones, Jr. So few are the pages, so brief the poems, that, opening the little volume to read "The Piper" on the first page, or the "Good Night" on the last, one will read all between just to see if there is any bit of beauty, in thought or expression, overlooked in the previous perusals. Not often does one come upon any little book with so much of clear gold and so little of turbid alloy. It is not easy to choose the one number which can represent this young singer of promise. . . .
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Kansas City Star</hi></p>
                
                <p>Even nowadays, when few desire to turn aside from the maddening crowd and think for a little hour, a young man's first book of poems is a thing notable and rich in potentiality. Out of the periods like ours, vari-colored, surging, openly dedicated to the material, and frankly contemptuous and skeptical of spiritual some of the world's rarest poets have grown. . . . "The Path o' Dreams" is the title of a thin, wide-margined volume containing a score and half-a-score of quiet, unheralded, but withal precious little poems&#8212;a little book to be valued for the sake of the knowledge that some minds still seek refuge from the turmoil, and because the verses themselves are simple and sincere.</p>
                
                <p>The poet is Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., and sometimes his thought lies in a quatrain, sometimes in two or three stanzas with a form gracefully their own, but never does it couch in intricate lines or metres, nor does any poem attain the length of a page. While the virile quality that makes itself known in the work of another new poet attracting much attention, <hi rend="caps">A. E.</hi> Housman, is as yet not apparent to the same degree in the verse before us, the grace of repose, the poet's necessary and undefinable sadness and the sense of color in words are all present, and there is often an exquisite if unobtrusive art form. A poet may speak once, and then remain silent. Again his speech is that of one who must cry in the wilderness. Time will decide whether Mr. Jones has more to say. In waiting, let us be glad of verses such as these.           &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Chicago Evening Post.</hi></p>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0006b"/>
                
                <head>
                The Poetry of Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr.
                    <lb/>
                Latest Volume
                    <lb/>
                <hi rend="caps">THE VOICE IN THE SILENCE</hi> $1.25 <add><note type="authorial">-K</note></add>
                    <lb/>
                Third Edition
                    <lb/>
                With a Foreword by <hi rend="caps">JAMES LANE ALLEN</hi>
                    <lb/>
                Address: Thomas <hi rend="caps">B.</hi> Mosher, 45 Exchange St., Portland, Maine
                </head>
                <p>Mr. Jones sees beauty and it captures him. To realize the vision is given to few, though many follow the quest, and that is why one hails with ready ardor Mr. Jones and two or three others like him as true seers. To them, since their hearts have been pure, life holds promise that is reflected from what has gone before. Memory becomes prophecy under the light of beauty, and voices its message insistently in an under-current of suggestion. These poets are not professed teachers. They do not penetrate slowly to the core; they are at the core and radiate out-ward. Beauty speaks through them; they have no need to apostrophise her. To such, and they are few, the pageant of nature is only a back-ground for the tabernacle of their own souls. Witness "The Pines," which was written by Mr. Jones in no mood of detachment . . . In him, vision reflects beauty, and this reflected beauty, is phrashed consumately in shy, reticent numbers, which sing themselves in the soul as well as in the mind.
                    <note type="authorial"><hi rend="caps">E.J.O</hi>'Brien</note>          &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Boston Transcipt.</hi></p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THE ROSE-JAR,</hi>   Third Edition $1.25
               
                <p>The third edition of Mr. Jones' volume of poems comes to us appropriately dressed in Mr. Mosher's excellent type and binding, to be welcomed by old admirers and to win new ones. The contents now so familiarly known to lovers of poetry are practically without change, but there have been added to the collection the beautiful sonnets , "Ave atque Vale," written in memory of Arthur Upson. These memorial sonnets enrich the volume whose music is so exquisitely dedicated to the memory of the poet's mother. Mr. Jones' art we have discussed in these columns at some length. It is an art characterized with restraint and tenderness. in which the moods are full of wistful wonder and delicate intuitions. The simplicity of these poems is strikingly notable, the feeling is always deep and persuasive, and the substance is glowingly full of human sentiment. They express a very rare and perfect sympathy with life and nature in their youth, with just that mellow consciousness of foreborne existence which adds a signficance to all experiences of the world. In this sonnet, "As in a Rose-Jar," is the essence of this fine poetic instinct: (quoted).
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">William Stanley Braithwaite</hi> in Boston Transcript.</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Jones has unmistakably the Swinburnian gift of melodious tones in his verse. The overtones of haunting melodies run through all that he does, taking their hold in the fascinated ear, no matter whether the thought sinks deep in the mind or not.               
                    &#8212;(<hi rend="italic">The Listener</hi>)&#8212;<hi rend="italic">Boston Transcript,</hi></p>
                
                <p>Few contemporary poets have surer mastery of the sonnet than Mr. Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr. These stately lines are from a new edition of "The Rose-Jar." 
                    ("To Song" quoted.) <note type="authorial">Joyce <unclear>H</unclear>ilmer</note>           &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The Literary Digest.</hi></p>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">23</fw>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0007a"/>
                
                <p>The poetry of Mr. Jones is sometimes verse of eloquent individuality. 
                    &#8212; <hi rend="italic">Boston Advertiser.</hi></p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THE ROSE-JAR</hi>&#8212;Second Edition <note type="authorial">-1909</note>
                
                <p>This enlarged second edition of an earlier collection of Mr. Jones' verse is full of a very real charm which no true lover of poetry can fail to catch, but so elusive as to defy all expression in words. Mr Jones is one of our younger poets and one already of a real fruition. His song has all the simplicity of expression of some of the sweetest of the Elizabethan lyrics and subtle, haunting music of its own,&#8212;a music that continues to sound sweetly and faintly in memory after the book has been laid aside. It often reminds one of the work of Richard LeGallienne; Mr. Jones has the same wonderful gift of catching and expressing in song the fleeting and intangible moods that are so vital a part of our emotional life and yet so seldom expressed. He sings of love and youth and spring and the aspects of a sereneNature among the hills. His work is sheer poetry of a very beautiful sort.
                    &#8212;<hi rend="caps">R.T.</hi> Pearl in <hi rend="italic">The Four Seas, Boston.</hi></p>
                
                <p>His verses have a charm all their own. His style has all the character of graceful simplicity and unlabored expression. Well-poised, with a commendable feeling of restraint, he writes in many forms, always with rythmic fluency and with fine melodic flow.
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Commercial Tribune, Cinncinati.</hi></p>
                    
                <hi rend="caps">AVE ATQUE VALE</hi>&#8212;In Memoriam Arthur Upson <note type="authorial">-1909</note>
                
                <p>They who are familiar with a certain exalted sweetness that marked Arthur Upson's lyrics will welcome two small collections of sonnets by Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr. These are "Ave atque Vale," in memory of Arthur Upson, and a second little book of fugitive sonnets. . . . The quality of these sonnets is like the ember of Nature's flame rather than the burnt offering of Passion, an undertone too strong for mere pathos and too selfless for mere resignation&#8212;a breath of wistful beauty. 
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The Baltimore News.</hi></p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">INTERLUDES</hi>  <note type="authorial">-1908</note>
                
                <p>Although Mr. Jones' latest collection is contained within the twenty-four pages of a little paper-covered pamphlet, it need not be neglected because of its slightness or brevity. For, unlike many who aspire to fame as poets, Mr. Jones has a discreet sense of reticence that gives his accomplishment a more definite purpose and a more permanent value. He is not lavish of his gifts, and we doubt not that his tendency towards self-criticism has kept in his portolio many a hidden poem that might be well disclosed. So carefully is the present series of eighteen poems selected that they will stand the severest test, and, best of all, it is their simplicity that rings most truly. . . .            &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Boston Transcript.</hi></p>
                
                <p>Those who read and enjoyed Mr. Jones' charming little volume of verse, entitled <hi rend="italic">From Quiet Valleys</hi>, which was reviewed in the December <hi rend="italic">Arena</hi>, will welcome this little collection of sonnets and lyrics. Most of the poems are pitched in a minor key, but all reveal an intimate spiritual insight and understanding, and the same love of nature in her various moods which marked the former work.          &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The Arena</hi>, Boston.</p>
                
                    <pb facs="nei.j4a.14.18-24_0007b"/>
                    
                <hi rend="caps">FROM QUIET VALLEYS</hi> <note type="authorial">-1907</note>
                
                <p>In the Sahara-like waste of modern verse, it is a real delight to come across a volume containing real poetry. We have some excellent rhymsters and many writers who sem to imagine that poetry calls for neither imagination, rhythm, nor reason; but few present-day verse-makers in America are entitled to be called poets. In "From Quiet Valleys" Mr. Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., has given us some genuine poetry.
                    &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The Arena</hi>, Boston.</p>
                
                <p>. . . Mr. Jones has read his Keats with devout heart, and this devotion colors much of his poetry, especially the sonnets. I have seen few modern singers come so close to the witchery of the immortal odes as Mr. Jones does in "Romance." . . .           &#8212;<hi rend="caps">Pittsburg Gazette-Times</hi></p>
                
                <p>. . . Here is another volume, bearing the title "From Quiet Valleys," and written by Mr. Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr. This "Nocturne" exemplifies the author's quiet and graceful manner . . Mr. Jones is a poet of nature, and has felt the soothing ministries of woods and fields and skies. His verse, moreover, is freighted with enough of imagination to be truly significant of the life of the spirit.          &#8212;<hi rend="italic">The Dial,</hi> Chicago.</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., who has already come before the public role of a poet through his "The Path o' Dreams" and "The Rose-Jar," once more speaks to the world in "From Quiet Valleys." In this attractive collection Mr. Jones has not only maintained the high poetic standard established in his other works, but has entered upon broader fields . . .  Mr. Jones is a young man with remarkable gifts, and his writings show a maturity of thought and artistic observance that augur brightly for the future.         &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Boston Post.</hi></p>
                
                <p>A book of poems, "From Quiet Valleys," by Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr., is before us. If memory serves us properly, this is Mr. Jones' third publication of verses, two other volumes, called "The Path o' Dreams" and "The Rose-Jar," being the first to call attention to young Mr. Jones' genius. . . . "From Quiet Valleys" shows a decided advance in the poet's art. His forms are more varied&#821;he writes in every acceptable form, with a favor to the sonnet&#8212;his thought is more mature, his vision broader. . . . A few numbers from his earlier works are reproduced, thus enabling one to judge the poet's scope and splendid, healthy growth. "From Quiet Valleys" is wotrh<sic>worth</sic> while&#8212;for Mr. Jones and those who love the best of the better poetry.           &#8212;<hi rend="italic">Boston Traveler.</hi></p>
                
                <hi rend="caps">THE ROSE-JAR</hi><note type="authorial">* -1906</note>
                
                <p>Verse much more than respectable in quality, and charming because of its unpretentiousness, is to be found in The Rose-Jar" by Thomas <hi rend="caps">S.</hi> Jones, Jr. Ballades, triolets, rondeaux, we find here, and many a sonnet. His singing is not artificial in spirit. Indeed, it is marked by a natural simplicity that is not at all forced on the one hand, or appropximate to crude <hi rend="italics">gaucherie</hi> on the other. In the development of the minor strain he is almost faultless. His sense of proportion is good, and his work betrays no strain, no pose. The limpidity of his utterance is a great charm. His impressions are distinctly conveyed, and never with a forcing of the key. The sincerity of his work is a strong impression that it gives forth. It is innocent of any conscious precosity, and it is void of the usual neologies and the efforts of rococo locutions that trip the feet of so many of the minor bards who would mount Parnassus. His book</p>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">24</fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>

