<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.15.50-52_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from John Myers O'Hara to John G. Neihardt, December 11, 1932</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.15.50-52_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from John Myers O'Hara to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1932-12-11">December 11, 1932</date>
                    <extent>2 pages, plus envelope</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages, plus envelope</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>2 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.50-52_0001"/>
                
                <note type="curatorial">242 243 Neihardt Collection</note>
                <fw type="curatorial">50</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline><hi rend="caps">N.Y.</hi> Dec. 11. 1932</dateline>
                
                    <salute>My dear Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I was glad indeed that you liked "Hellas The Immortal"&#8212; a little tome in which I have gathered, as a sort of Greek mosaic, several translations from books that have long been favorites of mine. The translation of <unclear>Levan's</unclear> "Prayer" is the first complete and accurate one in English. There are two others, I believe, but both are abridged, and do not give with justice the poetic beauty of the text.</p>
                
                <p>The letter of Acredia will indeed be an addition to the autographed coy of "The Trophies". The book is now out of print, and some day, an account of the <unclear>second</unclear> edition, will be sought by Collectors. All your kind thoughts are deeply appreciated, and I believe them an hundred fold.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely and gratefully,</salute>
                
                    <signed>John Myers OHara</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
            
                
            <div1 type="enclosure">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.50-52_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">51</fw>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="caps">ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH</hi>
                
                    Of Making Many Books
                    <hi rend="caps">JOHN G. NEIHARDT</hi>
                </fw>
                
                <head>Truly a Pagan</head>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">PAGAN SONNETS</hi>. By John Myers O'Hara. (Smith &amp; Sale, Portland, Me.  $2.)</p>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">SOME</hi> months ago this column contained some enthusiastic comment on Heredia's sonnets, "The Trophies," as translated by John Myers O'Hara in collaboration with John Hervey. It was remarked that O'Hara is unsurpassed as a sonneteer, and those who may still care for exquisite verse and are unaquainted with O'Hara's work may prove the remark a merely obvious one by reading the volume listed above. Indeed, the truth of the remark is quite commonly granted by critics, regardless of clique affiliations. This surprising unanimity may not be wholly unrelated to the fact that O'Hara is in no way a competitor in the rough-and-tumble writing game of the day. Few indeed really want to do what he does, and still fewer could if they would. It's not easy, it's not novel, and it simply doesn't pay in any sense to save the esthetic. O'Hara is obviously and avowedly a man born out of his time and quite content to be so. He is truly a Pagan, but not in the curiously ignorant sense of the word as commonly understood just now, when any semi-illiterate with a quite intelligible penchant for hell-raising and general vulgarity can call himself a Pagan and get away with it. O'Hara's paganism is a noble way of viewing man, his relation to men and to the cosmos. Contrary to a going notion, that way does not involve a lack of self-control and is far removed from the possibilities of a vulgarian. Incidentally it is a way of viewing mankind and his world that produced in its day some of the finest spirits this world has ever known. Nor is it inconceivable that mankind may yet return to it. But the verse, merely as verse&#8212;there is magic in it!</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>-------</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">CYRUS HALL M</hi>c<hi rend="caps">CORMICK</hi>.  By Wm. <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> Hutchison. (The Century Co., New York City)</p>
                
                <p>Any adequate study of the life of Cyrus McCormick is certain to be an important contribution to the history of civilization, for the invention of the horse-drawn reaper 100 years ago marked the beginning of a new era in the fundamental industry of mankind, and of profound change in Western culture. In more than his inventions McCormick was a man of the future, for he was by no means the traditional mechanical genius incapable of making his way in a shrewd world. He was, in fact, an extremely canny and capable business man of the modern type, and as early as 1850 he had established a factory in Chicago and was developing methods of machine production and a sales organization
                <unclear/>
                War years and after.</p>
                
                <p>The work gives evidence of the most painstaking research and is unquestionably valuable.</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>-------</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">FADS, FRAUDS, AND PHYSICIANS</hi>. By <hi rend="caps">T.</hi> Swan Harding. (Lincoln MacVeagh, the Dial Press, New York City. $3.50.)</p>
                
                <p>Purports to "put the layman wise to what goes on under the cover of medical ethics" and makes a plea for State medicine. The author seems to quote authority for his statements. He does not attack the medical profession as a whole, realizing that there are doctors and doctors. The truth of much that he has to say is apparent even to the layman. The rest is for the experts to wrangle over. But it would be curious lapsus naturae if chicanery in some degree did not follow the competitive-profit motive into the realm of medicine, since it certainly follows everywhere else, even into the realms of religion, art and literature.</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>-------</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">THE SAGA OF THE VOLSUNGS</hi>. Translated by Margaret Schlauch. (<hi rend="caps">W.W.</hi> Norton &amp; Co., New York City.)</p>
                
                <p>This latest addition to the altogether admirable Scandinavian Classics series, issued under the auspices of the American-Scandinavian Foundation, presents a very readable new translation of the finest of the heroic legends of the North&#8212;The Saga of Ragnar Ladbrok and the Lay of Kraka. Though adults who may be interested in epic litearture<sic>literature</sic> will find the book a delight, it should prove especially charming to youngsters in their 'teens.</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>-------</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">EARLY AMERICAN SILVER</hi>. By <hi rend="caps">C.</hi> Louise Avery . (The Century Co., New York City. $4.)</p>
                
                <p>The sixth volume in the Century Library of American antiques designed for the guidance of collectors, the former volumes having been concerned with early American prints, costumes, glass, furniture and pottery. The author is assistant curator of the Department of Decorative Arts in the Metropolitan Museum. There are 64 plates and many line drawings illustrating the various forms in which the art of the silversmith in America has been expressed from Colonial days to the present.</p>
                
                <milestone unit="section"/><ab>-------</ab>
                
                <p><hi rend="caps">CONQUEROR OF SPACE</hi>. By Georgette Carneal. (Horace Liveright, New York City $3.)</p>
                
                <p>The complete life story of Lee de Forest, whose inventions are said to have done more for the development of wireless communication than those of any other, with the possible exception of Marconi. The author has gotten her material directly from De Forest himself. It is an elaboration of the ancient <unclear/></p>
                
            </div1>
            
            
            <div1 type="envelope">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.15.50-52_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">52</fw>
                
                <ab type="postmark">
                    GRAND CENT. ANNFX NY-3 
                    DEC 1<unclear/>
                    830 PM
                    1932
                </ab>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>3 Cent Stamp</figDesc>
                    <p>UNITED STATES POSTAGE WASHINGTON 3 CENTS 3</p>
                </figure>
                
                <ab type="address">
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt, Esq.,</addrLine>
                            <addrLine>Branson,</addrLine>
                                <addrLine>Missouri.</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </ab>
                
                <note type="curatorial">Found in <hi rend="underline">Hellas</hi> the <hi rend="underline">Immortal</hi> &#8212; John Myers O'Hara Smith and Sale Portland, Maine 1932</note>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
