<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.36a.27-29">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Winfred Blevins to John G. Neihardt, July 23, 1972</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.36a.27-29</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Winfred Blevins to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1972-07-23">July 23, 1972</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 type-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="2">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.27"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">27</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        37 South Lake Shore Drive 
                        Agoura, California 91301
                        July 23, 1972
                    </dateline>
                    
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Dr. John <hi rend="caps">G.</hi> Neihardt</addrLine> 
                        <addrLine>English Department</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Missouri</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Columbia, Missouri</addrLine>
                    </address>
                
                    <salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>I could scarcely have been more surprised when a <del>fir</del> friend told me that she had seen a marvellous story-teller on the Dick Cavett show and had rushed out to buy his book. She handed me the book, and it turned out to be <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi>. I was also astonished to hear her say that you had been on the Cavett not once but several times, and to discover behind the title page of <hi rend="underline">Black Elk Speaks</hi> that it has gone through 13 printings in paper. I must say shame-facedly that I thought that appreciation of your work did not extend to so large a band. I am very pleased for you.</p>
                
                <p>By now you must be looking toward the bottom of this letter to discover who I am; very likely you won't remember the name. If you hang onto old records, you <add>^may</add> find my name on the roster of your class in the writing of poetry for the autumn of 1959. (I was nicknamed Bill then.) If I'm lucky, you may remember two afternoons of tale-telling, philosophizing, and human communicating at your farm around that time. The afternoons were memorable for me.</p> 
                
                <p>I write partly to greet you after twelve years and to express my pleasure <del>of the</del> at the public response to <del>work</del> your work and thought. But I also have a particular need to talk with you.</p> 
                
                <p>This week I will be signing a contract to write a book about the mountain men of 1815-1845, whose characters and adventures you know far better than I. The book is a simple one: I have always thought that these men deserved mythic and heroic status in our <del>i</del> history far more than the cowboys, lawmen, badmen, and settlers whom the movies and the comic books have popularized. I will choose a dozen or so mountain men and tell their stories in prose in a semi-dramatized, <del>f<unclear>a</unclear>ctual</del>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="italics">Malibu Lake Mt. Club, Ltd.,</hi> Malibu Lake, Agoura, Calif. 91301 ∙ Phone: (213) 889-1211
                
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>At the base of mountains, sailboats on a lake</figDesc>
                    </figure>
                </fw>
                    
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.28"/>
                    
                <fw type="curatorial">28</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">page two</fw>
                    <del>factual</del>
                    <lb/>
                    
                    factual form. I hope, in my research, to bring to light some material that<del>i</del> is new, or that has not been printed in other than monograph form for the edification of a very fe<del/><add>w</add> historians. My main object, though, is simply to bring a great <del><unclear/> <add><unclear/></add></del> <add>men</add> a larger public, <add>in factual form.</add> The book will be published by Nash Publishing, a Los Angeles firm; they are asking for late <del>p</del> spring publicaiton, which seems to me a formidably short time and which we probably won't make.</p>
                
                <p>Naturally, I have again gotten out of my copy of <hi rend="underline">Cycle of the West</hi><del>.</del><add>,</add> and am re-reading it. Clearly, you could be an important source of original material to me, and could probably <del>anse</del> answer many questions and solve anomalies left ambiguous by the historical books that have been written. Your sources, as I remember, were largely oral--stories told by the men who were there or by others <del>wo</del> who heard them. Though <hi rend="underline">Cycle of the West</hi> is fictionalized, you have, both in the book and doubtless in memory, a lot of material about the period and the men which has never been <del>publihse</del> published. If you are willing, I hope that we can talk by telephone once or twice in the near future, and that I can fly to Missouri to talk at some length, when I am <del/> far enough along to know fully what my questions are. If you are amenable to that, I would like very much to<del/> hear from you soon.</p> 
                
                <p>The twelve years since I was graduated from the University have been full--and if not always grat<del/><add>i</add>fying, at least vividly <del>alvi</del> alive. I went to Columbia University, where I found the academics stultifying but got the Master's degree. Then I <del>dd</del> did some more graduate work and taught at several universities before deciding that I didn't want to be an academic, I wanted to be a writer.</p> 
                
                <p><del>t</del></p>
                
                <p>I wrote a good deal of poetry and fiction during this time, and translated some; some of it found its way into the literary quarterlies. Six years ago, with the help of the Rockefeller Foundation, I set<del>o</del> out to become a critic. I reviewed theater and music for the Los Angeles Times; now I am entertainment <del>eid<unclear/>t</del> editor, stage critic, and film critic for the Los Angeles Herald-Examiner. I will resign from that job to write this book.</p> 
                
                <p><del>I look forward to hearing from you. And <unclear/> I would very much enjoy seeing you again</del></p>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="italics">Malibu Lake Mt. Club, Ltd.,</hi> Malibu Lake, Agoura, Calif. 91301 ∙ Phone: (213) 889-1211
                    
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>At the base of mountains, sailboats on a lake</figDesc>
                    </figure>
                </fw>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.36a.29"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">29</fw>
                <fw type="authorial">page three</fw>
                    
                <p>I hope that <del/> this letter reaches you. I don't know, in fact, whether you are still at the university.</p>
                
                <p>I look forward to hearing from you. And I would very much enjoy seeing you again.</p> 
                <closer>
                    <salute>Sincerely,</salute>
                    
                    <signed>Winfred Blevins</signed>
                    <signed>Winfred Blevins</signed>
                </closer>
                
                <postscript>
                    <opener><hi rend="caps">P. S.</hi>:</opener> <p>I ju<del/><add>^s</add>t called Columbia for your address and telephone number. The operator said immediately, "Oh, he <del>doesnt</del> doesn't live here anymore, but he's doing fine, I saw him on television two or three weeks ago. His daughter lives here. Her name is Alice <del>Thomason</del> Thompson. You want the number?" Incredible luck. Because of that luck, this letter is going to your Nebraska address.</p> 
                </postscript>
                
                <fw type="imprint">
                    <hi rend="italics">Malibu Lake Mt. Club, Ltd.,</hi> Malibu Lake, Agoura, Calif. 91301 ∙ Phone: (213) 889-1211
                    
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>At the base of mountains, sailboats on a lake</figDesc>
                    </figure>
                </fw>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
