<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.29.29-30">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Elanita Frey to John G. Neihardt, January 28, 1961</title>
                <author>Frey, Elanita</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
                    <addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
                    <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                </address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.29.29-30</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Frey, Elanita</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Elanita Frey to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1961-01-28">January 28, 1961</date>
                    <extent>2 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>John G. Neihardt Center Research Library, Aly Collection</repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>2 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Emmons, Delos C. (Delos Carleton), 1888-1965</term>
                    <term>Bratton, Mae</term>
                    <term>Petri, Hilda Neihardt</term>
                    <term>Frey, Elanita</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term>India</term>
                    <term>Kansas City (Mo.)</term>
                    <term>Phoenix (Ariz.)</term>
                    <term>Brigham City (Utah)</term>
                    <term>Arizona</term>
                    <term>Missouri</term>
                    <term>Moab (Utah)</term>
                    <term>Kayenta (Ariz.)</term>
                    <term>Monument Valley (Ariz.)</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sentBy">
                    <persName>Frey, Elanita</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                    <date when="1961-01-28"/>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="deliveredTo">
                    <persName ref="https://viaf.org/viaf/59087102">Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName>
                    <placeName></placeName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John G., 1881-1973.</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2016"><name xml:id="amm">Morrison, Ashley</name>Transcription</change>
            <change when="2018"><name xml:id="cme">Elliott, Catherine</name>Initial Encoding</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.29.29-30"/>
                <note type="curatorial">29</note>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>
                        Jan 28-1961
                    </dateline>
                </opener>
                
                <salute>Gaki, dear Friend-</salute>
                <p>Well, let's see what happens to this note!! Perhaps by now some honest person for my  previous letter and has given it to you. Regardless, it contained my happy birthday wishes and my regrets that I was unable to walk into the pary and to call out-Hi Gaki! Would that have rocked the assembly? Am glad Com. Emmons had the courtesy to remember you also. In someways, BIA people are sorry he goes out of office, but in other ways, his performance lacked qualities on which our Southwest Indian friends had pinned certain Hopes.</p>
                <p>I called our friend Mae Bratton to tell her of your party and she to was</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.29.29-30"/>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                
                <p>happy to learn of the occassion. Now that you sent me the news clipping, I shall give her my other copy. You see, my "stoolie" in K.C. rushed the article to me P. Q, and I was selfish enough to keep it, but now, I shall bloom out in graciousness and give Mae B. that one and keep yours? Ain't I a mean ole Navajo witch??</p>
                <p>In my other note, I also inguired if this coming summer would bring you to Phoenix and if Hilda et al would come too. Last year I was in Brigham City for nearly the entire month of June and I learned I had missed you on your way to and from Arizona. My vacation plans are still nebulous, but I hope to see Missouri</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.29.29-30"/>
                <note type="curatorial">30</note>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                
                <p>in June. I have a couple of camp-out trips planned in July and August for my beloved Navajo Reservation. Did that last year and had a tremendous time. This time I want to go to Moab, Utah and takeoff from there into Kayenta and Monument Valley. Pick up your bedroll and come along!!</p>
                <p>Despite the lack of concrete evidence such as letters, I think of Hilda ever so frequently and especially do I think often of our walk into the pasture and the long, involved conversation until the wee morning hours. My heart indeed fills up when I recall her words regarding her personal problems. And, Joh, Si-'Kis -(Navajo for friend) I recalled our over a special line you wrote long ago - "The miracle of being love at all" - How utterly true!</p>
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.29.29-30"/>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                <note type="curatorial"></note>
                
                <p>My work as "dean of women" in the girls dorm, continues to give me joy and heartache at one time. School is now over 1/2 completed, and as I take a backward glance, I feel lucky to have come through this far so well. The other "over-schoulder" glance tells me I've not met the needs of 1/2 these kids and I'm crushed; My little ones need so much actual demonstration of somebody's caring, and my big old high school girls need to know I understand their crazy ways and that I strive to have them turn out ot be the best in the land. Guess it will all come out in the wash 10 years from now. -</p>
                <p>Gaki,again a Happy Anniverasy!! I look forward to seeing you this summer wither here of there!! My constant thoughts and good wishes to Hilda et al. -</p>
                <p>Thanks again for your copy of the K.C. article.</p>
                
                <closer>
                    <salute>Mit Lieher to all-</salute>
                    <signed>Elanita-</signed>
                    <signed>"Yanabah" (Navajo)</signed>
                </closer>
            </div1>
            
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
