<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.0.2/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.26.66c-66e_0001-3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt, March 14, 1958</title>
                <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                <principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2013</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
                </distributor>
                <pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
                <address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
                <idno>nei.j4a.26.66c-66e_0001-3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p></p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <notesStmt><note></note></notesStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</author>
                    <title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lucile Aly to John G. Neihardt</title>
                    <date when="1958-03-14">March 14, 1958</date>
                    <extent>3 pages</extent>
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository></repository>
                        <idno></idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <p>3 hand-written pages</p>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support></support>
                                <extent>3 pages
                                    <dimensions unit="mm"><height></height><width></width></dimensions>
                                </extent>
                                <condition>
                                    <p></p></condition>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                        <handDesc hands="1">
                            <handNote xml:id="type"><p>Media: type</p></handNote>
                            <handNote xml:id="jgn1" medium="pen"><p>Media: black ink</p></handNote>
                        </handDesc>
                        <typeDesc>
                            <typeNote><p></p></typeNote>
                        </typeDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history><origin></origin>
                        <provenance></provenance>
                        <acquisition></acquisition>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
                
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction>
                    <p></p>
                </correction>
                <normalization>
                    <p></p>
                </normalization>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Correspondence</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term>Business</term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau</persName></person></particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2015"><name xml:id="swa">Adrales, Samantha W.</name> Initial Encoding</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="az">Zeljkovic, Arman</name> Proofreading</change>
            <change when="2011"><name xml:id="ep">Pedigo, Erin</name> Transcription</change>
            
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            
            <div1 type="letter">
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66c-66e_0001"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66c</fw>
                
                <opener>
                    <dateline>March 14, 1958</dateline>
                
                    <salute>Dear Mr. Neihardt,</salute>
                </opener>
                <p>You <unclear>cannot</unclear> possibly know how much I appreciate your letter and comments. I know how much time all that takes, and you are wonderful to  do it. Bower is reading your comments over now for the third time, and he keeps looking up to say "You must be <hi rend="underline">careful</hi> with these papers. You must not let <hi rend="triple underline">anything</hi> happen to them."</p>
                
                <p>When I have <unclear>revised</unclear> the chapter I will send it back to you just to be sure &#8212; I want very much to have everything I write about you true as well as factual, and that is why it's good you can see it and make corrections. As you say, this chapter suffers from being part of a dissertation. It's out of focus to begin with because it has to be <unclear>keyed</unclear> to speech, and that throws the emphasis to your speaking and your criticism. That is all wrong, of course, but it's the only way in the dissertation. But I'd like the distortion to be as slight as possible, the part that is included must be true to the spirit and mood. I'd redo the <hi rend="caps">P-D</hi> paragraph; when I read it over I saw what you meant. Those are the things I want to catch. I understood the situation, but I didn't see what my <unclear>sketchy version</unclear> implied. I <unclear>can't</unclear> tell the whole story till the biography, but I'll help it.</p>
                
                <p>The biography chapter suffers a little too because some of the material that might go into it I am reserving for other chapters. The <unclear>Edwin Markhham</unclear> comments, for example, the Speyer reception, and a lot of things like that go into the readings chapter. I'm enclosing Chapter II, which takes up your rehtorical theory. Chapter III, now under way, is an analysis of your speaking <unclear>according</unclear> to the <unclear>classical</unclear> five canons. It is the <unclear/> of the <hi rend="underline">speaking</hi> part, as dissertations go, but I'm separating the lectures for Chapter IV because they are a chapter themselves. Chapter V will be readings. Your practice is <unclear>Aristotelian</unclear>; you may be surprised at how many of <unclear>Aristotle's lines</unclear> of argument you used. You could have written a <unclear>treatise</unclear> on rhetoric &#8212; but the <hi rend="underline">Songs</hi> were more important. I'm glad you did exactly what you did.</p>
                
                <p>In the last part I think I will add the statement from <del>D</del>Vicki Dewey's mother to Frances <unclear>McCurdy</unclear> that coming to Missouri was <unclear>worth</unclear> it for the opportunity to meet you and be in your class. You are right
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66c-663_0002"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66d</fw>
                
                    about "flaming" socialist &#8212; it's a breach of style besides being misleading. I should do something to keep the <unclear>word</unclear> <hi rend="underline">socialist</hi> from setting up wrong <unclear>connotations</unclear>; you were never a socialist as most people define the term in these times. Don't you think I should delete it altogether unless I can make <unclear>clear</unclear> that it really meant anti-materialistic humanitarian &#8212; or is that redundant?</p>
                
                <p>I will change the <hi rend="underline">traditionalism</hi> too. Words like that can carry <unclear>overtones</unclear> because of their label -<unclear>gravity</unclear>. It's not a precise contrast anyway; I'll reword. <hi rend="underline">Pessimism</hi> is better than <hi rend="underline"><unclear>cynicism</unclear></hi> for Robinson. I'll change that. It grew on him, didn't it? I've been reading his poetry to follow your reviews of it, and his later poems have a <unclear>different tone</unclear> from the early ones. The <unclear>Princeton</unclear> library, by the way, is looking for your letters from Robinson. The man there thinks it's a shame they <unclear>aren't</unclear> all together, and he has promised to let me know if he finds any trace.</p>
                
                <p>Mrs. Winkelman wrote me that a bunch of old <unclear>Nebraska</unclear> papers have <unclear>turned</unclear> up in somebody's attic in <unclear>Wismer</unclear>, and she is going to comb them for articles about you and send me facsimiles. I'm <unclear>enclosing</unclear> a poem she sent that may be yours. If you remember it, it's interesting to know, because you were only 15 &#8212; it's 1896. She also sent a small notice of your marriage in the <hi rend="underline">West Point <unclear>Republican</unclear></hi> and I'd like to add a few sentences from it to the chapter if you wouldn't mind. They are to the effect that your writing had "enhanced the glory" of your town country and state, and that this marriage was a <unclear/> to increase the light of art and literature."</p>  
                
                <p>I don't want to forget to tell you about our visit with Mr. Chaffee. He and the Skillings were very much pleased that you had sent the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>. They showed it to me and asked all sorts of questions about you. They are all reading the <hi rend="underline">Cycle</hi>, and you are adding a glow to their lives. You would like Mr. Skillings. He is confined to a hospital bed, and he's pretty weak, but he is alert and interested in everything. He is really an enthusiast on the Indian Wars, and knows a good bit about Custer and the <unclear>various</unclear> events of the war. They had not yet read the <hi rend="underline">Song of the Indian Wars</hi>, and I wish I could be there
                
                <pb facs="nei.j4a.26.66c-66e_0003"/>
                
                <fw type="curatorial">66e</fw>
                
                    when they do to see their faces. Mr. Skillings rather thinks <unclear>Reno</unclear> was made a scapegoat in the Custer fight business &#8212; we had a good time talking about it.</p>
                
                <p>Mr. Chaffee said something I want to ask you about too. He says Williams Jennings Bryan used to come to Wayne in the summers and teach at <del>Wayne</del><add>the college</add>; he stayed at the Chaffees. Apparently he was a friend of Dr. Pile. Do you remember anything about this? Did you ever meet him?</p>
                
                <p>You are certainly right about patterns. I have felt it too in my life, although I didn't have an assignment like yours &#8212; just a <unclear>sense</unclear> that I had something to do in the world that I was being prepared for. It's a strange feeling that can't be <unclear>expressed</unclear> to other people except very rarely, because <unclear>most</unclear> would think such a feeling "queer." Much more than I can explain I feel a deep down current of &#8212; well, <hi rend="underline">sympathy</hi> is the <unclear>closest word</unclear>, but it's not exact &#8212; for you and Mrs. Neihardt. Bower feels it too &#8212; a psychic kinship as if we knew the same things, or at least <hi rend="underline">some</hi> of the same things. I could write a book about Mrs. Neihardt &#8212; when I have read some of the letters she wrote to the girls I have loved her and them and my own daughters all in the same, <unclear>pulse-beat</unclear>. I'm not <unclear>unique</unclear> in this &#8212; hundreds of years from now other people will read the letters and feel the same way. You are both gifts to the world in a sense; each of you is all men or all women without losing a <unclear>jot</unclear> of your own individuality. It has given you a responsibility that you met and <unclear>accepted</unclear>, and I can never see that vanity <unclear/> in at all. I simply cannot see vanity in anything have ever said or done or thought. You respect your work, that's all, and you should.</p>
                
                <p>This is a volume, but I did want to thank you and bring you up to date on our visits with Mr. Chaffee. Will go up to see him again, and I still have some letters out that I'll <unclear>report</unclear> or when I get answers.</p>
                
                <p>Our best to everyone, and please <unclear>read</unclear> this chapter at your <unclear>leisure</unclear>. The third <unclear>one</unclear> will take a little time yet.</p>
                <closer>
                    <signed>Lucile Aly</signed>
                </closer>
                
            </div1>
        </body>
        
        <back></back>
    </text>
</TEI>
