<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="nei.j4a.28.9a-9e">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Letter from Lewis Atherton to John G. Neihardt, January 19, 1960</title>
<author>Atherton, Lewis Eldon</author>
<principal>Gossin, Pamela</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>The Papers of John G. Neihardt</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno>nei.j4a.28.9a-9e</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note>Including contract with University of Missouri.</note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Atherton, Lewis Eldon</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Letter from Lewis Atherton to John G. Neihardt, January 19, 1960</title>
<date when="1960-01-19">January 19, 1960</date>
<extent>5 pages</extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p>5 typed pages</p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Correspondence</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Business</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Parker, Ralph Halsted, 1909-1990</term>
<term>Bowling, Dale O.</term>
<term>Robnett, Mary</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="works">
<term type="Neihardt"></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
<correspDesc>
<correspAction type="sentBy">
<persName>Atherton, Lewis Eldon</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
<date when="1960-01-19"/>
</correspAction>
<correspAction type="deliveredTo">
<persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName>
<placeName>Columbia (Mo.)</placeName>
</correspAction>
</correspDesc>
<particDesc><person role="recipient"><persName>Neihardt, John Gneisenau, 1881-1973</persName></person></particDesc>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name>Weakly, Laura K.</name> Proofreading and encoding</change>
<change when="2017"><name>Dakota State University</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

 <text>
<body>

<div1 type="letter">
<pb facs="nei.J4a.28.9a-9e_0002" />

<note type="curatorial">9a</note>
<div2>
<fw>
<address>
<addrLine>UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI</addrLine>
<addrLine>COLUMBIA</addrLine>

<addrLine>INTER-DEPARTMENT CORRESPONDENCE</addrLine>
</address>
</fw>

<opener>
<address>
<addrLine>TO: Dr. John C. Neihardt</addrLine>
<addrLine>209 Jesse Hall</addrLine>
</address>
<dateline>January 19, 1960</dateline>

<salute>Dear Dr. Neihardt:</salute>
</opener>

<p>I have been talking with Mr. Peterson, the University attorney, about
a contract to cover your papers. I am enclosing a copy of the type of contract
which is ordinarily used. We shall, of course, want to make some
 changes in this. One thing that we must decide is whether you want to deposit,
at this time, all the remaining papers that you have. In that case,
a contract somewhat similar to the blank form enclosed should be adequate.
On the other hand, if you wish to retain, until the time of your death, the
papers now in your possession, the legal document would need to be drawn as
a "Deed of Gift" specifying delivery of the manuscripts by the administrator
of your estate. Whichever form you wish to use will include the following
reservations: 1. That the papers will be restricted during your
lifetime to use only by students approved by you. If you wish, we can
place additional restrictions. 2. That the Western Historical Manuscripts
Collection will provide care and preservation of these papers comparable to
that availabe in the Library of Congress. Professor Peterson suggested
that the Section 4 of the enclosed contract might, perhaps, be adequate coverage.
But I shall be happy to include the promise of care comparable to that
given by the Library of Congress. 3. The Western Historical Manuscripts
Collection will calendar the papers and will make available a list of the papers
included in the John G. Neihardt Collection for the use of any research
library seeking such information.</p>

<p>I am writing this letter and including a copy of our usual type of
contract so that you can think the matter over before I see you again.
I shall come to your office at 11:00 Thursday, the 21st in the hopes of
 discussing what we shall include in the contract. If you cannot be there
at that time, I shall try to arrange another date.</p>

<p>I am greatly excited over your suggestion that you would consider
giving your library to the University of Missouri at the time of your
death. If we used the core of material of this library as the
John G. Neihardt Memorial Collection and maintained it intact in a fitting
place in our library. I believe that it would be a great stimulus
in the future to others to give books relating to the field which you
have made famous as a means of expanding our holdings in the field.</p>


</div2>

<pb/>
<div2>
<fw>
<address>
<addrLine>UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI</addrLine>
<addrLine>COLUMBIA</addrLine>

<addrLine>INTER-DEPARTMENT CORRESPONDENCE</addrLine>
</address>
</fw>

<opener>
<address>
<addrLine>TO: Dr. John C. Neihardt</addrLine>
</address>

Page 2<lb/>

<dateline>January 19, 1969</dateline>

<salute>SUBJECT:</salute>
</opener>

<p>Dr. Ralph Parker plans to talk to you about this matter in the near
future.</p>

<closer>
<salute>With best regards.</salute>

<salute>Sincerely yours,</salute>

<signed>Lewis Altherton</signed>

<address>
<addrLine>Lewis Atherton, director</addrLine>
<addrLine>Western Historical Manuscripts Collection</addrLine>
<addrLine>Professor of History</addrLine>
</address>

<note>LA:mf</note>
<note>Encl.</note>

</closer>

</div2>

<pb/>
<note type="curatorial">9c</note>

<div2>
<head>AGREEMENT FOR GIFT OF PAPERS AND LIBRARY OF JOHN G. NEIHARDT</head>

<p>THIS AGREEMENT, entered into their 14th day of April , 1961, by and between JOHN G. NEIHARDT, Donor, and THE CURATORS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI, a public corporation of the State of Missouri, University,</p>
	<p>WITNESSETH:</p>
	<p>1. That Donor hereby gives and transfers to University upon the terms and conditions hereinafter set forth his manuscript collection and his personal library, the delivery of which will be made upon the execution of this instrument.</p>
	<p>2. The manuscript collection shall be known and designated as the "John G. Neihardt Manuscript Collection" and the library shall be known and designated as the "John G. Neihardt Memorial Collection".</p>
	<p>3. In consideration of said gift the University agrees:</p>
		<p>A. To keep said manuscripts and library in a fireproof location and to use all reasonable care to assure the safety of said collection.</p>
		<p>B. To keep the manuscripts as a part of the Western Historical Manuscripts Collection and in the Western Historical Manuscripts Collection Room in the University Library Building and the same shall be classified with the director of said Collection. </p>
		<p>C. To keep the library intact at one focal point in the University Library-at-large.</p>
		<p>D. The manuscripts and library shall remain in the custody and quarters of the Western Historical Manuscripts Collection and the University Library and shall be removed only in case of emergency for temporary storage, in which case the University

<fw>1</fw>

<pb/>

<note type="curatorial">9d</note>

 shall use all reasonable care in selecting a safe and suitable temporary depository, and the same shall be returned to the original quarters as soon as possible.</p>
		<p>E. Any gifts of additional material to be added to the Neihardt Memorial Collection shall have affixed thereto a book-plate listing each volume as an addition to the Collection.</p>
		<p>F. To furnish to the Library of Congress reproductions of the Neihardt manuscripts. The reproductions shall be completed and sent to the Library of Congress within one (1) year after the date the Western Historical Manuscripts Collection returns to its permanent quarters.</p>
		<p>G. To use recommended standard procedures for the restoration and preservation of items in the Neihardt manuscripts, such as application of the laminating process, to documents that will benefit from it. This work shall be completed within one (1) year after the Western Historical Manuscripts Collection returns to its permanent quarters.</p>
	<p>4. In consideration of the University agreeing to accept and care for the manuscripts and library, Donor agrees that he will, by his will, provide that his library, exclusive of the part hereby given to the University, and any additional manuscripts that he may have will be bequeathed to the University.</p>
	<p>5. Donor agrees to make available to the University the concrete bust made of him by his wife when requested by the University for the purpose of having a bronze casting made therefrom for display in the University library. The same shall be returned to the Donor as soon as the bronze casting is completed. The University shall not be liable for the loss , or damage to the bust while it is


in its possession unless it shall fail to use reasonable care to
assure its protection and safety.</p>
	<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the Donor has hetero set his hand, and
the University has caused this instrument to be executed by its
duly authorized officers and its corporate seal to be hetero affixed.</p>

<ab>John G. Neihardt<lb/>
JOHN G. NEIHARDT<lb/>
DONOR</ab>

<ab>APPROVED:<lb/>
Ralph Parker<lb/>
Librarian<lb/>
Lewis Atherton<lb/>
Lewis Atherton, Director,<lb/>
Western Historical<lb/>
Manuscripts Collection<lb/>
THE CURATORS OF THE UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI
</ab>

<ab>ATTEST:<lb/>
Mary Robnett<lb/>
Mary Robnett, Secretary<lb/>
Dale  O. Bowling<lb/>
Dale O. Bowling, Business manager<lb/>
UNIVERSITY</ab>

<fw>3</fw>

</div2>
</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
